<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://selfh.st/apps</id>
  <title>AdGuard Home Releases</title>
  <updated>2025-02-27T22:31:40.485805-05:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>selfh.st</name>
    <email>contact@selfh.st</email>
  </author>
  <link href="https://selfh.st/apps" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>Self-hosted software releases generated by selfh.st</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/AdguardTeam/AdGuardHome/releases/tag/v0.107.53</id>
    <title>New release for AdGuard Home: AdGuard Home v0.107.53</title>
    <updated>2024-10-03T08:46:45-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>AdguardTeam/AdGuardHome</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;It's been a while since we postponed the next AdGuard Home update for a few months. But of course, we had a good reason for it: with the help of community members (we are very thankful to you! :pray:), we discovered two vulnerabilities and have been working on patching them. Testing the solutions took a bit longer than expected, but in the end, we believe in quality over speed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Luckily, it's not all patching vulnerabilities and fixing bugs; we've made some improvements, too. For example, we've added support for 64-bit RISC-V architecture and Ecosia search engine to Safe Search. Find the complete changelog below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Acknowledgments&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A special thanks to our open-source contributor, @javabean, to @itz-d0dgy and @go-compile for reporting the vulnerabilities, our community moderators team, as well as to everyone who filed and inspected issues, added translations, and helped us test this release!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Full changelog&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Security&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Previous versions of AdGuard Home allowed users to add any system file it had access to as filters, exposing them to be world-readable.  To prevent this, AdGuard Home now allows adding filtering-rule list files only from files matching the patterns enumerated in the &lt;code&gt;filtering.safe_fs_patterns&lt;/code&gt; property in the configuration file.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We thank @itz-d0dgy for reporting this vulnerability, designated CVE-2024-36814, to us.
- Additionally, AdGuard Home will now try to change the permissions of its files and directories to more restrictive ones to prevent similar vulnerabilities as well as limit the access to the configuration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We thank @go-compile for reporting this vulnerability, designated CVE-2024-36586, to us.
- Go version has been updated to prevent the possibility of exploiting the Go vulnerabilities fixed in &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/g/golang-announce/c/NKEc8VT7Fz0"&gt;1.23.2&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Added&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Support for 64-bit RISC-V architecture (#5704).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ecosia search engine is now supported in safe search (#5009).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Changed&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Upstream server URL domain names requirements has been relaxed and now follow the same rules as their domain specifications.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Configuration changes&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this release, the schema version has changed from 28 to 29.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The new array &lt;code&gt;filtering.safe_fs_patterns&lt;/code&gt; contains glob patterns for paths of files that can be added as local filtering-rule lists.  The migration should add list files that have already been added, as well as the default value, &lt;code&gt;$DATA_DIR/userfilters/*&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Fixed&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Property &lt;code&gt;clients.runtime_sources.dhcp&lt;/code&gt; in the configuration file not taking effect.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stale Google safe search domains list (#7155).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bing safe search from Edge sidebar (#7154).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Text overflow on the query log page (#7119).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Known issues&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Due to the complexity of the Windows permissions architecture and poor support from the standard Go library, we have to postpone the proper automated Windows fix until the next release.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Temporary workaround:&lt;/strong&gt;  Set the permissions of the &lt;code&gt;AdGuardHome&lt;/code&gt; directory to more restrictive ones manually.  To do that:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Locate the &lt;code&gt;AdGuardHome&lt;/code&gt; directory.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Right-click on it and navigate to &lt;em&gt;Properties → Security → Advanced&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(You might need to disable permission inheritance to make them more restricted.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Adjust to give the &lt;code&gt;Full control&lt;/code&gt; access to only the user which runs AdGuard Home.  Typically, &lt;code&gt;Administrator&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An example of a what a properly restricted configuration could look like:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="permissions" src="https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/c8ab24a4-e39c-46e9-8aef-49130ea76f8b" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/AdguardTeam/AdGuardHome/releases/tag/v0.107.53" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/AdguardTeam/AdGuardHome/releases/tag/v0.107.54</id>
    <title>New release for AdGuard Home: AdGuard Home v0.107.54</title>
    <updated>2024-11-06T08:26:47-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>AdguardTeam/AdGuardHome</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;This AdGuard Home update will be of particular interest to Windows users. We've made the necessary security improvements for Windows that we didn't have time to implement in the previous version. But there's always something for everyone in AdGuard Home updates, not just for Windows enjoyers: filters perform better now and, of course, we've done out fair share of bug fixing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Acknowledgments&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A special thanks to our open-source contributor @GnatorX, our community moderators team, as well as to everyone who filed and inspected issues, added translations, and helped us test this release!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Full changelog&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See also the &lt;a href="https://github.com/AdguardTeam/AdGuardHome/milestone/89?closed=1"&gt;v0.107.54 GitHub milestone&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Security&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;AdGuard Home now properly sets permissions to its files and directories on Windows (#7314).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Changed&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved filtering performance (#6818).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Fixed&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Repetitive statistics log messages (#7338).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Custom client cache (#7250).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Missing runtime clients with information from the system hosts file on first AdGuard Home start (#7315).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/AdguardTeam/AdGuardHome/releases/tag/v0.107.54" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/AdguardTeam/AdGuardHome/releases/tag/v0.107.55</id>
    <title>New release for AdGuard Home: AdGuard Home v0.107.55</title>
    <updated>2024-12-11T08:32:39-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>AdguardTeam/AdGuardHome</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;Time for another release! We encourage all Windows users to play close attention as it addresses a bug that has been affecting some Windows installations. For the rest of AdGuard Home aficionados, we've updated Go version to shore up some vulnerabilities and have dealt with a couple leaks :potable_water:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[!NOTE]
This release includes a fix for #7400, which was caused by changes related to #7314 that broke some Windows installations.  We've changed the approach to permission handling on Windows to be much more careful about modifying them, but if you're not concerned about this feature, you can always use a &lt;code&gt;--no-permcheck&lt;/code&gt; command line option (it works with the &lt;code&gt;-s install&lt;/code&gt; command).  This will disable any permission manipulation and may leave the system vulnerable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Acknowledgments&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A special thanks to our open-source contributor, @MaggieFero, our community moderators team, as well as to everyone who filed and inspected issues, added translations, and helped us test this release!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Full changelog&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See also the &lt;a href="https://github.com/AdguardTeam/AdGuardHome/milestone/90?closed=1"&gt;v0.107.55 GitHub milestone&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Security&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The permission check and migration on Windows has been fixed to use the Windows security model more accurately (#7400).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Go version has been updated to prevent the possibility of exploiting the Go vulnerabilities fixed in &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/g/golang-announce/c/3DyiMkYx4Fo"&gt;1.23.4&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Windows executables are now signed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Added&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;code&gt;--no-permcheck&lt;/code&gt; command-line option to disable checking and migration of permissions for the security-sensitive files and directories, which caused issues on Windows (#7400).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Fixed&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Setup guide styles in Firefox.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Goroutine leak during the upstream DNS server test (#7357).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Goroutine leak during configuration update resulting in increased response time (#6818).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/AdguardTeam/AdGuardHome/releases/tag/v0.107.55" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/AdguardTeam/AdGuardHome/releases/tag/v0.107.56</id>
    <title>New release for AdGuard Home: AdGuard Home v0.107.56</title>
    <updated>2025-01-23T09:11:42-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>AdguardTeam/AdGuardHome</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;We are steadily picking up the pace in the new year, starting with this small update. :runner: Inside are some fresh bugfixes, a new API, and an updated Go version to shore up some vulnerabilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Acknowledgments&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A special thanks to our open-source contributor @Hermholtz, our community moderators team, as well as to everyone who filed and inspected issues, added translations, and helped us test this release!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Full changelog&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Security&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Go version has been updated to prevent the possibility of exploiting the Go vulnerabilities fixed in &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/g/golang-announce/c/sSaUhLA-2SI"&gt;1.23.5&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Added&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The new HTTP API &lt;code&gt;POST /clients/search&lt;/code&gt; that finds clients by their IP addresses, CIDRs, MAC addresses, or ClientIDs.  See &lt;code&gt;openapi/openapi.yaml&lt;/code&gt; for the full description.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Deprecated&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;code&gt;GET /clients/find&lt;/code&gt; HTTP API is deprecated.  Use the new &lt;code&gt;POST /clients/search&lt;/code&gt; API.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Fixed&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Request count link in the clients table (#7513).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The formatting of large numbers on the dashboard (#7329).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/AdguardTeam/AdGuardHome/releases/tag/v0.107.56" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/AdguardTeam/AdGuardHome/releases/tag/v0.107.57</id>
    <title>New release for AdGuard Home: AdGuard Home v0.107.57</title>
    <updated>2025-02-20T09:58:55-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>AdguardTeam/AdGuardHome</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;The year 2025 is only picking up steam, but some of us already need a time out :clock10: Speaking of timeouts, in the new version we've added the ability to specify the upstream timeout in the Web UI, alongside with some bug fixes and security updates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Acknowledgments&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A special thanks to our open-source contributor @janpieper, our community moderators team, as well as to everyone who filed and inspected issues, added translations, and helped us test this release!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Full changelog&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See also the &lt;a href="https://github.com/AdguardTeam/AdGuardHome/milestone/92?closed=1"&gt;v0.107.57 GitHub milestone&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Security&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Go version has been updated to prevent the possibility of exploiting the Go vulnerabilities fixed in &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/g/golang-announce/c/xU1ZCHUZw3k"&gt;1.23.6&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Added&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The ability to specify the upstream timeout in the Web UI.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Changed&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Fastest IP address&lt;/em&gt; upstream mode now correctly collects statistics for all upstream DNS servers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Fixed&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The hostnames of DHCP clients not being shown in the &lt;em&gt;Top clients&lt;/em&gt; table on the dashboard (#7627).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The formatting of large numbers in the upstream table and query log (#7590).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/AdguardTeam/AdGuardHome/releases/tag/v0.107.57" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
