<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://selfh.st/apps</id>
  <title>AdventureLog Releases</title>
  <updated>2024-12-11T10:34:26.403093-05:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>selfh.st</name>
    <email>contact@selfh.st</email>
  </author>
  <link href="https://selfh.st/apps" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>Self-hosted software releases generated by selfh.st</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/seanmorley15/AdventureLog/releases/tag/v0.5.1</id>
    <title>New release for AdventureLog: AdventureLog v0.5.1</title>
    <updated>2024-08-11T13:49:11-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>seanmorley15/AdventureLog</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;This update fixes a few smaller bugs present in the last release. It also introduces a schema change for all adventures and users. &lt;strong&gt;UUIDs&lt;/strong&gt; are now the primary keys and are used to share Adventures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keep on exploring!&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/seanmorley15/AdventureLog/releases/tag/v0.5.1" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/seanmorley15/AdventureLog/releases/tag/v0.5.2</id>
    <title>New release for AdventureLog: AdventureLog v0.5.2</title>
    <updated>2024-08-17T09:01:25-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>seanmorley15/AdventureLog</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;Hi everyone!
Thanks so much for your support for AdventureLog over the past few days. AdventureLog is my first ever development project and I learned how to code to in order to build AdventureLog, for this reason there are some quirks that I have been working out along the way. These past few days have taught me a lot too! Sorry for the confusing setup process and thanks for being patient. Streamlining the setup is definitely a priority of mine. This update contains lots of bug fixes brought to my attention by the community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;What's New&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed issues with user changing email and not being able to sign in again&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added a consistent date format in all parts of the app&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed many deployment issues&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed duplicate visited regions from being added&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added option to disable registration&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Many other small things!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;What's Next:&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New create adventure modal&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ability to upload multiple images to an adventure and view them with a carousel&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ARM Image&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Start/end dates for adventures&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(lots more not mentioned here!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Resources:&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://docs.adventurelog.app/"&gt;Documentation Site&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Using a Synology NAS? Learn how to install AdventureLog on your NAS by mariushosting: &lt;a href="https://mariushosting.com/how-to-install-adventurelog-on-your-synology-nas/"&gt;https://mariushosting.com/how-to-install-adventurelog-on-your-synology-nas/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keep on adventuring and stay tuned for more!&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/seanmorley15/AdventureLog/releases/tag/v0.5.2" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/seanmorley15/AdventureLog/releases/tag/v0.6.0</id>
    <title>New release for AdventureLog: AdventureLog v0.6.0</title>
    <updated>2024-08-24T16:31:22-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>seanmorley15/AdventureLog</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h2&gt;What's New&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New GitHub workflows for multi-arch image generation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New docker-compose file with Traefik support&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New adventure creation and edit modal with multiple image support&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Adds support for end dates to adventures&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make images open in a display larger on click&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New transportation display card&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add new regions to world travel&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Makes the world travel data auto seed on startup&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Migrates to PostGIS database&lt;/strong&gt; (update docker-compose with correct database image if already using the app)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Adventures can now auto mark supported regions if they are located in one. This process can also be manually triggered in settings.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Many bugs have been fixes - thanks!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Contributors&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;@tedski made their first contribution in https://github.com/seanmorley15/AdventureLog/pull/234&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;@PhiCoderX made their first contribution in https://github.com/seanmorley15/AdventureLog/pull/249&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;@lovwyr made their first contribution in https://github.com/seanmorley15/AdventureLog/pull/260&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;@seanmorley15 developer and maintainer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keep on exploring!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Full Changelog&lt;/strong&gt;: https://github.com/seanmorley15/AdventureLog/compare/v0.5.2...v0.6.0&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/seanmorley15/AdventureLog/releases/tag/v0.6.0" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/seanmorley15/AdventureLog/releases/tag/v0.7.0</id>
    <title>New release for AdventureLog: AdventureLog v0.7.0</title>
    <updated>2024-10-15T23:55:07-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>seanmorley15/AdventureLog</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;Hi everyone! I am super excited to announce AdventureLog v0.7.0! This is one of the biggest updates I have ever released and I am super happy its finally ready for all of you to enjoy. The majority of this update is based around community feedback and ideas which is awesome!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;What's New&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Adventures 📍&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Adventures can now be visited multiple times by adding a new visit.&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Existing adventure dates will be automatically migrated to this new format&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Adventures now use categories for organization.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A new adventure creation/edit modal simplifies the process and has a cleaner overall design with dropdown menus.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Collections 🍱&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Collections can now be shared with other public users for collaboration!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Collections now have a link field so you can attach things like photo albums right to your collection.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;World Travel 🗺️&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The World Travel dataset now includes &lt;strong&gt;every ISO defined country and region&lt;/strong&gt;. It is based off of a new dataset &lt;a href="https://github.com/dr5hn/countries-states-cities-database"&gt;dr5hn/countries-states-cities-database&lt;/a&gt;. Searching for countries is now supported. Capitals and world regions are now listed on the country card.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Profiles 👥&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Users can now toggle their profile to be public. This allows other users to share collections with them for collaboration.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Bug Fixes 🐛&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed bug where collection dates during daylight savings time would cause errors in date placement&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed login issue with usernames of different cases&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Other&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New logo for AdventureLog! Thanks @redtechtiger!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Releases now include a multi-arch image like pushes to main&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Docker compose file now has more comments for clarity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New Aesthetic Dark theme (its my favorite by far)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Sponsorship 💖&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.buymeacoffee.com/seanmorley15"&gt;&lt;img alt="&amp;quot;Buy Me A Coffee&amp;quot;" src="https://www.buymeacoffee.com/assets/img/custom_images/orange_img.png" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
As a computer science student, I pour my free time into developing and enhancing AdventureLog, driven by my passion for this project and its potential to make adventure planning easier for everyone. Your support, no matter the amount, means the world to me. It shows that you believe in the project and its future. I’m excited to announce that I’ve launched my page on Buy Me A Coffee—check it out!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hope you all enjoy!
Feel free to join the release discussion below to share feedback and ideas or anything else related to this update!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Happy travels,
Sean @seanmorley15&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/seanmorley15/AdventureLog/releases/tag/v0.7.0" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/seanmorley15/AdventureLog/releases/tag/v0.7.1</id>
    <title>New release for AdventureLog: AdventureLog v0.7.1</title>
    <updated>2024-11-13T09:28:21-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>seanmorley15/AdventureLog</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;Hi everyone! I am super excited to announce the release of AdventureLog v0.7.1. This update includes a lot of improvements that make using AdventureLog more enjoyable and accessible. This update is largely community driven as it addresses more than 10 enhancement requests (thanks everyone!). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;What's New ✨&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Docker Compose Change  🐋&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[!IMPORTANT]&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;While the app will still function normally without these changes&lt;/em&gt;, they are recommended for the best support and stability
The &lt;strong&gt;migration guide&lt;/strong&gt; can be found here: https://adventurelog.app/docs/guides/v0-7-1_migration.html
- Migrated nginx inside of server container for easier deployment, removed external nginx requirement
- App now uses gunicorn for better performance at scale&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Adventures 📍&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Adventures can now be sorted by visit status (visited or planned) on the adventures screen.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Adventure create/edit modal now supports reverse geocoding locations. This means that for most places, the location field will be auto filled when you click on the map. It now has a popup of the associated world travel region and allows you to mark the region as visited if its not already. This makes it easier to track your world region visits!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The adventure map now shows previews of images and has the emoji of the category on the map pin!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In settings, you can perform a visited region check. This will scan all of your visited adventures and mark the associated world travel region as visited if its detected in the adventure. This serves as a bulk operation for for existing adventures.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;World Travel 🗺️&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;World travel regions can now be sorted by world regions and visit status. The statuses are fully visited, partially visited, and not visited.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Bug Fixes 🐛&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed a bug where sorting by date would return to home screen&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Localization 🌐&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Migrated app to a localization framework&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added toggle for languages on the &lt;code&gt;...&lt;/code&gt; menu in the top right.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Supported Languages&lt;/strong&gt;: English, Spanish, French, German, Italian, Chinese, Dutch, Swedish&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Other&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New login and signup screen featuring adventures from community members (submitted in discord server).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What's Next ⏭️&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Custom categories for adventures&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ability to link adventures to multiple collections&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MFA and ODIC auth&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Immich integration&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Sponsorship 💖&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.buymeacoffee.com/seanmorley15"&gt;&lt;img alt="&amp;quot;Buy Me A Coffee&amp;quot;" src="https://www.buymeacoffee.com/assets/img/custom_images/orange_img.png" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
As a computer science student, I pour my free time into developing and enhancing AdventureLog, driven by my passion for this project and its potential to make adventure planning easier for everyone. Your support, no matter the amount, means the world to me. It shows that you believe in the project and its future. I’m excited to announce that I’ve launched my page on Buy Me A Coffee—check it out!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hope you all enjoy!
Feel free to join the release discussion below to share feedback and ideas or anything else related to this update!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Happy travels,
Sean @seanmorley15&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/seanmorley15/AdventureLog/releases/tag/v0.7.1" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
