<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://selfh.st/apps</id>
  <title>Appsmith Releases</title>
  <updated>2024-10-16T22:32:00.717784-04:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>selfh.st</name>
    <email>contact@selfh.st</email>
  </author>
  <link href="https://selfh.st/apps" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>Self-hosted software releases generated by selfh.st</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/appsmithorg/appsmith/releases/tag/v1.41</id>
    <title>New release for Appsmith: Release v1.41 🌈</title>
    <updated>2024-09-17T23:38:12-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>appsmithorg/appsmith</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;New Features:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Action Redesign Enhancements:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Google Sheets Plugin:&lt;/strong&gt; Updated the configuration to use sections and zones format. This change improves organization and usability. (#36117)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Firestore Plugin:&lt;/strong&gt; Updated the configuration to use sections and zones format for better structure and management. (#36097)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MongoDB Plugin:&lt;/strong&gt; Redesigned configuration to use sections and zones format, enhancing configuration clarity. (#36098)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Databricks Plugin:&lt;/strong&gt; Revised the configuration to sections and zones format, streamlining setup. (#36057)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;S3 Plugin:&lt;/strong&gt; Upgraded the configuration to dual zone format and improved sorting field responsiveness. (#36090)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Table Search Enhancement:&lt;/strong&gt; Enabled table search to include both label and value for tables with select column types, providing a more comprehensive search experience. (#36061)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Auto Selection Feature:&lt;/strong&gt; Added automatic parent selection for removed components, simplifying component management. (#36282)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;UQI Upgrade:&lt;/strong&gt; Enhanced the S3 plugin configuration with a dual-zone format and improved field sorting responsiveness. (#36090)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Improved Error Messages:&lt;/strong&gt; Enhanced error messages for PostgreSQL connections to provide more clarity on connection issues. (#35167)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fixes:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;API Test File Consolidation:&lt;/strong&gt; Consolidated the API test file, improving organization and maintainability. (#36318)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DB URL Trimming:&lt;/strong&gt; Fixed issue with trimming DB URLs and removing special characters during backup and restore processes. (#36201)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reverse PR Comment Issue:&lt;/strong&gt; Addressed and fixed the issue related to reverse PR comments. (#36308)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;IDE Header Height:&lt;/strong&gt; Corrected the header height usage in the IDE to ensure consistent display. (#36297)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;503 Error Recovery:&lt;/strong&gt; Fixed recovery issue for 503 errors to enhance system reliability. (#36252)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Invalid Sheet Method Default:&lt;/strong&gt; Set a default invalid method value in Gsheet datasource to prevent errors. (#36264)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;List Widget Bug:&lt;/strong&gt; Fixed an issue with the list widget as per Bug29566 specifications. (#36260)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Page Data Call Issue:&lt;/strong&gt; Resolved issue where page data DB call was being executed twice, improving performance. (#36247)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Anthropic Plugin Configuration:&lt;/strong&gt; Updated the configuration for the Anthropic plugin with a better file structure. (#36223)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;RBAC Toast Errors:&lt;/strong&gt; Fixed an issue where RBAC errors were not displaying toasts, improving error visibility. (#36244)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gsheets Unauth Method Removal:&lt;/strong&gt; Removed unauthorized method from Gsheets to streamline functionality. (#36125)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;updateWithoutPermission Bug:&lt;/strong&gt; Corrected &lt;code&gt;updateWithoutPermission&lt;/code&gt; method to properly update user data instead of saving it. (#36206)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Select Key Value Fix:&lt;/strong&gt; Removed unnecessary select key-value selections and fixed default behavior. (#36158)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/appsmithorg/appsmith/releases/tag/v1.41" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/appsmithorg/appsmith/releases/tag/v1.42</id>
    <title>New release for Appsmith: Release v1.42 🌈</title>
    <updated>2024-09-26T02:36:09-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>appsmithorg/appsmith</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;New Features:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added a warning message in the response pane when the prepared statement is enabled. (#36407)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Made images adaptable to support both PostgreSQL and MongoDB URIs. (#36424)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Database queries are now responsive (#36168)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Fixes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Master package step now includes server artifacts for PostgreSQL and MongoDB. (#36516)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Resolved query instance failure caused by a missing prepared statement object. (#36493)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Corrected the initial store value in the query response tab test case. (#36487)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed the &lt;code&gt;isRequired&lt;/code&gt; validation property for table select columns. (#36375)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Resolved CTA button issue for Git import modal. (#36364)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Corrected the "show bindings" menu not appearing in split mode. (#36378)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Resolved an undefined &lt;code&gt;this.rootSpan&lt;/code&gt; bug in &lt;code&gt;PageLoadInstrumentation&lt;/code&gt;. (#36459)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed incorrect updating of &lt;code&gt;selectedRowIndex&lt;/code&gt; when the primary column is set. (#36393)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Resolved duplicate page name error not disappearing when navigating to other pages. (#36320)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed inline editing flaky test. (#36366)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Corrected &lt;code&gt;Datasource&lt;/code&gt; preview not taking full height. (#36389)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed NPE for policies when &lt;code&gt;policyMap&lt;/code&gt; is not present. (#36323)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed displaced "show bindings" sub-menu position. (#36340)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Resolved logger not working in plugins. (#36231)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed caddy partial metrics. (#36376)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/appsmithorg/appsmith/releases/tag/v1.42" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/appsmithorg/appsmith/releases/tag/v1.43</id>
    <title>New release for Appsmith: Release v1.43 🌈</title>
    <updated>2024-10-02T02:33:57-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>appsmithorg/appsmith</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h3&gt;Features&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;LRU Cache for MockDB Connections&lt;/strong&gt; (#36480): We've introduced a Least Recently Used (LRU) cache for our mockDB connections, improving performance and efficiency when handling database operations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Fixes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Modal Height Adjustment&lt;/strong&gt; (#36589): Resolved an issue with modal height by removing the minimum content constraint, ensuring a better user experience.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Plugin Action Editor Improvements&lt;/strong&gt; (#36574): Implemented quick fixes to enhance the current functionality of the Plugin Action Editor, making it more user-friendly and responsive.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Image Icon Alignment&lt;/strong&gt; (#35992): Fixed the alignment of icons when the data type is set to image, ensuring consistency and visual appeal.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;JavaScript Library Load Handling&lt;/strong&gt; (#36539): Improved the functionality for loading JavaScript libraries, particularly handling default exports more effectively.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mongo Schema Collections Order&lt;/strong&gt; (#36062): Corrected the order of Mongo schema collections in the Mongo plugin for better organization and clarity.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Unique Default Export Naming&lt;/strong&gt; (#36483): Updated the handling of JavaScript library default exports to use a unique name instead of the default key, reducing potential conflicts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/appsmithorg/appsmith/releases/tag/v1.43" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/appsmithorg/appsmith/releases/tag/v1.44</id>
    <title>New release for Appsmith: Release v1.44 🌈 - ERRONEOUS RELEASE</title>
    <updated>2024-10-10T00:31:42-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>appsmithorg/appsmith</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This release has been marked as defunct due to critical issues. Please avoid using this version. Please use v1.44.1 instead.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Fixes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Widget Icon in Connect To Options&lt;/strong&gt;: Resolved issue with widget icon display in the "Connect To" options within the one-click binding menu. (#36703)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Caddy Cache Control Headers&lt;/strong&gt;: Removed cache control headers for error-handled requests in Caddy. (#36590)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Spring Upgrade&lt;/strong&gt;: Cleared all sessions to support the Spring upgrade. (#36695)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Alert Message in Select Widget&lt;/strong&gt;: Ensured alert messages trigger only once when &lt;code&gt;onDropdownClose&lt;/code&gt; is called in the select widget. (#34812)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ShareApp Load Issue&lt;/strong&gt;: Fixed loading issue with ShareApp case. (#36627)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MySQL Plugin Tests&lt;/strong&gt;: Fixed MySQL plugin tests by closing open connections properly. (#36657)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Redundant Eval Trigger&lt;/strong&gt;: Removed a redundant eval trigger that caused unnecessary processes. (#36433)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Max Connection Pool Size&lt;/strong&gt;: Updated the max connection pool size and adjusted the &lt;code&gt;datasourceDestroy&lt;/code&gt; method for better resource management. (#36631)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Amazon S3 Large File Uploads&lt;/strong&gt;: Fixed an issue with large file uploads to Amazon S3. (#36584)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Toast Display Issue&lt;/strong&gt;: Fixed whitespace display in toast notifications. (#36629)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;New Query in List View&lt;/strong&gt;: Resolved issue where clicking "+" in list view did not create a new query. (#36467)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DSCrudAndBindings Spec Migration&lt;/strong&gt;: Updated the migration repository for DSCrudAndBindings specifications. (#36452)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Invalid Date in Table Widget&lt;/strong&gt;: Fixed issue with invalid date display in the table widget's date column when using Unix timestamp (ms). (#36455)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Features&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AI Chat Widget&lt;/strong&gt;: Initialized the AI chat widget. (#36610)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AIChat Stories and Tests&lt;/strong&gt;: Added stories and tests for AIChat to enhance functionality. (#36700)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Alert Component Multiple Lines&lt;/strong&gt;: Enabled support for multiple lines in the alert component. (#36126)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Improvements&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dependencies Cleanup&lt;/strong&gt;: Removed unused dependencies and explicitly installed the necessary ones to optimize performance. (#36573)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/appsmithorg/appsmith/releases/tag/v1.44" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/appsmithorg/appsmith/releases/tag/v1.45</id>
    <title>New release for Appsmith: Release v1.45 🌈</title>
    <updated>2024-10-15T05:45:07-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>appsmithorg/appsmith</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h2&gt;Features&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Show Chat Description&lt;/strong&gt; (#36805): Introduced the ability to display chat descriptions, improving clarity and communication within the chat interface.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Initial Assistant Message&lt;/strong&gt; (#36798): Added an initial message from the assistant to provide a more interactive and guided experience for users.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Updated GraphQL Form UI&lt;/strong&gt; (#36728): Improved the design and usability of the GraphQL form, making it easier to use and more intuitive.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Table Select Column Label Filtering&lt;/strong&gt; (#36755): Enabled filtering by select column labels in tables, offering enhanced data navigation and customization options.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Fixes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Improved Conditional Rendering in ChartWidget&lt;/strong&gt; (#36806): Enhanced the logic for conditional rendering in the ChartWidget to improve performance and responsiveness.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Added Inverse Dependencies in Default Response&lt;/strong&gt; (#36780): Corrected the handling of inverse dependencies in the default response for the &lt;code&gt;evaluateAndGenerateResponse&lt;/code&gt; function.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Removed Redundant Evaluation Trigger&lt;/strong&gt; (#36764): Removed unnecessary evaluation triggers to optimize performance and streamline execution.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prevented Objects from Collapsing in Debugger&lt;/strong&gt; (#36477): Fixed an issue where objects in the debugger collapsed during resizing, improving debugging efficiency.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;App Title Dropdown Closure Issue&lt;/strong&gt; (#36504): Resolved a bug that caused the app title dropdown to close when interacting with other components.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Focus Retention on Input Fields&lt;/strong&gt; (#36770): Ensured focus is retained on input fields during navigation, enhancing user experience in form interactions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;New Query Button Visibility&lt;/strong&gt; (#36766): Fixed an issue where the "New Query" button was not visible, restoring expected functionality.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Batched Evaluate Action Parameters&lt;/strong&gt; (#36482): Implemented chunking for evaluation action parameters to optimize performance during large-scale operations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/appsmithorg/appsmith/releases/tag/v1.45" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
