<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://selfh.st/apps</id>
  <title>Appsmith Releases</title>
  <updated>2024-10-07T01:31:54.229671-04:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>selfh.st</name>
    <email>contact@selfh.st</email>
  </author>
  <link href="https://selfh.st/apps" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>Self-hosted software releases generated by selfh.st</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/appsmithorg/appsmith/releases/tag/v1.39</id>
    <title>New release for Appsmith: Release v1.39 🌈</title>
    <updated>2024-09-05T01:43:14-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>appsmithorg/appsmith</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h3&gt;New Features:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Select Widget&lt;/strong&gt; (#35849): Added a new Select widget to give you more flexibility and control over user choices in forms and interfaces.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SSH Tunnel for Postgres&lt;/strong&gt; (#35449): Introduced support for SSH tunnels to securely connect to Postgres databases, improving security and connectivity.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Collection Sorting&lt;/strong&gt; (#35413): Added functionality to sort collections in the correct order, enhancing organization and usability.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Remove Clear Option for Required Select Widget&lt;/strong&gt; (#35060): Updated select widgets to remove the "clear" option for fields that are required, ensuring users make a selection.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Bug Fixes:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Intercom Anonymous User ID Handling&lt;/strong&gt; (#36017): Fixed the handling of anonymous user IDs in Intercom settings to ensure consistency and proper functionality.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Action Redesign and Container Query Removal&lt;/strong&gt; (#36014): Addressed issues with the redesign of the Action feature and removed redundant container queries for better performance.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prevent Errors in Debugger When Deleting List Widget&lt;/strong&gt; (#35820): Resolved errors occurring in the debugger when deleting list widgets, improving stability and reliability.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/appsmithorg/appsmith/releases/tag/v1.39" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/appsmithorg/appsmith/releases/tag/v1.40</id>
    <title>New release for Appsmith: Release v1.40 🌈</title>
    <updated>2024-09-11T23:38:09-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>appsmithorg/appsmith</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h3&gt;Fixes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;RBAC Errors Toasts&lt;/strong&gt; (#36244): Resolved issues preventing RBAC errors from displaying toast notifications.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Null Pointer Exception on Policy Copy&lt;/strong&gt; (#36172): Fixed a NullPointerException that occurred when creating a copy of a policy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Colorpicker Empty Value Regression&lt;/strong&gt; (#36157): Addressed a regression where the Colorpicker component would incorrectly handle empty color values.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Theming Font Selection Reversion&lt;/strong&gt; (#36119): Fixed a bug where selected fonts would revert when the associated color was removed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Forking Issue&lt;/strong&gt; (#35988): Corrected an issue affecting the forking process.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Error Toasts Wall&lt;/strong&gt; (#35839): Fixed an issue with error toast notifications not being displayed correctly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Removed Conditional for jslib Files&lt;/strong&gt; (#36115): Eliminated redundant conditional checks related to jslib files.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tooltip Box Width&lt;/strong&gt; (#35734): Corrected the tooltip box width issue where it was larger than the text in the property panel.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Postgres Plugin Blocking Call&lt;/strong&gt; (#36046): Resolved a blocking call issue within the Postgres plugin.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Back Button Redirection&lt;/strong&gt; (#35900): Fixed the back button functionality to correctly redirect to the applications page.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CSS for Meatball Icon&lt;/strong&gt; (#36112): Updated CSS to ensure the meatball icon is positioned correctly on the Application Card.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Embedded Datasource Persistence&lt;/strong&gt; (#36109): Made changes to ensure embedded datasource persistence with Git.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Features&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Action Redesign &amp;amp; UQI Plugin Config Upgrade&lt;/strong&gt; (#36087, #36092): Redesigned actions and upgraded UQI plugin configurations (Open AI and AWS) to the dual-zone format.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ComboBox WDS Component&lt;/strong&gt; (#36052): Added a new ComboBox component to the WDS library.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Action Redesign: Appsmith AI Plugin&lt;/strong&gt; (#36089): Updated the configuration for the Appsmith AI plugin to utilize sections and zones format.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Action Redesign: Google AI Plugin&lt;/strong&gt; (#36095): Modified the configuration for the Google AI plugin to adopt the sections and zones format.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Action Redesign: SMTP Plugin&lt;/strong&gt; (#36091): Upgraded the SMTP plugin configuration to the sections and zones format.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disable Create JS Object Option&lt;/strong&gt; (#36094): Disabled the option to create JS objects within the workflows editor.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/appsmithorg/appsmith/releases/tag/v1.40" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/appsmithorg/appsmith/releases/tag/v1.41</id>
    <title>New release for Appsmith: Release v1.41 🌈</title>
    <updated>2024-09-17T23:38:12-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>appsmithorg/appsmith</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;New Features:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Action Redesign Enhancements:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Google Sheets Plugin:&lt;/strong&gt; Updated the configuration to use sections and zones format. This change improves organization and usability. (#36117)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Firestore Plugin:&lt;/strong&gt; Updated the configuration to use sections and zones format for better structure and management. (#36097)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MongoDB Plugin:&lt;/strong&gt; Redesigned configuration to use sections and zones format, enhancing configuration clarity. (#36098)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Databricks Plugin:&lt;/strong&gt; Revised the configuration to sections and zones format, streamlining setup. (#36057)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;S3 Plugin:&lt;/strong&gt; Upgraded the configuration to dual zone format and improved sorting field responsiveness. (#36090)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Table Search Enhancement:&lt;/strong&gt; Enabled table search to include both label and value for tables with select column types, providing a more comprehensive search experience. (#36061)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Auto Selection Feature:&lt;/strong&gt; Added automatic parent selection for removed components, simplifying component management. (#36282)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;UQI Upgrade:&lt;/strong&gt; Enhanced the S3 plugin configuration with a dual-zone format and improved field sorting responsiveness. (#36090)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Improved Error Messages:&lt;/strong&gt; Enhanced error messages for PostgreSQL connections to provide more clarity on connection issues. (#35167)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fixes:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;API Test File Consolidation:&lt;/strong&gt; Consolidated the API test file, improving organization and maintainability. (#36318)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DB URL Trimming:&lt;/strong&gt; Fixed issue with trimming DB URLs and removing special characters during backup and restore processes. (#36201)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reverse PR Comment Issue:&lt;/strong&gt; Addressed and fixed the issue related to reverse PR comments. (#36308)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;IDE Header Height:&lt;/strong&gt; Corrected the header height usage in the IDE to ensure consistent display. (#36297)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;503 Error Recovery:&lt;/strong&gt; Fixed recovery issue for 503 errors to enhance system reliability. (#36252)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Invalid Sheet Method Default:&lt;/strong&gt; Set a default invalid method value in Gsheet datasource to prevent errors. (#36264)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;List Widget Bug:&lt;/strong&gt; Fixed an issue with the list widget as per Bug29566 specifications. (#36260)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Page Data Call Issue:&lt;/strong&gt; Resolved issue where page data DB call was being executed twice, improving performance. (#36247)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Anthropic Plugin Configuration:&lt;/strong&gt; Updated the configuration for the Anthropic plugin with a better file structure. (#36223)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;RBAC Toast Errors:&lt;/strong&gt; Fixed an issue where RBAC errors were not displaying toasts, improving error visibility. (#36244)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gsheets Unauth Method Removal:&lt;/strong&gt; Removed unauthorized method from Gsheets to streamline functionality. (#36125)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;updateWithoutPermission Bug:&lt;/strong&gt; Corrected &lt;code&gt;updateWithoutPermission&lt;/code&gt; method to properly update user data instead of saving it. (#36206)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Select Key Value Fix:&lt;/strong&gt; Removed unnecessary select key-value selections and fixed default behavior. (#36158)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/appsmithorg/appsmith/releases/tag/v1.41" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/appsmithorg/appsmith/releases/tag/v1.42</id>
    <title>New release for Appsmith: Release v1.42 🌈</title>
    <updated>2024-09-26T02:36:09-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>appsmithorg/appsmith</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;New Features:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added a warning message in the response pane when the prepared statement is enabled. (#36407)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Made images adaptable to support both PostgreSQL and MongoDB URIs. (#36424)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Database queries are now responsive (#36168)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Fixes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Master package step now includes server artifacts for PostgreSQL and MongoDB. (#36516)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Resolved query instance failure caused by a missing prepared statement object. (#36493)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Corrected the initial store value in the query response tab test case. (#36487)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed the &lt;code&gt;isRequired&lt;/code&gt; validation property for table select columns. (#36375)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Resolved CTA button issue for Git import modal. (#36364)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Corrected the "show bindings" menu not appearing in split mode. (#36378)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Resolved an undefined &lt;code&gt;this.rootSpan&lt;/code&gt; bug in &lt;code&gt;PageLoadInstrumentation&lt;/code&gt;. (#36459)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed incorrect updating of &lt;code&gt;selectedRowIndex&lt;/code&gt; when the primary column is set. (#36393)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Resolved duplicate page name error not disappearing when navigating to other pages. (#36320)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed inline editing flaky test. (#36366)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Corrected &lt;code&gt;Datasource&lt;/code&gt; preview not taking full height. (#36389)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed NPE for policies when &lt;code&gt;policyMap&lt;/code&gt; is not present. (#36323)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed displaced "show bindings" sub-menu position. (#36340)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Resolved logger not working in plugins. (#36231)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed caddy partial metrics. (#36376)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/appsmithorg/appsmith/releases/tag/v1.42" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/appsmithorg/appsmith/releases/tag/v1.43</id>
    <title>New release for Appsmith: Release v1.43 🌈</title>
    <updated>2024-10-02T02:33:57-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>appsmithorg/appsmith</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h3&gt;Features&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;LRU Cache for MockDB Connections&lt;/strong&gt; (#36480): We've introduced a Least Recently Used (LRU) cache for our mockDB connections, improving performance and efficiency when handling database operations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Fixes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Modal Height Adjustment&lt;/strong&gt; (#36589): Resolved an issue with modal height by removing the minimum content constraint, ensuring a better user experience.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Plugin Action Editor Improvements&lt;/strong&gt; (#36574): Implemented quick fixes to enhance the current functionality of the Plugin Action Editor, making it more user-friendly and responsive.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Image Icon Alignment&lt;/strong&gt; (#35992): Fixed the alignment of icons when the data type is set to image, ensuring consistency and visual appeal.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;JavaScript Library Load Handling&lt;/strong&gt; (#36539): Improved the functionality for loading JavaScript libraries, particularly handling default exports more effectively.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mongo Schema Collections Order&lt;/strong&gt; (#36062): Corrected the order of Mongo schema collections in the Mongo plugin for better organization and clarity.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Unique Default Export Naming&lt;/strong&gt; (#36483): Updated the handling of JavaScript library default exports to use a unique name instead of the default key, reducing potential conflicts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/appsmithorg/appsmith/releases/tag/v1.43" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
