<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://selfh.st/apps</id>
  <title>Appsmith Releases</title>
  <updated>2024-07-02T08:32:24.231555-04:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>selfh.st</name>
    <email>contact@selfh.st</email>
  </author>
  <link href="https://selfh.st/apps" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>Self-hosted software releases generated by selfh.st</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/appsmithorg/appsmith/releases/tag/v1.25</id>
    <title>New release for Appsmith: Release v1.25 🌈</title>
    <updated>2024-05-16T05:21:09-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>appsmithorg/appsmith</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fixes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Updated regex to expand scope for Git SSH connect URL  (#33426)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enabled atomic pushes in Git using an environment configuration (#33367)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Updated markings on the update of the same editor value (#33394)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Allowed bottom tabs to be selectable as text (#33263)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Resolved issue of Peek overlay overflowing in side by side mode (#33376)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Set up proxy variables at startup (#32451)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed issue where Modal Widget doesn't open with &lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;showModal&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; action in Anvil only (#33348)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Removed error for window fetch API (#33339)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Debug button now opens the Error tab (#33337)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved responsiveness of Api pane and settings (#33297)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed CREATE_JS_ACTION_ERROR that disallowed creating JS objects or updating actions on certain Git connected apps (#33303)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Resolved glitch issue (multiple selected to none) while dropping a building block (#33162)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Addressed the case of missing tabs (#33066)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved e2e autoLayout test (#33295)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Removed the scrollbar in the table widget when the data count is less than the number of rows being shown (#33290)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Updated placeholder in rest API body binary tab (#33272)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed OAuth2 client secret appearing in UI (#33281)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed asymmetric padding for sections and zones (#33204)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Corrected slash menu command to show all available queries and datasources (#33076)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added anonymous user check while registering the edit mode pulses (#33251)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Prevented UI segment re-render caused by route change (#33215)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed Select Widget when showing One click binding options (#33211)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Addressed button group specifications (#33234)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed UI issues in Create module button in split-screen view (#33095)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved Anvil drag preview for section widget (#33198)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Resolved Anvil Modal rendering issues when added via property pane (#33161)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Updated invite modal component to fix issue on EE and improve code splitting of a file (#33216)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Removed redundant action collection update call on page load in edit mode (#33139)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Started using SHA2 instead of SHA1 algorithms for signing during Git operations (#33166)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Disabled main JS rename from entity pane (#33202)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed Workspace name editor input disappearing on hovering over other menu items of workspace (#33179)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ensured authenticationType field is saved to the database (#33196)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Refactored &lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;isCurrentWidgetFocused&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; to &lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;isWidgetFocused&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; (#32990)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Removed existing widget selection implementation (#33129)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Features&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Updated font across Appsmith(#33008)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/appsmithorg/appsmith/releases/tag/v1.25" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/appsmithorg/appsmith/releases/tag/v1.26</id>
    <title>New release for Appsmith: Release v1.26 🌈</title>
    <updated>2024-05-21T07:10:18-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>appsmithorg/appsmith</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;New Features&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;New Tab UI Changes&lt;/strong&gt;: Implemented a refreshed user interface for tabs, improving usability and appearance. (#33228)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Text-Wrap Change&lt;/strong&gt;: Updated text-wrap functionality for better text display and management. (#33475)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bug Fixes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Custom Widget Icon Display&lt;/strong&gt;: Ensured that custom widget icons are displayed reliably even when no widget is found. (#33535)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lint Error for Appsmith Store Mutations&lt;/strong&gt;: Added a lint error to catch mutations in the Appsmith store, improving code quality and stability. (#33484)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tabs UI Updates&lt;/strong&gt;: Various updates and fixes to the tabs user interface for a smoother user experience. (#33536)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Modal Accessibility and Copy-Paste&lt;/strong&gt;: Improved modal accessibility and fixed issues with the copy-paste functionality. (#33509)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GSheet UI at 110% Zoom&lt;/strong&gt;: Resolved UI breaking issues when the Google Sheets interface is viewed at 110% zoom level. (#33525)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WDS Button Font Weight&lt;/strong&gt;: Adjusted the font weight of WDS buttons for better visual consistency. (#33489)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Peek Overlay Position Flickering&lt;/strong&gt;: Fixed the issue causing the peek overlay position to flicker. (#33499)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Modal Overlay Darkness&lt;/strong&gt;: Increased the perceived darkness of the modal overlay in WDS for better focus and user experience. (#33476)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Anvil Layout and Cleanup&lt;/strong&gt;: Made layout adjustments and performed general cleanup in the Anvil interface. (#33442)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Git ssh validation regex enhancement&lt;/strong&gt;: Updated SSH validation regular expression to enhance data validation, and allow custom usernames in ssh address. (#33426)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/appsmithorg/appsmith/releases/tag/v1.26" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/appsmithorg/appsmith/releases/tag/v1.27</id>
    <title>New release for Appsmith: Release v1.27 🌈</title>
    <updated>2024-06-06T23:01:23-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>appsmithorg/appsmith</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h3&gt;Fixes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[Perf Improvement] Removed unnecessary individual DB calls to plugin and fetched all at once (#33712)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added custom JS control for currency, notation, and thousand separator (#33877)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Removed building blocks on canvas (#33761)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed confirmation popup not dismissing after deleting a datasource (#33778)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Corrected general settings description (#33838)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ignored DSL parsing errors in the forking flow (#33831)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reverted the previous fix for table scrollbar and hid vertical scrollbar when needed (#33806)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Encoded queryParam value and fixed parsing logic for queryParams (#33720)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Showed loading state of application until all JS object update calls are complete (#33545)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Resolved new API getting added into the NA group (#33701)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added close button for Add pane when tabs are disabled (#33653)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed vanishing app details issue (#33698)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Removed the feature to download docker-compose file from admin settings (#33682)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed apiKey security issue (#33528)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added warning icon and tooltip to indicate empty datasources (#33618)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Addressed Add pane issues (#33627)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Removed the strict check for MongoDB URL (#33652)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed function undefined error after &lt;code&gt;resetWidget&lt;/code&gt; is called due to sync issues (#33600)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Considered Heroku deployment while generating Caddyfile (#33559)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed scrolling issues in Add tab (#33595)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Features&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Updated explorer slider widget icons (#33871)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Introduced Collapsible Bottom View (#33441)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added workflow triggerservice unit test cases (#4205)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Implemented autocommit for the server-side (#4080)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added workflow copy update (#4230)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added tenant information to Redis cache for quick fetch (#33641)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/appsmithorg/appsmith/releases/tag/v1.27" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/appsmithorg/appsmith/releases/tag/v1.28</id>
    <title>New release for Appsmith: Release v1.28 🌈</title>
    <updated>2024-06-13T23:07:06-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>appsmithorg/appsmith</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h3&gt;Fixes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Workflows Artifact Versioning&lt;/strong&gt;: Set evaluation version for workflows artifact to ensure compatibility and stability (#34197).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dynamic Text Field&lt;/strong&gt;: Corrected fields from &lt;code&gt;QUERY_DYNAMIC_INPUT_TEXT&lt;/code&gt; to &lt;code&gt;QUERY_DYNAMIC_TEXT&lt;/code&gt; for improved accuracy (#34108).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Protected Branch Widgets&lt;/strong&gt;: Resolved the issue where widgets were vanishing in protected branches, ensuring they remain visible (#34129).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Null Check&lt;/strong&gt;: Fixed null check failure on PostgreSQL branch to prevent runtime errors (#34090).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Onboarding Screen&lt;/strong&gt;: Hid the skip button when the application object is not present on the onboarding screen for a cleaner UI (#34048).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Link Behavior&lt;/strong&gt;: Improved link behavior for a more intuitive user experience (#34043).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Workflows Editor&lt;/strong&gt;: Implemented code split to resolve the run history resize issue in the workflows editor (#34049).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Currency Prefix&lt;/strong&gt;: Fixed issues related to currency prefix to ensure accurate financial data representation (#34039).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Canvas Cutoff&lt;/strong&gt;: Fixed preview mode canvas cutoff for better visual consistency (#33960).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Autocommit Feature&lt;/strong&gt;: Added fixes for disabling the autocommit feature without a feature flag, ensuring proper functionality (#34020, #34015).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GQL Editor Tabs&lt;/strong&gt;: Fetched actions and plugins before selecting the GraphQL editor tab to focus, improving user workflow (#33697).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Font Family Update&lt;/strong&gt;: Changed font family to PT root in privacy and terms &amp;amp; conditions pages for consistent typography (#33992).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scroll Behavior&lt;/strong&gt;: Added missing scroll-to-definition behavior for better navigation (#33973).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Label Selectability&lt;/strong&gt;: Made individual words in labels selectable to enhance text manipulation (#22110, #33922).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Datasource Form UI&lt;/strong&gt;: Fixed the UI of the datasource form footer for a more polished appearance (#33957).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;URL Selectability&lt;/strong&gt;: Made URLs selectable to facilitate easy copying and usage (#33952).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Features&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disable Overlay&lt;/strong&gt;: Removed the disable overlay for incorrect JavaScript objects, enhancing error handling and user experience (#33990).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/appsmithorg/appsmith/releases/tag/v1.28" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/appsmithorg/appsmith/releases/tag/v1.29</id>
    <title>New release for Appsmith: Release v1.29 🌈</title>
    <updated>2024-06-28T00:18:48-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>appsmithorg/appsmith</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h2&gt;New Features&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Add Support for Google Cloud Storage in S3 Plugin (#33938)&lt;/strong&gt;: Extended S3 plugin functionality to include support for Google Cloud Storage.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Side-by-Side Edit Mode Hover Analytics (#34185)&lt;/strong&gt;: Implemented hover analytics for side-by-side edit mode to improve user insights.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update Explorer Widget Icons (#34018)&lt;/strong&gt;: Updated the icons in the explorer widget for a more modern and intuitive interface.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Bug Fixes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Don't Call Modal onClose Method in Edit Mode (#34432)&lt;/strong&gt;: Prevented unnecessary calls to the modal &lt;code&gt;onClose&lt;/code&gt; method while in edit mode.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WDS Widgets Fix (#34387)&lt;/strong&gt;: Addressed several issues affecting WDS widgets.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prefetch APIs: Include Only Branchname Header in Request Key (#34389)&lt;/strong&gt;: Modified prefetch API requests to include only the &lt;code&gt;branchname&lt;/code&gt; header.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Revert to Passing Hook as a Prop for EE Compatibility (#34367)&lt;/strong&gt;: Reverted changes to maintain compatibility with the Enterprise Edition by passing hooks as props.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Supervisor Buffer Overflow Errors (#34351)&lt;/strong&gt;: Fixed buffer overflow errors in the supervisor component.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Retain Existing Flags Even if CS API Fails (#34306)&lt;/strong&gt;: Ensured existing flags are retained even when the CS API encounters an error.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Checkbox Column Misalignment on Table Widget (#34222)&lt;/strong&gt;: Corrected misalignment issues with the checkbox column in the table widget.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EvalTrigger Mutation Fix (#34106)&lt;/strong&gt;: Resolved issues with the &lt;code&gt;evalTrigger&lt;/code&gt; mutation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Property Pane Height Fix for Animation (#34276)&lt;/strong&gt;: Fixed property pane height issues related to animations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Learn More Link in Git Connect Success Modal (#34297)&lt;/strong&gt;: Fixed the "Learn More" link in the Git Connect success modal to navigate correctly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Unprotect Logic in Callout (#34244)&lt;/strong&gt;: Fixed logic errors in the callout's unprotect functionality.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fix for Regression in JS Query Refactor in Modules (#34186)&lt;/strong&gt;: Fixed a regression issue caused by the refactor of JS queries in modules.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DB URL Override Fails in Some Cases (#34206)&lt;/strong&gt;: Resolved issues where the DB URL override was failing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Set Eval Version for Workflows Artifact (#34197)&lt;/strong&gt;: Corrected the evaluation version setting for workflow artifacts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/appsmithorg/appsmith/releases/tag/v1.29" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
