<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://selfh.st/apps</id>
  <title>Appsmith Releases</title>
  <updated>2024-07-24T08:32:25.838010-04:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>selfh.st</name>
    <email>contact@selfh.st</email>
  </author>
  <link href="https://selfh.st/apps" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>Self-hosted software releases generated by selfh.st</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/appsmithorg/appsmith/releases/tag/v1.29</id>
    <title>New release for Appsmith: Release v1.29 🌈</title>
    <updated>2024-06-28T00:18:48-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>appsmithorg/appsmith</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h2&gt;New Features&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Add Support for Google Cloud Storage in S3 Plugin (#33938)&lt;/strong&gt;: Extended S3 plugin functionality to include support for Google Cloud Storage.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Side-by-Side Edit Mode Hover Analytics (#34185)&lt;/strong&gt;: Implemented hover analytics for side-by-side edit mode to improve user insights.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update Explorer Widget Icons (#34018)&lt;/strong&gt;: Updated the icons in the explorer widget for a more modern and intuitive interface.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Bug Fixes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Don't Call Modal onClose Method in Edit Mode (#34432)&lt;/strong&gt;: Prevented unnecessary calls to the modal &lt;code&gt;onClose&lt;/code&gt; method while in edit mode.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WDS Widgets Fix (#34387)&lt;/strong&gt;: Addressed several issues affecting WDS widgets.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prefetch APIs: Include Only Branchname Header in Request Key (#34389)&lt;/strong&gt;: Modified prefetch API requests to include only the &lt;code&gt;branchname&lt;/code&gt; header.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Revert to Passing Hook as a Prop for EE Compatibility (#34367)&lt;/strong&gt;: Reverted changes to maintain compatibility with the Enterprise Edition by passing hooks as props.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Supervisor Buffer Overflow Errors (#34351)&lt;/strong&gt;: Fixed buffer overflow errors in the supervisor component.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Retain Existing Flags Even if CS API Fails (#34306)&lt;/strong&gt;: Ensured existing flags are retained even when the CS API encounters an error.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Checkbox Column Misalignment on Table Widget (#34222)&lt;/strong&gt;: Corrected misalignment issues with the checkbox column in the table widget.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EvalTrigger Mutation Fix (#34106)&lt;/strong&gt;: Resolved issues with the &lt;code&gt;evalTrigger&lt;/code&gt; mutation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Property Pane Height Fix for Animation (#34276)&lt;/strong&gt;: Fixed property pane height issues related to animations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Learn More Link in Git Connect Success Modal (#34297)&lt;/strong&gt;: Fixed the "Learn More" link in the Git Connect success modal to navigate correctly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Unprotect Logic in Callout (#34244)&lt;/strong&gt;: Fixed logic errors in the callout's unprotect functionality.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fix for Regression in JS Query Refactor in Modules (#34186)&lt;/strong&gt;: Fixed a regression issue caused by the refactor of JS queries in modules.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DB URL Override Fails in Some Cases (#34206)&lt;/strong&gt;: Resolved issues where the DB URL override was failing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Set Eval Version for Workflows Artifact (#34197)&lt;/strong&gt;: Corrected the evaluation version setting for workflow artifacts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/appsmithorg/appsmith/releases/tag/v1.29" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/appsmithorg/appsmith/releases/tag/v1.30</id>
    <title>New release for Appsmith: Release v1.30 🌈</title>
    <updated>2024-07-08T01:51:08-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>appsmithorg/appsmith</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h3&gt;Fixes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Addressed an issue where Snowflake imports were failing due to connectivity or configuration issues (#34745). This fix ensures reliable data retrieval from Snowflake databases.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Updated the widget sidebar to accommodate airgapped environments, ensuring compatibility and usability in isolated network setups (#34656).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enhanced security by adding an encrypted icon to passphrase fields and updated labels to clearly indicate security measures (#34653).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed a specific issue with Google Sheets (gsheets) integration where selected sheets were not loading correctly (#34659).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Resolved inconsistencies in split mode resizing within the interface, ensuring a consistent and predictable user experience (#34517).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added compatibility enhancements to support older Snowflake datasources, maintaining functionality across different system versions (#34628).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved the highlighting functionality in the Anvil canvas for better visibility and interaction with design elements (#34553).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Implemented stricter controls to prevent passphrase data from being unintentionally sent to client devices (#34610).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Corrected a recent change to revert the "Overflow tabs list view" feature, restoring previous functionality (#34613).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Renamed workflow JavaScript functions to enhance clarity and maintain consistency in naming conventions (#34512).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Updated BuildingBlockSagas to handle nested object value replacements more effectively within complex queries (#34563).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Implemented a mechanism to truncate titles in tooltips within table cells if they exceeded 200 characters, improving readability (#34507).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ensured newly created queries are accurately updated with the correct widget bindings for seamless integration (#34248).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Disabled custom widgets for airgapped environments to maintain security and stability (#34540).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Implemented a backup mechanism to handle &lt;code&gt;isAtomicPushAllowed&lt;/code&gt; as false when required, ensuring system reliability (#33647).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Addressed a focus retention issue after deleting a datasource to maintain user workflow continuity (#34460).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enhanced widget functionality during building block paste operations by refining dynamic bindings for improved performance (#34318).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Features&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Refactored how SelectWidget handles sourceData to optimize data retrieval and management, improving overall efficiency (#34619).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Streamlined the datasource review page to provide a cleaner and more intuitive user interface for better data management (#34348).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Introduced a Snowflake key authentication server to enhance security measures and access controls (#34548).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added support for dynamic property paths in SelectWidget's sourceData configuration, allowing for more flexible data handling (#34574).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reintroduced the Overflow tabs list view feature, enabling users to manage large datasets more effectively (#34150).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Implemented support for key pair authentication for Snowflake databases behind a feature flag, expanding authentication options (#34399).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/appsmithorg/appsmith/releases/tag/v1.30" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/appsmithorg/appsmith/releases/tag/v1.31</id>
    <title>New release for Appsmith: Release v1.31 🌈</title>
    <updated>2024-07-11T23:31:57-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>appsmithorg/appsmith</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h3&gt;New Features&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Datasource Review Page Enhancement&lt;/strong&gt;: Cleaned up the datasource review page for a more organized and user-friendly experience, making it easier to navigate and manage datasources. [#34655]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Fixes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data Fetching Issue&lt;/strong&gt;: Resolved a problem where queries did not fetch any data when datasources were configured during app import, ensuring that data retrieval functions correctly. [#34789]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Generate Page Button Visibility&lt;/strong&gt;: Fixed an issue where the generate page button in &lt;code&gt;DSFormHeader&lt;/code&gt; was not correctly hidden, improving UI accuracy and behavior. [#34780]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Table Row Selection Issue&lt;/strong&gt;: Corrected a bug that prevented users from selecting rows in tables, enhancing interaction and usability. [#34753]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Datasource Validation Fix&lt;/strong&gt;: Addressed validation issues for datasource imports and save flows, ensuring accurate validation and smoother operation. [#34754]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Snowflake Import Issues&lt;/strong&gt;: Fixed various issues related to Snowflake imports, improving the import process and data handling. [#34745]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Overflow List UI Restoration&lt;/strong&gt;: Restored the new UI for the overflow list to address display issues and improve visual consistency. [#34658]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SelfReferenceRule Completion Update&lt;/strong&gt;: Updated the SelfReferenceRule to correctly display completions for other properties of an entity, enhancing accuracy in property references. [#34686]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/appsmithorg/appsmith/releases/tag/v1.31" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/appsmithorg/appsmith/releases/tag/v1.31.1</id>
    <title>New release for Appsmith: Release v1.31.1 🌈</title>
    <updated>2024-07-15T02:00:39-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>appsmithorg/appsmith</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;Fix issues opening pages with large number of widgets and/or bindings.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/appsmithorg/appsmith/releases/tag/v1.31.1" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/appsmithorg/appsmith/releases/tag/v1.32</id>
    <title>New release for Appsmith: Release v1.32 🌈</title>
    <updated>2024-07-17T23:13:04-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>appsmithorg/appsmith</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h3&gt;New Features&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;IDE Tab List Search View&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ve added a powerful new search view to the IDE tab list. This enhancement enables users to quickly locate and switch between open tabs, making it easier to manage your workspace efficiently. (#34759)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;cURL Import via Modal&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The cURL import process has been streamlined by moving it to a dedicated modal. This change provides a more intuitive and user-friendly interface for importing cURL commands, improving your overall experience. (#34830)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WDS Table Widget Suggested&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The WDS Table Widget has been added to the list of suggested widgets, making it easier for users to discover and utilize this useful tool for data presentation. (#34816)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Updated PrimaryColumnsControlV2&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The editable checkbox has been removed from the PrimaryColumnsControlV2 component, and related imports have been updated. This change simplifies the component and ensures it aligns with current design standards. (#34586)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Fixes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Modal Rename Reference Updates&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fixed issues related to updating references following the renaming of modals. This fix ensures that all references are correctly updated, preventing errors and improving overall stability. (#34855)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Buffer Size Error with DSL Migration&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Resolved a buffer size error encountered during DSL migration calls. This fix ensures smooth operation and prevents disruptions during data migrations. (#34905)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Improved Datasource Deletion Message&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Updated the datasource deletion message to enhance clarity. This change provides users with more precise and actionable feedback during the deletion process. (#34822)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CustomJsLib Import Flow&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Utilized the &lt;code&gt;isDryOps&lt;/code&gt; flag in the customJsLib import flow to improve process handling and ensure smoother imports of custom JavaScript libraries. (#34836)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Concurrent Modification Exception in Datasource Import&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Addressed an issue causing concurrent modification exceptions during the datasource import flow. This fix improves stability and prevents disruptions during the import process. (#34818)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/appsmithorg/appsmith/releases/tag/v1.32" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
