<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://selfh.st/apps</id>
  <title>BackupPC Releases</title>
  <updated>2025-08-02T10:37:16.861058-04:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>selfh.st</name>
    <email>contact@selfh.st</email>
  </author>
  <link href="https://selfh.st/apps" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>Self-hosted software releases generated by selfh.st</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/backuppc/backuppc/releases/tag/4.2.1</id>
    <title>New release for BackupPC: BackupPC 4.2.1 release</title>
    <updated>2018-05-07T13:31:58-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>backuppc/backuppc</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;This release allows the new backup delete CGI feature to be disabled for users and/or admins, plus a couple of minor bug fixes:
* Merged pull request #195.
* Added new config variable $Conf{CgiUserDeleteBackupEnable} that sets whether users and admins can delete backups via the CGI interface. The default value is 0, which means it's disabled for regular users but available for admins.
* Fixed delete backup bug in bin/BackupPC_Admin_SCGI reported by Julian Zielke in issue #193.
* Added check to dirCacheFlush() in bin/BackupPC_tarExtract to skip files that don't have attributes; reported by Tarak Patel.
* Removed extraneous duplicate variable assignment in lib/BackupPC/CGI/GeneralInfo.pm, from @moisseev (#195).&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/backuppc/backuppc/releases/tag/4.2.1" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/backuppc/backuppc/releases/tag/4.3.0</id>
    <title>New release for BackupPC: BackupPC 4.3.0 release</title>
    <updated>2018-11-25T17:18:43-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>backuppc/backuppc</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;This release includes a couple of new features (eg, checking inode usage on the BackupPC filesystem) and a few improvements (eg, html table sorting), and several bug fixes:
* Merged pull requests #200, #208, #216, #217, #229, #230, #231, #232, #233, #235.
* Added checking of file system inode usage, with new configuration settings $Conf{DfInodeUsageCmd} and $Conf{DfMaxInodeUsagePct}.
* bin/BackupPC_tarExtract: fixes to hardlink handling on incrementals, plus cleanup
* bin/BackupPC_backupDuplicate: fixed directory creation for copying v3 backups.
* bin/BackupPC_backupDelete: couple of inode-related bug fixes; also do fsck if $Conf{RefCntFsck} != 0.
* bin/BackupPC: fixed handling of dhcp hosts, reported by Jean-Marc.
* bin/BackupPC: improved version check of rsync_bpc to allow period before "beta", reported by @ktenney in issue #214.
* Added $Conf{EMailAdminSubject} to allow the admin email subject to be set.
* Changed default $Conf{CgiDateFormatMMDD} to 2 (YYYY-MM-DD), submitted by @moisseev (#231).
* Allow multiple groups in $Conf{CgiAdminUserGroup}, submitted by @moisseev (#235).
* Improvements to html table sorting, and made more tables sortable, submitted by @brenard and @moisseev (issue #199, PRs #200, #229, #230, #232).
* Add action type column to queue status page (#208), submitted by @brenard.
* lib/BackupPC/CGI/Summary.pm: host summary only reports age of completed backups (not partial or active), suggested by Michael Selway.
* lib/BackupPC/CGI/HostInfo.pm: show active backup as partial if there is no job running (to handle case of abnormal exit of BackupPC), reported by @8666 in issue #220.
* systemd/src/backuppc.service: added ExecReload, submitted by @opoplawski (#233).
* lib/BackupPC/Xfer/Rsync.pm: empty $Conf{RsyncdPasswd} is no longer fatal; removed remaining mentions of RsyncdAuthRequired from conf/config.pl and lib/BackupPC/Config/Meta.pm; reported by @jooola in issue #224.
* bin/BackupPC_dump: moved alarm($Conf{ClientTimeout}) to after all the pre-backup code (including expiry, duplication etc of backups, which could be slow) reported by Michael Selway.
* bin/BackupPC_refCntUpdate: added a couple of bpc_progress_state prints to improve status reporting during nightly (-m), reported by Michael Selway.
* lib/BackupPC/CGI/RSS.pm: added Disabled value to host info (copied from $Conf{BackupsDisable}); suggested by @danielmotaleite (issue #222).
* lib/BackupPC/Xfer/Rsync.pm: added checks for a couple of common rsync file error and error exit messages that now increment the xferErrs count.
* bin/BackupPC_tarExtract: errors related to a particular file are counted as Xfer errors, rather than considered fatal.
* bin/BackupPC_dump: added check that $LogFd is defined before using it.
* lib/BackupPC/Lib.pm: replaced exit() with POSIX::_exit() so that object destruction is skipped in the child process.  This fixes corruption of the compressed XferLOG file if the exec of $Conf{DumpPostUserCmd} fails.
* conf/config.pl: updated project home page to https://backuppc.github.io/backuppc in email message footers.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/backuppc/backuppc/releases/tag/4.3.0" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/backuppc/backuppc/releases/tag/4.3.1</id>
    <title>New release for BackupPC: BackupPC 4.3.1 release</title>
    <updated>2019-07-14T17:24:06-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>backuppc/backuppc</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;This release contains several bug fixes.
* Merged pull request #240.
* Fixed CGI host summary columns for new Comment value; reported by @karlis-irmejs (#245).
* Added support to BackupPC_tarCreate for PAX headers to allow large metadata values to be correctly encoded; reported by @seblu (#254).
* Fixed regexp in BackupPC so that versions like rsync-bpc 3.1.2beta0 are matched.  PR submitted by Adrien Ferrand (#240).
* Added more details to error messages when failing to connect to BackupPC server; reported by @dmak (#261).
* bin/BackupPC Main_Initialize() checks if a BackupPC server is running by trying to connect to it, in addition to existing check that PID exists; reported by @toggoboge (#264).
* Fixed utf8 encoded share names in deletion of orphan RsyncShareNames, reported by @Yann79 (#266).
* Fixed %Conf passing to perl code version of $bpc-&amp;gt;cmdSystemOrEval; reported by Jeff Kosowsky.
* BackupPC_backupDelete removes files with BPC_FTYPE_DELETED from filled merged backup; reported by Jeff Kosowsky.
* added Data::Dumper SortKeys(1) to lib/BackupPC/Storage/Text.pm so that config hash writes have repeatable order; suggested by @kr4ut (#275).
* bin/BackupPC_archive: use $bpc-&amp;gt;openPCLogFile() instead of manual LOG file rotation
* lib/BackupPC/CGI/Archive.pm: create client directory if it doesn't exist&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/backuppc/backuppc/releases/tag/4.3.1" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/backuppc/backuppc/releases/tag/4.3.2</id>
    <title>New release for BackupPC: BackupPC 4.3.2 release</title>
    <updated>2020-02-17T18:55:59-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>backuppc/backuppc</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;This release contains several bug fixes and a few minor features:
* Merged pull requests #278, #281, #289, #295, #297, #307, #308, #311, #312, #313, #314.
* Added per-host read/write exclusivity to worker programs, so command-line programs don't collide with backups or other operations; reported by @hamster65 (issue #299)
* Added $Conf{RsyncIncrArgsExtra} (issue #284)
* Added $Conf{ClientShareName2Path}, which allows mapping of share names/path to real paths on the client (eg, to backup a snapshot that's in a different directory to the share name path)
* Fixed v3 digest calculation in bin/BackupPC_backupDuplicate and bin/BackupPC_migrateV3toV4; reported by @palmtop (issue #291)
* Improved handling of BackupPC_nightly running for more than 24 hours: drop next queued run, and provide better log messages; reported by @guestisp (issue #303)
* Improved error checking on $Conf{BackupPCNightlyPeriod}, and update $Info-&amp;gt;{NightlyPhase} if it's larger than $Conf{BackupPCNightlyPeriod}; reported by @guestisp (issue #304)
* Fixed warnings in bin/BackupPC, submitted by @moisseev (#278)
* Avoid rrd updates using the same time stamp, submitted by @moisseev (#311, issue #305)
* Removed unused counting of renamed files, submitted by @moisseev (#281)
* Make tar xfer output parsing compatible with FreeBSD tar, submitted by @haarp (#289)
* Fix daemon stdin open to read mode, submitted by @moisseev (#308)
* Hosts config editor table layout CGI fix, submitted by @steven-de-wit (#297)
* Fixes to French translation, submitted by @pjoubert- (#295)
* Fixes to Italian translation, submitted by @guestisp (#314)
* Updated comments for Apache 2.4 config in httpd/src/BackupPC.conf, submitted by @NotAProfessionalDeveloper (#307)
* Documentation update for SCGI prerequisite, submitted by @guestisp (#312)
* Documentation update for nginx config, submitted by @guestisp (#313)&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/backuppc/backuppc/releases/tag/4.3.2" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/backuppc/backuppc/releases/tag/4.4.0</id>
    <title>New release for BackupPC: BackupPC 4.4.0 release</title>
    <updated>2020-06-20T19:28:02-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>backuppc/backuppc</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;This release contains several new features and some bug fixes.  New features include:
* any full/filled backup can be marked for keeping, which prevents any expiry or deletion
* any backup can be annotated with a comment (eg, "prior to upgrade of xyz")
* added metrics CGI (thanks to @jooola) that replaces RSS and adds Prometheus support
* tar XferMethod now supports xattrs and acls
* rsync XferMethod now correctly supports xattrs on directories and symlinks
* nightly pool scanning now verifies the md5 digests of a configurable fraction of pool files
* code runs through perltidy so format is now uniform (thanks to @jooola, with help from @shancock9 and @moisseev)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;New versions of BackupPC::XS (&lt;a href="https://github.com/backuppc/backuppc-xs/releases/tag/0.62"&gt;0.62&lt;/a&gt;) and rsync-bpc (&lt;a href="https://github.com/backuppc/rsync-bpc/releases/tag/3.0.9.15"&gt;3.0.9.15&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://github.com/backuppc/rsync-bpc/releases/tag/3.1.2.2"&gt;3.1.2.2&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="https://github.com/backuppc/rsync-bpc/releases/tag/3.1.3beta1"&gt;3.1.3beta0&lt;/a&gt;) are required.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to Jeff Kosowsky for extensive testing and debugging for this release, particularly around xattrs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are the more detailed changes:
* Merged pull requests #325, #326, #329, #330, #334, #336, #337, #338, #342, #343, #344, #345, #347, #348, #349
* Filled/Full backups can now be marked as "keep", which excludes them from any expiry/deletion.  Also, a backup-specific comment can be added to any backup to capture any important information about that backup (eg, "pre-upgrade of xyz").
* Added metrics CGI, which adds Prometheus support and replaces RSS, by @joola (#344, #347)
* Tar XferMethod now supports xattrs and acls; xattrs should be compatible with rsync XferMethod, but acls are not
* Sort open directories to top when browsing backup tree
* Format code using perltidy, and included in pre-commit flow, by @joola (#334, #337, #342, #343, #345).  Thanks to @joola and @shancock9 (perltidy author) for significant effort and support, plus improvements in perltidy, to make this happen.
* Added $Conf{PoolNightlyDigestCheckPercent}, which checks the md5 digest of this fraction of the pool files each night.
* $Conf{ClientShareName2Path} is saved in backups file and the share to client path mapping is now displayed when you browse a backup so you know the actual client backup path for each share, if different from the share name
* configure.pl now checks the per-host config.pl in a V3 upgrade to warn the user if $Conf{RsyncClientCmd} or $Conf{RsyncClientRestoreCmd} are used for that host, so that the new settings $Conf{RsyncSshArgs} and $Conf{RsyncClientPath} can be manually updated.
* Fixed host mutex handling for dhcp hosts; shifted initial mutex requests to client programs
* Updated webui icon, logo and favicon, by @moisseev (#325, #326, #329, #330)
* Added $Conf{RsyncRestoreArgsExtra} for host-specific restore settings
* Language files now all use utf8 charsets
* Bumped required version of BackupPC::XS to 0.62 and rsync-bpc to 3.0.9.15.
* Ping failure message only written to stdout only if verbose
* BackupPC_backupDelete removes partial v3 backup in HOST/new; fixes #324 reported by @thalueng
* BackupPC_backupDelete adds -f option to over keep, if set
* BackupPC_nightly: change -f to -F when running BackupPC_refCountUpdate during fsck
* Better formatting of eval cmd result in cmdSystemOrEvalLong()
* Remove zero count entries in per-backup and per-host poolCnt files
* Add a fake version parameter to the CSS URL to overcome caching
* Fixed ALRM typo in BackupPC_dump, by @rhansen (#348)
* Fixed command name in error message in BackupPC_archive, by @rhansen (#349)
* lib/BackupPC/Xfer/Rsync.pm skips adding --iconv option when $Conf{ClientCharset} is utf8 or empty, to avoid a long-standing rsync bug
* lib/BackupPC/Xfer/Rsync.pm provides a more informative warning when the client rsync exits with an IO error, and also includes the IO error in the xferErr count
* lib/BackupPC/Xfer/Smb.pm recognizes NT_STATUS_LOGON_FAILURE error
* Increase text length in config editor fields, by @moisseev (#336)
* Typo fix in config.pl, by @cure (#338)
* Minor documentation updates, removing old SourceForge links&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/backuppc/backuppc/releases/tag/4.4.0" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
