<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://selfh.st/apps</id>
  <title>Caddy Releases</title>
  <updated>2025-01-07T05:30:13.694350-05:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>selfh.st</name>
    <email>contact@selfh.st</email>
  </author>
  <link href="https://selfh.st/apps" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>Self-hosted software releases generated by selfh.st</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/releases/tag/v2.8.0</id>
    <title>New release for Caddy: v2.8.0</title>
    <updated>2024-05-29T16:36:47-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>caddyserver/caddy</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;Caddy 2.8 is here! With hundreds of improvements, Caddy is more scalable and capable than ever before. Featuring ACME Renewal Information (ARI) support, HTTP/3 to proxy backends, and so much more than we can list in a sentence, we are pleased to bring you one of the biggest Caddy updates yet. Documentation on our website will be updated in the coming days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We've implemented a &lt;em&gt;ton&lt;/em&gt; of improvements, fixes, and awesome new features based on your feedback. While some of them aren't particularly visible changes, they allow Caddy to scale better and be more reliable in demanding deployments. Many of the changes are quality-of-life improvements we hope you'll appreciate. Then there's improvements to &lt;a href="https://github.com/mholt/acmez"&gt;ACMEz&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://github.com/caddyserver/certmagic"&gt;CertMagic&lt;/a&gt;, and other dependencies which make Caddy better that may not show up in this list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was a lot of code that had been documented as &lt;em&gt;deprecated&lt;/em&gt; in place for a long time, so this version introduces a few more breaking changes than usual; please review the notes below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you to our sponsors and everyone in the community who contributed -- over 40 of you made your first contribution for this release. We couldn't have done it without your help. In particular, we'd like to recognize sponsors &lt;strong&gt;Stripe&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Framer&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;ZeroSSL&lt;/strong&gt; for their positive influence which have greatly enhanced the project. Caddy 2.8 is already being used in our sponsors' large-scale, multi-region production deployments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Want to join those ranks? &lt;a href="https://caddyserver.com/sponsor"&gt;Sponsor the Caddy project&lt;/a&gt; and benefit from development priority, dedicated private support, and much more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As with any server upgrades, please be sure to test and validate your configurations in a staging or test environment before deploying to production. Thank you and have a great day!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;:warning: Breaking changes:&lt;/strong&gt;
- ZeroSSL (#6229) (this is &lt;em&gt;one&lt;/em&gt; overall change, but requires some explanation):
    - Up to now, Caddy used both Let's Encrypt and ZeroSSL by default to get certificates without any configuration. In 2.8, this is changing slightly. Due to upcoming changes to ZeroSSL accounting policies, ZeroSSL now requires your email address to be able to access their free ACME endpoint.
    - As such, Caddy will only implicitly add the ZeroSSL issuer to your config if you provide an email address in your Caddyfile using the &lt;a href="https://caddyserver.com/docs/caddyfile/options#email"&gt;&lt;code&gt;email&lt;/code&gt; global option&lt;/a&gt;. (We have already recommended this for years.) If you already do this, you don't have to make any changes and you'll still get Let's Encrypt and ZeroSSL automatically as defaults.
    - If you use JSON to configure certificate automation policies, you will need to ensure you use the &lt;a href="https://caddyserver.com/docs/json/apps/tls/automation/policies/issuers/acme/#email"&gt;&lt;code&gt;acme&lt;/code&gt; issuer with your &lt;code&gt;email&lt;/code&gt; filled out&lt;/a&gt;, and the &lt;a href="https://caddyserver.com/docs/json/apps/tls/automation/policies/issuers/acme/#ca"&gt;&lt;code&gt;ca&lt;/code&gt; field&lt;/a&gt; set to &lt;a href="https://zerossl.com/documentation/acme/"&gt;ZeroSSL's ACME server URL&lt;/a&gt;. If you want redundancy with Let's Encrypt, be sure to specify another &lt;code&gt;acme&lt;/code&gt; issuer as well (defaults OK, but we recommend setting an email there too).
    - The &lt;a href="https://caddyserver.com/docs/modules/tls.issuance.zerossl"&gt;&lt;code&gt;zerossl&lt;/code&gt; issuer&lt;/a&gt; module is no longer ACME-capable and is now exclusively for the &lt;a href="https://zerossl.com/developer/"&gt;ZeroSSL API&lt;/a&gt;. An API key from your ZeroSSL account is required. (The &lt;a href="https://zerossl.com/features/acme/"&gt;ZeroSSL ACME server&lt;/a&gt; can still be used with the &lt;a href="https://caddyserver.com/docs/modules/tls.issuance.acme"&gt;&lt;code&gt;acme&lt;/code&gt; module&lt;/a&gt; pointed to ZeroSSL's ACME server. You can provide your account email and/or EAB as well.) &lt;strong&gt;If you were using the ZeroSSL issuer with an API key, it will now start using ZeroSSL's API,&lt;/strong&gt; which was probably the expected behavior anyways. The API has several advantages over the ACME endpoint, but may require payment:
        - Faster response times
        - IP certificates
        - Management tools in your ZeroSSL account dashboard
        - Technical support
    - To clarify, Let's Encrypt is still a default issuer even if you don't provide an email address (but we have always strongly recommended to do so).
    - You can still use ZeroSSL's ACME endpoint with your own External Account Binding (EAB) credentials.
    - See notes in #6229 for some examples and further explanations.
- Removed support for &lt;a href="https://github.com/caddy-dns/lego-deprecated"&gt;the &lt;code&gt;lego_deprecated&lt;/code&gt; DNS provider module&lt;/a&gt;. It has been deprecated for 4 years. Use &lt;a href="https://github.com/caddy-dns"&gt;&lt;code&gt;caddy-dns&lt;/code&gt; modules&lt;/a&gt; instead; there are over 50 to choose from already. They are more flexible, compile much leaner, and are easier to implement and support. If yours is not supported it can be easily implemented. &lt;a href="https://caddyserver.com/sponsor"&gt;Sponsors at or above the Business tier&lt;/a&gt; can request to have their provider implemented for free.
- On-demand TLS: The &lt;code&gt;ask&lt;/code&gt; option in the JSON has been deprecated in favor of a permission module (Caddyfile unchanged) (#6055), and Caddyfile support for &lt;code&gt;permission&lt;/code&gt; modules is added (6a02999)
- Admin API: &lt;code&gt;Etag&lt;/code&gt; (used for concurrency control) is now a header, not a trailer. This is less efficient, but still virtually no clients properly implement trailer support.
- For consistency, the &lt;code&gt;basicauth&lt;/code&gt; Caddyfile directive has been renamed to &lt;code&gt;basic_auth&lt;/code&gt; (#6092), and &lt;code&gt;skip_log&lt;/code&gt; has been renamed to &lt;code&gt;log_skip&lt;/code&gt;. The old names will continue to work for now, with a deprecation warning in the logs. (#6066).
- The &lt;code&gt;basic_auth&lt;/code&gt; handler no longer supports &lt;code&gt;scrypt&lt;/code&gt; (deprecated for nearly two years) (#6091)
- The &lt;code&gt;forwarded&lt;/code&gt; option has been deprecated for a long time and has now been removed from the &lt;code&gt;remote_ip&lt;/code&gt; matcher. Use the &lt;code&gt;client_ip&lt;/code&gt; matcher instead. (#6085)
- Reverse proxy: The &lt;code&gt;buffer_requests&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;buffer_responses&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code&gt;max_buffer_size&lt;/code&gt; settings have been removed after being deprecated for 14 months. Use &lt;code&gt;request_buffers&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;response_buffers&lt;/code&gt; instead if you need buffering.
- Go API: If you called &lt;code&gt;caddy.Context.AppIfConfigured()&lt;/code&gt;, it now returns an error, as part of a bug fix. (#6292)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Notable changes:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;acme_server: Configurable allow/deny policies (#5796)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;acme_server: Specify allowed challenge types (#5794)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;caddyfile: Plugin authors can now specify a default ordering for directives, making manual ordering by users less necessary (#5865)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;cmd: The &lt;code&gt;--adapter&lt;/code&gt; flag is not needed for config files ending with &lt;code&gt;.caddyfile&lt;/code&gt; (#5919)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;encode: More media types are now compressed by default (#6081)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;encode: Modify ETag when encoding to comply with RFC 9110 section 8.8.3 (#5849)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;encode: Configurable compression level for &lt;code&gt;zstd&lt;/code&gt; (#6140)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;handle_errors: Handling can now be filtered by response status code more easily (#5965)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;http: New &lt;code&gt;fs&lt;/code&gt; directive can declare a file system plugin to use (#5057)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;http: Sensitive headers in the logs are now replaced with &lt;code&gt;["REDACTED"]&lt;/code&gt; instead of empty array. (#5669)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;http: Several improvements to size logging, websockets, flushing, 1xx statuses, and QUIC. (#6173, #6175, #6202, #6150, #6164, #6168)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;http: Can now write access logs for a hostname to more than one logger (#6088)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;http: The &lt;code&gt;log_append&lt;/code&gt; handler can add fields to the access logs (#6066)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;http: Add &lt;code&gt;uuid&lt;/code&gt; field to access logs when the &lt;code&gt;{http.request.uuid}&lt;/code&gt; placeholder is used (#5859)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;http: Changed PROXY protocol libraries add TLV support (#5915)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;http: A new tracing mode writes each individual middleware handler to logs (#6313)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;http: Access logs use a different message ("unhandled") when an HTTP request is a no-op (#5182)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;file_server: The browse feature can now return a plaintext response (useful for terminals) (#6093)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;file_server: File listings can dereference symlinks if enabled (#5973)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;file_server: Directory listings now include total file size (#6003)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;file_server: Can use precomputed ETags from sidecar files (#6222)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;replacer: A new &lt;code&gt;{file.*}&lt;/code&gt; global placeholder is available, where &lt;code&gt;*&lt;/code&gt; is a path to a file on disk which contains a value (generally used for secrets) (#5463)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;reverse_proxy: HTTP/3 supported to backends (experimental) (#6312)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;reverse_proxy: Active health checks can now be configured with consecutive passes/fails to change status (#6154)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;reverse_proxy: A forward proxy can now be specified in config other than a single env var (#6114)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;reverse_proxy: Configurable trusted root CAs is now modular (#6065)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;reverse_proxy: SRV upstreams now support failovers/grace period with cache (#5832)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;reverse_proxy: TLS curves can now be configured (potential preparation for post-quantum) (#5851)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;root, rewrite: A &lt;code&gt;*&lt;/code&gt; matcher token is no longer required in the Caddyfile (#5844)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;tls: Client authentication validation methods are now modular/pluggable (#6050)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;tls: Trusted CA providers are now modular (#5784)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;tls: New &lt;code&gt;local_ip&lt;/code&gt; connection matcher (#6074)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;tls: Improvements and fixes when certificate managers are configured (#6229)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;tls: Refactor the On-Demand TLS &lt;code&gt;ask&lt;/code&gt; endpoint into a &lt;code&gt;permission&lt;/code&gt; module, making it pluggable (#6055)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;tls: Storage cleaning is now synced across instances that share the storage (#5940)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;tls: Supports ACME Renewal Information (ARI) draft spec, together with cert lifetime and OCSP/revocation status, to trigger certificate renewals&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;uri: Can now perform structured query rewrites with &lt;code&gt;uri query&lt;/code&gt; (#6120, #6165)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Changelog&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Full Changelog&lt;/strong&gt;: https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/compare/v2.7.6...v2.8.0&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ac0ad4da  Upgrade acmeserver to github.com/go-chi/chi/v5 (#5913)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;931656bd acmeserver: add policy field to define allow/deny rules (#5796)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;e1aa862e acmeserver: support specifying the allowed challenge types (#5794)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;e6f46c8d acmeserver: Add &lt;code&gt;sign_with_root&lt;/code&gt; for Caddyfile (#6345)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;4a0492f3 admin: Make &lt;code&gt;Etag&lt;/code&gt; a header, not a trailer (#6208)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;12174496 admin: Use xxhash for etag (#6207)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;7e2510ef build(deps): bump golangci/golangci-lint-action from 4 to 5 (#6289)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;4f3f6e35 build(deps): bump actions/setup-go from 4 to 5 (#6012)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;8a50f191 build(deps): bump actions/upload-artifact from 3 to 4 (#6013)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1bf72db6 build(deps): bump golang.org/x/crypto from 0.16.0 to 0.17.0 (#5994)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;223f3143 build(deps): bump peter-evans/repository-dispatch from 2 to 3 (#6080)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;30d63648 caddyauth: Drop support for &lt;code&gt;scrypt&lt;/code&gt; (#6091)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;f9e11158 caddyauth: Rename &lt;code&gt;basicauth&lt;/code&gt; to &lt;code&gt;basic_auth&lt;/code&gt; (#6092)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;f4840cfe caddyconfig: Use empty struct instead of bool in map (close #6224) (#6227)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;f6d2c293 caddyfile: Reject global request matchers earlier (#6339)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;c0273f1f caddyfile: Add heredoc support to &lt;code&gt;fmt&lt;/code&gt; command (#6056)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;d9aded01 caddyfile: Allow heredoc blank lines (#6051)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;8bbf8ec6 caddyfile: Assert having a space after heredoc marker to simply check (#6117)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;c369df5c caddyfile: Correctly close the heredoc when the closing marker appears immediately (#6062)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1f60328e caddyfile: Fix variadic placeholder false positive when token contains &lt;code&gt;:&lt;/code&gt; (#5883)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;750d0b83 caddyfile: Normalize &amp;amp; flatten all unmarshalers (#6037)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;9cd472c0 caddyfile: Populate regexp matcher names by default (#6145)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;b893c8c5 caddyfile: Reject directives in the place of site addresses (#6104)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;e7a534d0 caddyfile: Reject long heredoc markers (#6098)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;7c48b5fd caddyfile: Switch to slices.Equal for better performance (#6061)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;63d597c0 caddyhttp: Accept XFF header values with ports, when parsing client IP (#6183)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3d7d60f7 caddyhttp: Add &lt;code&gt;uuid&lt;/code&gt; to access logs when used (#5859)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;45132c5b caddyhttp: Add plaintext response to &lt;code&gt;file_server browse&lt;/code&gt; (#6093)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;6d97d8d8 caddyhttp: Address some Go 1.20 features (#6252)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;4c10a054 caddyhttp: Adjust &lt;code&gt;scheme&lt;/code&gt; placeholder docs (#5910)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;97a56d86 caddyhttp: Allow &lt;code&gt;header&lt;/code&gt; replacement with empty string (#6163)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;83ef61de caddyhttp: Apply auto HTTPS redir to all interfaces (fix #6226)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2fc620d3 caddyhttp: Fix linter warning about deprecation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;f5344f8c caddyhttp: Fix panic when request missing ClientIPVarKey (#6040)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2c48dda1 caddyhttp: Only attempt to enable full duplex for HTTP/1.x (#6102)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;12778880 caddyhttp: Register post-shutdown callbacks (#5948)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;7b48ce0e caddyhttp: Replace sensitive headers with REDACTED (close #5669)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;cc0c0cf0 caddyhttp: Security enhancements for client IP parsing (#5805)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;70953e87 caddyhttp: Support multiple logger names per host (#6088)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;bde46211 caddyhttp: Test cases for &lt;code&gt;%2F&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;%252F&lt;/code&gt; (#6084)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;c8559c44 caddyhttp: Use sync.Pool to reduce lengthReader allocations (#5848)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ddb1d2c2 caddyhttp: add http.request.local{,.host,.port} placeholder (#6182)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;924010cd caddyhttp: close quic connections when server closes (#6202)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;e0daa39c caddyhttp: record num. bytes read when response writer is hijacked (#6173)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;654a3bb0 caddyhttp: remove duplicate strings.Count in path matcher (fixes #6233) (#6234)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;b568a10d caddyhttp: support unix sockets in &lt;code&gt;caddy respond&lt;/code&gt; command (#6010)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;c93e3045 caddyhttp: suppress flushing if the response is being buffered (#6150)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;52822a41 caddyhttp: upgrade to cel v0.20.0 (#6161)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;224316ea caddyhttp: Move log WARN to INFO, reduce confusion (#6185)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;6dce4934 caddyhttp: Alter log message when request is unhandled (close #5182)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;4af38e5a caddyhttp: Log 4xx as INFO; 5xx as ERROR (close #6106)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fb63e2e4 caddyhttp: New experimental handler for intercepting responses (#6232)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;9ba99914 caddyhttp: Trace individual middleware handlers (#6313)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;c97292b2 caddypki: Allow use of root CA without a key. Fixes #6290 (#6298)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;4512be49 caddytest: Rename adapt tests to &lt;code&gt;*.caddyfiletest&lt;/code&gt; extension (#6119)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;4c90f142 caddytest: normalize the JSON config (#6316)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;8d7ac184 caddytls: Ability to drop connections (close #6294)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;6a029990 caddytls: Add Caddyfile support for on-demand permission module (close #6260)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;b24ae63e caddytls: Context to DecisionFunc (#5923)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;d129ae6a caddytls: Evict internal certs from cache based on issuer (#6266)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;57c5b921 caddytls: Make on-demand 'ask' permission modular (#6055)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;76c4cf5a caddytls: Option to configure certificate lifetime (#6253)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3609a4af caddytls: Remove shim code supporting deprecated lego-dns (#6231)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;dc9dd2e4 caddytls: Still provision permission module if ask is specified&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;4a09cf0d caddytls: Sync distributed storage cleaning (#5940)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;81413cae caddytls: Upgrade ACMEz to v2; support ZeroSSL API; various fixes (#6229)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3ae07a73 caddytls: clientauth: leaf verifier: make trusted leaf certs source pluggable (#6050)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;03f703a0 caddytls: verifier: caddyfile: re-add Caddyfile support (#6127)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;db3e19b7 caddytls: fix permission requirement with AutomationPolicy (#6328)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1fc151fa caddytls: remove ClientHelloSNICtxKey (#6326)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;e66040a6 caddytls: set server name in context (#6324)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;b359ca56 ci/cd: use the build tag &lt;code&gt;nobadger&lt;/code&gt; to exclude badgerdb (#6031)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;24b0ecc3 cmd: Add newline character to version string in CLI output (#5895)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;e473ae68 cmd: Adjust config load logs/errors (#6032)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;185ed6fe cmd: Assume Caddyfile based on filename prefix and suffix (#5919)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;e1f4b83f cmd: Fix panic related to config filename (fix #5919)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;8f87c5d9 cmd: Only validate config is proper JSON if config slice has data (#6250)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;56c6b3f6 cmd: Preserve LastModified date when exporting storage (#5968)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;de4959fe cmd: fix the output of the &lt;code&gt;Usage&lt;/code&gt; section (#6138)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;54823f52 cmd: reverseproxy: log: use caddy logger (#6042)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;d70608b6 cmd: upgrade: resolve symlink of the executable (#5891)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;d54dcf15 cmd: use automaxprocs for better perf in containers (#5711)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;e1b9a9d7 core: Add &lt;code&gt;ctx.Slogger()&lt;/code&gt; which returns an &lt;code&gt;slog&lt;/code&gt; logger (#5945)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;cbbd1df9 core: Always make AppDataDir for InstanceID (#5976)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;174c19a9 core: Apply SO_REUSEPORT to UDP sockets (#5725)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;46c5db92 core: OnExit hooks (#6128)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a7479302 core: Support NO_COLOR env var to disable log coloring (#6078)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;7c82e265 core: quic listener will manage the underlying socket by itself (#5749)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a6a45ff6 core: AppIfConfigured returns error; consider not-yet-provisioned modules (#6292)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2ce5c652 core: Fix bug in AppIfConfigured (fix #6336)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;03e0a010 encode: Configurable compression level for zstd (#6140)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3067074d encode: Improve Etag handling (fix #5849)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;9ab09433 encode: Slight fix for the previous commit&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;e698ec51 encode: write status immediately when status code is informational (#6164)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ba581146 events: Add debug log&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;7e52db82 fileserver: Add .m4v for browse template icon&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;8f9ffc58 fileserver: Add total file size to directory listing (#6003)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feb07a7b fileserver: Browse can show symlink target if enabled (#5973)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;b16aba5c fileserver: Enable compression for command by default (#5855)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;5d8b45c9 fileserver: Escape # and ? in img src (fix #6237)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;f3e849e4 fileserver: Implement caddyfile.Unmarshaler interface (#5850)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;d00824f4 fileserver: Improve Vary handling (#5849)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;362f33da fileserver: New --precompressed flag (#5880)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;5a4374be fileserver: Preserve query during canonicalization redirect (#6109)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;cabb5d71 fileserver: Set "Vary: Accept-Encoding" header (see #5849)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;567d96c6 fileserver: read etags from precomputed files (#6222)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;c839a98f filesystem: Globally declared filesystems, &lt;code&gt;fs&lt;/code&gt; directive (#5833)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;60abd72c fix: add back text/*&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;b8f729b8 fix: add more media types to the compressed by default list&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a4a64a6f gitignore: Add rule for caddyfile.go (#6225)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;9fc55a97 go.mod: CVE-2023-45142 Update opentelemetry (#5908)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fe2a02bf go.mod: Upgrade quic-go to v0.39.1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;b49ec051 go.mod: Updated quic-go to v0.40.1 (#5983)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ee358550 go.mod: update quic-go version to v0.40.0 (#5922)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a46ff50a go.mod: Upgrade to quic-go v0.43.0&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;b5227106 go.mod: Upgrade to quic-go v0.43.1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;dd203ad4 go.mod: CertMagic v0.21.0&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;d79c0f0d go.mod: Upgrade dependencies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;abdf1ae1 go.mod: go 1.22.3&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;258d9061 httpcaddyfile: Add &lt;code&gt;RegisterDirectiveOrder&lt;/code&gt; function for plugin authors (#5865)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;4181c79a httpcaddyfile: Add optional status code argument to &lt;code&gt;handle_errors&lt;/code&gt; directive (#5965)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2a78c9c5 httpcaddyfile: Allow nameless regexp placeholder shorthand (#6113)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;7984e6f6 httpcaddyfile: Fix TLS automation policy merging with get_certificate (#5896)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;f976c84d httpcaddyfile: Fix cert file decoding to load multiple PEM in one file (#5997)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;c2d889f8 httpcaddyfile: Fix redir &lt;to&gt; html (#6001)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;c27425ef httpcaddyfile: Keep deprecated &lt;code&gt;skip_log&lt;/code&gt; in directive order (#6153)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ac1f20b9 httpcaddyfile: Remove port from logger names (#5881)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;5e2f1b5c httpcaddyfile: Rewrite &lt;code&gt;root&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;rewrite&lt;/code&gt; parsing to allow omitting matcher (#5844)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3efda6fb httpcaddyfile: Skip automate loader if disable_certs is specified (fix #6148)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;da7d8cb2 httpcaddyfile: Sort skip_hosts for deterministic JSON (#5990)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;cb86319b httpcaddyfile: Support client auth verifiers (#6022)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feeb6af4 httpcaddyfile: Fix expression matcher shortcut in snippets (#6288)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;583c585c httpcaddyfile: Set challenge ports when http_port or https_port are used&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;96f638ea httpredirectlistener: Only set read limit for when request is HTTP (#5917)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3248e4c8 logging: Add &lt;code&gt;zap.Option&lt;/code&gt; support (#5944)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;b9c40e71 logging: Automatic &lt;code&gt;wrap&lt;/code&gt; default for &lt;code&gt;filter&lt;/code&gt; encoder (#5980)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;726a9a8f logging: Fix default access logger (#6251)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;01d5568b logging: Implement &lt;code&gt;append&lt;/code&gt; encoder, allow flatter filters config (#6069)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;0d44e3ec logging: Implement &lt;code&gt;log_append&lt;/code&gt; handler (#6066)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;91ec7544 logging: Inline Caddyfile syntax for &lt;code&gt;ip_mask&lt;/code&gt; filter (#6094)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;0c015470 logging: support &lt;code&gt;ms&lt;/code&gt; duration format and add docs (#6187)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;4356635d logging: Add support for additional logger filters other than hostname (#6082)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;8c2a72ad caddyhttp: Drop &lt;code&gt;forwarded&lt;/code&gt; option from &lt;code&gt;remote_ip&lt;/code&gt; matcher (#6085)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ed7e3c90 caddyhttp: &lt;code&gt;query&lt;/code&gt; matcher now ANDs multiple keys (#6054)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;387545a8 metrics: Record request metrics on HTTP errors (#5979)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;e0bf179c modules: fix some typo in conments (#6206)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;dc12bd97 proxyprotocol: use github.com/pires/go-proxyproto (#5915)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;dba556fe refactor: move automaxprocs init in caddycmd.Main()&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;80acf1bf replacer: Fix escaped closing braces (#5995)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;79797394 replacer: Implement &lt;code&gt;file.*&lt;/code&gt; global replacements (#5463)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;e7336cc3 replacer: use RWMutex to protect static provider (#6184)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;868af6a0 reverseproxy: Add grace_period for SRV upstreams to Caddyfile (#6264)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;613d544a reverseproxy: Accept EOF when buffering&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;f658fd05 reverseproxy: Add &lt;code&gt;tls_curves&lt;/code&gt; option to HTTP transport (#5851)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a9768d2f reverseproxy: Configurable forward proxy URL (#6114)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;0b381eb7 reverseproxy: Implement modular CA provider for TLS transport (#6065)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;d9ff7b18 reverseproxy: Only change Content-Length when full request is buffered (#5830)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;9f97df22 reverseproxy: Remove long-deprecated buffering properties&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;d93e027e reverseproxy: Reuse buffered request body even if partially drained&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;72ce78d9 reverseproxy: SRV dynamic upstream failover (#5832)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;74949fb0 reverseproxy: Use xxhash instead of fnv32 for LB (#6203)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;b40cacf5 reverseproxy: Wait for both ends of websocket to close (#6175)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;e65b97f5 reverseproxy: configurable active health_passes and health_fails (#6154)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;da6a569e reverseproxy: cookie should be Secure and SameSite=None when TLS (#6115)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1b9042bc reverseproxy: handle buffered data during hijack (#6274)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;53f70352 reverseproxy: use context.WithoutCancel (#6116)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;d05d715a reverseproxy: HTTP transport: fix PROXY protocol initialization (#6301)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;b2b29dcd reverseproxy: Implement health_follow_redirects (#6302)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;e60148ec reverseproxy: Pointer to struct when loading modules; remove LazyCertPool (#6307)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;5f6758da reverseproxy: Support HTTP/3 transport to backend (#6312)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;69290d23 rewrite: Implement &lt;code&gt;uri query&lt;/code&gt; operations (#6120)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;29f57faa rewrite: &lt;code&gt;uri query&lt;/code&gt; replace operation (#6165)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;c6673ad4 staticresp: Use the evaluated response body for sniffing JSON content-type (#6249)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;0900844c templates: Clarify &lt;code&gt;include&lt;/code&gt; args docs, add &lt;code&gt;.ClientIP&lt;/code&gt; (#5898)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;4e8245df templates: Delete headers on &lt;code&gt;httpError&lt;/code&gt; to reset to clean slate (#5905)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;18f34290 templates: Offically make templates extensible (#5939)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;f98f449f templates: Add &lt;code&gt;pathEscape&lt;/code&gt; template function and use it in file browser (#6278)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;4173e2c7 tls: accept placeholders in string values of certificate loaders (#5963)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ed41c924 tls: add reuse_private_keys (#6025)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;e965b111 tls: modularize trusted CA providers (#5784)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;0b5720fa tracing: add trace_id var (&lt;code&gt;http.vars.trace_id&lt;/code&gt; placeholder) (#6308)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;5ed86896 vars: Allow overriding &lt;code&gt;http.auth.user.id&lt;/code&gt; in replacer as a special case (#6108)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;d1325842 vars: Make nil values act as empty string instead of &lt;code&gt;"&amp;lt;nil&amp;gt;"&lt;/code&gt; (#6174)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;New Contributors&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;@perhapsmaple made their first contribution in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/5848&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;@ddl-ebrown made their first contribution in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/5908&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;@dlorenc made their first contribution in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/5949&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;@ankon made their first contribution in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/5923&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;@bmarwell made their first contribution in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/5971&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;@armadi1809 made their first contribution in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/5976&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;@jum made their first contribution in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/5968&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;@ddemoss222 made their first contribution in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/5880&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;@tgeoghegan made their first contribution in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/5979&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;@steffenbusch made their first contribution in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6003&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;@networkException made their first contribution in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6010&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;@insom made their first contribution in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6021&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;@rithvikvibhu made their first contribution in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6025&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;@zachgalvin made their first contribution in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6022&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;@subnut made their first contribution in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6001&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;@elee1766 made their first contribution in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/5833&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;@nebez made their first contribution in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/5805&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;@bbaa-bbaa made their first contribution in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6056&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;@AnomalRoil made their first contribution in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/5961&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;@jcchavezs made their first contribution in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6103&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;@ottenhoff made their first contribution in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6115&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;@thirdkeyword made their first contribution in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6151&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;@jbrown-stripe made their first contribution in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6161&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;@ImpostorKeanu made their first contribution in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6114&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;@sellskin made their first contribution in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6193&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;@jadidbourbaki made their first contribution in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6203&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;@reallylowest made their first contribution in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6206&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;@kylosus made their first contribution in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6093&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;@hassanila made their first contribution in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6223&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;@epelc made their first contribution in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6225&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;@danish-mehmood made their first contribution in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6227&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;@omalk98 made their first contribution in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/5919&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;@dev-polymer made their first contribution in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6140&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;@coderwander made their first contribution in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6243&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;@clauverjat made their first contribution in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6253&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;@apollo13 made their first contribution in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6298&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;@aliasgar55 made their first contribution in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6302&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;@szepeviktor made their first contribution in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6311&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;@DenebTM made their first contribution in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6278&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;@Ranveer777 made their first contribution in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6345&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/releases/tag/v2.8.0" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/releases/tag/v2.8.1</id>
    <title>New release for Caddy: v2.8.1</title>
    <updated>2024-05-30T10:31:22-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>caddyserver/caddy</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;Quick fixes for a few users related to directory permissions and matcher parsing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Changelog&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;40c582ce caddyhttp: Fix merging consecutive &lt;code&gt;client_ip&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;remote_ip&lt;/code&gt; matchers (#6350)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a52917a3 core: MkdirAll appDataDir in InstanceID with 0o700 (#6340)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/releases/tag/v2.8.1" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/releases/tag/v2.8.2</id>
    <title>New release for Caddy: v2.8.2</title>
    <updated>2024-06-02T00:46:25-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>caddyserver/caddy</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;A few more fixes of reported bugs related to ARI, &lt;code&gt;try_files&lt;/code&gt; with the root path (&lt;code&gt;/&lt;/code&gt;), and Caddyfile adapter detection on the CLI. See 2.8.0 release notes for details on 2.8.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Changelog&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;01308b4b I'm so tired of typos&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a63767d3 build(deps): bump golangci/golangci-lint-action from 5 to 6 (#6361)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;f8a2c602 caddyhttp: properly sanitize requests for root path (#6360)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;b7280e69 caddytls: Implement certmagic.RenewalInfoGetter&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;15faeacb cmd: fix auto-detetction of .caddyfile extension (#6356)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Full Changelog&lt;/strong&gt;: https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/compare/v2.8.1...v2.8.2&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/releases/tag/v2.8.2" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/releases/tag/v2.8.4</id>
    <title>New release for Caddy: v2.8.4</title>
    <updated>2024-06-02T08:24:47-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>caddyserver/caddy</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;Hotfix for the Caddyfile detection regression in v2.8.2. The v2.8.3 tag was mistakenly made on the wrong commit and is skipped.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Changelog&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;7088605c cmd: fix regression in auto-detect of Caddyfile (#6362)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/releases/tag/v2.8.4" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/releases/tag/v2.9.0</id>
    <title>New release for Caddy: v2.9.0</title>
    <updated>2024-12-31T12:34:20-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>caddyserver/caddy</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;Happy New Year! We're pleased to release Caddy 2.9. Aside from some minor new features, this release is mainly focused on refinements and bug fixes in many areas, including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Config loading&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Events&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Logging&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Placeholders&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reverse proxy and HTTP server performance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Matchers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;HTTP (esp. HTTP/3)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Metrics (per-host metrics)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Security&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;TLS automation &amp;amp; ACME ARI&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We realize there is extensive interest in Encrypted Client Hello (ECH) and post-quantum ciphers. These are slated to be supported in Go 1.24, which is scheduled for a stable release in approximately February. We did not want to force users to go through the inconvenience of installing pre-release, non-stock installations of Go, even though the RCs are quite stable and production-ready, in order to even compile Caddy, which is quite common given our plugin ecosystem. We anticipate a Caddy 2.10 release in the near future with these capabilities, built on Go 1.24.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We hope you will enjoy the 2.9 release. Thanks to all contributors, bug reporters, and helpers, and those organizations which deployed pre-release versions to production to help verify patches and features.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Changelog&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ef4e0224a8495fc29847d865087febdee8736e3b caddyfile: Fix comma edgecase in address parsing (#6616)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;b116dcea3d022cd2b060a978c499ac17e5d0a2e1 caddyhttp: Add &lt;code&gt;{?query}&lt;/code&gt; placeholder (#6714)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;c216cf551dcbd2de1da1b9fe8a7e179b76827753 caddyhttp: Allow matching Transfer-Encoding, add to access logs (#6629)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;197c564f2032becba14aeec0152fe5eeb639d6c1 caddyhttp: Set default ReadHeaderTimeout (1 min)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;09b2cbcf4d839adec91b189fea549d64a69e0595 caddyhttp: Add &lt;code&gt;MatchWithError&lt;/code&gt; to replace SetVar hack (#6596)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;c6f2979986d87d7236b132c687c8887c92248dd8 caddyhttp: Close http3 server gracefully (#6213)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;88fd5f3491ab888f69f0be02cea68a49164298eb caddyhttp: Use internal issuer for IPs when no APs configured&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;5c8dc344181c49bc7feade4a293bb4eed882b838 caddytls: Allow disabling storage cleaning, avoids writing two files (#6593)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;d7564d632fbed209e81978c5c2c529a7bf1836f7 caddytls: Drop &lt;code&gt;rate_limit&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;burst&lt;/code&gt;, has been deprecated (#6611)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;d398898b352a6a7e8ac5c24da01dd948fc334d77 cmd: Allow &lt;code&gt;add-package&lt;/code&gt; to select version of package (#6665)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;66c80caf236e2d98e61bf1bc8bb062d7b8c25430 cmd: Disable go1.23 tlskyber=1 experiment&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fb72793269d419b2b37b5f1db8141c63818be514 cmd: Reject multiple configs for fmt command (#6717)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;b3ce260389a88a35c9b0e0a19a93abfe92fb6e9f cmd: ignore missing keys during storage export (#6697)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;0182fb87fa7276463086c2360431a1c0dc797edf core: addresses.go funcs renames (#6622)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;e76405d55058b0a3e5ba222b44b5ef00516116aa core: Change ListenerFunc signature (#6651)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;315715e90ffa25c4ad0d8a96e828dbdf6f638583 core: Implement FastAbs to avoid repeated os.Getwd calls (#6687)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;d0e209e1da6cd6d7d61e83b851f2913ee31454f8 encode: good defaults (#6737)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;5ba1e06fd661aac2cbaab6d4a2ef63a9eb877a46 encode: try to use sendfile when compression is not used (#6749)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;bcaa8aaf114629031d10dcef0ca7680ae8163e32 encode: write status immediate for success response for CONNECT requests (#6738)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1d156527ea8fef0a96faa54d7ff61244e4be4094 events: Use &lt;code&gt;WithLazy&lt;/code&gt; to prevent eager serialization of the event data (#6671)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;6790c0e38abcc534c4b3365b6e438148001fd6df fastcgi: check for CONTENT_LENGTH when sending requests (#6661)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;eddbccd298f637c4785c891f5f96dbf103580fa8 fastcgi: remove dir redirection when useless in php_fastcgi (#6698)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;efd9251ad38a4fd9f7d900445400ac3c8e564c28 fileserver: Add &lt;code&gt;first_exist_fallback&lt;/code&gt; strategy for &lt;code&gt;try_files&lt;/code&gt; (#6699)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;d0123bd760f6c140f3b935159a55ba64899c84f8 fileserver: Fix policy &lt;code&gt;Validate()&lt;/code&gt; oversight (#6727)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;290cfea08f2486fb86dbc11eec96d79751180eda fileserver: add a test for precompressed defaults (#6743)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;5c2617ebf9303100fc8c6be2a80b966b2c7fb7f1 fileserver: good default for precompressed (#6736)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;cc23ad6402e6dace30b04f0d9113530a4d9541a9 fileserver: Add &lt;code&gt;file_limit&lt;/code&gt; option for browse (to be experimental) (#6648)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;350ad38f63f7a49ceb3821c58d689b85a27ec4e5 fileserver: Fix Caddyfile parsing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;9753c4451077d4459ec10cb3df27ab9dc4456290 fileserver: fix try_policy when instantiating file matcher from CEL (#6624)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;05cfb121ec3f214c0e45206c188f34bad4d4eb8c forwardauth: Skip copying missing response headers (#6608)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ed1c594cdbddf89829eaf1174f414028577b432d go.mod: Upgrade ACMEz to v3; and upgrade CertMagic&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3f3f8b3d5270add46d5fc7d99bdcc705ad2d5df4 go.mod: Upgrade CertMagic to v0.21.5&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;91e34139a17b8914a62669b275084b5d225e0624 go.mod: upgrade only some otel deps (#6676)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;22b9d512687cdcfbf0c574a645fcf0edd23a584f go.mod: Upgrade quic-go to 0.48.2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;b129ed6be88e40667a843bfab74abb3e5239bc8f httpcaddyfile: Fixes for &lt;code&gt;prefer_wildcard&lt;/code&gt; mode (#6636)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;afa778ae05503f563af0d1015cdf7e5e78b1eeec httpcaddyfile: Implement experimental &lt;code&gt;force_automate&lt;/code&gt; option (#6712)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;b183aec83c2d467706583ad9ea0e4e9c56077c55 httpcaddyfile: Implement log &lt;code&gt;sampling&lt;/code&gt; config (#6682)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1d106fa14d7bc150acb1107ea7d034d669f9f80d metrics: add &lt;code&gt;go&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;process&lt;/code&gt; collectors (#6704)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;388c7e898c6cbcddd2c59e8a902238a0b4f06857 metrics: move &lt;code&gt;metrics&lt;/code&gt;  up, outside &lt;code&gt;servers&lt;/code&gt; (#6606)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;8c3dd3de709040d72bd98a756a044c453d7e871e requestbody: Type-based error handling for &lt;code&gt;MaxBytesError&lt;/code&gt; (#6701)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;5e6024c48da68492761837af3806be1951fa4c24 reverseproxy: Fix log message&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;48ce47f1d44da485fbbf6be536a0e3822763f313 reverseproxy: Use correct cases for websocket related headers (#6621)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;825fe48e0654dc6e4e065df364a51ea79488e44b reverseproxy: Allow &lt;code&gt;0&lt;/code&gt; as weights for &lt;code&gt;weighted_round_robin&lt;/code&gt; (#6681)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;328fb614f0e9996b184f41d59b7092c21dd9c712 reverseproxy: Only handle websocket protocol (#6740)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;238f1108e6600049d9041abc88db24526ee4f882 reverseproxy: Revert #4952 - don't ignore context cancellation in stream mode&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;9c0c71e5774593e15a555d5c88de0af011e46394 reverseproxy: Rewrite requests and responses for websocket over http2 (#6567)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;c864b82ae13f9dc920ebd8782fe7c5b7007a3e1b reverseproxy: Set Content-Length when body is fully buffered (#6638)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fbf0f4c425b23c39dbddd975d36df506cca5f45b reverseproxy: Sync changes from stdlib for 1xx handling (#6656)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;5823eccf99d9fc6b4ffba8a78acfdb59c4ec0c97 rewrite: Don't add / in Caddyfile, do it after replacer (#6662)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;b443190b66055089d1e112abc992512ca4f6bfba sigtrap: always ignore SIGPIPE (#6645)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;f2c17d1f3fc4d9ad6324e05bab0c29aafb23e2e1 testing: sort force-automated hosts (#6756)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;669fc41e6321115df554d5f7d8eb55fdfbdaab18 tracing: Add &lt;code&gt;spanID&lt;/code&gt; field to access logs and &lt;code&gt;http.vars.span_id&lt;/code&gt; placeholder (#6646)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What's Changed&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make it possible to configure the &lt;code&gt;DisableStorageCheck&lt;/code&gt; setting for certmagic by @ankon in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6368&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;caddyhttp: Add test case to corpus by @mholt in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6374&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;cmd: remove zealous check of Caddyfile auto-detection by @mohammed90 in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6370&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ci: upgrade to goreleaser v2 by @mohammed90 in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6376&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;logging: Allow setting log file permissions by @ririsoft in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6314&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Split &lt;code&gt;run&lt;/code&gt; into a public &lt;code&gt;BuildContext&lt;/code&gt; and a private part by @ankon in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6378&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Write the header if none had been written in WriteResponse by @ankon in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6380&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix file mode configuration parsing by @ririsoft in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6383&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;go.mod: update tscert package by @willnorris in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6384&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;logging: Customizable &lt;code&gt;zapcore.Core&lt;/code&gt; by @kkroo in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6381&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;logging: set file mode when the file already exist. by @ririsoft in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6391&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;caddyfile: Pass blocks to &lt;code&gt;import&lt;/code&gt; for snippets by @elee1766 in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6130&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;reverseproxy: add Max-Age option to sticky cookie by @JasonYuan869 in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6398&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fileserver: Remove newline characters from precomputed etags by @armadi1809 in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6394&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix: http.intercept.header.* placeholders by @dunglas in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6429&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;reverseproxy: Only log host is up status on change by @klaxa in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6419&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix: don't compress already compressed fonts by @dunglas in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6432&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;caddyhttp: Reject 0-RTT early data in IP matchers and set Early-Data header when proxying by @mholt in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6427&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;reverseproxy: Add placeholder for host in active health check headers by @francislavoie in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6440&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;browse: add Content-Security-Policy w/ nonce by @steffenbusch in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6425&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;browse: fix Content-Security-Policy warnings in Firefox by @steffenbusch in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6443&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fileserver: Exclude symlink target size from total, show arrow on size by @francislavoie in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6412&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;reverseproxy: Fix dynamic upstreams ip version by @armadi1809 in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6448&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;reverseproxy: Add placeholder for networkAddr in active health check headers by @dylanschultzie in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6450&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add option to set which HTTP method to use for active health checks by @jbro in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6453&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;reverseproxy: Caddyfile support for health_method by @jbro in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6454&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;reverseproxy: add health_upstream subdirective by @dylanschultzie in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6451&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ci: correct &lt;code&gt;-tags nobadger&lt;/code&gt; on binary build by @girlbossceo in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6470&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Caddyfile support for TLS handshake matchers by @vnxme in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6461&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Caddyfile support for TLS connection and certificate selection policies by @vnxme in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6462&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;chore: update golangci config by @mohammed90 in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6479&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;encode: flush already compressed data to the stream by @WeidiDeng in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6471&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;proxyprotocol: Update WrapListener to use ConnPolicyFunc for PROXY protocol by @pi-prakhar in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6485&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fileserver: add &lt;code&gt;sort&lt;/code&gt; options by @lollipopkit in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6468&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;go.mod: update quic-go package by @WeidiDeng in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6498&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Runtime placeholders for selected TLS and HTTP matchers by @vnxme in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6480&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;replacer: &lt;code&gt;{file.*}&lt;/code&gt; global placeholder strips trailing newline by @steffenbusch in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6411&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;go.mod: update update golang/x/net by @WeidiDeng in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6500&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;reverse_proxy: apply keep-alive setting for h2c requests by @WeidiDeng in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6343&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix a regression in #6480: the context may have no replacer by @vnxme in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6510&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;caddyhttp: Export PrivateRangesCIDR() for plugins after #6480 by @vnxme in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6514&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ignore exec.ErrDot when starting caddy in background by @WeidiDeng in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6512&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ci: don't exit early on error in remote CI machine by @mohammed90 in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6519&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;reverseproxy: Active health checks request body option by @jbro in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6520&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;reverseproxy: Change logs for write errors to warn level by @jum in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6532&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;cmd: Use a factory to create the caddy root command by @elee1766 in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6533&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;chore: Fix a typo by @sunnyagain in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6534&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;error: run &lt;code&gt;error&lt;/code&gt; (msg) through replacer by @mohammed90 in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6536&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;reverseproxy: allow user to define source address by @mohammed90 in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6504&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;chore: build and test with Go 1.23 by @dunglas in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6526&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;tls: use Go default kex for the moment that include PQC by @bwesterb in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6542&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ci: prepare syso files for windows embedding in release by @WeidiDeng in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6406&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Performance: Prevents the zap logger from serializing the request in rewrite.go. by @AlliBalliBaba in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6541&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fileserver: move &lt;code&gt;sort&lt;/code&gt; to &lt;code&gt;browse&lt;/code&gt; by @lollipopkit in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6502&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;reverse_proxy: add placeholder http.reverse_proxy.retries by @steffenbusch in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6553&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix(#6551): Unexpected behaviour if caddyhttp.Route is provisioned twice    by @jbro in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6558&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;caddytls: Add sni_regexp matcher by @vnxme in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6569&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;rewrite: Avoid panic on bad arg count for &lt;code&gt;uri&lt;/code&gt; by @mister-turtle in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6571&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;perf: use zap's Check() to prevent useless allocs by @dunglas in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6560&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ci: update the linter action version by @mohammed90 in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6575&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;update quic-go to v0.47.0 by @marten-seemann in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6582&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;quic: enable qlog, controlled by QLOGDIR env by @marten-seemann in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6581&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;caddytls: Give a better error message when given encrypted private keys by @francislavoie in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6591&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;chore: Use slices package where possible by @francislavoie in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6585&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;caddyhttp: Optimize logs using zap's WithLazy() by @AlliBalliBaba in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6590&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;doc: remove docs of deprecated directives by @mohammed90 in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6566&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Implement issue #6296 passing FDs / socket activation by @MayCXC in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6573&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;caddyhttp: Fix listener wrapper regression from #6573 by @MayCXC in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6599&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;chore: Adjust incorrect &lt;code&gt;reverse_proxy&lt;/code&gt; Caddyfile comment by @francislavoie in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6598&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;http: ReponseWriter prefer ReadFrom if available by @WeidiDeng in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6565&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;caddytls: Support new tls.context module by @mholt in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6369&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Better errors when reloading by @mholt in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6601&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;caddyhttp: Escaping placeholders in CEL, add &lt;code&gt;vars&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;vars_regexp&lt;/code&gt; by @francislavoie in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6594&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;autohttps: Implement &lt;code&gt;auto_https prefer_wildcard&lt;/code&gt; option by @francislavoie in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6146&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;metrics: scope metrics to active config, add optional per-host metrics by @mohammed90 in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6531&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ci: install xcaddy to fix release flow by @mohammed90 in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6602&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;caddytls: Drop &lt;code&gt;rate_limit&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;burst&lt;/code&gt;, has been deprecated by @francislavoie in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6611&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;tests: Fix adapt test warning by @mohammed90 in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6619&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;docs: expand proxy protocol docs by @mohammed90 in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6620&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;caddyfile: Fix comma edgecase in address parsing by @francislavoie in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6616&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;reverseproxy: Use correct cases for websocket related headers by @WeidiDeng in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6621&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;chore: update quic-go to v0.48.0 by @marten-seemann in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6627&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;caddyhttp: Close http3 server gracefully by @WeidiDeng in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6213&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;metrics: move &lt;code&gt;metrics&lt;/code&gt;  up, outside &lt;code&gt;servers&lt;/code&gt; by @mohammed90 in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6606&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix: always ignore SIGPIPE by @dunglas in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6645&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fileserver: fix try_policy when instantiating file matcher from CEL by @effleurager in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6624&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;chore: fix some function names in comment by @davidwoood in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6650&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;core: addresses.go funcs renames by @MayCXC in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6622&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;tracing: Add &lt;code&gt;spanID&lt;/code&gt; field to access logs and &lt;code&gt;http.vars.span_id&lt;/code&gt; placeholder by @YifanYang6 in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6646&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;reverseproxy: Sync changes from stdlib for 1xx handling by @francislavoie in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6656&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;chore: Bump quic-go to 0.48.1, fixing a panic by @francislavoie in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6654&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;chore: compile without nosql's support for Postgres and MySQL by @dunglas in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6655&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;cmd: Allow &lt;code&gt;add-package&lt;/code&gt; to select version of package by @Botelho31 in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6665&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;httpcaddyfile: Fixes for &lt;code&gt;prefer_wildcard&lt;/code&gt; mode by @francislavoie in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6636&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use &lt;code&gt;WithLazy&lt;/code&gt; to prevent eager serialization of the event data by @ankon in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6671&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;forwardauth: Skip copying missing response headers by @francislavoie in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6608&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;caddyhttp: Add &lt;code&gt;MatchWithError&lt;/code&gt; to replace SetVar hack by @francislavoie in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6596&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;go.mod: upgrade only some otel deps by @mohammed90 in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6676&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fileserver: Add &lt;code&gt;file_limit&lt;/code&gt; option for browse by @atakanyenel in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6648&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;rewrite: Don't add &lt;code&gt;/&lt;/code&gt; in Caddyfile, do it after replacer by @francislavoie in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6662&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;caddytls: Allow disabling storage cleaning, avoids writing two files by @francislavoie in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6593&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ci: use commit sha in goreleaser-check by @mohammed90 in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6677&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;reverseproxy: Allow &lt;code&gt;0&lt;/code&gt; as weights for &lt;code&gt;weighted_round_robin&lt;/code&gt; by @suciptoid in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6681&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;httpcaddyfile: Implement log &lt;code&gt;sampling&lt;/code&gt; config by @nikonhub in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6682&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;core: Implement FastAbs to avoid repeated os.Getwd calls by @francislavoie in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6687&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;chore: Add &lt;code&gt;provides&lt;/code&gt; to &lt;code&gt;.deb&lt;/code&gt; releases by @francislavoie in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6691&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;chore: make FastAbs comment easier to understand by @WeidiDeng in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6692&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;cmd: ignore missing keys during storage export by @santhoshTpixler in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6697&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;perf: remove dir redirection when useless in php_fastcgi by @dunglas in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6698&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;requestbody: Type-based error handling for &lt;code&gt;MaxBytesError&lt;/code&gt; by @rishitashaw in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6701&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;metrics: add &lt;code&gt;go&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;process&lt;/code&gt; collectors by @mohammed90 in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6704&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ci: prevent jobs running on PRs from forks by @mohammed90 in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6720&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;caddyhttp: Add &lt;code&gt;{?query}&lt;/code&gt; placeholder by @francislavoie in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6714&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fileserver: Add &lt;code&gt;first_exist_fallback&lt;/code&gt; strategy for &lt;code&gt;try_files&lt;/code&gt; by @dunglas in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6699&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;cmd: &lt;code&gt;fmt&lt;/code&gt; prevents multiple files passed as args, add support for &lt;code&gt;--config&lt;/code&gt; by @armadi1809 in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6717&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fileserver: Fix policy &lt;code&gt;Validate()&lt;/code&gt; oversight by @francislavoie in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6727&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;chore: bump golang.org/x/net to v0.32.0 by @WeidiDeng in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6728&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;reverseproxy: Rewrite requests and responses for websocket over http2 by @WeidiDeng in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6567&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;chore: fix some typo in HTTPLoader comment by @jpadilla in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6735&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feat: good default for file_server.precompressed by @dunglas in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6736&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;test: add a test for precompressed defaults by @dunglas in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6743&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feat: good default for encode by @dunglas in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6737&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;encode: write status immediate for success response for CONNECT requests by @WeidiDeng in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6738&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;reverseproxy: Only handle extended connect for websockets by @bt90 in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6740&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;core: Change getListenerFromPlugin signature by @MayCXC in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6651&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;reverseproxy: Set &lt;code&gt;Content-Length&lt;/code&gt; when body is fully buffered by @WeidiDeng in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6638&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fastcgi: check for CONTENT_LENGTH when sending requests by @WeidiDeng in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6661&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;caddyhttp: Allow matching Transfer-Encoding, add to access logs by @francislavoie in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6629&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;encode: try to use sendfile when compression is not used by @WeidiDeng in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6749&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;httpcaddyfile: Implement &lt;code&gt;force_automate&lt;/code&gt; by @francislavoie in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6712&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;testing: sort force-automated hosts by @mohammed90 in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6756&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;New Contributors&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;@ririsoft made their first contribution in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6314&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;@JasonYuan869 made their first contribution in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6398&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;@klaxa made their first contribution in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6419&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;@dylanschultzie made their first contribution in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6450&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;@jbro made their first contribution in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6453&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;@girlbossceo made their first contribution in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6470&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;@vnxme made their first contribution in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6461&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;@pi-prakhar made their first contribution in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6485&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;@lollipopkit made their first contribution in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6468&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;@sunnyagain made their first contribution in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6534&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;@AlliBalliBaba made their first contribution in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6541&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;@mister-turtle made their first contribution in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6571&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;@MayCXC made their first contribution in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6573&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;@effleurager made their first contribution in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6624&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;@davidwoood made their first contribution in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6650&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;@YifanYang6 made their first contribution in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6646&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;@Botelho31 made their first contribution in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6665&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;@atakanyenel made their first contribution in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6648&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;@suciptoid made their first contribution in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6681&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;@nikonhub made their first contribution in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6682&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;@santhoshTpixler made their first contribution in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6697&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;@rishitashaw made their first contribution in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6701&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;@jpadilla made their first contribution in https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/pull/6735&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Full Changelog&lt;/strong&gt;: https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/compare/v2.8.4...v2.9.0&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/caddyserver/caddy/releases/tag/v2.9.0" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
