<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://selfh.st/apps</id>
  <title>Calibre-Web Automated Releases</title>
  <updated>2025-01-04T20:33:07.582419-05:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>selfh.st</name>
    <email>contact@selfh.st</email>
  </author>
  <link href="https://selfh.st/apps" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>Self-hosted software releases generated by selfh.st</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/crocodilestick/Calibre-Web-Automated/releases/tag/V2.0.0</id>
    <title>New release for Calibre-Web Automated: Version 2.0.0 - Bulk Editing, Auto-Library Detection, Wider Compatibilityand lots, lots more! ✨</title>
    <updated>2024-08-28T11:27:27-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>crocodilestick/Calibre-Web-Automated</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h1&gt;Version 2.0.0 - 28.08.2024 🌅🎉&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;🚨 Please &lt;strong&gt;Update to the latest DockerHub image ASAP&lt;/strong&gt; to avoid stability &amp;amp; import/ ingest issues that have been corrected from previous versions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you find any bugs, please be sure to create an issue in the &lt;a href="https://github.com/crocodilestick/Calibre-Web-Automated/issues"&gt;Issues Section&lt;/a&gt;! 🪲&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;New Features ✨&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Dockerfile is now freely available &amp;amp; provides &lt;em&gt;wider system / hardware compatibility&lt;/em&gt; 🐋&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Offical Support for Proxmox and NAS Based-Systems 💾&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you've previously tried to use CWA and couldn't get it to work properly, many permissions related issues from the previous releases have now been fixed and so V2.0.0 should now work for pretty much anyone! (except those on ARM-based systems)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;NEW FEATURE - Library Auto-Detect 📚🕵️&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Made to MASSIVELY simplify the setup process for both new and existing users alike&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;New Users without existing Libraries:&lt;/strong&gt; 🆕&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New users without existing Calibre Libraries no longer need to copy and paste &lt;code&gt;metadata.db&lt;/code&gt; files and point to their location in the Web UI, CWA will now automatically detect the lack of Library in your given bind and automatically create a new one for you! It will even automatically register it with the Web UI so you can really hit the ground running&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;New or Existing Users with Existing Libraries:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Simply bind a directory containing your Calibre Library (search is done recursively so it doesn't matter how deep in the directory it is) and CWA will now automatically find it and mount it to the Web UI&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Should you bind a directory with more than 1 Calibre Library in it, CWA will intelligently compare the disk sizes of all discovered libraries and mount the largest one&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;CWA supports only one library per instance though support for multiple libraries is being investigated for future releases&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;In the meantime, users with multiple libraries who don't want to consolidate them are advised to run multiple, parallel instances&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;NEW FEATURE - Easy Dark/ Light Mode Switching ☀️🌙&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Switch between Light &amp;amp; Dark Modes in just one click from anywhere!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Simply click/tap the 🕶️ icon on the  Web UI's navbar and switch between themes at your leisure&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;NEW FEATURE - Internal Update Notification System 🛎️&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Users will now be automatically notifed of the availability of new updates from within the Web UI&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Automatically triggered by a difference between the version number of the most recent GitHub release and the version installed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Set to only show once per calendar day until updated as to not be annoying&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Visible to Admin users only&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;NEW FEATURE - Manual Library Refresh ♻️&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ever had books get stuck in the ingest folder after an unexpected powercut ect.? Well say goodbye to having to manually copy the books to be ingested back in and out of the ingest folder, simply press the &lt;code&gt;Refresh Library&lt;/code&gt; button on the navbar of the Web UI and anything still sitting in the ingest folder will be automatically ingested!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;NEW FEATURE - Batch Editing &amp;amp; Deletion! 🗂️🗄️&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Say goodbye to clicking that edit button again, and again, and again just to remove or edit a single series!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To use, simply navigate to the &lt;code&gt;Books List&lt;/code&gt;page on the left hand side of the Web UI, select the books you wish to edit/ delete and use the buttons either above the table or within the headers to do whatever you need!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Courtesy of &lt;a href="https://github.com/jmarmstrong1207"&gt;@jmarmstrong1207&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Calibre-Web Automated" src="https://github.com/crocodilestick/Calibre-Web-Automated/raw/main/README_images/cwa-bulk-editting-diagram.png" title="Calibre-Web Automated Bulk Editing &amp;amp; Bulk Deletion" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Bugfixes 🐜:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed a slew of permissions related issues that previously prevented Proxmox users and users with NAS-Based systems from being able to run CWA without issue. These configurations are now officially supported!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed a bug with cover_enforcer.py where books with '/' characters in the title or author's name(s) would break the process&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed a bug that resulted in excessive memory usage over time when ingesting large libraries (1000+ books)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Tweaks/ Minor Improvments ✨:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Version Numbers of the installed distributions for CWA, Calibre, Stock CW, Kepubify and the Linuxserver.io base image are now all displayed at the bottom of the Settings page&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added links to the CWA Github and Discord in the Settings Page&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added Consistent CWA Branding throughout&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/crocodilestick/Calibre-Web-Automated/releases/tag/V2.0.0" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/crocodilestick/Calibre-Web-Automated/releases/tag/V2.0.1</id>
    <title>New release for Calibre-Web Automated: Version 2.0.1 - Minor Fix to Update Notification System</title>
    <updated>2024-08-29T11:01:54-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>crocodilestick/Calibre-Web-Automated</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;Very small update, only fixes the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A bug where the Update Availability notification would be shown even when no update was available. Now works as intended&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A bug some users where facing that resulted in a 500 error when trying to load the admin page&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CrocodileStick&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/crocodilestick/Calibre-Web-Automated/releases/tag/V2.0.1" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/crocodilestick/Calibre-Web-Automated/releases/tag/V2.1.0</id>
    <title>New release for Calibre-Web Automated: Version 2.1.0 - Major Fix for NAS &amp; Unraid users, more User Customisability, Major Improvements to the Ingest and Conversion systems and more! 🎊 ✨📖</title>
    <updated>2024-11-01T11:34:59-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>crocodilestick/Calibre-Web-Automated</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h2&gt;MAJOR FIX - Synology &amp;amp; Unraid Users (plus those running old Linux Kernels) 🎉&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;After months of working with the community to try and find a fix for the widespread issues Synology users in particular were having, we have finally arrived on a fix! 🎉&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The issue was that the most recent binaries utilised by CWA from the linuxserver &lt;code&gt;universal-calibre&lt;/code&gt; mod are incompatible with older versions of the Linux Kernel (particularly versions 4.4 and 3.2)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This meant that for users using older NASs ect., the binaries would be unavailable, rendering the CWA functions that require them unusable&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A fix was discovered by user @loli71 here in this &lt;a href="https://github.com/linuxserver/docker-calibre-web/issues/306#issuecomment-2342923994"&gt;thread&lt;/a&gt; who found that the binaries within V7.16 of the &lt;code&gt;universal-calibre&lt;/code&gt; mod are compatible with those still using older kernel versions!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Therefore from now on, baring issues, CWA will use V7.16 of the mod by default to ensure maximum compatibility for as many users as possible&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Special thank to @iroQuai, @Malek-GHub and @inkanyamba for their help in solving the issue in the now closed thread &lt;a href="https://github.com/crocodilestick/Calibre-Web-Automated/issues/55"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;New Features ✨&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added a CWA Settings panel to allow users to enable and disable certain CWA Settings based on their preferences&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added Ability to check the status of the CWA Monitoring services from within the Web UI&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added the ability for users to use the Convert-Library function from the Web UI using the "Convert Library to epub" button in the settings page&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added a new auto compression feature (cwa-auto-zipper) that automatically zips all backed up files, once a day just before midnight to minimise disk space and help keep backed up files organised. The feature is also user toggleable in the new CWA Settings page&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added a page called "Show CWA History" in the Admin Panel that users can now use to view the historical logs/ stats of all previous metadata enforcements, conversions &amp;amp; imports in the Web UI&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Major Changes ⛰️&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Updated base CW base version to 0.6.23 from 0.6.22&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reworked and vastly improved the auto ingest process to solve issues for a number of users and to improve reliability and performance&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Users who has their ingest folders on different drives to their Calibre Libraries were experiencing permission issues that could only be rectified through the mounting of a temp folder used by the old ingest process&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;With the new process these issues have been resolved on top of it being more reliable and performant in general&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Numerous changes have been made to make the ingest process much less destructive:&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The originals of converted and imported books, as well as those that have failed to be ingested, are now automatically backed up by default to &lt;code&gt;/config/processed_books&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This as well as many other functions are also now able to be disabled in the new "CWA Settings" page in the Admin Panel&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rewrote &lt;code&gt;convert-library.py&lt;/code&gt; to be much less destructive through the implementation of user toggleable file backup settings, more reliable and to support statistical output to cwa.db&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added fix for updated metadata &amp;amp; covers not reliably updating on Kobo devices. Courtesy of @tsheinen. &lt;a href="https://github.com/tsheinen/calibre-web/commit/a4781a62b2fde549a40b87ccabb6b0df20ce60a4"&gt;See the thread here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added the enforcement of Timezones given as environment variables. Previously giving a timezone as an environment variable didn't change the system clock of the container environment consistently for all users and functions and so now the &lt;code&gt;/etc/localtime&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;/etc/timezone&lt;/code&gt; files are automatically corrected during container startup by the &lt;code&gt;cwa-auto-zipper&lt;/code&gt; service, defaulting to UTC time if no TZ was given or in the event of an error or unrecognised timezone. This has made scheduled tasks more consistent and reliable.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added lock file for convert-library.py to prevent multiple simultaneous instances&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Minor Changes &amp;amp; Bugfixes ✅&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added greater support for special characters in Book Titles and Author Names&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved error handling for files that are unable to be successfully processed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix for bug where the Web UI could become unavailable due to not receiving a response for a API query to the project's GitHub page. Courtesy of @Buco7854&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Made it so CWA only checks for available updates once per day&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Made it so that the "Enable Uploads" setting in the Feature Configuration screen is on by default for new installs as new users who had yet to enable it were confused by not being able to upload new covers for example&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added oneshot service at init to check for and remove any potential leftover cwa lock files (cwa-init-remove-locks)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added default paths to included calibre &amp;amp; kepubify binaries so their additional functionality is enabled by default for new installs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deprecated new-book-detector as part of the reworking of the auto ingest system&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Renamed numerous scripts to make their functions clearer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Made the available update notifications optional through the new CWA Settings page&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed Library Refresh Pop-Up messaging&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Coming in V2.2.0 🍃&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Making CWA much more user configurable through the new CWA Settings panel e.g. giving users the ability to disable the conversion of certain formats ect.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Restoring the ability for users to rebrand the Web UI&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Re-enabling Split Library functionality and having it work seamlessly with CWA's other features&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/crocodilestick/Calibre-Web-Automated/releases/tag/V2.1.0" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/crocodilestick/Calibre-Web-Automated/releases/tag/V2.1.1</id>
    <title>New release for Calibre-Web Automated: Version 2.1.1 - Minor Bugfixes on V2.1.0</title>
    <updated>2024-11-01T20:48:05-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>crocodilestick/Calibre-Web-Automated</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h2&gt;Minor Bugfixes for bugs introduced in V2.1.0:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Calibre Binary location now set by default to /usr/bin in app.db&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Restored split setting option in config_db to prevent 500 errors some users were having&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed dependency issues introduced in convert-library&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added isfile check for convert-library.log to prevent crash on first run that could result if a log file didn't already exist&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Version 2.1.0 - Major Fix for NAS &amp;amp; Unraid users, more User Customisability, Major Improvements to the Ingest and Conversion systems and more! 🎊 ✨📖&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;MAJOR FIX - Synology &amp;amp; Unraid Users (plus those running old Linux Kernels) 🎉&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;After months of working with the community to try and find a fix for the widespread issues Synology users in particular were having, we have finally arrived on a fix! 🎉&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The issue was that the most recent binaries utilised by CWA from the linuxserver &lt;code&gt;universal-calibre&lt;/code&gt; mod are incompatible with older versions of the Linux Kernel (particularly versions 4.4 and 3.2)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This meant that for users using older NASs ect., the binaries would be unavailable, rendering the CWA functions that require them unusable&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A fix was discovered by user @loli71 here in this &lt;a href="https://github.com/linuxserver/docker-calibre-web/issues/306#issuecomment-2342923994"&gt;thread&lt;/a&gt; who found that the binaries within V7.16 of the &lt;code&gt;universal-calibre&lt;/code&gt; mod are compatible with those still using older kernel versions!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Therefore from now on, baring issues, CWA will use V7.16 of the mod by default to ensure maximum compatibility for as many users as possible&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Special thank to @iroQuai, @Malek-GHub and @inkanyamba for their help in solving the issue in the now closed thread &lt;a href="https://github.com/crocodilestick/Calibre-Web-Automated/issues/55"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;New Features ✨&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added a CWA Settings panel to allow users to enable and disable certain CWA Settings based on their preferences&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added Ability to check the status of the CWA Monitoring services from within the Web UI&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added the ability for users to use the Convert-Library function from the Web UI using the "Convert Library to epub" button in the settings page&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added a new auto compression feature (cwa-auto-zipper) that automatically zips all backed up files, once a day just before midnight to minimise disk space and help keep backed up files organised. The feature is also user toggleable in the new CWA Settings page&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added a page called "Show CWA History" in the Admin Panel that users can now use to view the historical logs/ stats of all previous metadata enforcements, conversions &amp;amp; imports in the Web UI&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Major Changes ⛰️&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Updated base CW base version to 0.6.23 from 0.6.22&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reworked and vastly improved the auto ingest process to solve issues for a number of users and to improve reliability and performance&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Users who has their ingest folders on different drives to their Calibre Libraries were experiencing permission issues that could only be rectified through the mounting of a temp folder used by the old ingest process&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;With the new process these issues have been resolved on top of it being more reliable and performant in general&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Numerous changes have been made to make the ingest process much less destructive:&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The originals of converted and imported books, as well as those that have failed to be ingested, are now automatically backed up by default to &lt;code&gt;/config/processed_books&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This as well as many other functions are also now able to be disabled in the new "CWA Settings" page in the Admin Panel&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rewrote &lt;code&gt;convert-library.py&lt;/code&gt; to be much less destructive through the implementation of user toggleable file backup settings, more reliable and to support statistical output to cwa.db&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added fix for updated metadata &amp;amp; covers not reliably updating on Kobo devices. Courtesy of @tsheinen. &lt;a href="https://github.com/tsheinen/calibre-web/commit/a4781a62b2fde549a40b87ccabb6b0df20ce60a4"&gt;See the thread here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added the enforcement of Timezones given as environment variables. Previously giving a timezone as an environment variable didn't change the system clock of the container environment consistently for all users and functions and so now the &lt;code&gt;/etc/localtime&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;/etc/timezone&lt;/code&gt; files are automatically corrected during container startup by the &lt;code&gt;cwa-auto-zipper&lt;/code&gt; service, defaulting to UTC time if no TZ was given or in the event of an error or unrecognised timezone. This has made scheduled tasks more consistent and reliable.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added lock file for convert-library.py to prevent multiple simultaneous instances&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Minor Changes &amp;amp; Bugfixes ✅&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added greater support for special characters in Book Titles and Author Names&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved error handling for files that are unable to be successfully processed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix for bug where the Web UI could become unavailable due to not receiving a response for a API query to the project's GitHub page. Courtesy of @Buco7854&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Made it so CWA only checks for available updates once per day&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Made it so that the "Enable Uploads" setting in the Feature Configuration screen is on by default for new installs as new users who had yet to enable it were confused by not being able to upload new covers for example&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added oneshot service at init to check for and remove any potential leftover cwa lock files (cwa-init-remove-locks)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added default paths to included calibre &amp;amp; kepubify binaries so their additional functionality is enabled by default for new installs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deprecated new-book-detector as part of the reworking of the auto ingest system&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Renamed numerous scripts to make their functions clearer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Made the available update notifications optional through the new CWA Settings page&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed Library Refresh Pop-Up messaging&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Coming in V2.2.0 🍃&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Making CWA much more user configurable through the new CWA Settings panel e.g. giving users the ability to disable the conversion of certain formats ect.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Restoring the ability for users to rebrand the Web UI&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Re-enabling Split Library functionality and having it work seamlessly with CWA's other features&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/crocodilestick/Calibre-Web-Automated/releases/tag/V2.1.1" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/crocodilestick/Calibre-Web-Automated/releases/tag/V2.1.2</id>
    <title>New release for Calibre-Web Automated: Version 2.1.2 - Multi-Platform Images, Personalise Your Instance and Big UI Improvements! ✨💪</title>
    <updated>2024-11-07T12:49:06-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>crocodilestick/Calibre-Web-Automated</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h2&gt;CWA is finally Multi-Platform!! 💪🎉&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This and all future releases are now Multi-Platform! From now on, CWA will have both &lt;code&gt;linux/amd64&lt;/code&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;code&gt;linux/arm64&lt;/code&gt; images available for each new version! &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;UI Changes &amp;amp; Fixes 📛&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fixed the user's ability to rebrand the Web UI&lt;/strong&gt; with whatever name they see fit&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To do so, navigate to the Settings/ Admin panel, select &lt;code&gt;Edit UI Configuration&lt;/code&gt; and under the &lt;code&gt;View Configuration&lt;/code&gt; tab, change the &lt;code&gt;Title&lt;/code&gt; field to whatever you want!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The name you select here will the replace the default &lt;strong&gt;Calibre-Web Automated&lt;/strong&gt; across the Web-UI ect. for all your users&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The branding will change throughout as soon as you've saved your changes, &lt;strong&gt;no restart required&lt;/strong&gt;!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Calibre-Web Automated - Re-Brand the Web UI" src="README_images/cwa-rebrand-ui.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Added descriptions for each setting in the CWA Settings page as well as tooltips&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Fixes and Improvements to the Book List page 🦋&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Header and page elements now conform to the same design language as the rest of the pages&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Bulk Edit buttons have been moved from the Table Headings to the top of the page and some of the page headings have been shortened to maximise the available horizontal space on any given device and make the page much easier to use (especially on mobile)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Pagination widget has been properly aligned and centred with regards to the other page elements&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Columns selection widget now expands to the left and into a already visible section of the page instead of off to the right and expanding the width of the page&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And in the &lt;strong&gt;CaliBlur/ Dark Theme&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The search button of the search field it now properly aligned and sized to the search field, no longer slightly smaller than it should have been to the ire of many&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The pagination widget on the top left is now themed black, orange and white to match the aesthetic of the rest of the UI elements&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;BEFORE 🤢&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Calibre-Web Automated - V2.1.2 Book List - Before" src="README_images/old-book-list.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;AFTER ✨&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Calibre-Web Automated - V2.1.2 Book List - After" src="README_images/new-book-list.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/crocodilestick/Calibre-Web-Automated/releases/tag/V2.1.2" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
