<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://selfh.st/apps</id>
  <title>Calibre-Web Automated Releases</title>
  <updated>2024-10-22T10:33:17.534654-04:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>selfh.st</name>
    <email>contact@selfh.st</email>
  </author>
  <link href="https://selfh.st/apps" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>Self-hosted software releases generated by selfh.st</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/crocodilestick/Calibre-Web-Automated/releases/tag/V1.2.0</id>
    <title>New release for Calibre-Web Automated: Version 1.2.0 - Cover Heaven &amp; New Super Easy Install! 🎉📚🐋</title>
    <updated>2024-07-23T17:20:54-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>crocodilestick/Calibre-Web-Automated</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h1&gt;Calibre-Web Automated 1.2.0 - Cover Heaven &amp;amp; New Super Easy Install! 🎉📚🐋&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Version 1.2.0 - Changelog&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;New Features&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Automatic Enforcement of Changes made to Covers &amp;amp; Metadata through the Calibre-Web UI!&lt;/strong&gt; 🙌📔&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Cover Enforcement CWA" src="https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/62270691-34b2-4560-b6ff-f176e1f99672" title="CWA 1.2.0 Cover Enforcement Diagram" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Something that's always bothered me as a Kindle user has been Calibre-Web's inability to change the Metadata and Covers stored within the &lt;code&gt;.epub&lt;/code&gt; files of our books, despite letting us change these things in the Web UI&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This has resulted in many people, including myself, running instances of both &lt;code&gt;Calibre-Web&lt;/code&gt; &lt;strong&gt;AND&lt;/strong&gt; full-fat &lt;code&gt;Calibre&lt;/code&gt;, to make use of &lt;code&gt;Calibre&lt;/code&gt;'s much more robust editing tools to change out those ugly covers and keep our Kindle Libraries looking a bit more\
    &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;~ a e s t h e t i c ~&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; and our metadata correct between devices&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Well, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;no more!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; ⏰&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using &lt;code&gt;CWA 1.2.0&lt;/code&gt;, whenever you change any &lt;strong&gt;Covers&lt;/strong&gt; or &lt;strong&gt;Metadata&lt;/strong&gt; using the &lt;code&gt;Calibre-Web&lt;/code&gt; UI, those changes will now be automatically applied directly to the &lt;code&gt;.epub&lt;/code&gt; files in your library, as well as in the Web UI itself, meaning that from now on what you see really is what you get!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;One Step Full Library Conversion&lt;/strong&gt; - Any format -&amp;gt; &lt;code&gt;.epub&lt;/code&gt; ✏️&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Calibre-Web Automated has always been designed with &lt;code&gt;.epub&lt;/code&gt; libraries in mind due to many factors, chief among which being the fact they are &lt;strong&gt;Compatible with the Widest Range of Devices&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Ubiquitous&lt;/strong&gt; as well as being &lt;strong&gt;Easy to Manage and Work with&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Previously this meant that anyone with &lt;code&gt;non-epub&lt;/code&gt; ebooks in their existing Calibre Libraries were unable to take advantage of all of &lt;code&gt;Calibre-Web Automator&lt;/code&gt;'s features reliably&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;So new to Version 1.2.0 is the ability for those users to quickly and easily convert their existing eBook Libraries, no matter the size, to &lt;code&gt;.epub Version 3&lt;/code&gt; format using a one step CLI Command from within the CWA Container&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This utility gives the user the option to either keep a copy of the original of all converted files in &lt;code&gt;/config/original-library&lt;/code&gt; or to trust the process and have CWA simply convert and replace those files (not recommended)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Full usage details can be found &lt;a href="#the-convert-library-tool"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Simple CLI Tools&lt;/strong&gt; for manual fixes, conversions, enforcements, history viewing ect. 👨‍💻&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Built-in command-line tools now also exist for:&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Viewing the Edit History of your Library files &lt;em&gt;(detailed above)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Listing all of the books currently in your Library with their current Books IDs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Manually enforcing the covers &amp;amp; metadata for ALL BOOKS&lt;/strong&gt; in your library using the &lt;code&gt;cover-enforcer -all&lt;/code&gt; command from within the container &lt;strong&gt;(RECOMMENDED WITH FIRST TIME USE)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Manually Enforcing the Covers &amp;amp; Metadata for any individual books by using the following command&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;cover-enforcer --dir &amp;lt;path-to-folder-containing-the-books-epub-here&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Full usage and documentation for all new CLI Commands can be found &lt;a href="#the-cover-enforcer-cli-tool"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Easy to View Change Database and Internal Automatic Logging&lt;/strong&gt; 📈&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Cover Enforcement CWA" src="https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/2b55533e-981d-4634-a431-ff99733ae2f8" title="CWA 1.2.0 Cover Enforcement Diagram" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In combination with the &lt;strong&gt;New Cover &amp;amp; Metadata Enforcement Features&lt;/strong&gt;, a database now exists to keep track of any and all enforcements, both for peace of mind and to make the checking of any bugs or weird behaviour easier, but also to make the data available for statistical analysis or whatever else someone might want to use the data for&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Full documentation can be found below &lt;a href="#checking-the-cover-enforcement-logs"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;IMPORTANT NOTE: ⚡ Current users of Calibre-Web Automated versions before 1.2.0 should perform a fresh install using the new DockerHub image method below to ensure stability and to keep up-to-date with future bugfixes and updates&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;New and Simplified Installation Methods&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Now Fully installable through Docker Compose using our Latest DockerHub Image!&lt;/strong&gt; 🐋🎉🙌&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Full install now possible using the Docker Compose file below (Full installation documentation can be found under the &lt;code&gt;Installation&lt;/code&gt; section of the projects GitHub):
~~~docker-compose&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;services:
  calibre-web-automated:
    image: crocodilestick/calibre-web-automated:latest
    container_name: calibre-web-automated
    environment:
      - PUID=1000
      - PGID=100
      - TZ=UTC
    volumes:
      - /path/to/config/folder:/config
      - /path/to/the/folder/you/want/to/use/for/book/ingest:/cwa-book-ingest
      - /path/to/your/calibre/library:/calibre-main # Point to your Calibre config folder not the 'Calibre Library' folder directly
      #- /path/to/where/you/keep/your/books:/books #Optional
      #- /path/to/your/gmail/credentials.json:/app/calibre-web/gmail.json #Optional
    ports:
      - 8084:8083 # Change the first number to change the port you want to access the Web UI, not the second
    restart: unless-stopped&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;~~~
- ## Updated Script Installer (Alternative Install Method) 👨‍💻
  - Due to updates to Calibre-Web, the script installer needs to be run within the included &lt;code&gt;calibre-web-base-image&lt;/code&gt;, newer versions of Calibre-Web are currently &lt;strong&gt;INCOMPATIBLE&lt;/strong&gt; with Calibre-Web Automated.
  - Script install method edited to support the new &lt;code&gt;1.2.0 features&lt;/code&gt; and simplified to make the installation as easy as possible
  - The Installer will now automatically detect any books in your Library that are not in &lt;code&gt;.epub&lt;/code&gt; format and will give the user the option to run the new Library Conversion Process during setup
  - Full documentation on this install method can be found under the &lt;code&gt;Installation&lt;/code&gt; section of the projects GitHub page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Bugfixes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed a few potential crashes during the Script Install process&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed errors that could occur during the import of books with non-english characters in the title or author's name ect.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed an error that could occur when many new books were placed into the ingest folder at once&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Overall speed and reliability improvements&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Upcoming Features 🌱 - &lt;em&gt;Coming Soon™&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Adding buttons to the Web UI to enable easier execution of features like full library conversion and others currently only available through the command-line interface&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reworking the book ingest system to be more robust and reliable when used with drives with slow transfer speeds&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Please suggest any ideas or wishes you might have! I'm open to anything! &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Future Development&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I've now been daily driving this version of Calibre-Web Automated (&lt;em&gt;formerly Calibre-Web Automator&lt;/em&gt;) for a couple weeks now and it now does everything I need for my reading workflow, I personally love the new features and hope you do to!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I will continue to maintain this project but as to new features I'm very much open to requests so please reach out with any suggestions or ideas you might have and I'll do my best to implement them!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;xoxo,\
CrocodileStick&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/crocodilestick/Calibre-Web-Automated/releases/tag/V1.2.0" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/crocodilestick/Calibre-Web-Automated/releases/tag/V1.2.1</id>
    <title>New release for Calibre-Web Automated: Version 1.2.1 - Major Bugfixes &amp; Base Update to 0.6.22 Oxana</title>
    <updated>2024-07-27T15:06:54-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>crocodilestick/Calibre-Web-Automated</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h1&gt;New in Version 1.2.1 - 27.07.2024&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🚨 &lt;strong&gt;TO ALL USERS&lt;/strong&gt; 🚨 Please update to the latest DockerHub image ASAP to avoid major issues with the old Import/Ingest System
- &lt;strong&gt;Major Bugfixes&lt;/strong&gt; to existing book &lt;strong&gt;Import &amp;amp; Ingest Methods&lt;/strong&gt; that could previously result in:
    - Some books being imported multiple times when importing large numbers at once
    - The ingestion of some books failing due to the import process triggering too quickly, before the transfer of said files is complete, leading to the attempted import of incomplete files which inevitably fails
    - Fixed auto importing folders recursively when copied into the ingest folder. &lt;strong&gt;Moving folders (rather than copy) still doesn't work. This has been fixed in the upcoming update&lt;/strong&gt;
    - Fixes courtesy of &lt;a href="https://github.com/jmarmstrong1207"&gt;@jmarmstrong1207&lt;/a&gt;
- &lt;strong&gt;Current issues&lt;/strong&gt;:
    - Mass importing can potentially cause duplication issues. This has been fixed in the upcoming update
- Base version of stock Calibre-Web updated to : &lt;strong&gt;V 0.6.22 - Oxana&lt;/strong&gt; which comes with the following fixes &amp;amp; features:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;| &lt;strong&gt;New features:&lt;/strong&gt;                                                                                     | &lt;strong&gt;Bug Fixes:&lt;/strong&gt;                                                                                                                                            |
|-------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------|-----------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------|
| &lt;sup&gt;lubimyczytac metadata fetches now the right tags section&lt;/sub&gt;                                   | &lt;sup&gt;CB7 metadata extraction working with newer version of py7zr&lt;/sub&gt;                                                                                    |
| &lt;sup&gt;OPDS catalog now only shows categories which are also visible in the normal User interface&lt;/sub&gt; | &lt;sup&gt;douban metadata fetching is working again&lt;/sub&gt;                                                                                                      |
| &lt;sup&gt;PRC is added as source for book conversion&lt;/sub&gt;                                                 | &lt;sup&gt;Improved Content Security Policy header&lt;/sub&gt;                                                                                                        |
| &lt;sup&gt;Added option for read status "Any" in Advanced Searching&lt;/sub&gt;                                   | &lt;sup&gt;Improvements for Caliblur! Dark Theme&lt;/sub&gt;                                                                                                          |
| &lt;sup&gt;Metadata Backup is supported now&lt;/sub&gt;                                                           | &lt;sup&gt;It's now possible to reset Kobo sync for other users&lt;/sub&gt;                                                                                           |
| &lt;sup&gt;Metadata Backup is supported now&lt;/sub&gt;                                                           | &lt;sup&gt;Improved parsing of book content on upload to prevent crashes&lt;/sub&gt;                                                                                  |
| &lt;sup&gt;In all categories a category "No category applied (None) is visible&lt;/sub&gt;                        | &lt;sup&gt;Refactored author renaming issue to prevent Oops Database corrupt messages&lt;/sub&gt;                                                                     |
|                                                                                                       | &lt;sup&gt;Fix on Windows that prevents starting calibre-web&lt;/sub&gt;                                                                                              |
|                                                                                                       | &lt;sup&gt;Ä Ö Ü are now counting as uppercase letters for Passwords&lt;/sub&gt;                                                                                      |
|                                                                                                       | &lt;sup&gt;Fix for Text reader to handle invalid mulitbyte sequence (mainly for CJK-Languaes)&lt;/sub&gt;                                                             |
|                                                                                                       | &lt;sup&gt;Fix for _internal folder showing up using windows installer version&lt;/sub&gt;                                                                            |
|                                                                                                       | &lt;sup&gt;Security fix: File upload mimetype is checked to prevent malicious file content in the books library&lt;/sub&gt;                                           |
|                                                                                                       | &lt;sup&gt;Security fix: Cross-site scripting (XSS) stored in comments section is prevented better (switching from lxml to bleach for sanitizing strings)&lt;/sub&gt; |&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/crocodilestick/Calibre-Web-Automated/releases/tag/V1.2.1" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/crocodilestick/Calibre-Web-Automated/releases/tag/V1.2.2</id>
    <title>New release for Calibre-Web Automated: Version 1.2.2 - Major Bugfixes, Book Import &amp; Ingest Finally Fully Working 🎊</title>
    <updated>2024-07-29T18:27:18-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>crocodilestick/Calibre-Web-Automated</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h1&gt;🚨 &lt;strong&gt;NEW UPDATE WITH FIXES&lt;/strong&gt; 🚨 - Version 1.2.2 - 29.07.2024&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;🚨 Please &lt;strong&gt;Update to the latest DockerHub image ASAP&lt;/strong&gt; to avoid major issues with the old Import/Ingest System and for &lt;strong&gt;General Stability Improvements&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This update should now render the Auto-Import system &lt;strong&gt;FULLY STABLE&lt;/strong&gt;, with all the major bugs now being fixed! 🎊&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you find any bugs however, please be sure to create an issue in the &lt;a href="https://github.com/crocodilestick/Calibre-Web-Automator/issues"&gt;Issues Section&lt;/a&gt;! 🪲&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Fixed Bugs:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed moving (not copying) a folder into cwa-book-ingest not detecting the folder and its contents&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed import duplication issues that sometimes happens from slower drive speeds or mass importing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;New Features:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Calibre-Web-Automated's Version Number now shows up alongside the version of the stock CW running as a base on the Settings page&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Coming Next (Version 1.2.3):&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Auto-Library Detection / Deployment to make installing &amp;amp; switching a breeze for anyone, existing libraries or no!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A Dockerfile for the project (&lt;strong&gt;finally!&lt;/strong&gt; 🎉)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/crocodilestick/Calibre-Web-Automated/releases/tag/V1.2.2" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/crocodilestick/Calibre-Web-Automated/releases/tag/V2.0.0</id>
    <title>New release for Calibre-Web Automated: Version 2.0.0 - Bulk Editing, Auto-Library Detection, Wider Compatibilityand lots, lots more! ✨</title>
    <updated>2024-08-28T11:27:27-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>crocodilestick/Calibre-Web-Automated</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h1&gt;Version 2.0.0 - 28.08.2024 🌅🎉&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;🚨 Please &lt;strong&gt;Update to the latest DockerHub image ASAP&lt;/strong&gt; to avoid stability &amp;amp; import/ ingest issues that have been corrected from previous versions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you find any bugs, please be sure to create an issue in the &lt;a href="https://github.com/crocodilestick/Calibre-Web-Automated/issues"&gt;Issues Section&lt;/a&gt;! 🪲&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;New Features ✨&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Dockerfile is now freely available &amp;amp; provides &lt;em&gt;wider system / hardware compatibility&lt;/em&gt; 🐋&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Offical Support for Proxmox and NAS Based-Systems 💾&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you've previously tried to use CWA and couldn't get it to work properly, many permissions related issues from the previous releases have now been fixed and so V2.0.0 should now work for pretty much anyone! (except those on ARM-based systems)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;NEW FEATURE - Library Auto-Detect 📚🕵️&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Made to MASSIVELY simplify the setup process for both new and existing users alike&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;New Users without existing Libraries:&lt;/strong&gt; 🆕&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New users without existing Calibre Libraries no longer need to copy and paste &lt;code&gt;metadata.db&lt;/code&gt; files and point to their location in the Web UI, CWA will now automatically detect the lack of Library in your given bind and automatically create a new one for you! It will even automatically register it with the Web UI so you can really hit the ground running&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;New or Existing Users with Existing Libraries:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Simply bind a directory containing your Calibre Library (search is done recursively so it doesn't matter how deep in the directory it is) and CWA will now automatically find it and mount it to the Web UI&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Should you bind a directory with more than 1 Calibre Library in it, CWA will intelligently compare the disk sizes of all discovered libraries and mount the largest one&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;CWA supports only one library per instance though support for multiple libraries is being investigated for future releases&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;In the meantime, users with multiple libraries who don't want to consolidate them are advised to run multiple, parallel instances&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;NEW FEATURE - Easy Dark/ Light Mode Switching ☀️🌙&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Switch between Light &amp;amp; Dark Modes in just one click from anywhere!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Simply click/tap the 🕶️ icon on the  Web UI's navbar and switch between themes at your leisure&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;NEW FEATURE - Internal Update Notification System 🛎️&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Users will now be automatically notifed of the availability of new updates from within the Web UI&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Automatically triggered by a difference between the version number of the most recent GitHub release and the version installed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Set to only show once per calendar day until updated as to not be annoying&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Visible to Admin users only&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;NEW FEATURE - Manual Library Refresh ♻️&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ever had books get stuck in the ingest folder after an unexpected powercut ect.? Well say goodbye to having to manually copy the books to be ingested back in and out of the ingest folder, simply press the &lt;code&gt;Refresh Library&lt;/code&gt; button on the navbar of the Web UI and anything still sitting in the ingest folder will be automatically ingested!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;NEW FEATURE - Batch Editing &amp;amp; Deletion! 🗂️🗄️&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Say goodbye to clicking that edit button again, and again, and again just to remove or edit a single series!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To use, simply navigate to the &lt;code&gt;Books List&lt;/code&gt;page on the left hand side of the Web UI, select the books you wish to edit/ delete and use the buttons either above the table or within the headers to do whatever you need!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Courtesy of &lt;a href="https://github.com/jmarmstrong1207"&gt;@jmarmstrong1207&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Calibre-Web Automated" src="https://github.com/crocodilestick/Calibre-Web-Automated/raw/main/README_images/cwa-bulk-editting-diagram.png" title="Calibre-Web Automated Bulk Editing &amp;amp; Bulk Deletion" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Bugfixes 🐜:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed a slew of permissions related issues that previously prevented Proxmox users and users with NAS-Based systems from being able to run CWA without issue. These configurations are now officially supported!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed a bug with cover_enforcer.py where books with '/' characters in the title or author's name(s) would break the process&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed a bug that resulted in excessive memory usage over time when ingesting large libraries (1000+ books)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Tweaks/ Minor Improvments ✨:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Version Numbers of the installed distributions for CWA, Calibre, Stock CW, Kepubify and the Linuxserver.io base image are now all displayed at the bottom of the Settings page&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added links to the CWA Github and Discord in the Settings Page&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added Consistent CWA Branding throughout&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/crocodilestick/Calibre-Web-Automated/releases/tag/V2.0.0" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/crocodilestick/Calibre-Web-Automated/releases/tag/V2.0.1</id>
    <title>New release for Calibre-Web Automated: Version 2.0.1 - Minor Fix to Update Notification System</title>
    <updated>2024-08-29T11:01:54-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>crocodilestick/Calibre-Web-Automated</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;Very small update, only fixes the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A bug where the Update Availability notification would be shown even when no update was available. Now works as intended&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A bug some users where facing that resulted in a 500 error when trying to load the admin page&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CrocodileStick&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/crocodilestick/Calibre-Web-Automated/releases/tag/V2.0.1" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
