<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://selfh.st/apps</id>
  <title>CheckCle Releases</title>
  <updated>2025-07-23T21:36:54.413902-04:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>selfh.st</name>
    <email>contact@selfh.st</email>
  </author>
  <link href="https://selfh.st/apps" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>Self-hosted software releases generated by selfh.st</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/operacle/checkcle/releases/tag/v1.0.0</id>
    <title>New release for CheckCle: 🚀 Initial Release - v1.0.0</title>
    <updated>2025-05-09T11:22:40-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>operacle/checkcle</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="checkcle-black" src="https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/20e78938-1fd1-446e-a942-d729c157136b" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This release marks the first official version of the project, providing core features for uptime monitoring and incident management. Key highlights include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Health Check &amp;amp; Uptime Monitoring (HTTP): Track the status of your servers and services with real-time monitoring.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dashboard UI with Live Stats: Visualize your monitoring data and receive instant updates on your system’s health.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Multi-user Authentication (Admin): Secure your platform with multi-user support, with admin privileges for full control.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Notifications (Telegram): Stay informed with instant notifications sent directly to your Telegram for all incidents and alerts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Docker Containerization: Easily deploy and run the system using Docker for seamless setup and scaling.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;💡 We’d love to hear from you!
If you have any suggestions, feedback, or feature requests, feel free to open an issue or submit a pull request. Your input helps improve the project and bring new features to life!&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/operacle/checkcle/releases/tag/v1.0.0" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/operacle/checkcle/releases/tag/v1.1.0</id>
    <title>New release for CheckCle: 🚀 Checkcle v1.1.0 – SSL Domain Monitoring &amp; Email Enhancements</title>
    <updated>2025-05-16T11:35:02-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>operacle/checkcle</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/3e398cee-f21e-4165-8f19-7efeadcd3b75" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;✨ New Features&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SSL Certificate Monitoring:&lt;/strong&gt; ✨ Introduced a new module to monitor SSL certificates, providing real-time insights and alerts for certificate expirations and issues (Also implemented for the Telegram notification of SSL Warning &amp;amp; Expiry Threshold)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Email Request Changes:&lt;/strong&gt; ✨ Implemented a feature allowing users to request changes to their email addresses, enhancing account management flexibility.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;UI:&lt;/strong&gt; Add Quick Tips Dialog&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;UI:&lt;/strong&gt; Add icon to link for the related information in header&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🛠 Improvements&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fixed:&lt;/strong&gt; fix to correct API base URL at runtime without hardcoding the domain or port. Now it works under any custom domain via reverse proxy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Performance Optimizations:&lt;/strong&gt; Improved backend processing speeds, reducing latency in data retrieval and display.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Updated&lt;/strong&gt; for Docker Run Command&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Updated&lt;/strong&gt; for user's active/inactive status from the backend in the profile details.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Upgraded&lt;/strong&gt; the pocketbase version V0.28.1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Codebase Refactoring&lt;/strong&gt;: Cleaned and organized code for better maintainability and scalability.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Official Website:&lt;/strong&gt; https://checkcle.io&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Official Live Demo Link:&lt;/strong&gt; https://demo.checkcle.io&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/operacle/checkcle/releases/tag/v1.1.0" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/operacle/checkcle/releases/tag/v1.2.0</id>
    <title>New release for CheckCle: 🚀 Checkcle v1.2.0 – New Maintenance and incident features; apply hotfixes</title>
    <updated>2025-05-26T11:44:24-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>operacle/checkcle</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;Release Date: May 26, 2025&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="maintenance-dahboard" src="https://pub-4a4062303020445f8f289a2fee84f9e8.r2.dev/images/maintenance-dahboard.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What's New ✨ (Features)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scheduled Maintenance Module:&lt;/strong&gt; Complete maintenance window management system&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create, edit, and delete maintenance windows&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Status tracking (Scheduled, In Progress, Completed, Cancelled)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Affected services management&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Timeline and duration planning&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Automatic status updates based on scheduled times&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Notification system for maintenance events&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PDF export functionality for maintenance reports&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Incident Management Module:&lt;/strong&gt; Comprehensive incident tracking system&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create, edit, and delete incidents&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Priority levels (Low, Medium, High, Critical)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Impact analysis and affected systems tracking&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Assignment to team members&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Status progression (Open, Investigating, Resolved, Closed)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Timeline tracking and resolution documentation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PDF export for incident reports&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;System Settings Panel:&lt;/strong&gt; Centralized system configuration&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Application name and URL configuration&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sender information settings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Role-based access control (Super Admin only)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mail Settings Panel:&lt;/strong&gt; SMTP configuration management&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SMTP server configuration (host, port, authentication) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;TLS/SSL encryption settings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Connection testing functionality&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Email Alerts function for: Login alerts, change email request, user verification confirmation (OTP coming later)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New Language added: German ([Deutsch] Thanks you for help! @michaelortnerit &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clickable Service Table Rows: Service table rows are now clickable, allowing users to navigate directly to service detail dashboards by clicking anywhere on the row&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Role-Based Access Control: Implemented proper basics permission handling for system settings based on user roles &amp;amp; Multi User Support.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Admin vs Superadmin Distinction: Clear separation of access levels between admin and superadmin users&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🛠 Improvements&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Improved User Experience:&lt;/strong&gt; Users can now access service details more intuitively without having to use the actions menu&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Permission Notice for Admins:&lt;/strong&gt; Admin users now see a clean "Permission Notice" message instead of error alerts when accessing restricted settings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SSL Certificate Overview Cards:&lt;/strong&gt; Updated SSL &amp;amp; Domain overview cards to match the Uptime Monitoring grid style with consistent gradient backgrounds and visual design&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can change email directly without making the email request change (SuperAdmin User)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Console Logging:&lt;/strong&gt; Added debugging logs to track navigation behavior&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;🐳 Docker Update: Improved checkcle Container Setup: We've updated the Docker configuration for the checkcle service to improve maintainability, persistence, and deployment consistency (Persistent data storage mapped to on the host volume)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🐛 Bug Fixes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed HTTP 500 Error: Resolved the 500 status error when saving system and mail settings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;API Method Compatibility: Updated API calls to use PATCH method with POST fallback for better PocketBase compatibility&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Error Handling: Improved error handling for settings operations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Eliminated False Error Alerts: Fixed issue where admin users were seeing "Error loading settings. HTTP error! status: 500" messages&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Conditional API Calls: Settings API calls now only execute for superadmin users, preventing unnecessary errors for admin users&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/operacle/checkcle/releases/tag/v1.2.0" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/operacle/checkcle/releases/tag/v1.3.0</id>
    <title>New release for CheckCle: 🚀 Checkcle v1.3.0 - Uptime Monitoring Features Are Fully Operational</title>
    <updated>2025-06-20T10:26:45-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>operacle/checkcle</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;Release Date: Jun 20, 2025
&lt;img alt="Screenshot 2025-06-20 at 9 04 29 PM" src="https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/e29031da-0561-457c-bec1-e85f1f73e9ed" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What's New ✨ (Features)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Go Implementation Architecture:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The project consists of 3 main Go services:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Service Operation Microservice - Uptime monitoring operations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Distributed Regional Check Agent - Regional network testing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Server Monitoring Agent - System metrics collection with gRPC support&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Service Types Supported:&lt;/strong&gt; All Uptime Monitoring Features Are Fully Operational&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;HTTP/HTTPS - Web service monitoring with SSL support&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ICMP Ping - Network connectivity testing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;DNS Resolution - Domain name resolution testing (A, AAAA, MX, TXT records)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;TCP Connectivity - Port connectivity testing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SSL Certificate Monitoring - Certificate expiration and validation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Main React Application Updated&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added a "Check Interval" field to the SSL certificate create/edit forms.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Implemented functionality to update the &lt;code&gt;check_at&lt;/code&gt; field with the current time when the "Check" button is clicked.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add error message and details columns: Adds error_message and details columns to the Incident History table in the service detail page.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Expand Uptime service form dialog&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🐛 Bug Fixes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix Real-time response time charts: Fix: Separate up/down graph areas
Separate the up and down areas in the response time history graph to improve clarity and correct the display of the down graph. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix email test setting functionality&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix: Uptime history timestamp and service ID&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/operacle/checkcle/releases/tag/v1.3.0" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/operacle/checkcle/releases/tag/v1.4</id>
    <title>New release for CheckCle: 🚀 CheckCle v1.4.0 - Distributed Monitoring, Server Agents, and Health Heatmaps</title>
    <updated>2025-07-22T12:04:33-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>operacle/checkcle</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;Release Date: Jul 22, 2025
&lt;img width="1619" height="968" alt="image" src="https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/fc5d2999-18c8-491e-9de6-3fb3c738957f" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;What's Changed&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🚀 Features 
* Introduced new feature server monitoring with real-time metrics. Includes a one-click install command for easy deployment.
* Distributed Monitoring Support: Uptime checks can now be distributed across multiple regional agents.
* Multiple agent selection supported for each uptime service.
* Docker Monitoring Dashboard:  Monitor your Docker containers directly from CheckCle.
* Health Heatmap:  Visualize uptime performance and outages over time with a new heatmap view in the monitoring detail dashboard.
* Pagination for Uptime Monitoring Table: Enhanced scalability with paginated service views.
* Multiple Notification Targets: Easily assign multiple notification methods per service.
* Japanese Translation: Thanks to @gnworks for contributing Japanese language support https://github.com/operacle/checkcle/pull/66
* Updated Incident Management Overview Cards linear-gradient by @lyker189 in https://github.com/operacle/checkcle/pull/73&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🔧 Improvements
* Improved Uptime Response History Chart: Smoother, more accurate rendering with better data aggregation.
* Data Refactor by Source: Monitoring data is now grouped and displayed by source for easier visibility and filtering.
* Documentation Update: README and CONTRIBUTING docs split into separate files per language for better organization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🛠 Fixes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Increased SSL Display Limit: SSL monitoring now displays up to 200 records reliably.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;High-Volume Uptime Monitoring Support: Fixed issues when monitoring over 50 uptime services simultaneously.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;⚙ Automation
* Automated script added for deploying the monitoring agent.
* One-click deploy script available for distributed regional agents and server monitoring setup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;New Contributors&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;@gnsworks made their first contribution in https://github.com/operacle/checkcle/pull/66&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;@lyker189 made their first contribution in https://github.com/operacle/checkcle/pull/73&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🙌  Special thanks to the community contributors and users for your feedback, support, and translations.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/operacle/checkcle/releases/tag/v1.4" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
