<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://selfh.st/apps</id>
  <title>CommaFeed Releases</title>
  <updated>2024-09-02T04:32:34.635670-04:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>selfh.st</name>
    <email>contact@selfh.st</email>
  </author>
  <link href="https://selfh.st/apps" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>Self-hosted software releases generated by selfh.st</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/Athou/commafeed/releases/tag/4.5.0</id>
    <title>New release for CommaFeed: CommaFeed 4.5.0</title>
    <updated>2024-07-06T15:38:44-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Athou/commafeed</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;significantly reduce the time needed to retrieve entries or mark them as read, especially when there are a lot of entries (#1452)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix a race condition where a feed could be refreshed before it was created in the database&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix an issue that could cause the websocket notification to contain the wrong number of unread entries when using mysql/mariadb&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix an error when trying to mark all starred entries as read&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;remove the &lt;code&gt;onlyIds&lt;/code&gt; parameter from REST endpoints since retrieving all the entries is now just as fast&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;remove support for microsoft sqlserver because it's not covered with integration tests (please open an issue if you'd like it back)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/Athou/commafeed/releases/tag/4.5.0" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/Athou/commafeed/releases/tag/4.6.0</id>
    <title>New release for CommaFeed: CommaFeed 4.6.0</title>
    <updated>2024-07-15T10:15:42-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Athou/commafeed</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;switched from Temurin to OpenJ9 as the JVM used in the Docker image, resulting in memory usage reduction by up to 50%&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix an issue that could cause old entries to reappear if they were updated by their author (#1486)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;show all entries regardless of their read status when searching with keywords, even if the ui is configured to show unread entries only&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/Athou/commafeed/releases/tag/4.6.0" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/Athou/commafeed/releases/tag/5.0.0</id>
    <title>New release for CommaFeed: CommaFeed 5.0.0</title>
    <updated>2024-08-18T03:51:34-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Athou/commafeed</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;CommaFeed is now powered by Quarkus instead of Dropwizard. Read the rationale behind this change in the &lt;a href="https://github.com/Athou/commafeed/discussions/1517"&gt;announcement&lt;/a&gt;.
The gist of it is that CommaFeed can now be compiled to a native binary, resulting in blazing fast startup times (around 0.3s) and very low memory footprint (&amp;lt; 50M).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CommaFeed now has a different package for each supported database.&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you are deploying CommaFeed with a precompiled package, please read &lt;a href="https://github.com/Athou/commafeed/tree/master?tab=readme-ov-file#download-a-precompiled-package"&gt;this section of the README&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you are building CommaFeed from sources, please read &lt;a href="https://github.com/Athou/commafeed/tree/master?tab=readme-ov-file#build-from-sources"&gt;this section of the README&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you are using the Docker image, please read the instructions on the &lt;a href="https://hub.docker.com/r/athou/commafeed"&gt;Docker Hub page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Due to the switch to Quarkus, the way CommaFeed is configured is very different (the &lt;code&gt;config.yml&lt;/code&gt; file is gone). Please read &lt;a href="https://github.com/Athou/commafeed/tree/master?tab=readme-ov-file#configuration"&gt;this section of the README&lt;/a&gt;.
  Note that a lot of configuration elements have been removed or renamed and are now nested/grouped by feature.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added a setting to prevent parsing large feeds to avoid out of memory errors. The default is 5MB.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use a different icon for filtering unread entries and marking an entry as read (#1506)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added various HTML attributes to ease custom JS/CSS customization (#1507)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Redis cache has been removed. There have been multiple enhancements to the feed refresh engine and it is no longer needed, even for instances with a large number of feeds.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The H2 migration tool that automatically upgrades H2 databases from format 2 to 3 has been removed. If you're using the H2 embedded database, please upgrade to at least version 4.3.0 before upgrading to CommaFeed 5.0.0.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/Athou/commafeed/releases/tag/5.0.0" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/Athou/commafeed/releases/tag/5.0.1</id>
    <title>New release for CommaFeed: CommaFeed 5.0.1</title>
    <updated>2024-08-19T10:11:26-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Athou/commafeed</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Configure native compilation to support older CPU architectures (#1524)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/Athou/commafeed/releases/tag/5.0.1" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/Athou/commafeed/releases/tag/5.0.2</id>
    <title>New release for CommaFeed: CommaFeed 5.0.2</title>
    <updated>2024-08-20T01:43:31-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Athou/commafeed</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix favicon fetching for Youtube channels in native mode when Google auth key is set&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix an error that appears in the logs when fetching some favicons&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/Athou/commafeed/releases/tag/5.0.2" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
