<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://selfh.st/apps</id>
  <title>DockFlare Releases</title>
  <updated>2025-05-15T18:36:15.500955-04:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>selfh.st</name>
    <email>contact@selfh.st</email>
  </author>
  <link href="https://selfh.st/apps" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>Self-hosted software releases generated by selfh.st</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/ChrispyBacon-dev/DockFlare/releases/tag/v1.0.1</id>
    <title>New release for DockFlare: Added Support for ARM64 &amp; Fixed Bugs</title>
    <updated>2025-04-21T05:23:55-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>ChrispyBacon-dev/DockFlare</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h2&gt;Key Improvements&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Fixed Critical Bugs&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved container detection logic to find cloudflared containers with truncated names&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed timezone-aware datetime handling for rule deletion timing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enhanced error handling during tunnel initialization and API communication&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Added Features&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;External Cloudflared Support&lt;/strong&gt;: Added comprehensive support for using externally managed cloudflared instances&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TLS Verification Control&lt;/strong&gt;: Implemented per-container TLS verification toggle via &lt;code&gt;cloudflare.tunnel.no_tls_verify&lt;/code&gt; label&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cross-Network Container Discovery&lt;/strong&gt;: Added ability to scan containers across all Docker networks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Custom Network Configuration&lt;/strong&gt;: Made cloudflared network name configurable&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;WebUI Improvements&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enhanced compatibility with reverse proxies and Cloudflare Tunnels&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added proper Content Security Policy (CSP) headers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed log streaming to work correctly behind proxies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved error display and status reporting for failed operations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Documentation Updates&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Expanded README with detailed information about all configuration options&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enhanced the example .env file with all available parameters and descriptive comments&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added troubleshooting section to help users resolve common issues&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved Docker Compose examples to demonstrate all configuration options&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Testing&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tested across multiple environments including:
- Standard Docker Compose deployment
- External cloudflared mode with pre-existing tunnels
- Behind reverse proxies and Cloudflare Tunnels&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Release Notes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This release adds significant flexibility for more complex deployment scenarios:
1. Users can now use externally managed cloudflared tunnels
2. Container discovery works across all Docker networks when needed
3. Custom network configuration allows better integration with existing setups
4. TLS verification can be controlled per-container
5. Deployment behind reverse proxies or Cloudflare Tunnels now works correctly&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/ChrispyBacon-dev/DockFlare/releases/tag/v1.0.1" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/ChrispyBacon-dev/DockFlare/releases/tag/v1.2</id>
    <title>New release for DockFlare: Support for multi-domain configuration using indexed labels in DockFlare</title>
    <updated>2025-04-22T03:50:49-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>ChrispyBacon-dev/DockFlare</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;Introduce support for multi-domain configuration using indexed labels in DockFlare, allowing multiple domains to be managed for a single container. Enhance the reconciliation process with performance optimizations, including batch processing and real-time status updates in the UI.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/ChrispyBacon-dev/DockFlare/releases/tag/v1.2" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/ChrispyBacon-dev/DockFlare/releases/tag/1.3</id>
    <title>New release for DockFlare: Dockflare Frontend Update &amp; Application Logo</title>
    <updated>2025-04-22T10:22:06-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>ChrispyBacon-dev/DockFlare</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h1&gt;Release Notes - Dockflare Frontend Update&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This update incorporates several fixes and improvements to the Dockflare status page frontend, enhancing user experience, stability, and visual consistency.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Key Highlights&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dark/Light Theme Fix:&lt;/strong&gt; Resolved issues with theme switching and persistence. The page now reliably initializes to the user's preferred theme (saved or system default) and toggles correctly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Protocol Handling:&lt;/strong&gt; Improved handling of HTTP/HTTPS protocols for forms and internal links to prevent mixed-content issues and ensure correct form submissions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Enhanced Stability:&lt;/strong&gt; Implemented stricter checks and better error handling in various parts of the frontend logic.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Branding Update:&lt;/strong&gt; Introduced the official application logo and banner in the page header.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Documentation:&lt;/strong&gt; Added a project Wiki on GitHub for extended documentation and guides.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Bug Fixes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Theme:&lt;/strong&gt; Fixed inconsistencies in dark/light theme application and toggling. Explicitly configured Tailwind for class-based dark mode.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Agent Control:&lt;/strong&gt; Prevented the "Start Agent" button from being enabled prematurely when the necessary tunnel ID or token was not yet available.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;API Status:&lt;/strong&gt; Corrected the logic for the API Status indicator (Tunnel Setup section) to more accurately reflect a fully configured state (requiring both ID and Token for internal tunnels, or ID for external).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Protocol Consistency:&lt;/strong&gt; Ensured forms and internal links consistently use the correct HTTP/HTTPS protocol matching the current page access.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Agent Status Display:&lt;/strong&gt; Improved robustness of agent status display to handle unknown or unavailable states gracefully.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Improvements&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;UI:&lt;/strong&gt; Updated the header to use the Dockflare application logo and banner for improved branding and visual identity.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;UI:&lt;/strong&gt; Added a visual "wildcard" badge next to wildcard hostnames in the Managed Ingress Rules table for better clarity.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;UI:&lt;/strong&gt; Tunnel Token row is now hidden in the Tunnel Details section when using an external cloudflared agent, as it's not relevant in that mode.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Code Quality:&lt;/strong&gt; Significantly refactored frontend JavaScript for improved readability, maintainability, and potentially better performance. Enhanced error handling in log streaming and server ping checks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Notes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Initialization and Reconciliation status indicators, previously removed in an earlier iteration of the unstable branch, have been retained from the stable version.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The clickable links for hostnames in the Managed Ingress Rules table continue to use &lt;code&gt;https://&lt;/code&gt; for consistency and security.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/ChrispyBacon-dev/DockFlare/releases/tag/1.3" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/ChrispyBacon-dev/DockFlare/releases/tag/v1.4</id>
    <title>New release for DockFlare: Centralized Cloudflare Tunnel Visibility &amp; DNS Inspection Across Multiple Hosts</title>
    <updated>2025-05-10T16:16:40-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>ChrispyBacon-dev/DockFlare</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Feature Spotlight: Centralized Cloudflare Tunnel Visibility &amp;amp; DNS Inspection Across Multiple Hosts&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This release introduces a significant enhancement to DockFlare's monitoring capabilities, especially for users running DockFlare instances across multiple Docker hosts. It provides a much-needed holistic view of your entire Cloudflare Tunnel infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Challenge Addressed:&lt;/strong&gt;
Previously, if you were running DockFlare on several hosts, each managing its own tunnel, getting a complete overview required checking each DockFlare instance individually. This new feature consolidates that view.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Account-Wide Tunnel Listing:&lt;/strong&gt;
   - The main status page now includes a new section titled "All Cloudflare Tunnels on Account."
   - Instead of just seeing the tunnel managed by the local DockFlare, this table displays &lt;strong&gt;all&lt;/strong&gt; Cloudflare Tunnels found under the Cloudflare Account ID specified by your &lt;code&gt;CF_ACCOUNT_ID&lt;/code&gt; environment variable.
   - It provides a quick overview of each tunnel's name, ID, current status (e.g., healthy, degraded, down, inactive), creation date, and active &lt;code&gt;cloudflared&lt;/code&gt; connections (including colo names).
   - This is invaluable for users with multiple DockFlare deployments (e.g., 5-6 Docker hosts or more), as it offers a single pane of glass to monitor all tunnels associated with the account, regardless of which host they originate from.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Integrated DNS Record Viewer (from any DockFlare instance):&lt;/strong&gt;
   - Alongside each tunnel listed in the new "All Cloudflare Tunnels on Account" table, you'll find a &lt;code&gt;+&lt;/code&gt; icon.
   - Clicking this icon will dynamically fetch and display all CNAME DNS records that point to that specific tunnel's unique &lt;code&gt;cfargotunnel.com&lt;/code&gt; address, &lt;strong&gt;no matter which DockFlare instance is displaying the page.&lt;/strong&gt;
   - The displayed DNS records are clickable links, allowing for easy navigation to the actual hostnames.
   - This allows for quick verification from any of your DockFlare UIs which hostnames are currently routed through any given tunnel on your account.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Benefits:&lt;/strong&gt;
*   &lt;strong&gt;True Centralized Overview:&lt;/strong&gt; See all your account's tunnels and their DNS linkages from any single DockFlare instance, perfect for multi-host setups.
*   &lt;strong&gt;Simplified DNS Auditing:&lt;/strong&gt; Quickly identify which DNS hostnames are associated with which tunnel across your entire account.
*   &lt;strong&gt;Streamlined Troubleshooting:&lt;/strong&gt; More easily spot misconfigurations or understand traffic flow when dealing with multiple tunnels and hosts.
*   &lt;strong&gt;Reduced Context Switching:&lt;/strong&gt; No need to log into or expose multiple DockFlare instances just to check on different tunnels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I believe these additions will make managing and understanding your Cloudflare Tunnel setup with DockFlare, especially in distributed environments, significantly more powerful and intuitive!&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/ChrispyBacon-dev/DockFlare/releases/tag/v1.4" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/ChrispyBacon-dev/DockFlare/releases/tag/v1.6</id>
    <title>New release for DockFlare: DockFlare v1.6 - UI Power-Up &amp; Styling Overhaul! 🎉</title>
    <updated>2025-05-15T17:31:02-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>ChrispyBacon-dev/DockFlare</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h2&gt;DockFlare v1.6 - UI Power-Up &amp;amp; Styling Overhaul! 🎉&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This release marks a significant step forward for DockFlare, introducing highly-requested &lt;strong&gt;UI-driven management for Cloudflare Access Policies&lt;/strong&gt; and a &lt;strong&gt;major visual refresh with DaisyUI&lt;/strong&gt; for a more modern and consistent user experience!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Managing access to your services is now more flexible than ever. While Docker labels remain perfect for defining the initial state of your services and their Access Policies, you can now dynamically adjust these policies directly from the DockFlare Web UI. These UI changes are &lt;strong&gt;persistent&lt;/strong&gt;, overriding container labels and surviving restarts of both DockFlare and your application containers. Worried about losing your label-defined setup? A new "Revert to Labels" option ensures you can always go back to your declarative configuration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;✨ Highlights&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;🚀 UI-Driven Access Policy Management:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Override Labels:&lt;/strong&gt; Directly edit Access Policies (None, Bypass, Authenticate by Email, Default TLD) for any managed service via the new "Manage Policy" dropdown in the Web UI.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Persistent Changes:&lt;/strong&gt; UI-set Access Policies are saved in &lt;code&gt;state.json&lt;/code&gt; and take precedence over container labels, even after restarts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;"Revert to Labels" Button:&lt;/strong&gt; Easily switch a service's Access Policy back to be controlled by its Docker labels.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;"UI Override" Badge:&lt;/strong&gt; Clearly indicates in the UI when an Access Policy is managed by the UI.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;💅 Major UI Refresh with DaisyUI:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The entire Web UI has been restyled using DaisyUI components, providing a cleaner, more modern, and themeable interface.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Theme Selector:&lt;/strong&gt; Choose from a wide variety of pre-built DaisyUI themes (light, dark, cupcake, synthwave, and many more!) to personalize your DockFlare dashboard. Your preference is saved locally.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved consistency for buttons, alerts, badges, tables, and forms.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enhanced readability and usability across the dashboard.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Improved Table Layout:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The "Managed Ingress Rules" table columns have been reordered for better workflow: Status, Hostname, Service Target, Container, Access Policy, Manage Policy, Expires At (UTC), Actions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dropdowns in the table now attempt to position themselves intelligently to avoid being clipped.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Under-the-Hood Refinements:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Refactored core logic for handling Access Policies to support the new UI override system.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ensured &lt;code&gt;process_container_start&lt;/code&gt; and the reconciliation loop (&lt;code&gt;_run_reconciliation&lt;/code&gt;) correctly respect the &lt;code&gt;access_policy_ui_override&lt;/code&gt; flag.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;🔧 Key Changes &amp;amp; Fixes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Feature:&lt;/strong&gt; Implemented state persistence for UI-overridden Access Policies (&lt;code&gt;access_policy_ui_override&lt;/code&gt; flag in &lt;code&gt;state.json&lt;/code&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Feature:&lt;/strong&gt; Added new Flask route (&lt;code&gt;/revert_access_policy_to_labels&lt;/code&gt;) and backend logic for reverting UI policies to label-defined configurations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;UI:&lt;/strong&gt; Replaced custom policy edit popup with a DaisyUI dropdown component, improving usability and solving previous overflow issues.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;UI:&lt;/strong&gt; Integrated DaisyUI for most UI elements including cards, buttons, alerts, badges, tables, and form inputs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;UI:&lt;/strong&gt; Added a multi-theme selector.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;UI:&lt;/strong&gt; Reordered columns in the "Managed Ingress Rules" table for better information flow.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;UI:&lt;/strong&gt; Improved display for "Pending Label Sync" status.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Build:&lt;/strong&gt; Migrated to a multi-stage Docker build process to compile Tailwind CSS and DaisyUI styles.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fix:&lt;/strong&gt; Addressed various minor display and styling inconsistencies.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Docs:&lt;/strong&gt; README and Wiki updated&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;⚙️ For Users Updating&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Your existing &lt;code&gt;state.json&lt;/code&gt; file will be automatically updated to include the new &lt;code&gt;access_policy_ui_override&lt;/code&gt; field (defaulting to &lt;code&gt;false&lt;/code&gt; for existing rules not yet touched by the new UI).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;After updating, if you wish to manage an Access Policy via the UI, simply edit it using the new "Manage Policy" dropdown. This will automatically set the UI override.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;🙏 Thanks&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you for using DockFlare! I hope these new features improve your experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Docker Image:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;code&gt;alplat/dockflare:stable&lt;/code&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm excited for you to try out these new capabilities! As always, please report any issues or provide feedback on GitHub.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/ChrispyBacon-dev/DockFlare/releases/tag/v1.6" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
