<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://selfh.st/apps</id>
  <title>Dolibarr Releases</title>
  <updated>2025-07-24T09:37:02.463832-04:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>selfh.st</name>
    <email>contact@selfh.st</email>
  </author>
  <link href="https://selfh.st/apps" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>Self-hosted software releases generated by selfh.st</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/Dolibarr/dolibarr/releases/tag/20.0.3</id>
    <title>New release for Dolibarr: 20.0.3</title>
    <updated>2024-12-29T20:01:47-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Dolibarr/dolibarr</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;*&lt;/em&gt; ChangeLog for 20.0.3 compared to 20.0.2 &lt;/strong&gt;***
FIX: 17.0 - missing error handling for FactureRec::fetch in card-rec.php
FIX: 17.0 - warnings due to uninitialized variables + delete code that doesn't apply to recurring invoices (AFAIK, there is no recurring credit note feature)
FIX: #31159 - TVA Account by country is not used (#31984)
FIX: #31724 (#31885)
FIX: #31890 store empty line extrafields (#32152)
FIX: #31997
FIX: #32007 missing parameter on function multiSelectArrayWithCheckbox (#32008)
FIX: #32021
FIX: #32171 (#32172)
FIX: #32178: repair.php: fix missing 'as' with Postgres (#32179)
FIX: #32259
FIX: #32317 Error with report by month sales tax
FIX: #32391
FIX: #32402 Social Contribution - Update - Drop the attached employee
FIX: #32408 Dict - module Event organisation is stable now
FIX: #32467
FIX: Accounting Closure Duplicates, Subledger accounts, Account Labels and more... Update bookkeeping.class.php
FIX: add a line in expensereport refused
FIX: All contacts were loaded even if no thirdparty was selected (#31877)
FIX: asset: missing ref_ext field used in CommonObject::isExistingObject() (#31870)
FIX: assets: division by zero when trying to calculate depreciation on assets that don't have it (#31858)
FIX: avoid php8 warnings
FIX: broken feature, check if module is enabled
FIX: broken feature, entity can not be empty !
FIX: broken feature, wrong GETPOSTINT parameter
FIX: BUG #32454 (Third party creating vendor)
FIX: calculate start date of cloned task from cloned project (#31799)
FIX: can not convert to reduc if draft status
FIX: comparing strings with numbers can be touchy
FIX: Debug option not working replaced by the one that works.
FIX: default user in stat page
FIX: Ensure extraparams cannot be selected by the user (#32132)
FIX: GETPOST "$check" parameter can't be empty
FIX: Hidden dropdown download link in project
FIX: stop doing a full closure without duplicate lines generated by an unclean database
FIX: in projet/element.php total_time is always back to 0
FIX: (invoice): mutlicurrency_tx correct value
FIX: invoice: revenue stamp wrongly converted to int (#31840)
FIX: issue #28222 Edit date extrafield displayed on all on lines (#31914)
FIX: "location_incoterms" is a string
FIX: missing hook parameters
FIX: missing saving MAIN_SECURITY_MAX_NUMBER_FAILED_AUTH
FIX: old copy not needed in supplier order create method (#31733)
FIX: send mail to BCC when email formatted as Fullname &lt;email&gt; (#31983)
FIX: set birthday alert (#32133)
FIX: Status not correct in Public ticket list (#31922)
FIX: swiftmailer: correctly set errors-to header (#31826)
FIX: TakePos barcode rule (#31857)
FIX: Takepos: set the country of the default customer (#31915)
FIX: Update Accounting closure with missing too many A-Nouveau #30039)
FIX: Update on a sold line of bank entry set the type to empty, now it's fixed #22539 (#31888)
FIX: update status on create supplier order for trigger (#31642)
FIX: use tax with code on supplier order line give tax code missing in supplier invoice (#32018)
FIX: warning in agenda when user have no color and AGENDA_NO_TRANSPARENT_ON_NOT_BUSY=1
FIX: when create intervention from propal (or other object), element link is missing after creation (#32035)
FIX: with no perm on supplier, must not see  supplier of the best price
FIX: wrong check
FIX: wrong trigger name (MODIFY instead UPDATE)&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/Dolibarr/dolibarr/releases/tag/20.0.3" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/Dolibarr/dolibarr/releases/tag/20.0.4</id>
    <title>New release for Dolibarr: 20.0.4</title>
    <updated>2025-02-21T05:32:39-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Dolibarr/dolibarr</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;*&lt;/em&gt; ChangeLog for 20.0.4 compared to 20.0.3 &lt;/strong&gt;***
FIX: $this-&amp;gt;origin_object can not be instance of CommandeFournisseur if it is already an instanceof CommonObject
FIX: 17.0 API endpoints "PUT": prevent overwriting all extrafields if only some are supplied in the request cf. PR #29237
FIX: 17.0 - collisions in cache for dol_getIdFromCode
FIX: #18713
FIX: 20.0 - PHP8 fatal when creating a reception unless corresponding PDF model is enabled
FIX: #21294 Stock import sql query
FIX: #26250 fatal error on kit
FIX: #28702
FIX: #29624 - substitution of &lt;strong&gt;DATE_DELIVERY&lt;/strong&gt;
FIX: #32113
FIX: #32186
FIX: #32339 Delete a loan settlement is partial
FIX: #32387
FIX: #32477 Loan - Insurance amount need decimals
FIX: #32611
FIX: #32736 + avoid php warning
FIX: #32743
FIX: #32765 JS Error: Uncaught TypeError
FIX: #32801 VAT type is inverted in form VAT selector
FIX: #32840
FIX: #32843
FIX: #32880 - Tags are using a special rendering.
FIX: add other fields
FIX: autofill price with multicurrency on supplier doc
FIX: avoid phan error
FIX: avoid php8 warnings
FIX: avoid warning with the new Dolistore website
FIX: backport from develop to avoid php warning
FIX: Bad calculation of the theoretical stock. Did not take into account
FIX: bad dispatched quantities for batches on shipment card
FIX: Brian is in the kitchen
FIX: broken feature, compatibility with "Default search filters"
FIX: broken feature with check $pa_ht_isemptystring
FIX: Bug on select user on time.php (all project list)
FIX: can not delete files in task card
FIX: Check "$search_sale" only if it's an internal user
FIX: clean unique extrafields when create product combination
FIX: code not visible correctly into view of dictionary
FIX: compatibility between next_prev_filter and hook return
FIX: compatibility with multicompany
FIX: Complete path was started in #17243 for pdf_cannelle
FIX: Continue for eagle_proforma
FIX: country id is not saved when we provide country_code only
FIX: #CVE-2024-34051
FIX: delete supplier order when at least one line linked to customer order line
FIX: display error when loan can't be deleted
FIX: display full tree on shipment card when a kit contains a same component in other sub-kit
FIX: DROP INDEX IF EXISTS is not possible !
FIX: extrafields lost during creation from rec invoice
FIX: FEC import
FIX: Fiscal year - missing translation on status
FIX: Fix return value of hook sendMail when hook return -1 who must be return false in sendfile() function
FIX: GETPOST('private_message')
FIX: glob is better for search files with wildcard + avoid warning
FIX: if $force_entity = 0 ($force_entity != 'default') = false
FIX: Loan - Insurance amount need decimals
FIX: Many status on invoice linked object block
FIX: merge problem
FIX: missing company name if donation is linked to third party
FIX: missing default values if $objsrc or $soc fields are empty
FIX: missing edit extrafields inline for member card
FIX: missing quick edit for extrafields
FIX: more bugs and warnings
FIX: Multilangs : PDF lines description
FIX: Must not have both thirdparty and member.
FIX: ODT substitution when many HTML tags in string
FIX: on the road again
FIX: pdf_cannelle (supplier_invoice) add background - Complete #17243
FIX: Prices didn't update when clone a propale with update prices
FIX: product variants copy: also copy multiprice variations
FIX: refactorize (maybe broken feature for not received completely)
FIX: remove debug trace
FIX: remove socid when cloning a project without third parties
FIX: removes traces of &amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;lt;HEAD conflicts following the postponement of branch 13 modifications (#32014)
FIX: remove unused code
FIX: same broken feature for propal and invoice
FIX: select 2 no record found translate
FIX: selectcontact is loading all contacts if socid is empty and MAIN_ACTIONCOM_CAN_ADD_ANY_CONTACT is not set
FIX: selectcontact is loading all contacts when update event
FIX: select group and severity search fields on ticket list
FIX: send email to assigned user on ticket create
FIX: sql error with the new sql forge filter
FIX: sql "order by" is defined twice
FIX: status ticket update for new message
FIX: swap tests
FIX: switch on/off status of a page of the second website.
FIX: There were many status indicator in the invoice linked object block (propal card)
FIX: uniformize code
FIX: units used scale and scale is an integer
FIX: wrong alias table
FIX: wrong file path + avoid warning
FIX: wrong filter format
FIX: wrong "fournisseur" var value checking
FIX: wrong left margin
FIX: wrong message on update shipment
FIX: wrong ODT path for multicompany
FIX: wrong path for odt models
FIX: wrong search filter, empty product unit is "none"
FIX: wrong update function parameter
FIX: some wrong var type
FIX: some wrong var name&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/Dolibarr/dolibarr/releases/tag/20.0.4" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/Dolibarr/dolibarr/releases/tag/21.0.0</id>
    <title>New release for Dolibarr: 21.0</title>
    <updated>2025-03-06T11:20:45-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Dolibarr/dolibarr</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;*&lt;/em&gt; ChangeLog for 21.0.0 compared to 20.0 &lt;/strong&gt;***&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;For users:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NEW: NEW Module - help to setup OpenID Connect (#30317)
NEW: Module AI moved from experimental to stable
NEW: Add hidden option CONTRACT_HIDE_MYCOMPANY_SIGNATURE_SECTION_PDF
NEW: Add a tab on recurring invoice card to see the list of invoices generated from this recurring invoice (customer and supplier invoices) (#31463)
NEW: #28871 signed_status to commande (#30359)
NEW: #30269 linked project in column of last record tables (#30344)
NEW: Accountancy - Add general account on thirdparty
NEW: Accountancy - Add partial reconcile on subledger (#30027)
NEW: Accountancy - Option to select the label of operation (#31200)
NEW: Accountancy - Allow grouping taxes with primary line price (#26732)
NEW: Activate PHPUnit with tests on permission on $action ==...
NEW: Add advice for max size on list for better performance
NEW: Add an advanced permission to validate knowledge (#30855)
NEW: Add a test mode into the setup of AI module to test the AI prompts.
NEW: Add a tool to decrypt data encrypted in database.
NEW: Add auto generate document when reception is created (#30688)
NEW: Add badge for generate invoice client tab (#31559)
NEW: Add caldav on fichinter (#30582)
NEW: Add column agenda_id to implement the link between files and event
NEW: Add column "comment" in list of payment
NEW: Add constant to hide version (#30865)
NEW: Add country in search of project
NEW: add duration extrafields (#31595)
NEW: Add export for thirdparty bank accounts (#30807)
NEW: Add export profile to export MO and lines of consumption/production
NEW: Add option to store the text content of uploaded files into database (with conversion with pdftotext)
NEW: Add Filter Assistance for Filling Filters Field (#31646)
NEW: add last stock movement and product nature to StocksWithBatch export (#30578)
NEW: Add member title to the labels (#31710)
NEW: Add mode Customer price + level price (#31091)
NEW: add option to add external billing contact on the supplier_proposal pdf (#30298)
NEW: Add option to clone its default BOM when cloning a product (#30088)
NEW: Add option to enable PDF frame rounded corners
NEW: Add option to round weight and volume on shipment PDF
NEW: add pdf regeneration to mass action for shipments (#29970)
NEW: Add picto on list of notification email templates
NEW: add recurring supplier invoice on supplier tab #30945 #30949
NEW: Add sort by ref warehouse/product or ref product/warehouse on inventory product list (#31639)
NEW: Add some improvement for ODT Contracts (#31715)
NEW: Add terms of sale on documents (#24846)
NEW: Add thirdparty state in substitution array (#31549)
NEW: Add tooltip on closing accounting setup
NEW: add trigger for linking and unlinking invoices (#30182)
NEW: Add Unit price on supplier order stat product (#31055)
NEW: add warehouseId parameters in select_produit to limit result to existing product in select (#30477)
NEW: allow link feature to task (#30235)
NEW: Authorize modification of a partially shipped order (#31423)
NEW: autogenerate project reference in API (#30638)
NEW: automatically change status on answering a ticket (#30556)
NEW: Browser notifications use now jnotify (fix browser compatibility)
NEW: can add extrafields with dol_move (#30574)
NEW: Can change the type of a social contribution if no payment
NEW: can delete a category translation (#31396)
NEW: Can link an object to another using the ref. Close #31001
NEW: Can set a class on the tr lines of form setup lines
NEW: Can set border radius of list and tables
NEW: Can set date of transmission in 1 click when validating SEPA
NEW: Can set parameters with setup type yesno.
NEW: Can set the contact type for the autoassigned user that creates a project (#30444)
NEW: Can show raw value of oauth token
NEW: Can use a specific profile to send email for password forgotten
NEW: option to care grandchild (#31314)
NEW: Look and feel - checkbox to choose thirdparty nature (#30192)
NEW: Color line total and sub total (#26172)
NEW: Constant to hide user login times (#29815)
NEW: Const ASSET_ROUND_INTEGER_NUMBER_UPWARDS for ASSET Module. Compatibility to migrate from other accounting solutions. (#31615)
NEW: Content of tab "attached files" is more compact.
NEW: Contract signed status update (#30779)
NEW: Create thirdparty notification by action code (#30541)
NEW: Customer price and level price together
NEW: default configuration for event reminder (#31407)
NEW: determine multi-currency price on object line create tpl (#28021)
NEW: Display for socialnetworks admin
NEW: display mark rates in objectLineCreate (#30872)
NEW: due date in accounting bookkeeping list and card (#30061)
NEW: enhance the OAUTH2 token manager. Can refresh a token from page.
NEW: EPC QR CODE - Use bank owner account name instead of company (#31735)
NEW: fichinter list disable details option (#30884)
NEW: filter on invoice dates in product margin tab (#29997) and thirdparty margin tab (#29998)
NEW: FIX: Display invoice widgets by amount instead of number (#30215)
NEW: Add the Clone of company (#29755)
NEW: function for Preview In CKeditor products
NEW: FY Changed Period handle in Module Asset (#31618)
NEW: hidden option MAIN_TE_PRIVATE_FIRST_AND_LASTNAME_TO_UPPER (#31143)
NEW: Hide completed items in Link to (#31329)
NEW: Iban is saved encrypted
NEW: if a user is associated with the expense report, then that user will get an associated credit line ($tabtp) generated.
NEW: Implementing Billable tasks on projects using new attribute "billable" (#30092)
NEW: Include a protection into check update of module to detect malware
NEW: intervention signed status update (#30629)
NEW: INTRA VAT ID field optionally mandatory and/or invoice mandatory in thirdparty module setup (#31663)
NEW: Invoice - Generate payment information - Structured communication (#31376)
NEW: Invoice line import - fk_product can be a ref (#30795)
NEW: Look and feel v21 - Can have rounded border on tables
NEW: Look and feel v21 - Toolbar for WYSIWYG editor is short on smartphone
NEW: Management of extrafields on customer prices, level prices and default prices (#31313)
NEW: manage several type of dangerous goods for a same parcel (#30238)
NEW: Member - Can upload a file with drag and drop (#30265)
NEW: Move the picto in the first tab label always visible
NEW: ODTSubsitution for date_start_real / Contracts
NEW: Look and feel - Opacity for finished lines (#30219)
NEW: option: assign default roles to "individual" third-party contacts (#30499)
NEW: option to allow freezing qty in BOM service's line (#29990)
NEW: Add a page to list the lines of orderse (#31521)
NEW: pagination in product margin tab
NEW: payment term and mode on creating supplier (#31166) and third-party (#31067)
NEW: PDF Add Customer accountancy code (#31544)
NEW: PDF Add discount total if line discount exists (#31483)
NEW: PDF Add option to print rounded corner frames (#31172)
NEW: PDF Add shipping address in sales orders (#31293)
NEW: PDF Add total discount if line discount exists
NEW: PDF frame rounded corners
NEW: Prelevement - Use structured payment data for Belgium (#31383)
NEW: Preview product list when we choose model email layout Commerce (#30185)
NEW: Can upload a file with drag and drop: Thirdparty (#30263) - Product/Service (#30250) - Project (#30276) - Propale (#30315)
NEW: Public and private note options in thirdparty list (#31062)
NEW: redirect to expedition card if global search has unique result (#30108)
NEW: replenishment if the warehouse is set to the default selected user (#31229)
NEW: retrieve Thirdparty by account (#31283)
NEW: Share msg "not found" for widgets and add a button to add new record when none exists (#31309)
NEW: shipment signed status update (#30928)
NEW: Show detail of each multicurrency amount in popup of price
NEW: show holidays at bottom of activity/permonth.php page (#31550)
NEW: Show tooltip on number of qualified records
NEW: Signature or proposal from the Web portal (#30062)
NEW: Star Field Type for Extra Fields (#31348) and for for Module Builder (#31216)
NEW: Support option PDF_ADD_POSITION on shipment espadon template
NEW: Auto-suspend facture rec when nb gen max is reached (#31623)
NEW: The margin section can now be shown/hidden
NEW: Deal change in fiscal year period adjustments to shortened or extended periods (e.g., fiscal years of 9 or 15 months)
NEW: (ticket, admin): More options entries (#30548)
NEW: Update warehouse product list to add another sorting option (#30971)
NEW: Can set blacklist of words into answer of AI (#30385)
NEW: user list country filter (#30770)
NEW: vat rate with department in dict (#31628) (#31627)
NEW: When we export data of unlaterable log, we add an unalterable line in logs
NEW Add option THEME_STICKY_TOPMENU = 'scrollleftmenu_after_mainpage' (or 'disabled')
NEW value for FICHINTER_DISABLE_DETAILS. If FICHINTER_DISABLE_DETAILS is set to '2' details are disabled only on intervention list.
SEC: security avoid RCE using -'- sequence to pass --checkpoint-action parameter in tar command.
SEC: FIX Security path transversal with modulepart=medias (viewimage.php and download.php)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PERF: Reduce nb of requests into num_public_holiday
PERF: Reduce size for VCF files and virtualcard qrcode
PERF: Reduce time to show the page of unalterable logs with high data&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;For developers:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NEW: translation with action triggers API (#30595)
NEW: more complete stock product API call (#30567)
NEW: Projet - Add hook formconfirm (#31408)
NEW: Can choose the zip handler to build ODT.
NEW: Can force ip into log file name using a define('SYSLOG_FILE_ADDIP')
NEW: Can force log file name using a define('SYSLOG_FILE_ADDSUFFIX')
NEW: Can define the text on tooltip on a yesno check.
NEW: Introduce value 'password' for mode of sanitization in GETPOST.
NEW: Add getImageFromHtmlContent() method
NEW: Add gitleaks into pre-commit
NEW: Add hook after the line is processed in the sell journal page (#31439)
NEW: add hook dolibarrDelConst (#30672)
NEW: Add hook getLoginPageExtraContent, getPasswordResetPageExtraContent
NEW: add hook in dolibarr_set_const admin.lib.php (#30605)
NEW: Add hook on sell journal page for overwrite the processed journal data after the SQL request (#31033)
NEW: force_install_noedit : add value 3 to block all technical parameters excepted main_url (#30080)
NEW: Add a new hook on order list (#31315)
NEW: Add ID of the line in the trigger context for addLine(), updateLine() and deleteLine() on contract (#30343)
NEW: Add more log information
NEW: Add pagination data to some api routes (#29895)
NEW: Add test to forbidden NOW() SQL function.
NEW: API call to re-generate a users password. (#30590)
NEW: API close proposal now supports both private and public note (#30659)
NEW: API_LOGINS_ALLOWED_FOR_GET_EXTRAFIELD (#30562)
NEW: API /setup endpoint for getting action triggers (#30538)
NEW: HOOK FORMCONFIRM IN TICKET (#31321)
NEW: hook on expensereport added (#31380)
QUAL line classes for various business object classes have been moved to individual files.
QUAL: #30122 (#30131)
QUAL: AccountancySystem: maintenance work to uniformize and clean up (#31391)
QUAL: All $conf-&amp;gt;global-&amp;gt;module-&amp;gt;enabled are replaced with isModEnabled()
QUAL: bankline category table name (#30419)
QUAL: Clean code
QUAL: conformity PR for data structure of #29964 (#30014)
QUAL: Edition of currency is shared in a common tpl file
QUAL: Ergo btn and fix  (#30947)
QUAL: Move function csvClean into functions2.lib.php
QUAL: Move the public css file into the public directory
QUAL: Removed inclusion of the file json.lib.php
QUAL: simplifying readability of sql
QUAL: Standardize name of user cookies
QUAL: Suffix table name to have them created on module install
QUAL: The property -&amp;gt;domiciliation and -&amp;gt;propio on bank accounts has been
QUAL: Update inc.php (#29822)
QUAL: Use archiveOrBackupFile for MAIN_MAIL_DEBUG_LOG_WITH_DATE
QUAL: Use table_element in sql queries (#31355)
QUAL: rename const WORKFLOW_EXPEDITION_CLASSIFY_NEWD_INVOICE to WORKFLOW_RECEPTION_CLASSIFY_NEWD_INVOICE
QUAL: This configuration change in phan will report NEW: array types in phpdoc&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;WARNING:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following changes may create regressions for some external modules, but were necessary to make Dolibarr better:
* Prepare your module for deprecation of triggers code XXX_INSERT to support also XXX_CREATE.
* More class properties (with old name in french) are now deprecated in favor of the property name in english.
* The json emulator dol_json_encode/decode() is removed. The native json PHP module must be enabled/available (this is the case by default with most PHP installation).
* The deprecated GET parameter "&amp;amp;sall=" has been removed, use now the "&amp;amp;search_all=".
* The experimental and deprecated module WebserviceClient is completely removed (was never released and use deprecated architecture). It may be replaced with the stable module Webhook.
* The dynamic properties -&amp;gt;no_button_delete, -&amp;gt;no_button_edit, -&amp;gt;no_button_copy for $object Product that could be set by an external module must no more be
  set (not allowed by PHP 8.2). A module can already return an array with key 'no_button_delete', 'no_button_edit', 'no_button_copy' for the same purpose.
* The old function dol_bc($var, $moreclass = '') has been removed. If you called it, just stop to call it (the function has no effect since a long time).
* The trigger code CATEGORY_LINK and CATEGORY_UNLINK have been replaced with code CATEGORY_MODIFY. You can read -&amp;gt;context['linkto'] or -&amp;gt;context['unlinkoff'] to detect if we want to make a link or unlink.
* The property -&amp;gt;domiciliation and -&amp;gt;propio on bank accounts has been deprecated and replaced with property -&amp;gt;address and -&amp;gt;owner_name everywhere.
* If you were using the substitution key &lt;strong&gt;MEMBER_CIVILITY&lt;/strong&gt;, you must now use &lt;strong&gt;MEMBER_TITLE&lt;/strong&gt;
* The hidden title of tab that was hidden by the CSS class tabTitleText has been completely removed from HTML content.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/Dolibarr/dolibarr/releases/tag/21.0.0" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/Dolibarr/dolibarr/releases/tag/21.0.1</id>
    <title>New release for Dolibarr: 21.0.1</title>
    <updated>2025-04-06T15:22:59-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Dolibarr/dolibarr</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;*&lt;/em&gt; ChangeLog for 21.0.1 compared to 21.0.0 &lt;/strong&gt;***&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FIX: #33360
FIX: #33365 Global search for single shipment (#33401)
FIX: #33404 - to keep the method findNearest an agnostic method.
FIX: #33435 Warnings
FIX: Accountancy simplified - with multiple entities, amount of the entry is multiplied by the number of entities (#33370)
FIX: Add a new email for notification
FIX: Bad link to download tax vat document
FIX: Blank page on agenda event per user
FIX: blank page on smartphone for bank SEPA direct transfer page
FIX: close all services on contract will close all lines (#33466)
FIX: Count on supplier invoice list does not match count in DB (#33351)
FIX: CR on script output
FIX: CSS center end CSS in total
FIX: Duplicate load of extrafield -&amp;gt;fetch_optionals()
FIX: fatal error in notification sending email when error array is empty
FIX: Link to country setup on company setup page
FIX: Loading of deliveries in shipping card was loading everything
FIX: Missing ref_ext in group by in list of product
FIX: Must make different redirect in paymentok/ko according to frame or not.
FIX: PAIEMENT Wrong field displayed for DateChequeReceived (#33390)
FIX: picto for unknown mime type
FIX: Replace compromised tj-actions/changed-files (#33481)
FIX: Report by custom group was empty
FIX: Responsive
FIX: shipment dispatch origin line (#33415)
FIX: Show the default duration of a membership type.
FIX: Sort and search Ref Project column was missing (#33539)
FIX: syntax error on list of intervention for external users
FIX: text in tooltip on buttons when pb is not a permission problem
FIX: Translation of column in list of invoice
FIX: warnings (#33423)
FIX: Warning when getNomUrl is called before top_httphead
FIX: we must retrieve linked order_supplier and no other object (#33602)
SEC FIX: Reflected XSS reported by 柏天浩&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/Dolibarr/dolibarr/releases/tag/21.0.1" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/Dolibarr/dolibarr/releases/tag/21.0.2</id>
    <title>New release for Dolibarr: 21.0 2</title>
    <updated>2025-07-22T12:58:05-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Dolibarr/dolibarr</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;*&lt;/em&gt; ChangeLog for 21.0.2 compared to 21.0.1 &lt;/strong&gt;***&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FIX: 21.0: $height and $width can be ints, but also 'auto' (#34636)
FIX: #33030 (#34460)
FIX: #33727 Sec
FIX: #33774 #34214
FIX: #33854
FIX: #34313 Accountancy - Export with sources no longer works (#34324)
FIX: (#34448)
FIX: #34541 (#34597)
FIX: #34564 (#34590)
FIX: #34591 FIX: #34692
FIX: #34618 (#34621)
FIX: #34654
FIX: accountancy: bad filter on custom account groups (#34205)
FIX: accountancy balance: keep subtotals when sorting (#34001)
FIX: accountancy closure: if subledger_label is not found, PHP8.2 throws an error. (#34736)
FIX: accountancy: create new french PCG25-DEV accounting system in upgrade (#34036)
FIX: accountancy expensereport journal: php 8.1 warning (#34457)
FIX: accountancy fec export: remove dol_print_date warning (#34363)
FIX: accountancy general ledger: last total not shown if last account group shown has only one entry (#34251)
FIX: accountancy lettering: php8.1 warning (#34469)
FIX: Accountancy - Problem with constant ACCOUNTANCY_COMBO_FOR_AUX (#34414)
FIX: accountancy sales/purchases journal: sql error logged when no invoice in journal (#34339)
FIX: accountancy: warning when account not found in plan (#34030)
FIX: a comment without after a comma create a sql error (#33752)
FIX: Add others allowed tags (table, tr, td) for the prices history table displayed in the link url of the supplier product in supplier product prices list (#34532)
FIX: add payment to bank (#34263)
FIX: allow double colon and string obfuscation in dol eval for computed extra fields (#34015)
FIX: API expense report line comments (v18+) (#34297)
FIX: Approver must be able to approve even if user not in hierarchy.
FIX: asset depreciation: division by zero (#34218)
FIX: asset depreciation: php warnings (#34219)
FIX: avoid sql error when a comment is after without comma (#33758)
FIX: Backport fix of substitution of thirdparty info in notification
FIX: backport of replaceement of thirdparty information on notification
FIX: bad value for company ref crashes canvas feature (#34331)
FIX: bank payment rejection on SEPA (backport commit 100a657) (#33838)
FIX: BankTransfer information in line.php (#34425)
FIX: BankTransfer link in list.php (#34513)
FIX: BankTransfer link in rejets.php (#34424)
FIX: Bug filters (#34546)
FIX: Can set default value of the nature of member
FIX: Can set the default value of nature of thirdparty
FIX: cash control report: php warning (#34358)
FIX: common fields: php warning with select input field (#34495)
FIX: constant PAYMENTBYBANKTRANSFER_ADDDAYS was never saved (#33799)
FIX: creating acredit note from the remain to pay was always 0
FIX: DetecHTML on upload file from filemanager fails due to need to lock
FIX: Disallow special char in name of oauth entries
FIX: do not add a filter on status when doing a global search on project
FIX: Do not allow to force amount for online payment of order
FIX: do not forget extrafields for BOM in export lines (#34020)
FIX: Edition of target of menu entries
FIX: element must be visible to set focus on select input when using default values (#34406)
FIX: email collector: php 8 warning (#34496)
FIX: encoding issues with underscores in mb_convert_encoding functionality (#34411)
FIX: ensure dir exists before trying to move something in it (#34211)
FIX: event info tab: php 8.1 warning (#34458)
FIX: expense report card: mail notifications not sent (#34556)
FIX: expensereport payment list: php warning (#34453)
FIX: expensereport: php warning when generating pdf with multilangs (#34492)
FIX: files lib: multiple php 8.1 warnings (#34462)
FIX: filter agenda on user and resource SQL error (#34580)
FIX: HTML broken by the trunc.
FIX: html title when using custom value
FIX: if filter is set on export for Duree type filed, then there is SQL error (#34616)
FIX: interventions: sql error when signed_status not set (#34515)
FIX: js warning (Backport commit 84d982c) (#34555)
FIX: local taxes text in object line view mode (#34103)
FIX: local taxes text in PDF (#34343)
FIX: mandatory extrafelds on lines are not checked (#34228)
FIX: manufacturing orders: php 8.1 warnings on agenda tab (#34475)
FIX: mass assignment of sale representative
FIX: Missing ol in no escape tags (#34261)
FIX: modification de dates de pièces comptables sur plusieurs entités différentes (#34226)
FIX: oauth: php 8 warnings (#34027)
FIX: online propal sign: double header with logo when custom logo set (#34504)
FIX: Order error translation (#33834)
FIX: page of bom when only bom module is on
FIX: partial result on timespent list (#33855)
FIX: pgsql: boolean fields correctly defined in creation but not in migration (#34215)
FIX: pgsql: case sensitivity in select queries (#34028)
FIX: pgsql: error when creating sequences in migration scripts (#34021)
FIX: PHP 8 Error 500 (#34545)
FIX: prelevement order list: handle case of use by banktransfer module (#33801)
FIX: pre-send mail mass action: keep &lt;strong&gt;EMAIL&lt;/strong&gt; substitution (#34522)
FIX: prevent log warning with online signature url (#34361)
FIX: Product batch series - Title, help url et picto (#34560)
FIX: product multiprices: fatal error on vat update on php 8.2 (#34444)
FIX: product suplier tab: last modif date column was wrongly dependent of module barcode (#34170)
FIX: product translation: redirect after successful action (#34403)
FIX: projects: go back to edit view after cloning (#34221)
FIX: receptions: crash from api because of classes not found (#34523)
FIX: Remove useless amp; after &amp;amp; (#34288)
FIX: select supplier when creating object from project (#33766)
FIX: social contribution payment: correct error reporting (#34002)
FIX: stock control condition in reception delete (#33952)
FIX: Tmparray string not array (#34287)
FIX: Too heavy sql query (#34371)
FIX: try to fix v18 github action workflow (#34439)
FIX: Various payment - List - Can't see payment with subledger account (#34101)
FIX: warehouse list: broken status filter (#33667)
FIX: warnings when printing start/end date on line tpl (#34359)
FIX: wrong multicompany filter (#34714)
FIX: ws detection&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/Dolibarr/dolibarr/releases/tag/21.0.2" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
