<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://selfh.st/apps</id>
  <title>Easy!Appointments Releases</title>
  <updated>2025-07-06T11:36:55.045718-04:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>selfh.st</name>
    <email>contact@selfh.st</email>
  </author>
  <link href="https://selfh.st/apps" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>Self-hosted software releases generated by selfh.st</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/alextselegidis/easyappointments/releases/tag/1.4.1</id>
    <title>New release for Easy!Appointments: 1.4.1</title>
    <updated>2020-12-17T10:23:52-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>alextselegidis/easyappointments</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h2&gt;[1.4.1] - 2020-12-14&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Added&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;952: Add timezone support in the REST API, when managing users.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;955: Display confirmation modal when disabling a connected Google Calendar Sync.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Fixed&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;945: Google Calendar sync throws an error with all day Google Calendar Events.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;946: Typo in JavaScript code leads to a broken calendar view, when loading unavailability events with note contents.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;948: Multiple attendant services may lead to double booking.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;950: Cannot create provider without services via the API, some values (other endpoints) are optional too.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;953: Current time indicator in fullcalendar is showing time in local timezone and not in the user selected timezone.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;954: The password must be provided via the API when creating new users.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;img src="https://easyappointments.org/img/easyappointments-signature.png"&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Alex Tselegidis, Easy!Appointments Creator &lt;br&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://alextselegidis.com"&gt;Need a customization? Contact me in person!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/alextselegidis/easyappointments/releases/tag/1.4.1" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/alextselegidis/easyappointments/releases/tag/1.4.2</id>
    <title>New release for Easy!Appointments: 1.4.2</title>
    <updated>2021-07-27T04:46:48-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>alextselegidis/easyappointments</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h2&gt;[1.4.2] - 2021-07-27&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Added&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;1004: Add support for line breaks when displaying the service description in the frontend.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;1040: Support all-day events while syncing with Google Calendar.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Fixed&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;961: Timezone/UX issue: Wrong day is selected when timezone differs by -1 day.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;966: Secretaries are getting notification emails for providers that are not assigned to them.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;980: Missing Pacific (and potentially other) timezones.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;982: The Any-Provider option might lead to double bookings, if all the providers have the same number of appointments for the selected date.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;986: Managed to replicate appointment hash collisions.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;989: Fix Critical mistake resulting in wrong date&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;990: The API availabilities controller throws an error when generating availability for services with multiple attendants.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;991: Available hours generated with the "Any Provider" option in the booking page, may use the information of a provider that is not assigned to the selected service.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;993: Add support for PHP8 (vendor packages need to be updated).&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;1000: Small fix for the display of the delete button in table view.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;1011: Working plan exception - details pane shows incorrect details.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;1023: Backend calendar table events missing or duplicated.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;1026: The timepicker sliders do not work when using an iOS device.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;1029: Enhance SMTP functions of PHPMailer.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;1043: Unavailable events do not block time from services with multiple attendants.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;1046: Make sure that saving the modifications of a single break does not cancel any pending break edits.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;1068: Set minimum service duration field value to honor the value of EVENT_MINIMUM_DURATION.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;1073: Update PHPMailer dependencies.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;1074: In case of deletion of one appointment, system sends email to admins anyway even if they have email notifications disabled.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;1092: Javascript RangeError on appointment change causing disabled calendar dates.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;img src="https://easyappointments.org/img/easyappointments-signature.png"&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Alex Tselegidis, Easy!Appointments Creator
&lt;br&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://easyappointments.org/get-a-free-quote"&gt;Need a customization? Get a free quote!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/small&gt; &lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/alextselegidis/easyappointments/releases/tag/1.4.2" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/alextselegidis/easyappointments/releases/tag/1.4.3</id>
    <title>New release for Easy!Appointments: 1.4.3</title>
    <updated>2022-03-08T12:32:57-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>alextselegidis/easyappointments</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;Easy!Appointments is a self hosted, open source web scheduler application that is very easy to setup on your server.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a stable release, you can use it in production environments and/or update your existing installations. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;https://easyappointments.org&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;[1.4.3] - 2022-03-08&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Added&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;1208: Security configuration enhancements in the application.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;1209: Add support for PHP 8.1.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Changed&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;1207: Replace CodeIgniter with the system directory for smaller package size and more control over the framework.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;1210: Move the change language operation into a new public controller.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;1212: Remove the Google Calendar read-only scope use as it is not needed.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;1213: Switch to go-to-latest database migration configuration for simplicity.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;1216 Replace Google Client JS with the Google Calendar Template link in the book success page enhancement.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Fixed&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;1211: The table calendar view breaks for secretaries and providers due to appointment and unavailability removals bug.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;1214: Provider and secretary users can only add unavailabilities for their authorized users bug.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/alextselegidis/easyappointments/releases/tag/1.4.3" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/alextselegidis/easyappointments/releases/tag/1.5.0</id>
    <title>New release for Easy!Appointments: 1.5.0</title>
    <updated>2024-07-07T07:58:10-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>alextselegidis/easyappointments</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;Easy!Appointments is a self hosted, open source web scheduler application that is very easy to setup on your server.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a stable release, you can use it in production environments and/or update your existing installations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;https://easyappointments.org&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;[1.5.0] - 2024-07-07&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Added&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Display month with the earliest available day (#1075)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Allow admins to define the business closed dates (blocked-periods) (#432)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Allow working plan exceptions to be defined as non-working days (#1383)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create an official docker image of the project and host it on Docker Hub(#1116)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Automatically select the next available date in the booking page or display a message if this month is unavailable (#1204)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add Open Graph information to the public booking page so that it renders nicely once shared on social media apps (#1382)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Preselect the date with a query parameter (#1376)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add the location and notes fields to the appointment email notifications (if a value was provided) (#1341)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add date, from and till query parameters to the filter the appointments index results by date (#1134)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Allow the users to define their own status and assign them to appointments (#244)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add new setting for limiting new public bookings in the future (#1203)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Automatically enable the secure cookie config if the current installation uses HTTPS (#1126)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add language and timezone properties to the customer API resource (#1157)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add support for the definition of custom webhooks via the settings page (#581)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Allow the user to select their own preferred language (#1263)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Support multiple Bootswatch themes for the app (#1205)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Providers and secretaries must only be able to see and manage their own customers (#1199)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use the default service duration if the user just clicks on a calendar slot for creating a new appointment (#1237)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Google Calendar synchronisation failure when symbols/emoji appear in events to be imported (#1182)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add the customer timezone field in the appointment modal of the calendar page (#1094)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add a new setting that toggles the login link of the booking page (#1148)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add custom Matomo analytics integration (#974)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Prefill the form field though url parameters (#1021)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Color code events by provider or service (#422)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Service duration values shorter than 5 minutes should be acceptable via the services page (#1110)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add a new "is_private" flag to services and providers so that they do not appear in the booking page (#378)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Skip the first booking step when only one service and one provider are available (#349)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enable the change of the brand logo and colors from the backend (#789)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add the ability to temporarily block new appointments / set away message (#940)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add optional (configurable with setting) phone number validation (#820)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add an option to deactivate the remove-all-data function for customers (#808)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Skip the first booking step if both provider and service are preselected (#1117)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make delete appointment via API to send emails just like the calendar page does (#1101)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create new layout structure for the markup, so that common HTML markup is being reused (#1152)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Have an option to hide customer data fields during booking (#1081)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add a SECURITY.md file to the repository (#1122)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add support for custom fields on customers (#1133)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add from email/name and reply-to settings in the email.php configuration file (#1465)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create a new setting that will define the default timezone of the application (#1390)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Integrate CalDAV Protocol for appointment syncing (#209)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add LDAP / Active Directory integration (#128)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Changed&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do not allow a customer to book the same hours multiple times (#1420)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All the user roles with access to the backend calendar page can filter by services (#956)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Update Bootstrap to version 5 (#1150)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Update FullCalendar to version 5 (#1151)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The availability generation algorithm needs performance improvements when many appointments are stored in the system (#1171)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Support for relative paths when loading resources or working with the session (#1158)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Support line breaks when displaying the service description (#1149)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Remove the CodeIgniter fork from the composer.json file and re-import the system directory (#1109)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Fixed&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sync all the providers without errors, when the user clicks on the "sync" button and "all" is selected in the calendar page (#1365)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Non-working time not showing correctly in the week view of calendar (#1381)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make sure the booking cancellation is a post request and has a reason value provided (#1178)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Removed&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Remove the engine directory and files form the app (they're deprecated) (#971)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Remove the PHPMailer dependency from the app and use the built-in CodeIgniter mailer (#970)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/alextselegidis/easyappointments/releases/tag/1.5.0" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/alextselegidis/easyappointments/releases/tag/1.5.1</id>
    <title>New release for Easy!Appointments: 1.5.1</title>
    <updated>2025-01-20T09:30:31-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>alextselegidis/easyappointments</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;Easy!Appointments is a self hosted, open source web scheduler application that is very easy to setup on your server.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a stable release, you can use it in production environments and/or update your existing installations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;https://easyappointments.org&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;[1.5.1] - 2025-01-20&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Added&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add support for PHP 8.4 (#1640)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add new secret token header field to webhooks and default to X-EA-Token (#1607)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add company colors to notifications (#1569)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add Albanian Language Translations (#1646)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Fixed&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix the date parsing issue on Safari web browsers during the booking process (#1584)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix working plan configuration am/pm hour parsing so that it works in all languages (#1606)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improve the CalDAV syncing mechanism so that it connects to more systems without problems (#1622)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix various 1.5.0 API issues (#1562)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Correct email issues by replacing the internal email library with phpmailer (#1587)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix ICS file mimetype (#1630)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Incorrect Timezone Handling in CalDAV Synchronization Causes Time Shifts (#1626)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No color change in the appointment modal window (in the backend calendar) (#1641)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The plain user password might appear in the log messages in case of an error (#1590)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix loop when going a month back in an edge case (#1577)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dedicated provider links do not pre-select the relevant provider on the booking page (#1651)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Correct the service / provider booking header display (#1650)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/alextselegidis/easyappointments/releases/tag/1.5.1" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
