<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://selfh.st/apps</id>
  <title>Ente Photos Releases</title>
  <updated>2025-07-27T14:33:06.118872-04:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>selfh.st</name>
    <email>contact@selfh.st</email>
  </author>
  <link href="https://selfh.st/apps" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>Self-hosted software releases generated by selfh.st</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/ente-io/ente/releases/tag/photos-v1.0.4</id>
    <title>New release for Ente Photos: photos-v1.0.4</title>
    <updated>2025-04-25T02:50:38-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>ente-io/ente</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h2&gt;What's Changed&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This release includes a number of improvements, bug fixes, and updated translations for the mobile app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Features:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Search &amp;amp; Filter:&lt;/strong&gt; Added the ability to search and filter media by the uploader's name.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;New Translations:&lt;/strong&gt; Enabled translations for Romanian and Norwegian. Added support for Portuguese (Portugal).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Advanced Photos Option:&lt;/strong&gt; Introduced an advanced setting to disable curated memories.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Custom FFmpeg Kit:&lt;/strong&gt; Switched to a custom FFmpeg kit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Enhancements:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Image Embedding Caching:&lt;/strong&gt; Improved performance of image embedding caching.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Local Thumbnail Fetching:&lt;/strong&gt; Optimized fetching of local thumbnails using a queue for better efficiency.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Android - Ignored File Identifier:&lt;/strong&gt; Improved the identification of ignored files.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Memory Widget:&lt;/strong&gt; Limited the memory widget to cache a maximum of 50 files.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Package Updates:&lt;/strong&gt; Bumped various packages and replaced some dependencies.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Target SDK:&lt;/strong&gt; Upgraded the targetSdkVersion to 35.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bug Fixes:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Feature Flag Service:&lt;/strong&gt; Fixed a potential NullPointerException in the feature flag service.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Discovery Section:&lt;/strong&gt; Resolved an issue with the reload condition of the discovery section.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;iOS/macOS Lock Screen:&lt;/strong&gt; Fixed a bug where the lock screen could reappear on reinstall if it was previously enabled.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Photos - Datepicker:&lt;/strong&gt; Removed the datepicker dependency.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tag "Me" Flow:&lt;/strong&gt; Improved the user experience of the "tag me" feature.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Caching:&lt;/strong&gt; Addressed a caching issue.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ICU Syntax:&lt;/strong&gt; Fixed an ICU syntax error.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Flutter Secure Storage:&lt;/strong&gt; Downgraded &lt;code&gt;flutter_secure_storage&lt;/code&gt; to fix an issue where lock screen data persisted after reinstall on iOS.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Other:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Shared Media Files:&lt;/strong&gt; Deleted an old identifier for shared media files.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ONNX Debug Options:&lt;/strong&gt; Added debug options for ONNX.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sync Status Logging:&lt;/strong&gt; Added logging for sync status when the upload icon is hidden.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Smart Memories:&lt;/strong&gt; Smart memories will now only be shown if local indexing is enabled.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Full Changelog&lt;/strong&gt;: https://github.com/ente-io/ente/compare/photos-v1.0.0...photos-v1.0.4&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/ente-io/ente/releases/tag/photos-v1.0.4" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/ente-io/ente/releases/tag/photos-v1.0.10</id>
    <title>New release for Ente Photos: photos-v1.0.10</title>
    <updated>2025-05-10T02:47:09-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>ente-io/ente</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h2&gt;What's Changed&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This release focuses on bug fixes, performance improvements, and updated translations for the mobile app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Enhancements:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Photos - Video Editor:&lt;/strong&gt; Includes improvements to the video editor.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Resumable Upload:&lt;/strong&gt; Enabled gradual rollout for resumable upload functionality.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Streaming:&lt;/strong&gt; Includes performance improvements for streaming.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Backup Status Screen:&lt;/strong&gt; Updated the backup status screen.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pending Sync:&lt;/strong&gt; Surface storage utilization information for the pending sync section.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Audio Re-encoding:&lt;/strong&gt; Re-encodes audio using FFmpeg.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Faces Queue:&lt;/strong&gt; Implemented a queue for face processing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;File Upload:&lt;/strong&gt; Improve upload experience for large files over flaky networks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bug Fixes:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Photos - Build Error:&lt;/strong&gt; Fixed a build failure caused by a translation error.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Photos - Audio Session (iOS):&lt;/strong&gt; Removed the setting of the audio session category on iOS.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Photos - Wakelock:&lt;/strong&gt; Addressed and fixed wakelock-related bugs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Photos - "Not person" Response:&lt;/strong&gt; Fixed an issue with a null response for "Not person" identification.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Photos - Memories Update:&lt;/strong&gt; Fixed a regression in the update process for memories.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Photos - Share to Ente:&lt;/strong&gt; Resolved an issue when sharing content to Ente.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Splash Screen (iOS Simulator):&lt;/strong&gt; Fixed an issue where splash screens could get stuck during development with the iOS simulator.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Widget Mount Check:&lt;/strong&gt; Added a missing check for widget mounting.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FFmpeg-kit (Android):&lt;/strong&gt; Fixed an Android compilation issue with &lt;code&gt;ffmpeg-kit&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Other:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Refactoring:&lt;/strong&gt; Refactored code and removed unused methods.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;New Translations:&lt;/strong&gt; Included new translations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Norwegian String:&lt;/strong&gt; Setup a readable string for Norwegian.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Resource Intensive Features Logging:&lt;/strong&gt; Added logging to track whether resource-intensive features are enabled.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dark Mode App Icon (iOS):&lt;/strong&gt; Updated the dark mode app icon to align with iOS design guidelines.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Backup Failed Dialog:&lt;/strong&gt; Updated the appearance of the backup failed dialog.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Face Thumbnail Logging:&lt;/strong&gt; Added logging for face thumbnails.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Navigation to Backup Settings:&lt;/strong&gt; The "Waiting for network" status now navigates to the Backup Settings screen when tapped.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Version Updates:&lt;/strong&gt; Minor version bumps (v1.0.7, v1.0.8+1038).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Non-Ente Instance Banner:&lt;/strong&gt; Hid the referral promo banner for non-Ente instance users.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Full Changelog&lt;/strong&gt;: https://github.com/ente-io/ente/compare/photos-v1.0.4...photos-v1.0.10&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/ente-io/ente/releases/tag/photos-v1.0.10" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/ente-io/ente/releases/tag/photos-v1.1.0</id>
    <title>New release for Ente Photos: photos-v1.1.0</title>
    <updated>2025-05-30T00:54:08-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>ente-io/ente</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h2&gt;What's Changed&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This release focuses on new sharing capabilities, video playback enhancements, UI/UX improvements, performance optimizations, and updated translations for the mobile app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Enhancements&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Favorite Collections Sharing: Enable sharing favorite collections and display the sharer’s name. (@ua741)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New Widgets: Added new widgets for albums and people. You can customise which albums or people you want to see in these widgets as well. (@prateekmedia)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Streamable Video Playback: Play streamable video whenever available and cache video streams for shared files. (@ua741)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Resumable Upload Rollout: Increase gradual rollout for resumable uploads from 20% to 50%. (@ua741)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Multiple Collections: Add files to multiple collections at once. (@ashilkn)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Contacts Performance: Improve performance of the Contacts section. (@ashilkn)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;On This Day Memories: Introduce “On This Day” memories with notifications. (@laurenspriem)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Home &amp;amp; People Widgets: Randomize people and files in the People widget; refine widget settings and layout for empty states. (@ashilkn)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All Albums UI/UX: Revamp the All Albums screen for better UI, UX, and performance. (@AmanRajSinghMourya)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Select multiple albums when you want to add a photo to an album. (@AmanRajSinghMourya)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Participant Flow: Refactor the add participant page for improved usability. (@ashilkn)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Localization &amp;amp; Formatting: Fix date formatting according to device locale. (@ua741)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Bug Fixes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Email Delinking: Enable delinking email from persons without a face. (@ua741)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stream Options: Show switch-stream options for shared video files. (@ua741)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Duration Calculation: Correct duration computation from playlists and handle missing metadata. (@ua741)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Android Video Playback: Switch to original video playback on Android for compatibility. (@ua741)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hide Shared Files: Fix logic to hide both shared and collected files when toggled off. (@ua741)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Upload Cleanup: Clean up origin files after hard upload failures. (@ua741)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Face Detection UI: Display detected faces with lower confidence scores. (@laurenspriem)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reordering Faces: Prevent reordering of selected faces in the People widget. (@ashilkn)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;D2D Backup: Exclude app data during device-to-device backup/transfer. (@lucasmz-dev)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Other&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Download URL Lookup: Refactor download URL resolution logic. (@ua741)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Repaint Optimization: Wrap EnteLoadingWidget with RepaintBoundary to avoid unnecessary repaints. (@ashilkn)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SeekBar UI: Update SeekBar color to backgroundElevatedLight. (@ua741)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Trust Store: Trust the user’s trust store on Android. (@denysvitali)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Translations: New translations added via GitHub Actions. (@github-actions)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;New Contributors&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;@denysvitali made their first contribution in https://github.com/ente-io/ente/pull/5999&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;@lucasmz-dev made their first contribution in https://github.com/ente-io/ente/pull/6028&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Full Changelog&lt;/strong&gt;: https://github.com/ente-io/ente/compare/photos-v1.0.10...photos-v1.1.0&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/ente-io/ente/releases/tag/photos-v1.1.0" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/ente-io/ente/releases/tag/photos-v1.1.53</id>
    <title>New release for Ente Photos: photos-v1.1.53</title>
    <updated>2025-07-03T06:25:38-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>ente-io/ente</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h2&gt;What's Changed&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This release focuses on new features, enhancements and bug fixes, along with updated translations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Features&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Improved Face Recognition:&lt;/strong&gt; See all detected faces, provide feedback on similar faces, and add/remove faces from a single photo.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Autoplay Memories:&lt;/strong&gt; New experience for memories, including autoplay, swipe to next and more.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Birthday Notifications:&lt;/strong&gt; Receive opt-out notifications for all birthdays you have saved on Ente, along with a collection of their best photos.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Background Uploads:&lt;/strong&gt; Introducing background uploads for iOS, in addition to Android&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Resumable Uploads and Downloads:&lt;/strong&gt; All uploads and downloads now have the ability to be paused and resumed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Uploading Large Video Files:&lt;/strong&gt; Increased file size limit to 10GB.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Enhancements&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Album UI:&lt;/strong&gt; Made improvements to the album user interface.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hashing Speed:&lt;/strong&gt; Improved hashing speed by using file streams.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Home Gallery Refresh:&lt;/strong&gt; Reduced home gallery refresh rate during iOS upload/indexing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Streaming:&lt;/strong&gt; Minor fixes and refactoring for streaming.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Download Percentage:&lt;/strong&gt; Now shows download percentage during downloads.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Memories:&lt;/strong&gt; Improved memory notifications and memory updates.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Caching:&lt;/strong&gt; Improved caching for memories and magic search.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;High-Resolution Images:&lt;/strong&gt; Improved handling of high-resolution image rendering.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People Page:&lt;/strong&gt; Added suggestions on the all people page.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Face Thumbnails:&lt;/strong&gt; Refactored face thumbnail processing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Faces UX:&lt;/strong&gt; Made user experience improvements for faces.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Album Creation:&lt;/strong&gt; Trimmed whitespace from new album names.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Search Query:&lt;/strong&gt; Trimmed whitespace from search queries.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scroll Offset:&lt;/strong&gt; Remembers the last scroll offset when adding assets from the device.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Persons Entities:&lt;/strong&gt; Caches persons entities.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Person Avatar:&lt;/strong&gt; Uses cached mapping for person avatars.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;On This Day:&lt;/strong&gt; Lowered requirements for "On This Day" memories.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Widgets:&lt;/strong&gt; Additional fixes for widgets.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Collections:&lt;/strong&gt; Implemented batch operations for collection sheets.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Backup Status:&lt;/strong&gt; The "Waiting for network" status now navigates to Backup Settings.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;File Uploads:&lt;/strong&gt; Removed &lt;code&gt;NativeAdapter&lt;/code&gt; to support larger file uploads.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Bug Fixes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sandbox Files:&lt;/strong&gt; Treats sandbox files as unique during upload.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Translation Error:&lt;/strong&gt; Fixed a build failure due to a translation error.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wakelock:&lt;/strong&gt; Fixed wakelock bugs and ensured wakelock is taken to continue video downloads.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Audio Session Category (iOS):&lt;/strong&gt; Removed the setting of the audio session category on iOS.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Contacts Section:&lt;/strong&gt; Fixed updates to the contacts section on &lt;code&gt;PeopleChangedEvent&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;"Not person" Null Response:&lt;/strong&gt; Fixed null responses for "Not person."&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Splash Screens (iOS Simulator):&lt;/strong&gt; Fixed splash screens getting stuck during development.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Widget Mount:&lt;/strong&gt; Added a missing check for widget mount.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Deletion:&lt;/strong&gt; Fixed various deletion issues.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Memories Update Regression:&lt;/strong&gt; Fixed a regression in memories updates.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Album Links:&lt;/strong&gt; Fixed duplicate page opens for album links.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Album Deselection:&lt;/strong&gt; Fixed deselection of albums with back navigation in the second tab and albums list.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Recommended Filters:&lt;/strong&gt; Fixed recommended filters going blank when calling &lt;code&gt;setState&lt;/code&gt; from different screens.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Memory Animation:&lt;/strong&gt; Handled play/pause animation in memory when the bottom sheet is open.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Widget Display:&lt;/strong&gt; Fixed widget display issues.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Already Linked Email:&lt;/strong&gt; Fixed handling of already linked email errors.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Birthday Notification Timeout:&lt;/strong&gt; Timeout for "on this day" notifications on Android at the end of the day.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ML Consent Bar:&lt;/strong&gt; Fixed incorrectly showing the ML consent bar.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Compute Lock:&lt;/strong&gt; Fixed not requesting compute lock if streaming is disabled.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;OS Specific Device Health:&lt;/strong&gt; Uses OS-specific logic for computing device health.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Local Only Assets:&lt;/strong&gt; Skips hash check for local-only assets.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Public Link Handling:&lt;/strong&gt; Logged event source for public link handling.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Network Error:&lt;/strong&gt; Logged request ID on network errors.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Streaming:&lt;/strong&gt; Fixed streaming issues.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tonemap Logic:&lt;/strong&gt; Uses correct tonemap logic for photos.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;arb&lt;/code&gt; with Multiple Plurals:&lt;/strong&gt; Fixed &lt;code&gt;arb&lt;/code&gt; files with multiple plurals.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Other&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Compute Controller:&lt;/strong&gt; Added a compute controller.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Refactoring:&lt;/strong&gt; Refactored and removed unused methods.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Docs:&lt;/strong&gt; Updated &lt;code&gt;launch.json&lt;/code&gt; in mobile docs to include &lt;code&gt;cronetHttpNoPlay=true&lt;/code&gt; for Android.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Logging:&lt;/strong&gt; Logs whether resource-intensive features are enabled.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;New Translations:&lt;/strong&gt; Includes various new translations for mobile.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;New Contributors&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;@grittypuffy made their first contribution in https://github.com/ente-io/ente/pull/6132&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;@JacquesLucke made their first contribution in https://github.com/ente-io/ente/pull/6148&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;@alewi7 made their first contribution in https://github.com/ente-io/ente/pull/6104&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;@yusufdanis made their first contribution in https://github.com/ente-io/ente/pull/6185&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;@sam-maloney made their first contribution in https://github.com/ente-io/ente/pull/6195&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;@t4ba made their first contribution in https://github.com/ente-io/ente/pull/6196&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;@fco-pires made their first contribution in https://github.com/ente-io/ente/pull/6297&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;@SteamRadionice made their first contribution in https://github.com/ente-io/ente/pull/6329&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;@Sickjuicy made their first contribution in https://github.com/ente-io/ente/pull/6355&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;@lappiesja made their first contribution in https://github.com/ente-io/ente/pull/6393&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;@hlmartin made their first contribution in https://github.com/ente-io/ente/pull/6399&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Full Changelog&lt;/strong&gt;: https://github.com/ente-io/ente/compare/photos-v1.1.0...photos-v1.1.53&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/ente-io/ente/releases/tag/photos-v1.1.53" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/ente-io/ente/releases/tag/photos-v1.1.57</id>
    <title>New release for Ente Photos: photos-v1.1.57</title>
    <updated>2025-07-15T07:39:22-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>ente-io/ente</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h2&gt;What's Changed&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[mob][photos] Fix contact result in search section by @AmanRajSinghMourya in https://github.com/ente-io/ente/pull/6443&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[mob][photos] Better copy for describing why device is not ready for local indexing by @ashilkn in https://github.com/ente-io/ente/pull/6446&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[mob] Fix strings by @vishnukvmd in https://github.com/ente-io/ente/pull/6454&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[mobile] Restructure folders by @ua741 in https://github.com/ente-io/ente/pull/6461&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[mob][photos] Fix share action  by @AmanRajSinghMourya in https://github.com/ente-io/ente/pull/6464&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[mobile] Fix corner smoothing by @AmanRajSinghMourya in https://github.com/ente-io/ente/pull/6500&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[mobile] Fix hero animation for &lt;code&gt;on Ente&lt;/code&gt; section by @AmanRajSinghMourya in https://github.com/ente-io/ente/pull/6499&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[mobile] Fix memory edge cases by @AmanRajSinghMourya in https://github.com/ente-io/ente/pull/6482&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[mob] Fix throttling when multipart is disabled by @ua741 in https://github.com/ente-io/ente/pull/6508&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[mobile] New translations by @github-actions[bot] in https://github.com/ente-io/ente/pull/6338&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[mob] Bump version by @ua741 in https://github.com/ente-io/ente/pull/6510&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[mob][photos] hotfixes by @prateekmedia in https://github.com/ente-io/ente/pull/6511&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[mob][photos] haptic fixes by @prateekmedia in https://github.com/ente-io/ente/pull/6512&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[mob][photos] Fix free up space failing when trying to delete lot of files at one shot by @ashilkn in https://github.com/ente-io/ente/pull/6518&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Full Changelog&lt;/strong&gt;: https://github.com/ente-io/ente/compare/photos-v1.1.53...photos-v1.1.57&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/ente-io/ente/releases/tag/photos-v1.1.57" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
