<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://selfh.st/apps</id>
  <title>FileRun Releases</title>
  <updated>2025-03-22T19:31:42.473153-04:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>selfh.st</name>
    <email>contact@selfh.st</email>
  </author>
  <link href="https://selfh.st/apps" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>Self-hosted software releases generated by selfh.st</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/blakeblackshear/frigate/releases/tag/v0.13.1</id>
    <title>New release for Frigate: 0.13.1 Release</title>
    <updated>2024-01-31T18:34:59-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>blakeblackshear/frigate</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h2&gt;What's Changed&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Quick fix docs by @NickM-27 in https://github.com/blakeblackshear/frigate/pull/9506&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Increase hash map size by @blakeblackshear in https://github.com/blakeblackshear/frigate/pull/9515&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Full Changelog&lt;/strong&gt;: https://github.com/blakeblackshear/frigate/compare/v0.13.0...v0.13.1&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/blakeblackshear/frigate/releases/tag/v0.13.1" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/blakeblackshear/frigate/releases/tag/v0.13.2</id>
    <title>New release for Frigate: 0.13.2 Release</title>
    <updated>2024-02-17T09:54:01-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>blakeblackshear/frigate</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h2&gt;What's Changed&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Update Makefile for 0.13.2 by @NickM-27 in https://github.com/blakeblackshear/frigate/pull/9687&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nms optimize for stationary cars by @NickM-27 in https://github.com/blakeblackshear/frigate/pull/9684&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;More robust onvif handling by @hawkeye217 in https://github.com/blakeblackshear/frigate/pull/9635&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don't fail if message is received before websocket start by @NickM-27 in https://github.com/blakeblackshear/frigate/pull/9634&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Birdseye enhancements by @NickM-27 in https://github.com/blakeblackshear/frigate/pull/9778&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add detailed errors for unsupported label uploading to frigate+ by @Maximo-Guk in https://github.com/blakeblackshear/frigate/pull/9775&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Onvif: skip non-video profiles in setup by @hawkeye217 in https://github.com/blakeblackshear/frigate/pull/9708&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mention that AMD CPUs work just fine with OpenVINO by @svenstaro in https://github.com/blakeblackshear/frigate/pull/9740&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Revise VSCode hostname info in docs by @printplaatreparatie in https://github.com/blakeblackshear/frigate/pull/9709&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Docs: Fix and clarify which /dev/video devices to use with Raspberry Pi by @m-d-brown in https://github.com/blakeblackshear/frigate/pull/9509&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;remove reference to the term credit by @blakeblackshear in https://github.com/blakeblackshear/frigate/pull/9799&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added documentation for time-lapse export (master) by @mike2307 in https://github.com/blakeblackshear/frigate/pull/9804&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;docs: fix links to full configuration reference by @lawm in https://github.com/blakeblackshear/frigate/pull/9808&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix builds by @blakeblackshear in https://github.com/blakeblackshear/frigate/pull/9852&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use zoom space id in Onvif RelativeMove setup by @hawkeye217 in https://github.com/blakeblackshear/frigate/pull/9859&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix birdseye camera comparison by @NickM-27 in https://github.com/blakeblackshear/frigate/pull/9887&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Format by @NickM-27 in https://github.com/blakeblackshear/frigate/pull/9889&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;New Contributors&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;@Maximo-Guk made their first contribution in https://github.com/blakeblackshear/frigate/pull/9775&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;@svenstaro made their first contribution in https://github.com/blakeblackshear/frigate/pull/9740&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;@printplaatreparatie made their first contribution in https://github.com/blakeblackshear/frigate/pull/9709&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;@m-d-brown made their first contribution in https://github.com/blakeblackshear/frigate/pull/9509&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;@mike2307 made their first contribution in https://github.com/blakeblackshear/frigate/pull/9804&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;@lawm made their first contribution in https://github.com/blakeblackshear/frigate/pull/9808&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Full Changelog&lt;/strong&gt;: https://github.com/blakeblackshear/frigate/compare/v0.13.1...v0.13.2&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/blakeblackshear/frigate/releases/tag/v0.13.2" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/blakeblackshear/frigate/releases/tag/v0.14.0</id>
    <title>New release for Frigate: 0.14.0 Release</title>
    <updated>2024-08-08T09:18:42-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>blakeblackshear/frigate</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h2&gt;Images&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;ghcr.io/blakeblackshear/frigate:0.14.0&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;ghcr.io/blakeblackshear/frigate:0.14.0-standard-arm64&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;ghcr.io/blakeblackshear/frigate:0.14.0-tensorrt&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;ghcr.io/blakeblackshear/frigate:0.14.0-tensorrt-jp4&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;ghcr.io/blakeblackshear/frigate:0.14.0-tensorrt-jp5&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;ghcr.io/blakeblackshear/frigate:0.14.0-rk&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Changes since RC2&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;None&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Major Changes for 0.14.0&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Breaking Changes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are several breaking changes in this release, Frigate will attempt to update the configuration automatically. In some cases manual changes may be required. It is always recommended to &lt;strong&gt;backup your current config and database&lt;/strong&gt; before upgrading:
- Simply copy your current config file to a new location
- Stop Frigate and make a copy of the &lt;code&gt;frigate.db&lt;/code&gt; file&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Your existing events will not be visible in Frigate's new UI&lt;/strong&gt;
- An entirely new way of reviewing camera footage has been implemented in Frigate 0.14, and existing events could not be migrated
- Recordings can still be viewed in the new UI using the recordings viewer (From Live view, click/tap on a camera and select the &lt;em&gt;History&lt;/em&gt; button at the top left)
- You may want to export any starred/favorite events before upgrading
- If you are using the Home Assistant integration, events can still be viewed there
- Recording (&lt;code&gt;enabled: True&lt;/code&gt; for &lt;code&gt;record&lt;/code&gt; in your config) is required to see review items and motion data in the UI&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Zone/mask coordinates are now stored in the config as relative values&lt;/strong&gt;
- Frigate's configuration migrator will read your existing mask/zone coordinates and convert them for relative use internally on startup
- Using the built-in mask/zone editor will make your config file incompatible with prior versions of Frigate
- If you have mask/zone coordinate values that exceed the detect resolution, it will be ignored and you will see warnings in the log. Delete the mask or zone from your config and then use the editor in the UI to recreate it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The UI's live mode is now intelligently selected&lt;/strong&gt;
- The &lt;code&gt;live_mode&lt;/code&gt; config option is now deprecated and should be removed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Backwards incompatible database changes&lt;/strong&gt;
- There are a number of changes made to Frigate's database, which are not backwards compatible. A backup of the database is automatically made on startup, but &lt;strong&gt;a manual backup is highly recommended&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Other breaking changes&lt;/strong&gt;
- RTMP was deprecated in 0.13 and has been fully removed in 0.14. You will need to remove any &lt;code&gt;rtmp&lt;/code&gt; references in your config file.
- OpenVINO has been upgraded, and Intel Neural Compute sticks are no longer supported. Support for YOLO-NAS models has been added. Additionally, &lt;code&gt;AUTO&lt;/code&gt; mode now maps to &lt;code&gt;GPU&lt;/code&gt; internally to avoid some unresolved issues with &lt;code&gt;AUTO&lt;/code&gt;. The existing &lt;code&gt;YOLO-X&lt;/code&gt; model will not work in this version.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Brand New UI&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Frigate 0.14's UI has been completely rewritten (&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=iJa3dNEO5qQ"&gt;helpful walkthrough video from a user&lt;/a&gt;) and optimized for desktop and mobile devices, aiming to simplify the user experience by focusing on two specific goals:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Allow you to quickly see what's currently happening or what just happened on your cameras&lt;/strong&gt;. The new Live view features a real-time dashboard with live camera feeds and a filmstrip of animated thumbnails showing recent activity.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Make reviewing video footage more efficient&lt;/strong&gt;. Frigate intelligently identifies parts of your timeline for review by leveraging the underlying data about motion and tracked objects. The new Review area implements a scrollable grid of thumbnails alongside a timeline where a hover or swipe begins a preview playback. Review items can be configured to be pre-categorized into &lt;em&gt;alerts&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;detections&lt;/em&gt; based on cameras and/or zones. The review area also provides a motion review mode, allowing real-time scrubbing of video footage for any objects of interest that Frigate may have missed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Frigate 0.14's UI will likely change the way you review your camera footage. It's a big change, but we love it and hope you do too. See &lt;a href="https://github.com/blakeblackshear/frigate/discussions/11136"&gt;the announcement post&lt;/a&gt; for more information regarding the motivation, ideas, and design decisions behind the new UI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Dashboard&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new home page for Frigate is intended to be a real-time dashboard for your cameras. Recent alerts are represented by animated thumbnails in a filmstrip view above your camera feeds. Your camera images update once per minute when no detectable activity is occurring to conserve bandwidth and resources. As soon as any motion is detected, cameras seamlessly switch to a full-resolution live stream. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Custom camera groups are now supported. Add any of your cameras (including the Birdseye camera) to user-definable groups and easily toggle between them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;On desktops and tablets, cameras in a camera group can be resized and rearranged via dragging.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Screen Shot 2024-05-18 at 18 00 22 PM" src="https://github.com/blakeblackshear/frigate/assets/14866235/b4248c21-9f1b-49f8-8b14-f5fb44c6163c" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Live View&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clicking a camera from the dashboard will bring up a full-resolution live view where you can quickly access historical footage, use PTZ controls, toggle camera audio, use two-way talk, and more. Zooming with pinch or a scroll wheel is also supported.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Screen Shot 2024-05-18 at 18 02 30 PM" src="https://github.com/blakeblackshear/frigate/assets/14866235/ac4609d0-6cce-4cdf-b366-0d6a1b0d0230" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Review&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Review area of Frigate 0.14 is for quickly reviewing historical footage of interest from your cameras. Review items are indicated on a vertical timeline and displayed as a grid of &lt;em&gt;previews&lt;/em&gt; - bandwidth-optimized, low frame rate, low resolution videos. Hovering over or swiping a preview plays the video and marks it as reviewed. If more in-depth analysis is required, the preview can be clicked/tapped and the full frame rate, full resolution recording is displayed. Review items are filterable by date, object type, and camera.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Screen Shot 2024-05-18 at 18 01 12 PM" src="https://github.com/blakeblackshear/frigate/assets/14866235/e40e1352-07f0-435c-a9b0-fdbaa60629bf" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Alerts and Detections&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not every segment of video captured by Frigate may be of the same level of interest to you. Video of people who enter your property are a different priority than those walking by on the sidewalk. For this reason, Frigate 0.14 categorizes review items as &lt;em&gt;alerts&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;detections&lt;/em&gt;. By default, all &lt;em&gt;person&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;car&lt;/em&gt; objects are considered alerts. You can refine categorization of your review items by configuring required zones for them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See the &lt;a href="https://docs.frigate.video/configuration/review"&gt;review docs for more information&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Motion review&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Frigate 0.13, there isn’t a way to see motion activity on a timeline and watch video at that time. The ability to scrub video for things Frigate missed has been one of the most common feature requests. Within the Motion tab of the Review section, you can now scrub through the timeline for all cameras simultaneously with a timeline showing relative motion activity. In order to avoid scrubbing over time periods already included in alerts and detections, you can also scrub in motion only mode.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="https://github.com/blakeblackshear/frigate/assets/569905/a21a16b1-f8d2-4af9-beb7-6d17c49cccaa" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;History&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Frigate 0.14, full frame rate, full resolution camera footage (called "recordings" in earlier versions) can be viewed and scrubbed via a timeline. Previews of your other cameras are displayed and scrubbed alongside the main selected camera.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Exporting footage from the History view has been drastically improved. Choose predefined time periods, enter a time directly, or drag handles on the timeline to select an export range.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Past exports can be viewed, renamed, deleted, and downloaded from the dedicated Export pane, accessible from the navigation bar.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Other Notable UI Changes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;System stats&lt;/strong&gt; - New charts and graphs with colored segments to track system usage history and more quickly identify problems or issues.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Status bar&lt;/strong&gt; - A new status bar gives at-a-glance CPU/GPU usage as well as any problems or issues with Frigate.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;New log viewer&lt;/strong&gt; - The log viewer now provides a pane with links to solutions for common issues.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Real-time motion tuning&lt;/strong&gt; - Tune motion detection settings for your cameras without editing your config file and restarting. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;New mask and zone editor&lt;/strong&gt; - Edit your masks and zones with a much-improved editor. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Authentication&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Frigate now supports authentication. Frigate manages users and authentication using JWT tokens via a cookie or authorization header. Additionally, a new proxy section in the config allows you to use the user header passed from common authentication proxies such as authelia, authentik, oauth2_proxy, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Authentication is enforced on a new port 8971, and port 5000 is still unauthenticated for backwards compatibility. If you want to use Frigate's authentication, update your reverse proxy to point at port 8971 instead of 5000.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Support for role based authorization (admin/user roles) will come in a future release and will support upstream authentication proxies.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Home Assistant integration needs to be pointed at port 5000. Some recommended configuration examples are in the &lt;a href="https://docs.frigate.video/integrations/home-assistant#configuration"&gt;updated docs&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See &lt;a href="https://docs.frigate.video/configuration/authentication"&gt;the documentation for more information.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;TLS&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since Authentication should really be used over secure connections, TLS is also enabled by default for port 8971. It can be disabled in the config file with the following yaml:
&lt;code&gt;yaml
tls:
  enabled: False&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Custom certificates can also be used following the &lt;a href="https://docs.frigate.video/configuration/tls"&gt;tls docs&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Frigate+&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Frigate 0.14 now offers a dedicated page for Frigate+ submissions, allowing more specific filtering by score and a faster workflow. Support has also been added to upload frames directly from the History view.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Other notable improvements&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Loitering Time&lt;/strong&gt; - Zones now support a &lt;code&gt;loitering_time&lt;/code&gt; configuration which can be used to only consider an object as part of a zone if they loiter for the specified number of seconds. This can be used, for example, to create alerts for cars that stop on the street but not cars that just drive past your camera.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Two-way talk&lt;/strong&gt; - For supported cameras, two-way talk can be used directly from a camera's live view.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PWA-optimized&lt;/strong&gt; - The UI has been optimized to work as a progressive web app. Pin Frigate to your iOS home screen or install on Android for a full app-like experience.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rockchip boards now support object detection&lt;/strong&gt; -  See &lt;a href="https://docs.frigate.video/configuration/object_detectors/#rockchip-platform"&gt;the Rockchip documentation&lt;/a&gt; for more information.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Automatic hardware acceleration&lt;/strong&gt; - automatic detection and configuration of hardware acceleration for ffmpeg is attempted on startup&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;New review related MQTT topics and API endpoints&lt;/strong&gt; - New MQTT topics and api endpoints are available for reviews. These will likely be a better topic for notifications.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Fixes and changes&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Better ONVIF support - PTZ controls will now show for more ONVIF PTZ cameras&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use ZMQ for interprocess communication&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;hwaccel_args are now automatically detected for Nvidia, AMD, and Intel based systems.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stationary object detection has been improved especially for parked cars.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Additional support for IPV6&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RTMP has been removed (after previous deprecation). This is handled by the automatic config migration upon upgrade.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;FAQ&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have a question that's not answered here? Look at the most updated list of FAQs &lt;a href="https://github.com/blakeblackshear/frigate/discussions/12724"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="https://github.com/blakeblackshear/frigate/discussions"&gt;open a discussion&lt;/a&gt; on Github.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Upgrade issues&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I'm seeing "add mask expects relative coordinates only" in my logs.&lt;/strong&gt; 
This is usually caused by a mask or zone having coordinates larger than the camera's &lt;code&gt;detect&lt;/code&gt; resolution. The easiest fix would be to remove the mask/zone, restart Frigate, and use the new mask/zone editor to recreate it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What happened to all my events?&lt;/strong&gt;
An entirely new way of reviewing camera footage has been implemented in Frigate 0.14, so any "events" from any previous versions of Frigate will not be migrated and will not be visible in the new UI. This includes any favorited/starred events. Recordings can still be viewed in the new UI using the recordings viewer (From Live view, click/tap on a camera and select the &lt;em&gt;History&lt;/em&gt; button at the top left).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I'm seeing "Preview Not Found" in the UI a lot. Why?&lt;/strong&gt;
Frigate 0.14 now generates "previews": bandwidth-optimized, low frame rate, low resolution videos for your camera footage. These previews are not generated for any footage from older versions of Frigate. Historical full recordings are still viewable from your cameras, however. From Live view, click/tap on a camera and select the &lt;em&gt;History&lt;/em&gt; button at the top left.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Usage&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Are there any tutorials or videos on how to use the new version?&lt;/strong&gt;
Yes, see the &lt;a href="https://app.supademo.com/showcase/clvi4jyof0kpfh7gr9921vsb7"&gt;guided demo&lt;/a&gt; and a &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=iJa3dNEO5qQ"&gt;helpful walkthrough video from a user&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Can I make the cameras take up more space on my dashboard?&lt;/strong&gt;
Yes you can, on desktop screens only. Create a camera group, and then use the edit layout button (bottom right) to resize/reposition your cameras on the dashboard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Where is Birdseye view in the new UI?&lt;/strong&gt;
Birdseye is accessible by creating a camera group and adding the Birdseye camera to the camera group. Birdseye is also accessible by navigating directly to &lt;code&gt;frigate_ip:port/#birdseye&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why are there black bars and empty space around my cameras in the new Live dashboard?&lt;/strong&gt;
Cameras are kept in a standard 16x9 aspect ratio grid layout. If your camera's aspect ratio is not 16x9 (or a multiple of 16x9 like a wide angle 32x9), black bars may appear on any of the sides of the camera image. One solution would be to adjust your camera's resolution in firmware to fit any multiple of the 16x9 aspect ratio. You could also use Birdseye, which is Frigate's solution for an automatic live view layout without black bars. See the &lt;a href="https://docs.frigate.video/configuration/birdseye#birdseye-layout"&gt;Birdseye docs&lt;/a&gt; for ways to configure Birdseye's resolution, aspect ratio, and layout preferences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It doesn't seem like my cameras are streaming on the Live dashboard. Why?&lt;/strong&gt;
On the Live dashboard, your camera images will update once per minute when no detectable activity is occurring to conserve bandwidth and resources. As soon as any motion is detected, cameras seamlessly switch to a full-resolution live stream.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Can I export footage from the review screen?&lt;/strong&gt;
Yes, right click (desktop) or long press (mobile) to choose item(s) you want to export, then press the export button in the header.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What happened to the timelapse export feature?&lt;/strong&gt;
It's not in the UI, but the API is still available. Most users were using that feature to create videos to manually review each day. One of the main focuses of the new UI was to ensure that isn't necessary. The only remaining use cases we are aware of are for very long periods of time. Having frigate do long exports on high resolution recordings on the server is a really inefficient way to accomplish that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How can I view snapshots with bounding boxes?&lt;/strong&gt;
Snapshots have been deprecated in favor of the new review item format. To understand why, consider the situation where two people, one with a dog, walked past your house. At the same time, a car drove by on the street behind them. In this scenario, Frigate would have tracked 4 "events". One for each person, the dog, and the car. In 0.13, you would have had 4 separate videos to watch, even though they would have all overlapped. In 0.14, these separate objects are combined into a single review item which represents the period in time where these objects were active on the camera. Reviews for a single camera cannot overlap. Displaying separate snapshots for this scenario in a way that shows they are connected is not only difficult, but also less helpful than having a combined thumbnail and easy to view video preview that quickly shows what exactly happened. Even though snapshots are no longer available in the 0.14 UI review pipeline, they are still available in the Frigate+ view, on the filesystem, and viewable through Home Assistant's media browser. A screen to help debug review items and answer the question "why was this review item created?" will be coming in a future version (feature request is &lt;a href="https://github.com/blakeblackshear/frigate/issues/11399"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How can I tune what I see in alerts and detections?&lt;/strong&gt;
You can restrict alerts and detections to specific objects/labels or exclude a camera entirely. See the &lt;a href="https://docs.frigate.video/configuration/review"&gt;review docs&lt;/a&gt;. You can also restrict alerts and detections to objects entering zones. The Camera Settings screen in the UI provides a lot of granular control. See the &lt;a href="https://docs.frigate.video/configuration/zones#restricting-alerts-and-detections-to-specific-zones"&gt;zone docs&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How can I switch the live view type?&lt;/strong&gt;
In Frigate 0.13, a dropdown menu in the UI allowed users to select between jsmpeg, MSE, or WebRTC. In 0.14, Frigate intelligently selects the best type of live view method for the cameras on your dashboard based on network conditions and features, so this is no longer user selectable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Can I "star" or "favorite" events like in 0.13?&lt;/strong&gt;
No, that feature has been removed in 0.14 in favor of Exports. If you have footage you'd like to "favorite" or retain in 0.14, use the export tools. Unlike favorite events in 0.13, exported footage in 0.14 can be given a label/name and is searchable from the Exports page. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Are there any keyboard shortcuts in the UI for desktop devices?&lt;/strong&gt;
Yes. In the Review pane, Ctrl/Cmd-A selects all of your review items. On Live camera view, you can use the arrow keys along with + and - to control a PTZ camera. In the Logs view, page up/page down and arrow up/arrow down will scroll the logs. Wherever video controls appear (History view, Motion Review), the left and right arrows will seek the video backwards and forwards by 10 seconds. The up and down arrow keys will seek the video by 1 second. The "f" key toggles fullscreen, "m" toggles muting, and the space bar toggles playback/pause. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have a question that's not answered here? &lt;a href="https://github.com/blakeblackshear/frigate/discussions"&gt;Open a discussion&lt;/a&gt; on Github.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Full Changelog&lt;/strong&gt;: https://github.com/blakeblackshear/frigate/compare/v0.13.2...v0.14.0&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/blakeblackshear/frigate/releases/tag/v0.14.0" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/blakeblackshear/frigate/releases/tag/v0.14.1</id>
    <title>New release for Frigate: 0.14.1 Release</title>
    <updated>2024-08-29T18:32:51-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>blakeblackshear/frigate</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h2&gt;Images&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/blakeblackshear/frigate/pkgs/container/frigate/264807004?tag=0.14.1"&gt;ghcr.io/blakeblackshear/frigate:0.14.1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/blakeblackshear/frigate/pkgs/container/frigate/264798475?tag=0.14.1-standard-arm64"&gt;ghcr.io/blakeblackshear/frigate:0.14.1-standard-arm64&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/blakeblackshear/frigate/pkgs/container/frigate/264802776?tag=0.14.1-tensorrt"&gt;ghcr.io/blakeblackshear/frigate:0.14.1-tensorrt&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/blakeblackshear/frigate/pkgs/container/frigate/264799894?tag=0.14.1-tensorrt-jp4"&gt;ghcr.io/blakeblackshear/frigate:0.14.1-tensorrt-jp4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/blakeblackshear/frigate/pkgs/container/frigate/264799401?tag=0.14.1-tensorrt-jp5"&gt;ghcr.io/blakeblackshear/frigate:0.14.1-tensorrt-jp5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/blakeblackshear/frigate/pkgs/container/frigate/264806818?tag=0.14.1-rk"&gt;ghcr.io/blakeblackshear/frigate:0.14.1-rk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a maintenance release for Frigate 0.14 that includes bugfixes as well as performance and stability improvements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What's Changed&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix auth when serving Frigate at a subpath (https://github.com/blakeblackshear/frigate/pull/12815)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix iOS export buttons (https://github.com/blakeblackshear/frigate/pull/12755)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ensure review cameras are sorted by config UI order if specified (https://github.com/blakeblackshear/frigate/pull/12789)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix default model for rknn detector (https://github.com/blakeblackshear/frigate/pull/12807)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add button to mark alert as reviewed in filmstrip (https://github.com/blakeblackshear/frigate/pull/12878)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add confirmation dialog before deleting review items (https://github.com/blakeblackshear/frigate/pull/12950)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix manual events (https://github.com/blakeblackshear/frigate/pull/12951)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add pan/pinch/zoom capability on Frigate+ view snapshots (https://github.com/blakeblackshear/frigate/pull/12953)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hide recording button when disabled in config (https://github.com/blakeblackshear/frigate/pull/12997)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Recordings view fixes (https://github.com/blakeblackshear/frigate/pull/13005)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix missing last hour preview in recordings view (https://github.com/blakeblackshear/frigate/pull/13027)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix export name and NaN showing in Frigate+ slider (https://github.com/blakeblackshear/frigate/pull/13030)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Prevent error when github sends bad data (https://github.com/blakeblackshear/frigate/pull/13077)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add shortcut key "r" to mark items as reviewed in Review pane (https://github.com/blakeblackshear/frigate/pull/13087)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix Frigate+ view from inadvertently reloading (https://github.com/blakeblackshear/frigate/pull/13160)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix live player from getting stuck while loading streams and from lagging behind in poor network conditions (https://github.com/blakeblackshear/frigate/pull/13143)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ensure previews that are generated late are not falsely excluded (https://github.com/blakeblackshear/frigate/pull/13193)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ensure only enabled birdseye cameras are considered active (https://github.com/blakeblackshear/frigate/pull/13194)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;UI fixes (https://github.com/blakeblackshear/frigate/pull/13246)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix cgroup detecting 0 cpu cores (https://github.com/blakeblackshear/frigate/pull/13271)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add tooltip for icons in review event list (https://github.com/blakeblackshear/frigate/pull/13334)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don't allow periods in zone or camera group names (https://github.com/blakeblackshear/frigate/pull/13400)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add portal to the live player tooltip (https://github.com/blakeblackshear/frigate/pull/13389)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/blakeblackshear/frigate/releases/tag/v0.14.1" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/blakeblackshear/frigate/releases/tag/v0.15.0</id>
    <title>New release for Frigate: 0.15.0 Release</title>
    <updated>2025-02-08T13:45:30-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>blakeblackshear/frigate</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h2&gt;Images&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/blakeblackshear/frigate/pkgs/container/frigate/346561789?tag=0.15.0"&gt;ghcr.io/blakeblackshear/frigate:0.15.0&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/blakeblackshear/frigate/pkgs/container/frigate/346560162?tag=0.15.0-standard-arm64"&gt;ghcr.io/blakeblackshear/frigate:0.15.0-standard-arm64&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/blakeblackshear/frigate/pkgs/container/frigate/346563665?tag=0.15.0-tensorrt"&gt;ghcr.io/blakeblackshear/frigate:0.15.0-tensorrt&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/blakeblackshear/frigate/pkgs/container/frigate/346560753?tag=0.15.0-tensorrt-jp4"&gt;ghcr.io/blakeblackshear/frigate:0.15.0-tensorrt-jp4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/blakeblackshear/frigate/pkgs/container/frigate/346561586?tag=0.15.0-tensorrt-jp5"&gt;ghcr.io/blakeblackshear/frigate:0.15.0-tensorrt-jp5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/blakeblackshear/frigate/pkgs/container/frigate/346580730?tag=0.15.0-rk"&gt;ghcr.io/blakeblackshear/frigate:0.15.0-rk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/blakeblackshear/frigate/pkgs/container/frigate/346567043?tag=0.15.0-rocm"&gt;ghcr.io/blakeblackshear/frigate:0.15.0-rocm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/blakeblackshear/frigate/pkgs/container/frigate/346562983?tag=0.15.0-h8l"&gt;ghcr.io/blakeblackshear/frigate:0.15.0-h8l&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Changes since RC2&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;None&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Major Changes for 0.15.0&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Breaking Changes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are several breaking changes in this release, Frigate will attempt to update the configuration automatically. In some cases manual changes may be required. It is always recommended to &lt;strong&gt;back up your current config and database&lt;/strong&gt; before upgrading:
1. Simply copy your current config file to a new location
2. Stop Frigate and make a copy of the &lt;code&gt;frigate.db&lt;/code&gt; file&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rewritten SHM system&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The SHM system has been rewritten to be more stable. This means that a large % of shared memory (SHM) will be used by default but the total usage will not fluctuate, and Frigate will not fail from SHM overflowing. However, this also means that having the correct SHM size for your cameras, detector, and hardware is more important to having a smooth experience with Frigate. A new calculation is done on startup, so if your &lt;code&gt;shm_size&lt;/code&gt; is too low then a warning will be printed in the log stating that it needs to be increased. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Recording configuration changed&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;code&gt;record&lt;/code&gt; config has been refactored to allow for direct control of how long &lt;code&gt;alerts&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;detections&lt;/code&gt; are retained. These values will be automatically populated from your current config, but you may want to adjust the values that are set after updating. See the updated docs &lt;a href="https://docs.frigate.video/configuration/record"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and ensure your updated config retains the footage you want it to.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ffmpeg updates&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ffmpeg has been updated to version 7. Some Intel users may need to change what &lt;code&gt;hwaccel&lt;/code&gt; preset they are using (&lt;code&gt;preset-vaapi&lt;/code&gt; may need to now be &lt;code&gt;preset-intel-qsv-h264&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;preset-intel-qsv-h265&lt;/code&gt;) if camera feeds are not functioning correctly after upgrading. This may need to be adjusted on a per-camera basis. If a &lt;code&gt;qsv&lt;/code&gt; preset is not working properly, you may still need to use a &lt;code&gt;preset-vaapi&lt;/code&gt; or revert to the previous ffmpeg version as described below.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The new version provides many improvements, but the old version can still be run if needed by specifying &lt;code&gt;path: "5.0"&lt;/code&gt; in your &lt;code&gt;ffmpeg:&lt;/code&gt; config entry. For example:
    &lt;code&gt;ffmpeg:
      path: "5.0"&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ffmpeg presets have been updated. It is always recommended to use &lt;a href="https://docs.frigate.video/configuration/ffmpeg_presets/"&gt;ffmpeg presets&lt;/a&gt; rather than manual arguments.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;ffmpeg&lt;/code&gt; is no longer part of &lt;code&gt;$PATH&lt;/code&gt;. In most cases this is handled automatically.&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;go2rtc &lt;code&gt;exec&lt;/code&gt; streams will need to add the full path for ffmpeg which in most cases will be &lt;code&gt;/usr/lib/ffmpeg/7.0/bin/ffmpeg&lt;/code&gt;. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If the go2rtc config has &lt;code&gt;bin: ffmpeg&lt;/code&gt; defined, it needs to be removed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The nested &lt;code&gt;model&lt;/code&gt; config under a &lt;code&gt;detector&lt;/code&gt; has been simplified to just &lt;code&gt;model_path&lt;/code&gt; as a string value. This change will be handled automatically through config migration.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Submitting to Frigate+&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Frigate+ view in the UI has been replaced by the new Explore view. See the notes below.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Explore&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new Explore pane in Frigate 0.15 makes it easy to explore every object tracked by Frigate. It offers a variety of filters and supports keyword and phrase-based text search, searching for similar images, and searching through descriptive text generated by AI models.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The default Explore pane shows a summary of your most recent tracked objects organized by label. Clicking the small arrow icon at the end of the list will bring you to an infinitely scrolling grid view. The grid view can also be set as the default by changing the view type from the Settings button in the top right corner of the pane.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Explore pane also serves as the new way to submit images to Frigate+. Filters can be applied to only display tracked objects with snapshots that have not been submitted to Frigate+. The left/right arrow keys on the keyboard allow quick navigation between tracked object snapshots when looking at the Tracked Object Details pane from the grid view.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;AI/ML Search&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Frigate 0.15 introduces two powerful search features: Semantic Search and GenAI Search. Semantic Search can be enabled on its own, while GenAI Search works in addition to Semantic Search.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Semantic Search&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Semantic Search uses a CLIP model to generate embeddings (numerical representations of images) for the thumbnails of your tracked objects, enabling searches based on text descriptions or visual similarity. This is all done locally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For instance, if Frigate detects and tracks a car, you can use similarity search to see other instances where Frigate detected and tracked that same car. You can also quickly search your tracked objects using an "image caption" approach. Searching for "red car driving on a residential street" or "person in a blue shirt walking on the sidewalk at dawn" or even "a person wearing a black t-shirt with the word 'SPORT' on it" will produce some stunning results. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Semantic Search works by running an AI model locally on your system. Small or underpowered systems like a Raspberry Pi will not run Semantic Search reliably or at all. A dedicated GPU and 16GB of RAM is recommended for best performance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See the &lt;a href="https://docs.frigate.video/configuration/semantic_search"&gt;Semantic Search docs&lt;/a&gt; for system requirements, setup instructions, and usage tips.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Screen Shot 2024-10-15 at 07 38 16 AM" src="https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/34272304-179f-4154-a57c-b5f5bf6a8797" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Generative AI&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GenAI Search employs generative AI models to create descriptive text for the thumbnails of your tracked objects, which are stored in the Frigate database to enhance future searches. Supported providers include Google Gemini, Ollama, and OpenAI, so you can choose whether you want to send data to the cloud or use a locally hosted provider.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See the &lt;a href="https://docs.frigate.video/configuration/genai"&gt;GenAI docs&lt;/a&gt; for setup instructions and use case suggestions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Improved Tools for Debugging&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Review Item Details Pane&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A new Review Item Details pane can be viewed by clicking / tapping on the gray chip on a review item in the Review pane. This shows more information about the review item as well as thumbnails or snapshots for individual objects (if enabled). The pane also provides links to share the review item, download it, submit images to Frigate+, view object lifecycles, and more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/4b32f163-e60d-49b4-834f-17f6aec09282" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Object Lifecycle Pane&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Recordings Timeline from Frigate 0.13 has been improved upon and returns to 0.15 as the &lt;code&gt;Object Lifecycle&lt;/code&gt;, viewable in the Review Details pane as well as the new Explore page. The new pane shows the significant moments during the object's lifecycle: when it was first seen, when it entered a zone, became stationary, etc. It also provides information about the object's area and size ratio to assist in configuring Frigate to tune out false positives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/8e5f9dbb-869f-41ea-8962-2dd609719a7e" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Native Notifications&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Frigate now supports notifications using the &lt;a href="https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/API/Push_API"&gt;WebPush&lt;/a&gt; protocol. This allows Frigate to deliver notifications to devices that have registered to receive notifications in the Frigate settings, delivering them in a timely and secure manner. Currently, notifications will be delivered for all review items marked as alerts. More options for native notifications will be supported in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/7a30feb7-6e37-45ff-bb06-ab36ea93b505" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See the &lt;a href="https://docs.frigate.video/configuration/notifications"&gt;notifications docs&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;New Object Detectors&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;ONNX&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ONNX is an open model standard which allows for a single model format that can run on different types of GPUs. The &lt;code&gt;default&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;tensorrt&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code&gt;rocm&lt;/code&gt; Frigate build variants include GPU support for efficient object detection via ONNX models, simplifying configuration and support more models. There are no default included ONNX models for object detection. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;AMD MiGraphX&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Support has been added for AMD GPUs via ROCm and MiGraphX. Currently there is no default included model for this detector. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Hailo-8&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Support has been added for the &lt;a href="https://hailo.ai/products/ai-accelerators/hailo-8-ai-accelerator/"&gt;Hailo8&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://hailo.ai/products/ai-accelerators/hailo-8l-ai-accelerator-for-ai-light-applications/"&gt;Hailo-8L&lt;/a&gt; hardware for object detection on both arm64 and amd64 platforms. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Other UI Changes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rework the Storage metrics pane to be more clear how much storage each camera is using&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Camera stream info button has been added to the camera metrics page allowing easy access to see camera codec information&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add button for downloading the full set of logs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The timeline handlebar will now automatically scroll while viewing recordings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Review items and exports can now be shared via your browser's sharing pane or via direct link url. A secure context is required for the browser/OS sharing pane to function&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add the ability to rename camera groups&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add middle mouse button support in the Review pane to open full recordings view in a new tab&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add Nvidia GPU encode and decode stats to system metrics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New desktop keyboard shortcuts. In addition to the numerous keyboard shortcuts available with 0.14, 0.15 adds several more. In Live view, the numeric keys (1-9) will move PTZ cameras to presets. In Review, Page Up and Page Down will scroll through review items&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Accessibility updates for users with screen readers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Other Backend Changes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;FFMPEG updated to 7.0&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;OpenVINO updated to 2024.3&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use FastAPI instead of Flask for the Frigate API&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add service manager infrastructure&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Install onevpl tools and update drivers for Intel&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If record is disabled for a camera then that camera will not save frames to the preview during that time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix stalled connections to certain onvif cameras&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix autotracking absolute zoom interpolation logic&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;TensorRT models are no longer generated by default, the ENV var must be set&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Full Changelog&lt;/strong&gt;: https://github.com/blakeblackshear/frigate/compare/v0.14.1...v0.15.0&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/blakeblackshear/frigate/releases/tag/v0.15.0" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
