<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://selfh.st/apps</id>
  <title>GoatCounter Releases</title>
  <updated>2025-07-12T05:36:31.979948-04:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>selfh.st</name>
    <email>contact@selfh.st</email>
  </author>
  <link href="https://selfh.st/apps" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>Self-hosted software releases generated by selfh.st</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/arp242/goatcounter/releases/tag/v2.3.0</id>
    <title>New release for GoatCounter: v2.3.0</title>
    <updated>2022-10-17T07:47:54-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>arp242/goatcounter</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h2&gt;2022-10-17 v2.3.0&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Expand campaigns: the &lt;code&gt;utm_campaign&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;campaign&lt;/code&gt; parameter now is tracked separately, and add a dashboard panel for campaigns. See: https://www.goatcounter.com/help/campaigns&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Old data isn't backfilled as this information wasn't stored.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are now binaries for Windows, macOS, {Free,Open}BSD, and illumos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WebSockets are now disabled by default, as it turned out a lot of people had trouble proxying them. You can enable it with &lt;code&gt;goatcounter serve -websocket&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Add &lt;code&gt;-dbconn&lt;/code&gt; flag for &lt;code&gt;serve&lt;/code&gt; to allow setting the maximum number of connections. The default is also lowered from 25 to 16 for PostgreSQL.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Add &lt;code&gt;-store-every&lt;/code&gt; flag to control how often to persist pageviews to the database.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Add "Sites that can embed GoatCounter" setting to allow embedding GoatCounter in a frame.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Add "Hide UI for public view" setting to allow hiding the UI chrome and display only the charts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quite a few bugfixes and minor additions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/arp242/goatcounter/releases/tag/v2.3.0" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/arp242/goatcounter/releases/tag/v2.4.0</id>
    <title>New release for GoatCounter: v2.4.0</title>
    <updated>2022-11-08T17:22:02-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>arp242/goatcounter</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add a more fully-featured API that can also retrieve the dashboard statistics. See https://www.goatcounter.com/help/api for documentation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is still as "v0" because some details may still change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Default API ratelimit is now 4 requests/second, rather than 4 requests/10 seconds. You can use the &lt;code&gt;-ratelimit&lt;/code&gt; flag to configure this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Can now also merge paths instead of just deleting them (the "Settings → Delete pageviews" tab was changed to "Manage pageviews").&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Add &lt;code&gt;goatcounter dashboard&lt;/code&gt;, which uses the new API to display the dashboard in the terminal (only a basic non-interactive overview for now).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Add a "Show fewer numbers" user setting; this is intended to still give a reasonably useful overview of what happens on your site but prevent an “obsession” over the exact number of visitors and stats.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No longer store or display "pageviews": always store and display "visitors" instead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The visitor count is the only thing that's interesting in pretty much all cases; the "raw" pageviews are still stored for some future purposes (such as "time on page"), but are no longer stored in most other contexts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add infrastructure for "dark mode".&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is not yet enabled by default because all "dark mode" themes look "bad" on my eyes, and I'm not really sure what works well for people who do like it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So some help is needed here. See: https://github.com/arp242/goatcounter/issues/586#issuecomment-1287995673&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/arp242/goatcounter/releases/tag/v2.4.0" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/arp242/goatcounter/releases/tag/v2.4.1</id>
    <title>New release for GoatCounter: v2.4.1</title>
    <updated>2022-11-15T18:44:23-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>arp242/goatcounter</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix regression that caused the charts for SQLite to be off.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/arp242/goatcounter/releases/tag/v2.4.1" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/arp242/goatcounter/releases/tag/v2.5.0</id>
    <title>New release for GoatCounter: v2.5.0</title>
    <updated>2023-12-13T21:58:03-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>arp242/goatcounter</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;This release requires Go 1.21.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Features:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Quite a few tables are rewritten to a more efficient format. For small to medium instances this will take a few minutes at the most, but if you have very large instances this may take a few hours. It also requires enough free disk space to rewrite the &lt;code&gt;hits&lt;/code&gt; table.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to run steps manually then you can view the migration with:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;  % goatcounter db migrate -show 2023-05-16-1-hits
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or if you use PostgreSQL:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;  % goatcounter db migrate -show -db postgresql+dbname=goatcounter 2023-05-16-1-hits
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;User-Agent&lt;/code&gt; header is no longer stored; only the browser and system parsed out of there. It's pretty reliable, and especially mobile browser User-Agents are ridiculously unique. It was always stored only "in case the detection got it horribly wrong", but this has never been needed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Add &lt;code&gt;proxy&lt;/code&gt; option in &lt;code&gt;serve -tls&lt;/code&gt; flag,  to give a hint that a secure connection will be used, so we know what value to use for the cookie secure/samesite flags.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Add &lt;em&gt;experimental&lt;/em&gt; "dark mode"; this needs to be enabled explicitly in the user settings. I need help to make this decent:
  https://github.com/arp242/goatcounter/issues/586#issuecomment-1287995673&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Show difference of pageviews compared to previous period on the dashboard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Make setup of a new installation a bit easier: instead of telling people to use the CLI, display a form when the database is 100% empty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fixes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Collecting stats was broken when "sessions" was disabled in the site settings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use navigator.sendBeacon by default in count.js. This will allow using click events on things like PDF files and external URLs:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="file.pdf" data-goatcounter-event="file.pdf"&gt;
  &lt;a href="http://example.com" data-goatcounter-event="ext-example.com"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes the order of pages was wrong when using PostgreSQL.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Few smaller bugfixes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/arp242/goatcounter/releases/tag/v2.5.0" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/arp242/goatcounter/releases/tag/v2.6.0</id>
    <title>New release for GoatCounter: v2.6.0</title>
    <updated>2025-06-08T15:58:59-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>arp242/goatcounter</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;This release changes a number of default values. In most cases this shouldn't break anything, but be sure to read the section.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This release requires Go 1.21.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Changes in defaults&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The default values for the &lt;code&gt;-listen&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;-tls&lt;/code&gt; flags have changed from &lt;code&gt;-listen=:443 -tls=tls,rdr,acme&lt;/code&gt; to &lt;code&gt;-listen=:8080 -tls=none&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The previous defaults were "production ready", but in practice many people don't use the built-in TLS and ACME certificate generation but a proxy like nginx or Caddy. In addition, it's also easier to get started with the new defaults.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The default SQLite database location changed from &lt;code&gt;./db/goatcounter.sqlite3&lt;/code&gt; to &lt;code&gt;./goatcounter-data/db.sqlite3&lt;/code&gt;. The old file will still be used as a default if it exists, so this shouldn't break any existing setups.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The default ACME secrets location changed from &lt;code&gt;./acme-secrets&lt;/code&gt; to &lt;code&gt;./goatcounter-data/acme-secrets&lt;/code&gt;. The old directory will still be used as a default if it exists, so shouldn't break any existing setups.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No longer check for &lt;code&gt;window.goatcounter.vars&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;window.counter&lt;/code&gt; in &lt;code&gt;count.js&lt;/code&gt;. These were changed a week or so after the initial release over five years ago. AFAIK no one is using them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you do, then use &lt;code&gt;window.goatcounter&lt;/code&gt; (or &lt;code&gt;data-goatcounter-settings&lt;/code&gt;) instead of &lt;code&gt;window.goatcounter.vars&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;data-goatcounter="url"&lt;/code&gt; on the script tag instead of &lt;code&gt;window.counter&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No longer store individual pageviews in the &lt;code&gt;hits&lt;/code&gt; table by default.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The pageviews in the &lt;code&gt;hits&lt;/code&gt; table are never used for displaying the dashboard, only for the CSV export. Not storing it has two advantages:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;More privacy-friendly; we only store aggregate data, not exact data.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Uses less disk space, potentially a lot less for larger sites.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The downsides are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It may make debugging a bit harder in some cases.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Exporting pageviews won't be possible, because this data no longer exist. You can still use the API to get aggregate data.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Storing individual pageviews in the &lt;code&gt;hits&lt;/code&gt; table can be enabled from &lt;em&gt;Settings → Data Collection → Individual pageviews&lt;/em&gt;. Existing sites with recent exports should have it enabled automatically.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Existing data isn't removed, so you will have to manually run &lt;code&gt;truncate hits&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;delete from hits&lt;/code&gt; if you want to free up some disk space.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Features&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Include Dockerfile and publish images on DockerHub. See README for details.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take default values of CLI flags from environment variables as &lt;code&gt;GOATCOUNTER_«FLAG»&lt;/code&gt;, where «FLAG» is identical to the CLI flag name. The CLI always takes precedence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Automatically load GeoIP database from &lt;code&gt;./goatcounter-data/&lt;/code&gt; directory if it exists; it automatically loads the first .mmdb file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Improve log parsing:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Add more formats for &lt;code&gt;-datetime&lt;/code&gt;: &lt;code&gt;unix_sec&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;unix_milli&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;unix_nano&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;unix_sec_float&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code&gt;unixmilli_float&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Add &lt;code&gt;$url&lt;/code&gt; format specifier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Add &lt;code&gt;bunny&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;caddy&lt;/code&gt; log formats.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Improve dark theme, and enable by default if set in browser/system preferences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Add translations for Chinese, Korean.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Add HTTP2 Cleartext (h2c) handler to improve compatibility with some proxies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Add &lt;code&gt;-base-path&lt;/code&gt; flag to allow running GoatCounter under a different path such as &lt;code&gt;example.com/stats&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Allow importing Google Analytics reports. Google Analytics doesn't really offer a meaningful export, but does allow exporting "reports" with the totals per path. We can't show anything useful on the dashboard, but we can use it to show correct totals on the visitor counter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sites are no longer soft-deleted for 7 days. The deletion is still as a background job as it may take a while.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Fixes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use img-based fallback if sendBeacon fails in count.js. This helps with some sites that forbid using connect-src from the CSP (e.g. neocities).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Disable keyboard input on datepicker. Previously the arrow keys would move the date, but this was more annoying than anything else and prevented manually twiddling the text.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Set CORS on the visitor counter (&lt;code&gt;/counter/[..].json)&lt;/code&gt; in case of errors. It would only set &lt;code&gt;Access-Control-Allow-Origin&lt;/code&gt; if the operation succeeded, but not on errors so you'd never see the error.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Strip trailing slash from visitor counter. Trailing slashes are always stripped for paths in the dashboard, so do it in the visitor counter as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Better error if SQLite DB directory isn't writable when creating a new database. SQLite doesn't try to create the file until the first SQL command, which happens to be the version check. This would fail with a confusing &lt;code&gt;requires SQLite 3.35.0 or newer; have ""&lt;/code&gt; error.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Better styling when printing the dashboard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Correctly populate the &lt;code&gt;languages&lt;/code&gt; table when creating a new database. Previously collecting language statistics didn't work correct due to this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/arp242/goatcounter/releases/tag/v2.6.0" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
