<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://selfh.st/apps</id>
  <title>Hoarder Releases</title>
  <updated>2024-12-23T07:32:03.642006-05:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>selfh.st</name>
    <email>contact@selfh.st</email>
  </author>
  <link href="https://selfh.st/apps" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>Self-hosted software releases generated by selfh.st</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/hoarder-app/hoarder/releases/tag/v0.17.0</id>
    <title>New release for Hoarder: 0.17.0</title>
    <updated>2024-09-22T12:25:00-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>MohamedBassem/hoarder-app</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the &lt;code&gt;0.17.0&lt;/code&gt; release of Hoarder. We have a bunch of new features and UX improvements including SSO support (finally), bulk tag/list actions, better bookmark importing experience, and bunch of other stuff. In this release, we're welcoming @nghduc97  and @Mxrk as first time contributors!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you're enjoying Hoarder, you can consider supporting it &lt;a href="https://buymeacoffee.com/mbassem"&gt;here ☕️&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;New Features&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Single Sign On (SSO) support is finally here for OIDC compliant providers. This was the most requested feature and it's now here thanks to @kamtschatka. You can read about how to configure it &lt;a href="https://docs.hoarder.app/configuration#authentication--signup"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We've done multiple improvements to the bookmark importing experience:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bookmark importing now live in the settings page.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can now import bookmarks from a Pocket export.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Imported bookmarks will keep their title, tags and creation date.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A new list will be created that will include all your newly imported bookmarks. You can remove/rename this list after making sure that everything went according to plan.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can now customize the banner image for links and manipulate all its other attachments in the bookmark preview page.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can now bulk add/remove tags and lists to bookmarks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some mobile app improvements:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In case you were facing issues connecting to hoarder from the app, there's now a "Connection testing" functionality that shows you a more descriptive issue about the problem you're hitting.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The app was by default following the theme (e.g. light/dark mode) of the system. You can now configure explicitly the theme that you want in the settings.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There's a new floating quick add button to quickly save new bookmarks from within the app.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For ollama users, you can now configure the timeout of the inference worker in case ollama's responses are slow. You can also configure a model keep alive TTL so that ollama can drop the model from memory if it's not used for that configure period. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We have a new compact layout to quickly skim through your bookmarks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;UX Improvements&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In the tags editor, you can now quickly remove the last tags by pressing backspace.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The tags editor will now feel much faster by optimistically applying the changes before they are committed on the server.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;On the mobile app, server errors (e.g. connection errors) will have a much better UI indicating the problem and giving you an option to retry.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lists are now sorted alphabetically thanks to @kamtschatka.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Signup dialog now shows a less confusing message when signups are disabled thanks @nghduc97&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Fixes&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Completely deleting a tag was broken, now it's fixed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Screenshots&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;New Mobile Settings Page&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width="386" alt="Screenshot 2024-09-22 at 4 58 33 PM" src="https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/f351c0db-9b7c-48d1-b0ca-76f2c34766fa"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Connection Testing&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width="407" alt="Screenshot 2024-09-22 at 4 52 07 PM" src="https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/70d46ff9-ded8-497f-8203-489021cb4763"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;SSO Support&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width="407" alt="Screenshot 2024-09-22 at 4 52 33 PM" src="https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/8b653987-d923-420a-8b14-2cffd3f7327a"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Compact Layout&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width="1401" alt="Screenshot 2024-09-22 at 4 53 46 PM" src="https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/6cac935c-5ecf-4d65-be92-809811a02104"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;New Import UI&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width="711" alt="Screenshot 2024-09-22 at 4 57 14 PM" src="https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/7cd6ceeb-951f-47b4-ab14-0f6827b5f4a9"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;New Bulk Actions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width="425" alt="Screenshot 2024-09-22 at 4 55 52 PM" src="https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/089d6f2e-4c86-4721-9bd1-c16cc21bb473"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;New Attachments Section&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width="478" alt="Screenshot 2024-09-22 at 4 55 14 PM" src="https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/067bf3c9-391d-4a27-80d0-e4f516141481"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Upgrading&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To upgrade:
* If you're using HOARDER_VERSION=release, run &lt;code&gt;docker compose pull &amp;amp;&amp;amp; docker compose up -d&lt;/code&gt;.
* If you're pinning it to a specific version, upgrade the version and then run &lt;code&gt;docker compose pull &amp;amp;&amp;amp; docker compose up -d&lt;/code&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;All Commits&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix(web): Show a scrollbar in the tag editor. Fixes #368 (#404) by @kamtschatka in d0e7ca2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feature(web): Show attachments and allow users to manipulate them. by @MohamedBassem in a770e55&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;release: Release mobile and extension to include SSO changes by @MohamedBassem in 55f5c7f&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feature(mobile): Allow users to login with API keys in the mobile app by @MohamedBassem in 5fe330c&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feature(extension): Allow login directly with an API key by @kamtschatka in 26521b7&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feature(web): Add support for importing bookmarks from Pocket by @MohamedBassem in 9dd6f21&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feature(web): Preserve title, tags and createdAt when importing a netscape html. Fixes #401 by @MohamedBassem in d62c972&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feature(web): Move bookmark imports into settings by @MohamedBassem in 52024ab&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;refactor: Extract useUpload into its own reusable hook by @MohamedBassem in 6b5c597&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feature(web): Add healthecheck api endpoint (#332) by @Mxrk in 3377969&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;build: Fix nextjs build after upgrading to 14.2 by @MohamedBassem in 7cd857c&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;deps: Upgrade turbo by @MohamedBassem in 8fa2009&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;deps: Upgrade nextjs to 14.2.13 by @MohamedBassem in 55201db&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;docs: Fix docs build and add sso to readme by @MohamedBassem in e585ce6&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix(web): Better message when signups are disabled (#374) by @nghduc97 in 34fb5fb&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feature: Added support for custom OIDC providers to set up authentication. Fixes #92 (#307) by @kamtschatka in b9724b7&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;deps: Upgrade drizzle and next auth drizzle adapter by @MohamedBassem in 80749d5&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix: Fix deleting tags broken due to wrong column name by @MohamedBassem in fb63f55&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feature(web): Alphabetical sorting for lists. Fixes #315 (#351) by @kamtschatka in 064d5f8&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feature(web): Add a compact layout. Fixes #379 by @MohamedBassem in 47939a5&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feature(worker): Allow configuring inference job timeout and ollama keep alive. Fixes #389 #224 by @MohamedBassem in f263f9e&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix(web): removing referrer header when clicking on links. Fixes #387 (#388) by @kamtschatka in 3b8cebb&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix(mobile): Fix some icon colors in dark mode by @MohamedBassem in 095995d&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feature(mobile): Add a page for testing connection to server by @MohamedBassem in 3452e47&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feature(mobile): Add settings page for configuring the theme by @MohamedBassem in 66fcf02&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feature(mobile): Add proper error handling for server errors by @MohamedBassem in b9c7857&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;docs: Update screenshots in docs by @MohamedBassem in 09e16ba&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;release(mobile): Bump mobile version to 1.6.2 by @MohamedBassem in 21aaf83&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feature(mobile): Show the view bookmark modal for links as well by @MohamedBassem in cddae8f&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feature(mobile): Add a floating button for quickly adding new bookmarks by @MohamedBassem in 2bfa73f&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;readme: Add full page archive and bulk actions to readme by @MohamedBassem in 3944505&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix(web): Add optimistic rendering for the tags editor by @MohamedBassem in 300f3c5&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feature(web): Manage tags in bulk actions by @MohamedBassem in 67729c1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feature(web): Pop tag in TagEditor on pressing backspace. #368 by @MohamedBassem in 6d4d1a6&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feature(web): Show the number of bulk selected bookmarks by @MohamedBassem in 77adb84&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feature(web): Allow adding to lists in bulk actions. #368 by @MohamedBassem in ddc7e5d&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/hoarder-app/hoarder/releases/tag/v0.17.0" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/hoarder-app/hoarder/releases/tag/v0.17.1</id>
    <title>New release for Hoarder: 0.17.1</title>
    <updated>2024-09-27T04:41:05-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>MohamedBassem/hoarder-app</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;This is a small hotfix for the &lt;a href="https://github.com/hoarder-app/hoarder/releases/tag/v0.17.0"&gt;0.17.0 release&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;🐞 Fixes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When importing bookmarks from a netscape html file, there was a bug that would result in the importing bookmarks getting all of your tags. This is fixed in https://github.com/hoarder-app/hoarder/commit/12d3371d12d5709adc6e23b53792cf1dc28a8a06 &amp;amp; https://github.com/hoarder-app/hoarder/commit/4db50c234fb0da8747b902a7c1e551cc54451f4c.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A "name" is no longer required from SSO providers. @kamtschatka fixed that in https://github.com/hoarder-app/hoarder/commit/e1feeceda475b117dde99a971f87e20a149f7edf.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/hoarder-app/hoarder/releases/tag/v0.17.1" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/hoarder-app/hoarder/releases/tag/v0.18.0</id>
    <title>New release for Hoarder: 0.18.0</title>
    <updated>2024-10-13T10:50:38-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>MohamedBassem/hoarder-app</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the &lt;code&gt;0.18.0&lt;/code&gt; release of Hoarder! This release introduces customizable tagging rules (aka customizing the prompt), new UI look, selective full page archives, infinite scrolling, more bulk actions and more! As usual, we'd like to welcome our first time contributors @jarednipper, @Trugamr, @cedmax and @CrypticC3s4r! We also have @Lucius346346 working behind the scene on improving the UX of Hoarder with amazing designs! And finally, we have our usual contributors @kamtschatka and @mdsaban! Also thanks to @Papierkorb for the help in suggestions to improve the LLM prompt!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also now have a public roadmap which you can check for the features that we're planning to deliver &lt;a href="https://github.com/orgs/hoarder-app/projects/1"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. Go upvote the features that you're waiting for!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you're enjoying Hoarder, you can consider supporting it &lt;a href="https://buymeacoffee.com/mbassem"&gt;here ☕️&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;New Feature&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Introducing customizable tagging rules: You can now customize the prompt that we use to generate the tags to your linkings and add custom rules for the LLM to adhere to!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can use this to define your tagging rules in natural language and let the LLM take care of applying it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you don't want to enable "Full page archives" by default, you can now selectively archive particular pages that you want to keep forever thanks to @kamtschatka!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can now export your bookmarks from Hoarder and re-import them back in another instance (note: currently images and pdfs are not exported).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can now customize the context length of the inference model using the &lt;code&gt;INFERENCE_CONTEXT_LENGTH&lt;/code&gt; flag:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The bigger this value is, the more of your content the model will see and will be able to give you better tagging.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;However, the bigger the context window, the more expensive the request is for OpenAI money-wise and for ollama resource-wise.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The current default is &lt;code&gt;2048&lt;/code&gt; tokens (~2048 words).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Better asset tracking and management:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We're now currently correctly accounting for all asset sizes in the database. You can view the usage of every user now in the admin panel.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Old assets are not automatically accounted for and you'll have to click the new &lt;code&gt;Compact Asset&lt;/code&gt; button in the admin panel to backfill that data. This button also removes assets that are dangling (aka not linked to any bookmark).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This work is in preparation for supporting better privacy checks in the future when we implement public and collaborative lists.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can now attach custom image banners to your notes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Those banners will appear at the top of your notes when you expand them as well as in the &lt;code&gt;List&lt;/code&gt; layout.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We're still figuring out a good way to render them in the grid and masonry layouts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;UX Improvements&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We have a refreshed UI looks thanks to amazing designs by @Lucius346346!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We now have a sticky navbar for better experience in bulk editing thanks to @mdsaban.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We also have a new profile options dropdown in the header where the user and admin settings buttons got moved to.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We now have infinite scrolling for pagination so that you no longer need to click the &lt;code&gt;Show more&lt;/code&gt; button.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bulk actions improvements:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There's now a &lt;code&gt;Select all&lt;/code&gt; button to select all the currently visible bookmarks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Copy links&lt;/code&gt; is also a thing to bulk copy the source links of a bunch of bookmarks thanks to @kamtschatka.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can now trigger AI tag regeneration for all bookmarks or the ones that that failed only in the admin panel.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When you hoard text from other webpages by the extension (by highlighting text -&amp;gt; right click -&amp;gt; add to hoarder) the source link will now be preserved with the text.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We have a new tabbed user settings page as it was getting quite long.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sidebar items were not clickable around the boarder which was annoying. @Trugamr fixed that!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Fixes&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For those who want to go all-in on Oauth, you can now set &lt;code&gt;DISABLE_PASSWORD_AUTH=true&lt;/code&gt; which will forbid any password-based authentication/signup. This is implemented by @kamtschatka.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The All Tags page was taking too long to load when you have too many tags. @kamtschatka landed some improvements to the performance of this page.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Editing lists from the sidebar was broken, now it's fixed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When you wipe your hoarder's database while still logged in the browser, users were getting some confusing behavior with confusing database errors. This is now fixed, and hoarder will automatically log you out if your account is no longer there.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;@Mxrk Added docker healthchecks to the dockerfile and also source label so that hoarder's updates can be correctly reflected in stuff like renovate.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Screenshots&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The new UI Look&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width="1209" alt="Screenshot 2024-10-13 at 3 16 59 PM" src="https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/0b13bf69-d0a1-4afc-90ca-826f898c3ae1"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Profile Options&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width="272" alt="Screenshot 2024-10-13 at 3 49 02 PM" src="https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/8e5e403c-a52c-4e39-a36a-eebcf96999b8"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;AI Settings and Tagging Rules&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width="982" alt="Screenshot 2024-10-13 at 3 18 55 PM" src="https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/d67296d1-26c3-4c55-b346-b0e3d9568d16"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;New Import/Export Buttons&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width="1345" alt="Screenshot 2024-10-13 at 3 19 46 PM" src="https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/729bd9c6-18df-4ca3-a70c-7d612b8d1f5a"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Num Bookmarks &amp;amp; Asset Sizes in Admin Panel&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width="1327" alt="Screenshot 2024-10-13 at 3 22 13 PM" src="https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/798fb564-5cb3-4ff8-9230-8262c4642e25"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;New Admin Actions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width="669" alt="Screenshot 2024-10-13 at 3 22 21 PM" src="https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/4e166fdd-f872-4961-beed-779bf2a029cc"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Upgrading&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To upgrade:
* If you're using HOARDER_VERSION=release, run &lt;code&gt;docker compose pull &amp;amp;&amp;amp; docker compose up -d&lt;/code&gt;.
* If you're pinning it to a specific version, upgrade the version and then run &lt;code&gt;docker compose pull &amp;amp;&amp;amp; docker compose up -d&lt;/code&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;All Commits&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix: Add support for importing notes from the hoarder export - @MohamedBassem in 43ed698&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix(web): Fix settings tab overflow on mobile layouts - @MohamedBassem in cdd0088&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix(web): Fix profile option icon in mobile layouts - @MohamedBassem in 8741ab0&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix(web): Fix slowness in loading the all tags UI. Fixes  #382 (#390) - @kamtschatka in 4791a53&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feature: Allow importing hoarder's own bookmark file. Fixes #527 - @MohamedBassem in de9cf0a&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feature: Support regenerating AI tags only for failed bookmarks - @MohamedBassem in 2ccc15e&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;build: Use node 22 for CI - @MohamedBassem in fb57f25&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;deps: Upgrade nodejs to v22 - @MohamedBassem in 1390337&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;deps: Upgrade metascraper for faster docker builds - @MohamedBassem in 31bcad8&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feature(web): Implement a new profile options drop menu and move user and admin settings there - @MohamedBassem in b36eea8&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;docs: Add a section to installation docs about optional features - @MohamedBassem in 0d94506&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;docs: Remove the warning about ollama being new - @MohamedBassem in 5e44cfb&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix(web): Fix react error in search input - @MohamedBassem in 6035dff&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feature: Allow customizing the inference's context length - @MohamedBassem in 1b09682&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feature: Introduce a mechanism to cleanup dangling assets - @MohamedBassem in c16173e&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feature: Allow to disable default password login after SSO is configured. Fixes #406 (#502) - @kamtschatka in 9f87207&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix(web): Reset search query and bulk edit when navigating away from the current page - @MohamedBassem in 02a5b35&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feature(web): Introduce a new sticky navbar. Fixes 520  (#515) - @mdsaban in 1f768be&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;docker: Add HEALTHCHECK to Dockerfile (#508) - @Mxrk in e2644eb&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;docker: add Source Label to Dockerfile (#509) - @Mxrk in 904eb5a&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix(web): Fix sidebar list edit dialog not working. Fixes #447 - @MohamedBassem in 09e0659&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;refactor: Start tracking bookmark assets in the assets table - @MohamedBassem in 1e5c575&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;refactor: Include userId in the assets table - @MohamedBassem in db2d346&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;readme: Add a security policy - @MohamedBassem in e6d4ff9&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feature: Allow disabling password signups (#413) - @kamtschatka in 4a3775a&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feature: Allow attaching custom banners to notes. Fixes: #106 - @MohamedBassem in 8a13095&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix: Drop the usage of useCursorV2 from the server - @MohamedBassem in 99c6232&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix(mobile): Drop the floating add button. Fixes #439 - @MohamedBassem in c017328&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feature: Persevere the source URL of clipped texts from the extension. Fixes #448 - @MohamedBassem in b147c8e&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feature(web): Async validate JWT account and sign out the user if they no longer exist - @MohamedBassem in f1c956a&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feature(web): Change the settings page to be tabbed - @MohamedBassem in 3a8d197&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix(web): Simplify the language for inference settings - @MohamedBassem in 03e938a&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix(web): Change export format to have content as a top level key - @MohamedBassem in 1f7da9a&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;docker: Fix the docker-based development env (#456) - @CrypticC3s4r in 3f22801&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;docs: Fix typo in installation docs (#465) - @jarednipper in f6192da&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feature(web): Allow users to export their links and notes - @MohamedBassem in c8a3c1e&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;readme: Fix installation link in the readme (#482) - @disappointingsupernova in 463d041&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feature(cli): Add ability to get all bookmark IDs of a list. Fixes #442 (#446) - @kamtschatka in 4bda7a9&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;deps: Upgrade openai package - @MohamedBassem in b56655c&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feature(web): Add ability to manually trigger full page archives. Fixes #398 (#418) - @kamtschatka in 8b69cdd&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feature(web): Add ability to rerun inference on all bookmarks. Fixes 443 - @MohamedBassem in 5281531&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix(web): Improve SidebarItem tap target accessibility (#409) - @Trugamr in 8fe1927&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feature(web): Add the ability to customize the inference prompts. Fixes #170 - @MohamedBassem in 36fb5a4&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;deps: Upgrade drizzle-kit - @MohamedBassem in 57f5faa&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix(web): Fix another hydration error in copy to clipboard - @MohamedBassem in b32a832&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feature(web): Add infinite scrolling support - @MohamedBassem in ab1c837&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix(web): Fix some hydration errors in bulk actions - @MohamedBassem in 41f4e6b&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feature(web): Add a select all button to bulk actions - @MohamedBassem in badf697&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feature(web): Add a bulk action to copy links into clipboard. Fixes #427 (#433) - @kamtschatka in ee0aad5&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/hoarder-app/hoarder/releases/tag/v0.18.0" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/hoarder-app/hoarder/releases/tag/v0.19.0</id>
    <title>New release for Hoarder: 0.19.0</title>
    <updated>2024-11-09T11:22:49-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>MohamedBassem/hoarder-app</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the &lt;code&gt;0.19.0&lt;/code&gt; release of Hoarder! This release is packed with a lot of new features! The long awaited REST APIs, RSS subscriptions, AI summarization, Image OCR, archiving videos, importing from Omnivore, and more!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you're enjoying Hoarder, you can consider supporting it &lt;a href="https://buymeacoffee.com/mbassem"&gt;here ☕️&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;New Feature&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;RSS Subscriptions&lt;/strong&gt; 🧪: You can now subscribe to RSS feeds and Hoarder will automatically pull them every hour.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can use this to auto hoard stuff from your favourite blogs, subreddits, or youtube channels.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This feature is still experimental and haven't been tested on a a wide variety of feeds. Please file issues whenever you face any problems using it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The long awaited &lt;strong&gt;REST API&lt;/strong&gt; is here. You can view the API docs &lt;a href="https://docs.hoarder.app/api"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can view the OpenAPI spec &lt;a href="https://github.com/hoarder-app/hoarder/blob/main/packages/open-api/hoarder-openapi-spec.json"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; in case you want to generate clients for it. I'm planning to offer an official Typescript SDK some time in the future.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AI Summarization&lt;/strong&gt;: Hoarder now has the ability to generate summaries for the links that you hoard! Check the screenshots section to see it in action.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Currently, summarization is a manual action. In the future, we'll add support for auto summarization.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Video downloads&lt;/strong&gt;: For ultimate hoarding, Hoarder now has the ability to download videos from the links that you hoard (e.g. youtube) thanks to @kamtschatka.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Given that videos can be huge, this is an opt-in feature. You can enable it with &lt;code&gt;CRAWLER_VIDEO_DOWNLOAD=true&lt;/code&gt;. Find more configuration options &lt;a href="https://docs.hoarder.app/configuration#crawler-configs"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hoarder uses &lt;a href="https://github.com/ytdl-org/youtube-dl"&gt;ytdl&lt;/a&gt; under the hood, and you can find their list of supported files &lt;a href="https://ytdl-org.github.io/youtube-dl/supportedsites.html"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Omnivore Imports&lt;/strong&gt;: Omnivore &lt;a href="https://blog.omnivore.app/p/omnivore-is-joining-elevenlabs"&gt;is shutting down&lt;/a&gt;. You can now import your bookmarks from Omnivore into Hoarder. Check the documentation &lt;a href="https://docs.hoarder.app/import"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;User Management&lt;/strong&gt;: Admins can now reset user passwords, change their roles and even create new users thanks to @kamtschatka.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Image OCR&lt;/strong&gt;: Hoarder will now attempt to read and index text in the images that you hoard! Check the configuration variables &lt;a href="https://docs.hoarder.app/configuration#ocr-configs"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Others:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;@kamtschatka Added authentication failure logging in case you want to configure fail2ban against hoarder logs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;UX Improvements&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We have a new redesigned settings page to better support the new options we're adding. Check it out in the screenshot section.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can use &lt;code&gt;Cmd/Ctrl + K&lt;/code&gt; to quickly focus on Hoarder's searchbar.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We reverted the mobile apps to again view webpages inline, but now added buttons for quick actions underneath it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Fixes&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Single new lines in notes were getting lost in markdown. @kamtschatka fixed that.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pocket switched their export format to CSVs instead of their old format. Hoarder now supports importing the new format.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tags that had numbers or dashes in them were getting skipped, this is now fixed. Thanks @MakeSomeGood for the bug report and investigation!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;code&gt;All Tags&lt;/code&gt; page was getting very slow when there's a lot of tags. This turned out to be a small misconfiguration in the database that we fixed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Custom prompts had a max length of 100, which wasn't enough to some people. The new limit is 500.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Screenshots&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;AI Summarization&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/062bcfcc-139c-421d-8caf-0941998f8575&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;RSS Feeds &amp;amp; New Settings Page&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width="1482" alt="Screenshot 2024-11-09 at 4 11 59 PM" src="https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/1908577c-2b8c-4a60-8a45-0d7b239ac0a5"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Admin User Management&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width="973" alt="Screenshot 2024-11-09 at 4 15 47 PM" src="https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/180e030c-0dbb-45c0-8241-c3f614513393"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Upgrading&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To upgrade:
* If you're using HOARDER_VERSION=release, run &lt;code&gt;docker compose pull &amp;amp;&amp;amp; docker compose up -d&lt;/code&gt;.
* If you're pinning it to a specific version, upgrade the version and then run &lt;code&gt;docker compose pull &amp;amp;&amp;amp; docker compose up -d&lt;/code&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;All Commits&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix: Increase max prompt length to 500 chars instead of 100 - @MohamedBassem in 8ce272d&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;docs: Add documentation about how to import from pocket and omnivore - @MohamedBassem in 2b6eb7c&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;docs: Update CLI importing docs to better handle large collections (#630) - @bjornmonnens in e57937e&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix: Remove old downloaded video when it gets refreshed - @MohamedBassem in a24755d&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix: Only update bookmark tagging/crawling status when worker is out of retries - @MohamedBassem in f8bed57&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix: Feed refreshes were not getting re-enqueued for failed jobs - @MohamedBassem in 10070c1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ui: Mark the RSS subscriptions as an experimental feature - @MohamedBassem in 9ca49b2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix: Fix slow AllTags page because of misconfigured tagId index. Fixes #528 - @MohamedBassem in 8f44c81&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix: Pass arguments to monolith and yt-dlp as array for better escaping - @MohamedBassem in cbaa033&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feature: Add support for importing bookmarks from Omnivore. Fixes #602 - @MohamedBassem in 7ec5746&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix: Adopt pocket's new export format. Fixes #570 - @MohamedBassem in 7042f26&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix: Fix bug in tag normalization regex. Fixes #595 - @MohamedBassem in 306567b&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feature: Schedule RSS feed refreshes every hour - @MohamedBassem in d34b538&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feature(web): Add the ability to view the bookmarks of a particular rss feed - @MohamedBassem in fa8286a&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feature: Add support for subscribing to RSS feeds. Fixes #202 - @MohamedBassem in cf1a251&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix(mobile): Fix bookmarkview page on android not showing bookmark actions. Fixes #603 - @MohamedBassem in 2efc7c8&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix: Fix type in the separate container env variable - @MohamedBassem in 4c94b37&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feature: Archive videos using yt-dlp. Fixes #215 (#525) - @kamtschatka in 4a13c36&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;docs: Add a FAQ page (#590) - @kamtschatka in 3b7451f&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;deps: Extract the queue implementation into its own repos - @MohamedBassem in a746e9a&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ui: Redesign the settings page and move it to its own layout - @MohamedBassem in eb7da99&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix: Index the summary in search - @MohamedBassem in 801ba36&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix: Some visual fixes to the AI summary - @MohamedBassem in e06a5ea&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix: Fix search input escape listener to only work when the input is in focus - @MohamedBassem in 9d6d70d&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix: Fix build by regenerating the openai spec - @MohamedBassem in c0b0691&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feature: Add a summarize with AI button for links - @MohamedBassem in 731d2df&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;refactor: Move inference to the shared package - @MohamedBassem in 3e727f7&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;docker: Add a flag to detect apps running in legacy container setup - @MohamedBassem in db45aaf&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;release(mobile): Bump mobile version to 1.6.5 - @MohamedBassem in bb344e5&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feature(mobile): Use inline WebView for expanding bookmarks - @MohamedBassem in 2ce42a8&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feature: Add OCR support for images. Fixes #296 - @MohamedBassem in 019b5d2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ci: Add a build step that ensures that open api spec doesn't diverge - @MohamedBassem in f793646&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ci: Fix build by adding corepack enable to CI - @MohamedBassem in 5b20d97&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;docs: Add link to discord to navbar - @MohamedBassem in 09d29e4&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;api: Add tag ids and support variable baseURL - @MohamedBassem in b476e91&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;docs: Generate OpenAPI docs - @MohamedBassem in 6ffa51d&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;chore: Define hoarder's rest API in zod format - @MohamedBassem in 3c1ec3a&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix: Improve field names in the tag APIs - @MohamedBassem in 4086c37&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feature(api): Add REST APIs to update bookmarks, tags and lists - @MohamedBassem in e89a386&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feature(api): Add REST APIs to manipulate lists and tags for bookmarks - @MohamedBassem in 20e5225&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feature: Add APIs to create new lists and bookmarks - @MohamedBassem in 10dcf2e&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix: Better handling for body JSON parsing errors - @MohamedBassem in f5fd3c4&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feature: Add DELETE REST APIs for bookmarks, lists and tags - @MohamedBassem in 719e25d&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feature: Add GET REST APIs for bookmarks, lists and tags - @MohamedBassem in 62395ec&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;featue: Add infra for REST APIs and implement GET /bookmarks - @MohamedBassem in fb297ea&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix(workers): Pin execa to avoid ERR_PACKAGE_PATH_NOT_EXPORTED error - @MohamedBassem in a822ff2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feature(web): Add keyboard shortcut to focus on search bar. Fixes #449 (#554) - @kamtschatka in cbc268e&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feature: Allow reseting user password, change their roles and create new users. Fixes #495  (#567) - @kamtschatka in 9a56e58&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feature: Log authentication failures to support fail2ban. Fixes #477 (#569) - @kamtschatka in 0debc6b&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;chore: Adding issue templates (#546) - @Inventhrice in e55362e&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix(web): Single linebreaks are lost when viewing textnote card. Fixes #549 (#551) - @kamtschatka in 6977ba7&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;release(mobile): Bump mobile version to 1.6.4 - @MohamedBassem in 4454d63&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix(mobile): Improve connection testing accuracy - @MohamedBassem in 90953fd&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/hoarder-app/hoarder/releases/tag/v0.19.0" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/hoarder-app/hoarder/releases/tag/v0.20.0</id>
    <title>New release for Hoarder: 0.20.0</title>
    <updated>2024-12-22T06:21:02-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>MohamedBassem/hoarder-app</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the &lt;code&gt;0.20.0&lt;/code&gt; release of Hoarder! This release adds internationalization support, new markdown editor, mobile app improvements, broken link management and more! As usual, we're welcoming our new contributors: @Tukks, @vhsdream, @sweepies, @PeterDaveHello, @wuast94 and @eltociear!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you're enjoying Hoarder, you can consider supporting it &lt;a href="https://buymeacoffee.com/mbassem"&gt;here ☕️&lt;/a&gt; or via github &lt;a href="https://github.com/sponsors/MohamedBassem"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;New Features&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hoarder's UI now comes in multiple languages&lt;/strong&gt;!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can change the language of the UI now to English, German, French, Swedish, Simplified and Traditional Chinese.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you want to see your language there or want to improve some existing translation, you can do that via weblate &lt;a href="https://hosted.weblate.org/engage/hoarder/"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;New experimental WYSIWYG markdown editor&lt;/strong&gt; for notes by @Tukks!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You'll now get a preview of the notes you're writing as you're writing them!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A bunch of mobile app improvements&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can now manage tags from the app. Super overdue, I know.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We have a new cleaner "info" page with the ability to edit title/tags/lists all in one page.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The mobile app now looks &lt;em&gt;slightly&lt;/em&gt; more native. We've got rid of the dedicated search tag, switched to native modals, and used native page headers when possible.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Note: The apps are yet to be approved by apple &amp;amp; google.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Broken Link management&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hoarder now stores the status codes it got when crawling websites which will allow you to identify and decide what to do about broken links.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This is now mainly useful for people doing large imports into hoarder, but in the future, we'll use the same mechanism to support automatic link liveness healthchecks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chrome as an optional dependency (aka minimal installation)&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chrome is no longer a hard dependency. This is useful for people running hoarder in resource constrained environments.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you don't specify a &lt;code&gt;BROWSER_WEB_URL&lt;/code&gt;, hoarder will fallback to a plain HTTP requests to the websites you add instead of crawling them with chrome.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Without chrome, you'll lose the ability to get screenshots from the websites you crawl, and websites that heavily rely on javascript won't work properly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;With chrome and meilisearch being optional dependencies, you can now get a single-container minimal installation of hoarder by sacrificing some of the features.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;New installation methods&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Debian / Ubuntu one click installation script (&lt;a href="https://docs.hoarder.app/next/Installation/debuntu"&gt;docs&lt;/a&gt;) by @vhsdream&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you're a proxmox user, you can also get a one click LXC container running hoarder using &lt;a href="https://community-scripts.github.io/ProxmoxVE/scripts?id=hoarder"&gt;proxmox's helper scripts&lt;/a&gt; again thanks to @vhsdream.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PikaPod (&lt;a href="https://docs.hoarder.app/next/Installation/pikapods"&gt;docs&lt;/a&gt;) are now offering paid hoarder hosting (~$3/month) for the less tech savvy folks out there. Disclaimer: they're sharing some of their revenue from Hoarder with us.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tags placeholder in AI prompt customization:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can use the placeholders &lt;code&gt;$tags&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;$aiTags&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;$userTags&lt;/code&gt; in the prompt. These placeholders will be replaced with all tags, ai generated tags or human created tags when automatic tagging is performed thanks to @kamtschatka.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;With that, you can use this to instruct the LLM to only use existing tags (instead of coming up with new ones). Be careful though if you have a lot of tags as it might increase the cost of the tagging significantly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This mechanism is just a temporary solution. We're working on a mechanism to support this natively, in a much cheaper way.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;New community projects documentation page&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;a href="https://docs.hoarder.app/next/community-projects"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;):&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;With the release of the REST API in the last version, we started seeing some community projects pop up. So we're starting a new documentation page to list them out for visibility.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hoarder now has a &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.raycast.com/luolei/hoarder"&gt;raycast extension&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; and an &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.alfredforum.com/topic/22528-hoarder-workflow-for-self-hosted-bookmark-management/"&gt;alfred workflow&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; thanks to @foru17 and @yinan-c. Go install them now!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you develop a new extension for hoarder, let us know as we'd love to feature it in that page!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Others:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We've added the ability to show admin warnings in the admin panels for misconfigurations or future migrations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;UX Improvements&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We're now trimming email addresses out of whitespaces during signin thanks to @sweepies!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Fixes&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;AI summarization sometimes included the LLM's response to the prompt (e.g. "Ok, I'll summarize ..."). We're now instructing the model to only respond with the summary.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix broken homepage when hitting a bookmark with an invalid image URL.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Multiple worker reliability improvements specially in countries with restricted internet.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The worker container doesn't need to download pnpm on startup anymore as it's now bundled in the container.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The crawler's adblock list download now has a timeout and can be completely bypassed with &lt;code&gt;CRAWLER_ENABLE_ADBLOCKER=false&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The worker was sometimes hanging in the screenshot call. This now has a timeout as well.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Screenshots&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The new Markdown Editor&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width="710" alt="Screenshot 2024-12-22 at 12 59 10 PM" src="https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/9eadef85-679c-4c21-b2f6-432f75d7056d" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Broken Link Management&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width="978" alt="Screenshot 2024-12-22 at 1 04 43 PM" src="https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/3cadceb4-deb3-4588-af7a-5b2617ba5266" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Mobile App Improvements&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;New options at the bottom of the bookmark preview page&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/a192f806-0431-4390-afc9-641bbfb90967" width="300px" alt="3EA11BCA-C06A-4681-AC44-D87DB9BC8954"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tag Management
&lt;img src="https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/a6cdf234-ff11-4e91-ba85-8850f2cd12a8" width="300px" alt="9A4562B4-9429-41CA-AFCC-0A45941D3ACF"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new info page
&lt;img src="https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/56b52981-e556-49fa-9db5-b3445984cd76" width="300px" alt="E679CFD4-7EEB-4910-8FD6-B1EC92090D81"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Admin Notices&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width="251" alt="Screenshot 2024-12-22 at 12 57 10 PM" src="https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/943ae106-8eec-4f29-a145-766531ef9d19" /&gt;
&lt;img width="979" alt="Screenshot 2024-12-22 at 12 57 20 PM" src="https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/a73f734c-9501-4d7c-b01b-02d5df1c7cdb" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Raycast extension and Alfred workflows&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Those screenshots are from the authors of the extensions.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.raycast.com/luolei/hoarder"&gt;Raycast extension&lt;/a&gt; by @foru17&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/9624c0f8-b4d8-4b9b-bc3a-5ae4335cc193" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.alfredforum.com/topic/22528-hoarder-workflow-for-self-hosted-bookmark-management/"&gt;Alfred workflow&lt;/a&gt; by @yinan-c&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/61bcba3b-93b8-47e4-ba53-e1da9a525fc2" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Upgrading&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To upgrade:
* If you're using HOARDER_VERSION=release, run &lt;code&gt;docker compose pull &amp;amp;&amp;amp; docker compose up -d&lt;/code&gt;.
* If you're pinning it to a specific version, upgrade the version and then run &lt;code&gt;docker compose pull &amp;amp;&amp;amp; docker compose up -d&lt;/code&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;All Commits&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;i18n: Enable the Swedish translation - @MohamedBassem in e3b8cda&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;i18n: Merge translations from weblate - @MohamedBassem in ab1f49b&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feature: Add an admin notice about the usage of the legacy container images - @MohamedBassem in 4bfb3b4&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;release(mobile): Bump mobile version to 1.6.7-4 - @MohamedBassem in 2245887&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;deps: Upgrade nextjs to 14.2.15 - @MohamedBassem in 7c05bc8&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;deps: Upgrade prettier to 3.4.2 - @MohamedBassem in 1aa7639&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;docs: Add the community projects page to docs - @MohamedBassem in 973d552&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feature: WYSIWYG markdown for notes. Fixes #701 (#715) - @Tukks in 40c5262&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Translated using Weblate (German) - @murray3k in 14f8937&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Translated using Weblate (Dutch) - Guido (via weblate) in 17fdd93&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added translation using Weblate (Dutch) - Guido (via weblate) in 25ebd8e&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Translated using Weblate (Swedish) - Marcus skoding (via weblate) in 20968ec&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added translation using Weblate (Swedish) - Marcus skoding (via weblate) in 883087b&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix: trim whitespace from email on signin page (#714) - @sweepies in 16f2ce3&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix(mobile): useLayoutEffect for navigator changes - @MohamedBassem in 6fba9d1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ui(mobile): Use native search bar for manage tags page - @MohamedBassem in deadcb9&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix(mobule): Fix keyboard issues in the info screen - @MohamedBassem in 6055f50&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ui(mobile): Make page titles more native - @MohamedBassem in f4b2bac&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feature: Store crawling status code and allow users to find broken links. Fixes #169 - @MohamedBassem in 705d539&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;docs: Add Linux install script and documentation (#707) - @vhsdream in a7b1386&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feature(workers): Allow running hoarder without chrome as a hard dependency. Fixes #650 - @MohamedBassem in 1810100&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix(mobile): Use keyboard avoiding view in the info page - @MohamedBassem in 5a49691&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix(extension): Fix dev build. Fixes #670 - @MohamedBassem in 1a2b600&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix: Instruct the model to only respond with the summary when summarizing content - @MohamedBassem in b9f1a59&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix(workers): Add spaces in tag placeholders for better tokenization - @MohamedBassem in 036554a&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feature: Add support for tag placeholders in custom prompts. #111 (#612) - @kamtschatka in fdf28ae&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;release(mobile): Bump mobile version to 1.6.7-2 - @MohamedBassem in 82af305&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;docs: Fix docs build - @MohamedBassem in 6392cca&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;deps(mobile): Upgrade to Expo 52 (#692) - @MohamedBassem in fd4a996&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;release(mobile): Bump mobile version to 1.6.7-1 - @MohamedBassem in d32457e&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feature(mobile): Add support for creating tags from the manage tags page - @MohamedBassem in 2e5cd59&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix(mobile): Dont dismiss keyboard on tag selection - @MohamedBassem in dd80f91&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;release(mobile): Bump mobile version to 1.6.7 - @MohamedBassem in bf80fa2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feat(mobile): Add support for managing tags from mobile - @MohamedBassem in 2745330&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feat(mobile): Allow editing titles and a cleaner info page - @MohamedBassem in fbb2644&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ui(mobile): Replace bottom sheet with native screens (#690) - @MohamedBassem in 5522e20&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;readme: Add weblate translations to readme - @MohamedBassem in 4bb7487&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ui(mobile): Remove the dedicated search page and add a search bar in home - @MohamedBassem in cc84e01&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;docs: Add pikapods.com as installation option (#676) - @m3nu in df19d39&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;i18n: Add zh-TW Traditional Chinese locale (#689) - @PeterDaveHello in dcba3c4&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix(workers): Set a timeout on the screenshot call and completely skip it if screenshotting is disabled - @MohamedBassem in 6ccdbe5&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix(workers): Don't block connection to chrome when failing to download adblock list. #674 - @MohamedBassem in 378ad9b&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;chore(workers): Add extra logging for browser connection errors - @MohamedBassem in 393d097&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;readme: Add github sponsor - @MohamedBassem in 5533632&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;docker: Preinstall pnpm for the worker job to prevent downloading it on startup. #666 - @MohamedBassem in ae78ef5&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix: Fix homepage not loading when hitting adding invalid URL during crawling. Fixes #626 - @MohamedBassem in dd20fb7&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feature: Allow setting bookmark metadata during creation - @MohamedBassem in 82cd3bb&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;docs: fix typo in inference.ts (#640) - @eltociear in 64e759a&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;translations: Add german, french and chinese LLM translations - @MohamedBassem in 0d6af2f&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feature: Add i18n support. Fixes #57 (#635) - @MohamedBassem in 4354ee7&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;docker: Upgrade meilisearch to v1.11.1 (#629) - @wuast94 in 9f2c7be&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix: Fix SummarizeWithAI button to use an ActionButton - @MohamedBassem in d73f001&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;docs: Release the 0.19 docs - @MohamedBassem in bff02d6&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;readme: Add RSS, REST API and video archival to README - @MohamedBassem in 6ccaec9&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/hoarder-app/hoarder/releases/tag/v0.20.0" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
