<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://selfh.st/apps</id>
  <title>Hoarder Releases</title>
  <updated>2024-10-06T18:31:57.166678-04:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>selfh.st</name>
    <email>contact@selfh.st</email>
  </author>
  <link href="https://selfh.st/apps" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>Self-hosted software releases generated by selfh.st</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/hoarder-app/hoarder/releases/tag/v0.14.0</id>
    <title>New release for Hoarder: 0.14.0</title>
    <updated>2024-05-23T20:02:54-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>MohamedBassem/hoarder-app</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the &lt;code&gt;0.14.0&lt;/code&gt; release of Hoarder! I want to welcome our two new contributors @kamtschatka who added a bunch of quality of life improvements and @lilacpixel who fixed a bunch of cosmetic issues in Hoarder! I also want to thank @Collectathon who published Hoarder's template on unraid which was a very popular request from unraid users!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note: You probably want to read the Upgrading section for that release. No breaking changes, but some recommendations are mentioned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Announcements&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hoarder is now available on the unraid store thanks to @Collectathon! The docs now include an unraid installation section &lt;a href="https://docs.hoarder.app/Installation/unraid"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The iOS app has finally been accepted in the app store (&lt;a href="https://apps.apple.com/gb/app/hoarder-app/id6479258022"&gt;link&lt;/a&gt;). Thanks a lot to all the beta testers during that time! You can still continue using TestPilot if you want the latest versions fasters, but you can also now switch to the prod version if you want stability.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;New Features&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Link deduping is here. When adding a link that you've hoarded before, it won't be re-added and instead you'll be prompted to go to your original link. When adding it from the browser extension, the existing bookmark's tags and lists will be shown allowing you to alter them if needed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Note: Unless you're on the latest mobile version, a deduped link will be silently ignored (without any visual indications). Upgrade to the latest version to get a message telling you that it already exists.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To quickly merge tags, @kamtschatka added support for dragging and dropping tags on each others to merge them together! To aid with the merging, you can now sort the tags in the "All tags" page by name instead of count.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can now batch add multiple links to the bookmark editor card (one per line) and hoarder will import them in one go.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hoarder can now take full page screenshots (instead of only the top of the page) thanks to @kamtschatka. This is disabled by default as it consumes a lot of space, but can be enabled by setting &lt;code&gt;CRAWLER_FULL_PAGE_SCREENSHOT=true&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In the list management dialog, you can now quickly archive a bookmark after adding it to lists. This is useful to those who follow &lt;code&gt;Inbox Zero&lt;/code&gt; for their homepage.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hoarder is now using openai's new model &lt;code&gt;gpt-4o&lt;/code&gt; by default for image tagging. It's faster and 50% cheaper!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Fixes&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Local tagging with Ollama is now more robust thanks to @kamtschatka refactoring the prompt a bit so that model doesn't lose context on what the instructions actually are.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bookmarks that were created in the same second (usually as part of a mass import) were sometimes skipped between pages. This is now fixed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A lot of cosmetic touches by @lilacpixel:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clicking on images in the bookmark list now opens the bookmark preview popup.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clicking on an image in the preview popup will open it in full quality in a new browser tab.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Long titles used to overflow in modals and in the bookmark grid. This is also fixed by @lilacpixel.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The bookmark preview popup's input fields now have full width to better show the available tags.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The tags in the tags editor are now sorted lexicographically.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Screenshots&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Link Deduping&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width="417" alt="Screenshot 2024-05-24 at 12 40 28 AM" src="https://github.com/hoarder-app/hoarder/assets/2418637/da0c6fa8-de12-4b0c-9ca2-9a6493aa1ddf"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;New Archive Button in "Manage Lists" Dialog&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width="501" alt="Screenshot 2024-05-24 at 12 41 05 AM" src="https://github.com/hoarder-app/hoarder/assets/2418637/c728a618-5686-4540-8e55-9d284fc2eebe"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Multi-URL import&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width="504" alt="Screenshot 2024-05-24 at 12 41 41 AM" src="https://github.com/hoarder-app/hoarder/assets/2418637/092bb332-aadf-4e9d-b534-869706ca8513"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Drag and Drop tag merging&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;https://github.com/hoarder-app/hoarder/assets/2418637/0e75625c-6295-4ced-b019-cf409f3ad7df&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Upgrading&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The repo got moved to its own organization, and the docker images unfortunately didn't get moved. which means you might want to update the docker images to the new urls. I'll keep updating the old images for the foreseeable future though. In your docker-compose file, change:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;ghcr.io/mohamedbassem/hoarder-web&lt;/code&gt; to &lt;code&gt;ghcr.io/hoarder-app/hoarder-web&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;ghcr.io/mohamedbassem/hoarder-workers&lt;/code&gt; to &lt;code&gt;ghcr.io/hoarder-app/hoarder-workers&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To improve chrome's stability for large pages, add &lt;code&gt;--disable-dev-shm-usage&lt;/code&gt; to the existing list of arguments of the chrome container.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To upgrade:
* If you're using HOARDER_VERSION=release, run &lt;code&gt;docker compose pull &amp;amp;&amp;amp; docker compose up -d&lt;/code&gt;.
* If you're pinning it to a specific version, upgrade the version and then run &lt;code&gt;docker compose pull &amp;amp;&amp;amp; docker compose up -d&lt;/code&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;All Commits&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;build: Attempt to fix docker permission error - @MohamedBassem in eac54e6&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;docker: Update docker images to point to the new repo URLs - @MohamedBassem in 6839289&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;docs: Change references from the old repo URL to the new one - @MohamedBassem in 1506ff0&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix(web): Stop pre-loading all the bookmark lists in the bookmark grid - @MohamedBassem in 8274d07&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feature(web): Add an archive button to list management dialog - @MohamedBassem in f99f4c0&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix(web): Sort the tags in the TagsEditor of the preview dialog. Fixes #171 - @MohamedBassem in bfcf0a4&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix: Fix missing bookmarks during pagination if they got created in the same second. Fixes #140 - @MohamedBassem in e8b4775&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feature(web): Allow adding multiple URLs at once #158 (#167) - @kamtschatka in d1ad84b&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ui(web): Set tag input field in preview modal to 100% width to fix overflow issues on select dropdown (#165) - @lilacpixel in cb62db7&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feature(inference): Improve ollama tagging (#162) - @kamtschatka in fdc27d3&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;docs: Add documentation for installing hoarder on unraid. Fixes #81 - @MohamedBassem in eb218ce&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix: Add the missing bookmark URL index migration - @MohamedBassem in c9dc23f&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix(web): Simplify the logic for tag drag and dropping - @MohamedBassem in e5fd9ee&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feature(web): Improve merging of tags by simple drag and drop #144 (#154) - @kamtschatka in 1fee129&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;build: An empty commit to fix vercel's build - @MohamedBassem in 6eea671&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feature(inference): Upgrade the default vision model to the new gpt-4o-2024-05-13 which is faster and 2x cheaper - @MohamedBassem in 168aed0&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feature(web): Clicking an image in the preview modal will open it in a new tab (#159) - @lilacpixel in c0aa6d5&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ui(web): Fixed overflow issues for very long titles (#152) - @lilacpixel in 747efa5&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feature(crawler): Allow connecting to browser's websocket address and launching the browser on demand. This enables support for browserless - @MohamedBassem in 39025a8&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feature(worker): Allow configuring redis with a password - @MohamedBassem in f64a5f3&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix(crawler): Add --disable-dev-shm-usage to chrome container - @MohamedBassem in 9b5ef3a&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feature(mobile): Show server address in the settings - @MohamedBassem in 8521580&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ui(mobile): Add horizontal margins to the bookmark cards - @MohamedBassem in e6c9ef4&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;tests: Add tests for bookmark deduplication - @MohamedBassem in ecfcba5&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feature: Take full page screenshots #143 (#148) - @kamtschatka in d33be14&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feature: Clicking preview for image assets brings up the details modal (#147) - @lilacpixel in cbc8dde&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Development Instructions are incomplete/not working (fixes #145) (#146) - @kamtschatka in 1e317d9&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;landing: Add google and ios badges to the landing page - @MohamedBassem in edf5fdb&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;readme: Add the iOS app store link to the readme and docs - @MohamedBassem in 7f3e482&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feature: Dedup links on creation. Fixes #49 - @MohamedBassem in 32b5a02&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;build: Add iOS and android builds to github actions - @MohamedBassem in 02ef4bf&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix(cli): Remove limit from array length when listing bookmarks. Fixes #135 - @MohamedBassem in 2ed134e&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;build: Add a workflow to auto publish the CLI to npm - @MohamedBassem in 79777bd&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix(cli): Allow bookmark listing to fetch all pages instead of only the first one. Fixes #135 - @MohamedBassem in 27f45d5&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix: Allow zod to coerce the crawler timeout from strings. Fixes #134 - @MohamedBassem in 81e49fa&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/hoarder-app/hoarder/releases/tag/v0.14.0" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/hoarder-app/hoarder/releases/tag/v0.15.0</id>
    <title>New release for Hoarder: 0.15.0</title>
    <updated>2024-07-06T07:01:10-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>MohamedBassem/hoarder-app</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the &lt;code&gt;0.15.0&lt;/code&gt; release of Hoarder! It's been a while since the previous release, but this release is packed with a lot of new quality of life improvements and features. This releases wouldn't have been possible without the tons of contributions from @kamtschatka, @mdsaban &amp;amp; @AhmadMuj. I also want to welcome our first time contributors @kou029w &amp;amp; @devome. If you're interested in helping us develop hoarder, you can join our #development channel on &lt;a href="https://discord.gg/NrgeYywsFh"&gt;hoarder's discord&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;New Features&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bulk actions are now a thing thanks to a contribution from @mdsaban. You can now bulk favourite, archive or delete bookmarks. In the next release, you'll be able to bulk add/remove bookmarks from lists.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Full page archival is now here (powered by &lt;a href="https://github.com/Y2Z/monolith"&gt;monolith&lt;/a&gt;). This will download everything that's in the page so that you can have an offline copy of that page even if that page disappears from the internet afterwards. The archives are typically quite large, so this feature is disabled by default. If you're a true hoarder, you can enable it with &lt;code&gt;CRAWLER_FULL_PAGE_ARCHIVE=true&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When you hoard a URL that points to a pdf or an image, Hoarder will now treat them as pdfs/images instead of links while keeping a reference to their original source. This will also allow automatic tagging to work correctly on those links. (thanks @kamtschatka!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can now import your chrome bookmarks (or any Netscape compatible bookmark file) by exporting them from chrome, then drag and drop the exported file to hoarder. All links in the export will be imported. (thanks @kamtschatka!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For those hoarding code snippets, @kamtschatka added syntax highlighting to code blocks and a way to quickly copy the block.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hoarder is now available on arch linux's user repo (AUR) and is maintained by @devome. A new wiki page with &lt;a href="https://docs.hoarder.app/Installation/archlinux"&gt;installation instructions&lt;/a&gt; is now available.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;UX Improvements&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;@mdsaban revamped how both the user and admin settings pages look like.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In the list layout, the editor will expand as you type longer notes thanks to @AhmadMuj.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can now paste images directly in the editor card and they'll get automatically uploaded thanks to @AhmadMuj.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Fixes&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The layout selector is now more clearly shown above the bookmark grid thanks to @mdsaban.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tags that were added manually were not correctly propagating to the search index. This is now fixed by @kamtschatka. You might want to trigger a reindex from the admin page if you've attached some manual tags.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;@kamtschatka fixed a long standing bug that prevented firefox users from using the browser extension without a valid HTTPS certificate.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The editor card previously allowed you to save empty notes, this has now been fixed by @mdsaban.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Increased list name max size to 40 chars up from 20.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We previously had an upper limit on note sizes that we removed a while ago. However, we forgot to remove it when editing a note. @AhmadMuj fixed that.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The CLI was previously printing invalid JSONs. Now there's a proper JSON mode thanks to @kamtschatka.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For CJK environments, there's now a sans-serif fallback font thanks to @kou029w.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Automatically inferred tags could have contained an extra space in the beginning of the tag, @kamtschatka fixed that.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Screenshots&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Bulk Editing in Action&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;https://github.com/hoarder-app/hoarder/assets/45597394/d8625dfe-dcb6-4b1f-91a6-8dbe289cebdb&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Revamped Admin Page&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="https://github.com/hoarder-app/hoarder/assets/2418637/cb375b37-c88e-453f-ab9b-55c2b309fa95" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Revamped Settings Page&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="https://github.com/hoarder-app/hoarder/assets/2418637/0aec69b0-89c7-4fc0-8003-a94b5cbb2793" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Full Page Archives&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width="1159" alt="Screenshot 2024-07-06 at 11 47 31 AM" src="https://github.com/hoarder-app/hoarder/assets/2418637/ba0c05d8-5194-4e2a-8c7e-bf02669252f1"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;PDF/Image URL recognition&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;https://github.com/hoarder-app/hoarder/assets/2418637/fa9f2323-f0f3-4ce3-9818-e4e65e32fa54&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Upgrading&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To upgrade:
* If you're using HOARDER_VERSION=release, run &lt;code&gt;docker compose pull &amp;amp;&amp;amp; docker compose up -d&lt;/code&gt;.
* If you're pinning it to a specific version, upgrade the version and then run &lt;code&gt;docker compose pull &amp;amp;&amp;amp; docker compose up -d&lt;/code&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;All Commits&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix(web): Add sans-serif fallback for Inter font in CJK environments (#272) by @kou029w  in #72f03b2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix: Renaming full page archive asset file doesn't work inside docker. Fixes #273 by @MohamedBassem in #5e9b04a&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feat: Add bulk edit option for bookmarks. Fixes #84 (#259) by @mdsaban in #d193d9b&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix: fixed an issue that would half the textarea in grid layout after submitting a bookmark (#269) by @kamtschatka in #bf92fa3&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;refactor: fixed typos in BookmarkTypes (#268) by @kamtschatka in #4e70fe3&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;refactor: drag and drop improvements (#264) by @kamtschatka in #9cd6170&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix: Increase list name size to max 40 chars up from 20. Fixes #254 by @MohamedBassem in #9883c6b&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix: Fix duplicate bookmarks in links with assets by @MohamedBassem in #3d495cd&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;refactor: added the bookmark type to the database (#256) by @kamtschatka in #e648646&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;refactor: remove redundant code from crawler worker and refactor handling of asset types (#253) by @kamtschatka in #ccbff18&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ui: refactor admin settings page (#249) by @mdsaban  in #e107f8b&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ui: Changes for user settings page (#251) by @mdsaban in #a637130&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feature: Automatically transfer image urls into bookmared assets. Fixes #246 by @MohamedBassem in #1071095&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ui(web): move layout selector to main screen (#252) by @mdsaban in #8f0e9b1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;refactor: extract assets into their own database table. #215 (#220) by @kamtschatka in #9ce6958&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix(landing): image width on landing page (#250) by @mdsaban in #0f54a18&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feature: add support for PDF links. Fixes #28 (#216) by @kamtschatka in #be1b7f7&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix(web): Fix save action on empty card. Fixes #225 (#243) by @mdsaban in #ccfff6b&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ui: Improve landing page for homepage (#238) by @mdsaban in #16f21bf&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feature(web): Enhance the bookmark textarea in the list layout (#247) by @AhmadMuj in #ac05ecf&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;readme: broken readme links (#233) by @mdsaban in #348bd80&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix: Remove the bookmark update text limit (#244) by @AhmadMuj in #671fc32&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix(web): text paste bug introduced with image paste (#232) by @mdsaban in #23faf46&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;docs: add Arch Linux installation docs (#223) by @devome in #dc19313&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feature(web): support pasting image in the Editor Card (#228) by @AhmadMuj in #6823caf&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;release(cli): Bump CLI version to 0.13.5 by @MohamedBassem in #219329b&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;release(cli): Bump CLI version to 0.13.4 by @MohamedBassem in #5f263a3&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix(cli): Bookmark list output is not a valid JSON. Fixes #150 (#181) by @kamtschatka in #cde9726&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;refactor: Extract the bookmark polling logic into a separate shared component by @MohamedBassem in #6928800&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix: Trigger search re-index on bookmark tag manual updates. Fixes #208 (#210) by @kamtschatka in #546139e&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feature(web): Add syntax highlighting to code blocks and a quick copy button. Fixes #195 (#197) by @kamtschatka in #be1bb38&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix(cli): Fix CLI version in help message. Fixes #139 by @MohamedBassem in #f7a7753&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feature(extension): Add a context menu to open your hoarder saves. Fixes #188 (#206) by @kamtschatka in #2d0af0b&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix(web): Changed the toast to contain a more detailed error message in case the bookmark is already part of the list. Fixes #179 (#213) by @kamtschatka in #049e79d&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix(workers): AI infered tags can contain " " at the beginning. Fixes #184 (#194) by @kamtschatka in #be8b91f&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix(crawler): Only update the database if full page archival is enabled by @MohamedBassem in #9d89f98&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;docs: Document the new CRAWLER_FULL_PAGE_ARCHIVE flag by @MohamedBassem in #9198c1b&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feature: Full page archival with monolith. Fixes #132 by @MohamedBassem in #dedc5fb&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feature: Allow import Netscape HTML format (#163) by @kamtschatka in #033e8a2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;build: Let the upload-artificat action do the compression by @MohamedBassem in #bb431be&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;release(extension): Bump extension version to 1.2.1 by @MohamedBassem in #8688dd4&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;build: Add a workflow to build the extension by @MohamedBassem in #c9b1307&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix(extension): Drop the https restriction in firefox. Fixes #23 by @kamtschatka in #875cc35&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix(cli): Switched to cursorV2 to make use of the fix for #140 and prevent infinite loops (#176) by @kamtschatka in #6dc67cf&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/hoarder-app/hoarder/releases/tag/v0.15.0" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/hoarder-app/hoarder/releases/tag/v0.16.0</id>
    <title>New release for Hoarder: 0.16.0</title>
    <updated>2024-08-31T14:44:19-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>MohamedBassem/hoarder-app</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the &lt;code&gt;0.16.0&lt;/code&gt; release of Hoarder. Sorry for the long delay since the last release! We'd like to welcome to our first time contributors @Mxrk, @j-fuentes &amp;amp; @rootly-be!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NOTE: This release is backward compatible with the previous release, but it's highly recommended that you check out the &lt;code&gt;Upgrading&lt;/code&gt; section in the release notes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;New Features&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deploying Hoarder is now simpler. We're getting rid of two containers in this release:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Redis is no longer needed as a dependency and is replaced by a sqlite-backed queue implementation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There's now a new container that acts as both the &lt;code&gt;web&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;workers&lt;/code&gt; container. You no longer need two different hoarder containers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The old images will continue to work just fine for the foreseeable future to make this release backward compatible. Upgrading to the new image is highly recommended though.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;gpt-4o-mini&lt;/code&gt; is now the default OpenAI model. This model is 3X cheaper than the previous default!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The mobile app received a bunch of overdue updates:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added the ability to manage bookmark lists from the app.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can now add/remove lists from the app.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can view full notes by tapping on the notes card and you can now edit them as well&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can zoom into uploaded images.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can add/view attached notes to bookmarks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There's now a unified editor for new links and notes. Still pretty basic though.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can now configure the image quality of the uploaded images. Keep in mind that for large images, you might want to increase &lt;code&gt;MAX_ASSET_SIZE_MB&lt;/code&gt; from the default of &lt;code&gt;4MB&lt;/code&gt;, otherwise, you'll get an &lt;code&gt;Asset too big&lt;/code&gt; error.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hoarder's notes now support checklists, tables and auto-links in markdown thanks to @kamtschatka&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you have the browser extension installed, you'll find now a new &lt;code&gt;Add to Hoarder&lt;/code&gt; button that you can use to send links, texts, images, to hoarder directly. Note: If you're using chrome, you'll need to be on v127 or older. Thanks @kamtschatka!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;@j-fuentes added &lt;a href="https://docs.hoarder.app/Installation/kubernetes"&gt;kubernetes installation instruction&lt;/a&gt; to the wiki.  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;UX Improvements&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When renaming bookmark titles or tags, pressing Enter will save the changes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Fixes&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Importing a lot of URLs from the UI used to error, this no longer the case thanks @kamtschatka.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SVG weren't correctly loading in full page archives using monolith, @kamtschatka fixed it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bulk deletion confirmation dialog wasn't automatically dismissed after the deletion. This is now fixed by @kamtschatka.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;On the mobile app, login fails if your server URL had an extra slash at the end. @Mxrk fixed that!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Upgrading&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;⚠️ If you have ongoing crawlings/inference/indexing jobs in Hoarder, you'll need to re-enqueue them from the admin panel after the upgrade.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As mentioned in the release notes, this release removes the need for the &lt;code&gt;redis&lt;/code&gt; container and the worker container. Although the migration is optional given that the old images will work, it's highly recommended, to migrate, you'll need to do the following:
1. Remove the redis container and its volume if it had one.
2. Move the environment variables that you've set exclusively to the &lt;code&gt;workers&lt;/code&gt; container to the &lt;code&gt;web&lt;/code&gt; container.
3. Delete the &lt;code&gt;workers&lt;/code&gt; container.
4. Rename the web container image from &lt;code&gt;hoarder-app/hoarder-web&lt;/code&gt; to &lt;code&gt;hoarder-app/hoarder&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The diff for the compose file will look something like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;```diff
diff --git a/docker/docker-compose.yml b/docker/docker-compose.yml
index cdfc908..6297563 100644
--- a/docker/docker-compose.yml
+++ b/docker/docker-compose.yml
@@ -1,7 +1,7 @@
 version: "3.8"
 services:
   web:
-    image: ghcr.io/hoarder-app/hoarder-web:${HOARDER_VERSION:-release}
+    image: ghcr.io/hoarder-app/hoarder:${HOARDER_VERSION:-release}
     restart: unless-stopped
     volumes:
       - data:/data
@@ -10,14 +10,10 @@ services:
     env_file:
       - .env
     environment:
-      REDIS_HOST: redis
       MEILI_ADDR: http://meilisearch:7700
+      BROWSER_WEB_URL: http://chrome:9222
+      # OPENAI_API_KEY: ...
       DATA_DIR: /data
-  redis:
-    image: redis:7.2-alpine
-    restart: unless-stopped
-    volumes:
-      - redis:/data
   chrome:
     image: gcr.io/zenika-hub/alpine-chrome:123
     restart: unless-stopped
@@ -37,24 +33,7 @@ services:
       MEILI_NO_ANALYTICS: "true"
     volumes:
       - meilisearch:/meili_data
-  workers:
-    image: ghcr.io/hoarder-app/hoarder-workers:${HOARDER_VERSION:-release}
-    restart: unless-stopped
-    volumes:
-      - data:/data
-    env_file:
-      - .env
-    environment:
-      REDIS_HOST: redis
-      MEILI_ADDR: http://meilisearch:7700
-      BROWSER_WEB_URL: http://chrome:9222
-      DATA_DIR: /data
-      # OPENAI_API_KEY: ...
-    depends_on:
-      web:
-        condition: service_started&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;volumes:
-  redis:
   meilisearch:
   data:
```&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To upgrade:
* If you're using HOARDER_VERSION=release, run &lt;code&gt;docker compose pull &amp;amp;&amp;amp; docker compose up -d&lt;/code&gt;.
* If you're pinning it to a specific version, upgrade the version and then run &lt;code&gt;docker compose pull &amp;amp;&amp;amp; docker compose up -d&lt;/code&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;All Commits&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feature(mobile): Allow interacting with images in the app. Fixes #352 - @MohamedBassem in 2fb8559&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feature(mobile): Add support for deleting lists - @MohamedBassem in 7593982&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feature(mobile): Allow configuring uploaded image quality in the mobile app - @MohamedBassem in fdf055a&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feature(mobile): Add ability to create basic lists from the app - @MohamedBassem in 1405540&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;release(mobile): Bump mobile version to 1.6.1 - @MohamedBassem in 410b0e7&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ui(mobile): Merge the editors for notes and links - @MohamedBassem in 49dc06e&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feature(mobile): Change the view bookmark page to be a modal and add tags and notes - @MohamedBassem in b094b2c&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ui(mobile): Change the add/edit note editor dialogs to be bottom sheets - @MohamedBassem in 8410a6d&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feature(mobile): Allow editing notes from the mobile app - @MohamedBassem in d8cf7c1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix(mobile): trim slash from url on signin. Fixes #311 (#361) - @Mxrk :) in 6fba4aa&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix(mobile): Allow expanding the text by clicking on bookmark card - @MohamedBassem in 0584ad2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix(mobile): Change the next note text input to have multiple lines by default - @MohamedBassem in dc68b44&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[docker] Adding chrome-service.yaml and adapt kustomization.yaml. Fixes #357 (#358) - @rootly-be in 809a9bc&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix(extension): Upgrade crxjs to 2.0 to add support for firefox - @MohamedBassem in 485276e&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;release(extension): Release version 1.2.2 - @MohamedBassem in 99b24bc&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[extension] Add context menu item in the browser extension. Fixes #155 (#278) - @kamtschatka in 0710147&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix(mobile): Change the hoarded page to no longer be a modal to allow AddToList to work - @MohamedBassem in c7f9feb&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;docs: Add Kubernetes installation with Kustomize (#324) - @j-fuentes in 7ddfcad&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;release(mobile): Bump mobile version to 1.6.0 - @MohamedBassem in 1ca951a&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feat(mobile): Add ability to manage lists - @MohamedBassem in 93afb75&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix(workers): Shutdown workers on SIGTERM - @MohamedBassem in 92c92c1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;docker: Change all images to be built from the same AIO base - @MohamedBassem in c72dbd0&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feat: Upgrade default openai models to gpt-4o-mini which are 3x cheaper - @MohamedBassem in b74bee8&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;cli: Extract tag management into separate subcommand - @MohamedBassem in f6ecef8&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;release(cli): Bump CLI version to 0.13.6 - @MohamedBassem in 4f661c4&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feature(cli): Allow updating tags/lists from CLI (#211) - @kamtschatka in 5e4decb&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;refactor: Remove unused BookmarkedTextViewer (#310) - @kamtschatka in eb0a28e&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;build: Add an all-in-one container - @MohamedBassem in 98fc559&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix: async/await issues with the new queue (#319) - @kamtschatka in c5c62de&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;chore(deps): Upgrade turbo and disable its daemon - @MohamedBassem in 4c23ea9&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;refactor: Replace the usage of bullMQ with the hoarder sqlite-based queue (#309) - @MohamedBassem in 9edd154&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[docs] Change the docs to versioned - @MohamedBassem in edbd98d&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feature: Add github markdown support which includes tables, checklists and auto links #300 (#302) - @kamtschatka in 888dad6&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;chore: Add a new sqlite based queue package - @MohamedBassem in f77a41a&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix: monolith not embedding SVG files correctly. Fixes #289 (#306) - @kamtschatka in aa3dce0&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix: Fix TRPC batchign failure because of long URLs. Fixes #281 (#291) - @kamtschatka in a222564&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feature(web): Save title and tag name changes on enter. Fixes #283 (#293) - @kamtschatka in 1396dd2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix: Delete confirmation doesn't disappear after bulk deletion of links using WebUI. Fixes #290 (#292) - @kamtschatka in e65aadb&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;chore: added a new table to store the config in the database (#279) - @kamtschatka in ee167be&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;landing: update landing page to include bulk actions - @MohamedBassem in 6a8d839&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix(web): Suppress hydration warnings caused by the dates in the bookmark grid - @MohamedBassem in d7fff89&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/hoarder-app/hoarder/releases/tag/v0.16.0" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/hoarder-app/hoarder/releases/tag/v0.17.0</id>
    <title>New release for Hoarder: 0.17.0</title>
    <updated>2024-09-22T12:25:00-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>MohamedBassem/hoarder-app</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the &lt;code&gt;0.17.0&lt;/code&gt; release of Hoarder. We have a bunch of new features and UX improvements including SSO support (finally), bulk tag/list actions, better bookmark importing experience, and bunch of other stuff. In this release, we're welcoming @nghduc97  and @Mxrk as first time contributors!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you're enjoying Hoarder, you can consider supporting it &lt;a href="https://buymeacoffee.com/mbassem"&gt;here ☕️&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;New Features&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Single Sign On (SSO) support is finally here for OIDC compliant providers. This was the most requested feature and it's now here thanks to @kamtschatka. You can read about how to configure it &lt;a href="https://docs.hoarder.app/configuration#authentication--signup"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We've done multiple improvements to the bookmark importing experience:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bookmark importing now live in the settings page.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can now import bookmarks from a Pocket export.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Imported bookmarks will keep their title, tags and creation date.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A new list will be created that will include all your newly imported bookmarks. You can remove/rename this list after making sure that everything went according to plan.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can now customize the banner image for links and manipulate all its other attachments in the bookmark preview page.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can now bulk add/remove tags and lists to bookmarks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some mobile app improvements:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In case you were facing issues connecting to hoarder from the app, there's now a "Connection testing" functionality that shows you a more descriptive issue about the problem you're hitting.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The app was by default following the theme (e.g. light/dark mode) of the system. You can now configure explicitly the theme that you want in the settings.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There's a new floating quick add button to quickly save new bookmarks from within the app.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For ollama users, you can now configure the timeout of the inference worker in case ollama's responses are slow. You can also configure a model keep alive TTL so that ollama can drop the model from memory if it's not used for that configure period. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We have a new compact layout to quickly skim through your bookmarks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;UX Improvements&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In the tags editor, you can now quickly remove the last tags by pressing backspace.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The tags editor will now feel much faster by optimistically applying the changes before they are committed on the server.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;On the mobile app, server errors (e.g. connection errors) will have a much better UI indicating the problem and giving you an option to retry.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lists are now sorted alphabetically thanks to @kamtschatka.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Signup dialog now shows a less confusing message when signups are disabled thanks @nghduc97&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Fixes&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Completely deleting a tag was broken, now it's fixed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Screenshots&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;New Mobile Settings Page&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width="386" alt="Screenshot 2024-09-22 at 4 58 33 PM" src="https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/f351c0db-9b7c-48d1-b0ca-76f2c34766fa"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Connection Testing&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width="407" alt="Screenshot 2024-09-22 at 4 52 07 PM" src="https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/70d46ff9-ded8-497f-8203-489021cb4763"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;SSO Support&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width="407" alt="Screenshot 2024-09-22 at 4 52 33 PM" src="https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/8b653987-d923-420a-8b14-2cffd3f7327a"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Compact Layout&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width="1401" alt="Screenshot 2024-09-22 at 4 53 46 PM" src="https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/6cac935c-5ecf-4d65-be92-809811a02104"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;New Import UI&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width="711" alt="Screenshot 2024-09-22 at 4 57 14 PM" src="https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/7cd6ceeb-951f-47b4-ab14-0f6827b5f4a9"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;New Bulk Actions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width="425" alt="Screenshot 2024-09-22 at 4 55 52 PM" src="https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/089d6f2e-4c86-4721-9bd1-c16cc21bb473"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;New Attachments Section&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width="478" alt="Screenshot 2024-09-22 at 4 55 14 PM" src="https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/067bf3c9-391d-4a27-80d0-e4f516141481"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Upgrading&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To upgrade:
* If you're using HOARDER_VERSION=release, run &lt;code&gt;docker compose pull &amp;amp;&amp;amp; docker compose up -d&lt;/code&gt;.
* If you're pinning it to a specific version, upgrade the version and then run &lt;code&gt;docker compose pull &amp;amp;&amp;amp; docker compose up -d&lt;/code&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;All Commits&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix(web): Show a scrollbar in the tag editor. Fixes #368 (#404) by @kamtschatka in d0e7ca2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feature(web): Show attachments and allow users to manipulate them. by @MohamedBassem in a770e55&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;release: Release mobile and extension to include SSO changes by @MohamedBassem in 55f5c7f&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feature(mobile): Allow users to login with API keys in the mobile app by @MohamedBassem in 5fe330c&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feature(extension): Allow login directly with an API key by @kamtschatka in 26521b7&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feature(web): Add support for importing bookmarks from Pocket by @MohamedBassem in 9dd6f21&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feature(web): Preserve title, tags and createdAt when importing a netscape html. Fixes #401 by @MohamedBassem in d62c972&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feature(web): Move bookmark imports into settings by @MohamedBassem in 52024ab&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;refactor: Extract useUpload into its own reusable hook by @MohamedBassem in 6b5c597&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feature(web): Add healthecheck api endpoint (#332) by @Mxrk in 3377969&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;build: Fix nextjs build after upgrading to 14.2 by @MohamedBassem in 7cd857c&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;deps: Upgrade turbo by @MohamedBassem in 8fa2009&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;deps: Upgrade nextjs to 14.2.13 by @MohamedBassem in 55201db&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;docs: Fix docs build and add sso to readme by @MohamedBassem in e585ce6&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix(web): Better message when signups are disabled (#374) by @nghduc97 in 34fb5fb&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feature: Added support for custom OIDC providers to set up authentication. Fixes #92 (#307) by @kamtschatka in b9724b7&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;deps: Upgrade drizzle and next auth drizzle adapter by @MohamedBassem in 80749d5&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix: Fix deleting tags broken due to wrong column name by @MohamedBassem in fb63f55&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feature(web): Alphabetical sorting for lists. Fixes #315 (#351) by @kamtschatka in 064d5f8&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feature(web): Add a compact layout. Fixes #379 by @MohamedBassem in 47939a5&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feature(worker): Allow configuring inference job timeout and ollama keep alive. Fixes #389 #224 by @MohamedBassem in f263f9e&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix(web): removing referrer header when clicking on links. Fixes #387 (#388) by @kamtschatka in 3b8cebb&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix(mobile): Fix some icon colors in dark mode by @MohamedBassem in 095995d&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feature(mobile): Add a page for testing connection to server by @MohamedBassem in 3452e47&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feature(mobile): Add settings page for configuring the theme by @MohamedBassem in 66fcf02&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feature(mobile): Add proper error handling for server errors by @MohamedBassem in b9c7857&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;docs: Update screenshots in docs by @MohamedBassem in 09e16ba&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;release(mobile): Bump mobile version to 1.6.2 by @MohamedBassem in 21aaf83&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feature(mobile): Show the view bookmark modal for links as well by @MohamedBassem in cddae8f&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feature(mobile): Add a floating button for quickly adding new bookmarks by @MohamedBassem in 2bfa73f&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;readme: Add full page archive and bulk actions to readme by @MohamedBassem in 3944505&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix(web): Add optimistic rendering for the tags editor by @MohamedBassem in 300f3c5&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feature(web): Manage tags in bulk actions by @MohamedBassem in 67729c1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feature(web): Pop tag in TagEditor on pressing backspace. #368 by @MohamedBassem in 6d4d1a6&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feature(web): Show the number of bulk selected bookmarks by @MohamedBassem in 77adb84&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feature(web): Allow adding to lists in bulk actions. #368 by @MohamedBassem in ddc7e5d&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/hoarder-app/hoarder/releases/tag/v0.17.0" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/hoarder-app/hoarder/releases/tag/v0.17.1</id>
    <title>New release for Hoarder: 0.17.1</title>
    <updated>2024-09-27T04:41:05-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>MohamedBassem/hoarder-app</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;This is a small hotfix for the &lt;a href="https://github.com/hoarder-app/hoarder/releases/tag/v0.17.0"&gt;0.17.0 release&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;🐞 Fixes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When importing bookmarks from a netscape html file, there was a bug that would result in the importing bookmarks getting all of your tags. This is fixed in https://github.com/hoarder-app/hoarder/commit/12d3371d12d5709adc6e23b53792cf1dc28a8a06 &amp;amp; https://github.com/hoarder-app/hoarder/commit/4db50c234fb0da8747b902a7c1e551cc54451f4c.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A "name" is no longer required from SSO providers. @kamtschatka fixed that in https://github.com/hoarder-app/hoarder/commit/e1feeceda475b117dde99a971f87e20a149f7edf.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/hoarder-app/hoarder/releases/tag/v0.17.1" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
