<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://selfh.st/apps</id>
  <title>Hoarder Releases</title>
  <updated>2024-04-17T03:32:25.392365-04:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>selfh.st</name>
    <email>contact@selfh.st</email>
  </author>
  <link href="https://selfh.st/apps" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>Self-hosted software releases generated by selfh.st</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/MohamedBassem/hoarder-app/releases/tag/v0.10.1</id>
    <title>New release for Hoarder: 0.10.1</title>
    <updated>2024-03-27T19:42:02-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>MohamedBassem/hoarder-app</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;Mostly a lot of minor fixes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix: Attempt to increase the reliability of the ollama inference by working around some of the errors in the ollama package.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix: There was a limit of 2k chars on notes. This is no longer there.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix: When a bookmark is deleted in the search page, it wasn't getting removed from the grid. This is now fixed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feature: In the editor card, you can now save the bookmark by pressing &lt;code&gt;Ctrl + Enter&lt;/code&gt; as well as the &lt;code&gt;Cmd + Enter&lt;/code&gt;. This should be more intuitive to windows users.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feature: You can now upload webp images.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feature: Maximum asset size was 4MB. Now it's configurable with the &lt;code&gt;MAX_ASSET_SIZE_MB&lt;/code&gt; env variable. This variable still defaults to 4MB.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ui: Red destructive color looks slightly better now in dark mode.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/MohamedBassem/hoarder-app/releases/tag/v0.10.1" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/MohamedBassem/hoarder-app/releases/tag/v0.11.0</id>
    <title>New release for Hoarder: 0.11.0</title>
    <updated>2024-04-02T13:14:22-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>MohamedBassem/hoarder-app</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the v0.11.0 release of Hoarder. This packs a bunch of new stuff and fixes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;New Features&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There's now a CLI tool to enable mass manipulations for your bookmarks. You can use it, for example, to mass import bookmarks from your previous tool. Check its docs &lt;a href="https://docs.hoarder.app/command-line"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, and you can check the initial version of importing bookmarks docs &lt;a href="https://docs.hoarder.app/import"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can now attach notes to your bookmarks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can now delete tags in the tag view page.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;code&gt;All Tags&lt;/code&gt; page now differentiates between manually attached tags and AI attached tags.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can specify the language of the auto generated tags with &lt;code&gt;INFERENCE_LANG=&amp;lt;lang&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; env variable. It currently defaults to &lt;code&gt;english&lt;/code&gt;. Thanks @COOHU-Kr for the suggestion!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The web UI now allows uploading multiple images at the same time. &lt;code&gt;Webp&lt;/code&gt; support also got added.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clicking &lt;code&gt;⌘ + E&lt;/code&gt; or (&lt;code&gt;ctrl + E&lt;/code&gt;) will now focus on the new bookmark editor. Thanks @chanunnaki for the idea!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Current server version is now shown in the admin panel. It'll also check github API to know if there are new version. You can disable the new version check with &lt;code&gt;DISABLE_NEW_RELEASE_CHECK=true&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In case you missed it, the android app is almost there (under google's mercy). If you can't wait, you can download the APK from &lt;a href="https://github.com/MohamedBassem/hoarder-app/issues/6"&gt;this issue&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Fixes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Search results are now sorted by relevance.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In some rare instances, the crawler was getting stuck parsing some pages preventing any other links from getting crawled. There's now a 30s timeout to solve this problem.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix the &lt;code&gt;sharp is missing&lt;/code&gt; error in the &lt;code&gt;web&lt;/code&gt; container logs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When logging out, people were getting redirected to &lt;code&gt;localhost:3000&lt;/code&gt; by mistake. Add &lt;code&gt;NEXTAUTH_URL=&amp;lt;server_url&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; to your env file to fix that. The installation docs has been updated.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Upgrade&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[Optional but hightly recommended] The initial docker compose was using an old chrome version (&lt;code&gt;v100&lt;/code&gt;). Bump the chrome container version to &lt;code&gt;v123&lt;/code&gt; by changing the chrome container image:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;from: &lt;code&gt;gcr.io/zenika-hub/alpine-chrome:100&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;to: &lt;code&gt;gcr.io/zenika-hub/alpine-chrome:123&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you're using &lt;code&gt;HOARDER_VERSION=release&lt;/code&gt;, run &lt;code&gt;docker compose pull &amp;amp;&amp;amp; docker compose up -d&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you're pinning it to a specific version, upgrade the version and then run &lt;code&gt;docker compose pull &amp;amp;&amp;amp; docker compose up -d&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Some screenshots from the release&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The new &lt;code&gt;All Tags&lt;/code&gt; page&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width="1292" alt="Screenshot 2024-04-02 at 5 20 16 PM" src="https://github.com/MohamedBassem/hoarder-app/assets/2418637/b99850e0-25e6-4b99-aaf6-f9ae0977731f"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Attaching notes to bookmarks&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width="363" alt="Screenshot 2024-04-02 at 5 20 49 PM" src="https://github.com/MohamedBassem/hoarder-app/assets/2418637/f6ac2a64-2c16-45d4-9987-8e536c35e438"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Server version in admin panel&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width="514" alt="Screenshot 2024-04-02 at 5 20 28 PM" src="https://github.com/MohamedBassem/hoarder-app/assets/2418637/7605f9c2-3196-4d52-a081-9ef72a541b0d"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The new CLI&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width="758" alt="Screenshot 2024-04-02 at 5 24 25 PM" src="https://github.com/MohamedBassem/hoarder-app/assets/2418637/0106253f-276d-47d4-8b5c-58061fd56d16"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/MohamedBassem/hoarder-app/releases/tag/v0.11.0" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/MohamedBassem/hoarder-app/releases/tag/v0.11.1</id>
    <title>New release for Hoarder: 0.11.1</title>
    <updated>2024-04-03T11:46:28-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>MohamedBassem/hoarder-app</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;This is a small hotfix release for v0.11.0.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;5ef2efe fix: Incorrect counts for tags in the AllTags page. Fixes #78&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/MohamedBassem/hoarder-app/releases/tag/v0.11.1" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/MohamedBassem/hoarder-app/releases/tag/v0.12.0</id>
    <title>New release for Hoarder: 0.12.0</title>
    <updated>2024-04-15T15:38:06-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>MohamedBassem/hoarder-app</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the &lt;code&gt;0.12.0&lt;/code&gt; release of hoarder! This release is special because we have our first full feature contribution by @AhmadMuj. Welcome to the contributors list @AhmadMuj! If you're interested in helping us develop hoarder, you can join the new &lt;code&gt;#development&lt;/code&gt; channel on &lt;a href="https://discord.gg/NrgeYywsFh"&gt;hoarder's discord&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;New Features&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Raspberry Pi support is now here!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can now upload pdfs and get them indexed and automatically tagged thanks to @AhmadMuj!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can now change the layout of the bookmark list. We're starting with three layouts:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Masonry&lt;/code&gt; which was the layout used before that release.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Grid&lt;/code&gt; where every card has a fixed height resulting in a strict grid.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;List&lt;/code&gt; which shows all bookmarks under each other in a list (screenshot attached later in the release notes).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Previously, you were only allowed to upload items from the homepage. Now you can upload directly in a list, tag or even the favourited/archived list.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Previously, the admin panel only allowed you to recrawl all bookmarks. @AhmadMuj added support for only crawling the failed ones (and showed some stats about them there as well).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The default OpenAI image model got upgraded to the new &lt;code&gt;gpt-4-turbo&lt;/code&gt; which should be more robust and accurate while costing the same.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can now add titles to bookmarks (and edit existing ones). Uploaded assets (images and pdfs) now automatically get their filename as a title. A new bookmark action bar got added to the bookmark preview page.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Changes in Behavior&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Previously, archived items were hidden from almost everywhere except the archived list which made it not very different from just deleting the item. Starting from this release, &lt;code&gt;archived&lt;/code&gt; items are only hidden from the homepage but will continue appearing in lists, search, etc. This is more aligned with other bookmark managers (e.g. pocket). With this change, you can now use &lt;code&gt;archiving&lt;/code&gt; to achieve &lt;code&gt;Inbox Zero&lt;/code&gt; on your homepage by archiving the items that no longer require your attention or articles that you've already read.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Fixes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Crawling robustness:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Default crawling timeout increased from &lt;code&gt;30s&lt;/code&gt; to &lt;code&gt;60s&lt;/code&gt; and default navigation timeout increase from &lt;code&gt;10s&lt;/code&gt; to &lt;code&gt;30s&lt;/code&gt;.  Both can now be controlled with the env variables &lt;code&gt;CRAWLER_JOB_TIMEOUT_SEC&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;CRAWLER_NAVIGATE_TIMEOUT_SEC&lt;/code&gt; respectively. You might want to increase them further if you're running hoarder on a low-perf machine or have a slow internet connection.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Crawling jobs are now retried 5 times before giving up on them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Crawler error messages are now more descriptive to help debug issues.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You no longer need to refresh the &lt;code&gt;All tags&lt;/code&gt; page when tags are changed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When a user is deleted, their on disk assets were not correctly deleted. This is now fixed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed error when adding notes with a colon in the first word.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Screenshots of the new features&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The new action bar in the preview page along with the new support for editing titles.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width="378" alt="Screenshot 2024-04-15 at 8 19 31 PM" src="https://github.com/MohamedBassem/hoarder-app/assets/2418637/d34b8bbf-b15f-4644-a1ca-7b63aa356baa"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The new &lt;code&gt;List&lt;/code&gt; view and its toggles.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width="380" alt="Screenshot 2024-04-15 at 8 18 54 PM" src="https://github.com/MohamedBassem/hoarder-app/assets/2418637/f1e6548b-2db0-4387-be2e-69585960938b"&gt;
&lt;img width="1050" alt="Screenshot 2024-04-15 at 8 19 06 PM" src="https://github.com/MohamedBassem/hoarder-app/assets/2418637/b5a6d17f-590e-41fb-8544-8b9decebad3c"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;PDF support&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width="341" alt="Screenshot 2024-04-15 at 8 33 36 PM" src="https://github.com/MohamedBassem/hoarder-app/assets/2418637/a7839791-8fa8-4e7b-8322-98daa0464a36"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Upgrade&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you're using &lt;code&gt;HOARDER_VERSION=release&lt;/code&gt;, run &lt;code&gt;docker compose pull &amp;amp;&amp;amp; docker compose up -d&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you're pinning it to a specific version, upgrade the version and then run &lt;code&gt;docker compose pull &amp;amp;&amp;amp; docker compose up -d&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;All Commits&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feature: Add title to bookmarks and allow editing them. Fixes #27 by @MohamedBassem in #81e0b28&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix(web): Fix some JS console errors in the preview page by @MohamedBassem in #5c9acb1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feature(web): Allow changing the bookmark grid layout (#98) by @MohamedBassem in #4f17ea6&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix: Differentiate between pending in db and in redis in admin job stats by @MohamedBassem in #cf0df0e&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feature: Recrawl failed links from admin UI (#95) by @AhmadMuj in #95cf8f4&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix: Increase default navigation timeout to 30s, make it configurable and add retries to crawling jobs by @MohamedBassem in #238c296&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feature: Add PDF support (#88) by @AhmadMuj in #be622e5&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feature(inference): Upgrade the default vision model to the new gpt-4-turbo by @MohamedBassem in #2806701&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix(crawler): Skip validating URLs in metascrapper as it was already being validated. Fixes #22 by @MohamedBassem in #a9242a5&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix: Delete the API key on logout from phone or extension by @MohamedBassem in #f696d33&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix(web): Fix the toggle theme button allowing clicks from anywhere in the dropdown item by @MohamedBassem in #5ab6c33&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix: Fix type in the useAddBookmarkToList hook by @MohamedBassem in #cae543c&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feature(web): Allow uploading directly into lists/tags. Fixes #69 by @MohamedBassem in #fe13408&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;refactor(web): Move the tooltip provider to the root of the app by @MohamedBassem in #994691b&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feature: Extract hook logic into separate package and add a new action bar in bookmark preview by @MohamedBassem in #79d61be&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix(workers): Increase default timeout to 60s, make it configurable and improve logging by @MohamedBassem in #4491831&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix(docker): Remove BUILDPLATFORM from Dockerfile by @MohamedBassem in #e0bb1fc&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix: Refresh the all tags page automatically when a tag is modified by @MohamedBassem in #044659f&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ui(web): Add a tooltip explaining what archived means by @MohamedBassem in #4cf9908&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix: Only consider text as URL in editor card if it has an http protocol. Fixes #86 by @MohamedBassem in #bc6ee2e&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feature: Change archived meaning to only mean removed from homepage by @MohamedBassem in #a81c394&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix: Delete user's assets when the user is deleted by @MohamedBassem in #91b088d&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;build: Increment android app versionCode by @MohamedBassem in #8af95fe&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/MohamedBassem/hoarder-app/releases/tag/v0.12.0" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/MohamedBassem/hoarder-app/releases/tag/v0.12.1</id>
    <title>New release for Hoarder: 0.12.1</title>
    <updated>2024-04-15T19:09:29-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>MohamedBassem/hoarder-app</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;This is a small hotfix for the &lt;a href="https://github.com/MohamedBassem/hoarder-app/releases/tag/v0.12.0"&gt;0.12.0 release&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix: Fix slice call in the content truncation logic which was resulting in excessive usage of context tokens. Fixes #94 by @MohamedBassem in #4629dac&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The bug fixed in this release resulted into mistakingly truncating the first 1500 words in large contents during tag inference (instead of taking only the first 1500 words). This had two side effects for bookmarks with a lot of content (&amp;gt; 1500 words):
1. Due to the truncation of the first 1500 words, you might have got some sub optimal tags for content with &amp;gt;1500 words.
2. For bookmarks with huge content size, you might have got inference failures due to hitting the context limits of the models you're using. And for the ones that were under the context size, they might have taken longer and used more credits than intended.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If this is a problem for you, you can trigger a re-index for the affected bookmarks.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/MohamedBassem/hoarder-app/releases/tag/v0.12.1" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
