<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://selfh.st/apps</id>
  <title>Immich Power Tools Releases</title>
  <updated>2024-08-23T10:33:10.457066-04:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>selfh.st</name>
    <email>contact@selfh.st</email>
  </author>
  <link href="https://selfh.st/apps" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>Self-hosted software releases generated by selfh.st</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/varun-raj/immich-power-tools/releases/tag/v0.1.3</id>
    <title>New release for Immich Power Tools: v0.1.3 - Potential Albums</title>
    <updated>2024-08-19T23:31:38-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>varun-raj/immich-power-tools</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h3&gt;Feature Overview:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We're excited to introduce a new asset organizing tool in Immich Power Tools: Potential Albums!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Automatically identify and suggest new albums based on unorganized photos grouped by date.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If a set of photos exceeds a certain threshold (yet to be finalized) and isn’t part of an existing album, the tool will suggest creating a new album.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This helps in organizing your timeline, making it easier to look back on your trips, conferences, or special moments as a whole.
Why This Feature?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During a recent import of photos from Google Photos, it became apparent that many photos from various events were not properly organized into albums. These photos were scattered across the timeline, making it difficult to reflect on specific events. To solve this, Potential Albums aims to help you easily identify and organize these photos into albums.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Feedback:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first version is live! Check it out in the repo: &lt;a href="https://github.com/varun-raj/immich-power-tools"&gt;Immich Power Tools&lt;/a&gt;. Your feedback and suggestions are highly appreciated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you like the feature, please give the repo a star ⭐️!&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/varun-raj/immich-power-tools/releases/tag/v0.1.3" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/varun-raj/immich-power-tools/releases/tag/v0.1.4</id>
    <title>New release for Immich Power Tools: v0.1.4</title>
    <updated>2024-08-20T01:41:46-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>varun-raj/immich-power-tools</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h3&gt;Dockerized&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With help of @sai80082 this project now runs on docker.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/varun-raj/immich-power-tools/releases/tag/v0.1.4" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/varun-raj/immich-power-tools/releases/tag/v0.1.5</id>
    <title>New release for Immich Power Tools: v0.1.5 - Fixes and production ready setup</title>
    <updated>2024-08-20T02:40:10-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>varun-raj/immich-power-tools</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;Finally I've stabilized the docker and production build.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fixes some bugs and dark theme issues.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/varun-raj/immich-power-tools/releases/tag/v0.1.5" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/varun-raj/immich-power-tools/releases/tag/v0.1.6</id>
    <title>New release for Immich Power Tools: 0.1.6 People Filtering &amp; Sorting</title>
    <updated>2024-08-21T13:16:34-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>varun-raj/immich-power-tools</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;One of the biggest challenge I faced when I migrated from Google photos to immich is that there are roughly around 10,000 faces I need to map to people, sadly Immich doesn’t support any filtering and sorting for this which made it pretty difficult for me to map them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today I tried to solve it with this implementation&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width="1440" alt="image" src="https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/b358494e-171c-4368-88e5-5926b7d23d76"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;🔎 Filtering&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this release I brought in two filters that will greatly help you in finding the right ones to tag.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Max Asset Count:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Imagine you’re in the game of hiding off unwanted or random people’s face but you don’t know how to find it quickly, then its a nightmare mainly when you’ve case like me of 10,000 images.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To solve this I brought in Max Asset Count where you can filter faces that are only in 5-10 photos and you know they are mostly not so close people whom you can ignore and hide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Show Only Nameless:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every got annoyed by seeing already tagged people again and again? This is exactly why this new filter is. When you tag someone take them off your list and worry only about the people who aren’t and get your work done faster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For me it worked more like a checklist 🚀&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;🌪️ Sorting&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Based on asset count&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was done with the pure intention of letting users juggle between people with more number of occurrence and the ones who comes once in a blue moon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Based on updated time&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lost a record while you’re on an tagging spree? This comes handy, if you want to find someone you recently edited or whom you rarely edited.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More features are coming soon! Stay tunes for updates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read the full changelog here -&amp;gt; https://immich-power-tools.featureos.app/changelog/0-1-6-people-filtering-sorting&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/varun-raj/immich-power-tools/releases/tag/v0.1.6" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
