<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://selfh.st/apps</id>
  <title>Invidious Releases</title>
  <updated>2024-03-27T11:30:39.580821-04:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>selfh.st</name>
    <email>contact@selfh.st</email>
  </author>
  <link href="https://selfh.st/apps" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>Self-hosted software releases generated by selfh.st</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/iv-org/invidious/releases/tag/0.18.0</id>
    <title>New release for Invidious: Version 0.18.0: Native Notifications and Optimizations</title>
    <updated>2019-06-06T00:12:28-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>iv-org/invidious</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;Hope everyone has been doing well. This past month there have been &lt;a href="https://github.com/omarroth/invidious/compare/0.17.0...0.18.0"&gt;97 commits&lt;/a&gt; from 10 contributors. For the most part changes this month have been on optimizing various parts of the site, mainly subscription feeds and support for serving images and other assets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm quite happy to mention that support for Greek (&lt;code&gt;el&lt;/code&gt;) has been added, which I hope will continue to make the site accessible for more users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Subscription feeds will now only update when necessary, rather than periodically. This greatly lightens the load on DB as well as making the feeds generally more responsive when changing subscriptions, importing data, and when receiving new uploads.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Caching for images and other assets should be greatly improved with &lt;a href="https://github.com/omarroth/invidious/issues/456"&gt;#456&lt;/a&gt;. JavaScript has been pulled out into separate files where possible to take advantage of this, which should result in lighter pages and faster load times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This past month several people have encountered issues with downloads and watching high quality video through the site, see &lt;a href="https://github.com/omarroth/invidious/issues/532"&gt;#532&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://github.com/omarroth/invidious/issues/562"&gt;#562&lt;/a&gt;. For this coming month I've allocated some more hardware which should help with this, and I'm also looking into optimizing how videos are currently served.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;For Developers&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;viewCount&lt;/code&gt; is now available for &lt;code&gt;/api/v1/popular&lt;/code&gt; and all videos returned from &lt;code&gt;/api/v1/auth/notifications&lt;/code&gt;. Both also now provide &lt;code&gt;"type"&lt;/code&gt; for indicating available information for each object.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An &lt;code&gt;/authorize_token&lt;/code&gt; page is now available for more easily creating new tokens for use in applications, see &lt;a href="https://github.com/omarroth/invidious/issues/473#issuecomment-496230812"&gt;this comment&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;a href="https://github.com/omarroth/invidious/issues/473"&gt;#473&lt;/a&gt; for more details.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A POST &lt;code&gt;/api/v1/auth/notifications&lt;/code&gt; endpoint is also now available for correctly returning notifications for 150+ channels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;For Administrators&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are two new schema changes for administrators: &lt;code&gt;views&lt;/code&gt; for adding view count to the popular page, and &lt;code&gt;feed_needs_update&lt;/code&gt; for tracking feed changes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As always the relevant migration scripts are provided which should run when following instructions for &lt;a href="https://github.com/omarroth/invidious/wiki/Updating"&gt;updating&lt;/a&gt;. Otherwise, adding &lt;code&gt;check_tables: true&lt;/code&gt; to your config will automatically make the required changes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Native Notifications&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://omar.yt/81c3ae1839831bd9300d75e273b6552a86dc2352/native_notification.png" title="Example of native notification, available in repository under screnshots/native_notification.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://omar.yt/81c3ae1839831bd9300d75e273b6552a86dc2352/native_notification.png" height="160" width="472"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is now possible to receive &lt;a href="https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/API/Notifications_API"&gt;Web notifications&lt;/a&gt; from subscribed channels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can enable notifications by clicking "Enable web notifications" in your preferences. Generally they appear within 20-60 seconds of a new video being uploaded, and I've found them to be an enormous quality of life improvement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although it has been fairly stable, please feel free to report any issues you find &lt;a href="https://github.com/omarroth/invidious/issues"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; or emailing me directly at omarroth@protonmail.com.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Important to note for administrators is that instances require &lt;a href="https://github.com/omarroth/invidious/wiki/Configuration"&gt;&lt;code&gt;use_pubsub_feeds&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and must be served over HTTPS in order to correctly send web notifications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Finances&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Donations&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.patreon.com/omarroth"&gt;Patreon&lt;/a&gt; : \$49.73&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://liberapay.com/omarroth"&gt;Liberapay&lt;/a&gt; : \$100.57&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Crypto : ~\$11.12 (converted from BCH, BTC)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Total : \$161.42&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Expenses&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;invidious-load1 (nyc1) : \$10.00 (load balancer)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;invidious-update1 (s-1vcpu-1gb) : \$5.00 (updates feeds)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;invidious-node1 (s-1vcpu-1gb) : \$5.00 (web server)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;invidious-node2 (s-1vcpu-1gb) : \$5.00 (web server)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;invidious-node3 (s-1vcpu-1gb) : \$5.00 (web server)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;invidious-node4 (s-1vcpu-1gb) : \$5.00 (web server)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;invidious-node5 (s-1vcpu-1gb) : \$5.00 (web server)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;invidious-node6 (s-1vcpu-1gb) : \$5.00 (web server)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;invidious-db1 (s-4vcpu-8gb) : \$40.00 (database)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Total : \$85.00&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See you all next month!&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/iv-org/invidious/releases/tag/0.18.0" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/iv-org/invidious/releases/tag/0.19.0</id>
    <title>New release for Invidious: Version 0.19.0: Communities</title>
    <updated>2019-07-13T00:48:22-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>iv-org/invidious</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;Hello again everyone! Focus this month has mainly been on improving playback performance, along with a couple new features I'd like to announce. There have been &lt;a href="https://github.com/omarroth/invidious/compare/0.18.0...0.19.0"&gt;109 commits&lt;/a&gt; this past month from 10 contributors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This past month has seen the addition of Chinese (&lt;code&gt;zh-CN&lt;/code&gt;) and Icelandic (&lt;code&gt;is&lt;/code&gt;) translations. I would like to give a huge thanks to their respective translators, and again an enormous thanks to everyone who helps translate the site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm delighted to mention that &lt;a href="https://github.com/FreeTubeApp/FreeTube"&gt;FreeTube 0.6.0&lt;/a&gt; now supports 1080p thanks to the Invidious API. I would very much recommend reading the &lt;a href="https://freetube.writeas.com/freetube-release-0-6-0-beta-1080p-and-a-lot-of-qol"&gt;relevant post&lt;/a&gt; for some more information on how it works, along with several other major improvements. Folks that are interested in adding similar functionality for their own projects should feel free to get in touch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This past month there has been quite a bit of work on improving memory usage and improving download and playback speeds. As mentioned in the previous release, some extra hardware has been allocated which should also help with this. I'm still looking for ways to improve performance and feedback is always appreciated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Along with performance, a couple quality of life improvements have been added, including author thumbnails and banners, clickable titles for embedded videos, and better styling for captions, among some other enhancements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Communities&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Support for YouTube's &lt;a href="https://creatoracademy.youtube.com/page/lesson/community-tab"&gt;communities tab&lt;/a&gt; has been added. It's a very interesting but surprisingly unknown feature. Essentially, providing comments for a channel, rather than a video, where an author can post updates for their subscribers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's commonly used to promote interesting links and foster discussion. I hope this feature helps people find more interesting content that otherwise would have been overlooked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;For Developers&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For accessing channel communities, an &lt;code&gt;/api/v1/channels/comments/:ucid&lt;/code&gt; endpoint has been added, with similar behavior and schema to &lt;code&gt;/api/v1/comments/:id&lt;/code&gt;, with an extra &lt;code&gt;attachment&lt;/code&gt; field for top-level comments. More info on usage and available data can be found in the &lt;a href="https://github.com/omarroth/invidious/wiki/API#get-apiv1channelscommentsucid-apiv1channelsucidcomments"&gt;wiki&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An &lt;code&gt;/api/v1/auth/feeds&lt;/code&gt; endpoint has been added for programmatically accessing a user's subscription feed, with options for displaying notifications and filtering an existing feed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An &lt;code&gt;/api/v1/search/suggestions&lt;/code&gt; endpoint has been added for retrieving suggestions for a given query.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;For Administrators&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is now possible to disable more resource intensive features, such as downloads and DASH functionality by adding &lt;code&gt;disable_proxy&lt;/code&gt; to your config. See &lt;a href="https://github.com/omarroth/invidious/issues/453"&gt;#453&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href="https://github.com/omarroth/invidious/wiki/Configuration"&gt;Wiki&lt;/a&gt; for more information and example usage. I expect this to be a big help for folks with limited bandwidth when hosting their own instances.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Finances&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Donations&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.patreon.com/omarroth"&gt;Patreon&lt;/a&gt; : \$38.39&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://liberapay.com/omarroth"&gt;Liberapay&lt;/a&gt; : \$84.85&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Crypto : ~\$0.00 (converted from BCH, BTC)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Total : \$123.24&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Expenses&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;invidious-load1 (nyc1) : \$10.00 (load balancer)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;invidious-update1 (s-1vcpu-1gb) : \$5.00 (updates feeds)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;invidious-node1 (s-1vcpu-1gb) : \$5.00 (web server)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;invidious-node2 (s-1vcpu-1gb) : \$5.00 (web server)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;invidious-node3 (s-1vcpu-1gb) : \$5.00 (web server)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;invidious-node4 (s-1vcpu-1gb) : \$5.00 (web server)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;invidious-node5 (s-1vcpu-1gb) : \$5.00 (web server)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;invidious-node6 (s-1vcpu-1gb) : \$5.00 (web server)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;invidious-node7 (s-1vcpu-1gb) : \$5.00 (web server)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;invidious-node8 (s-1vcpu-1gb) : \$5.00 (web server)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;invidious-node9 (s-1vcpu-1gb) : \$5.00 (web server)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;invidious-node10 (s-1vcpu-1gb) : \$5.00 (web server)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;invidious-db1 (s-4vcpu-8gb) : \$40.00 (database)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Total : \$105.00&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The goal on Patreon has been updated to reflect the above expenses. As mentioned above, the main reason for more hardware is to improve playback and download speeds, although I'm still looking into improving performance without allocating more hardware.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As always I'm grateful for everyone's support and feedback. I'll see you all next month.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/iv-org/invidious/releases/tag/0.19.0" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/iv-org/invidious/releases/tag/0.19.1</id>
    <title>New release for Invidious: Hotfix 0.19.1</title>
    <updated>2019-07-29T20:49:53-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>iv-org/invidious</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;Minor fix to video extractor after changes by YouTube. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is recommended to update to this version immediately.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/iv-org/invidious/releases/tag/0.19.1" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/iv-org/invidious/releases/tag/0.20.0</id>
    <title>New release for Invidious: Version 0.20.0: Custom Playlists</title>
    <updated>2019-11-05T23:42:30-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>iv-org/invidious</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;It's been quite a while since the last release! There've been &lt;a href="https://github.com/omarroth/invidious/compare/0.19.0..0.20.0"&gt;198 commits&lt;/a&gt; from 27 contributors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A couple smaller features have since been added. Channel pages and playlists in particular have received a bit of a face-lift, with both now displaying their descriptions as expected, and playlists providing video count and published information. Channels will also now provide video descriptions in their RSS feed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Turkish (tr), Chinese (zh-TW, in addition to zh-CN), and Japanese (jp) are all now supported languages. Thank you as always to the hard work done by translators that makes this possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The feed menu and default home page are both now configurable for registered and unregistered users, and is quite a bit of an improvement for users looking to reduce distractions for their daily use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;For Administrators&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;feed_menu&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;default_home&lt;/code&gt; are now configurable by the user, and have therefore been moved into &lt;code&gt;default_user_preferences&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;```yaml
feed_menu: ["Popular", "Top"]
default_home: Top&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;becomes:&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;default_user_preferences:
  feed_menu: ["Popular", "Top"]
  default_home: Top
```&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Several new options have also been added, including the ability to set a support email for the instance using &lt;code&gt;admin_email: EMAIL&lt;/code&gt;, and forcing the use of a specific connection in the case of rate-limiting using &lt;code&gt;force_resolve&lt;/code&gt; (see below).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;For Developers&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Authenticated endpoints are now &lt;a href="https://github.com/omarroth/invidious/wiki/Authenticated-Endpoints"&gt;properly documented&lt;/a&gt;, as well how to generate and use API tokens. My hope is that this makes some of the more &lt;a href="https://github.com/omarroth/invidious/wiki/Authenticated-Endpoints#get-apiv1authnotifications"&gt;interesting&lt;/a&gt; endpoints more accessible for developers to use in their own applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;API endpoints for interacting with custom playlists have also been added with documentation available &lt;a href="https://github.com/omarroth/invidious/wiki/Authenticated-Endpoints#get-apiv1authplaylists"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Custom playlists&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is probably the feature that has been the longest in the pipe and that I'm quite pleased is now implemented. It is now possible to create custom playlists, which can be played and edited through Invidious. API endpoints have also been added (documentation &lt;a href="https://github.com/omarroth/invidious/wiki/Authenticated-Endpoints#get-apiv1authplaylists"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall I'm quite pleased with how smoothly it has been rolled out and with the experience so far, and I'm exctited for how it can be extended and improved in future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a href="https://instances.invidio.us"&gt;instances.invidio.us&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is now possible to view a list of public instances (as provided in the &lt;a href="https://github.com/omarroth/invidious/wiki/Invidious-Instances"&gt;wiki&lt;/a&gt;) through an API or a pretty new interface &lt;a href="https://instances.invidio.us"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. It combines uptime information, statistics from each instance and basic information already provided in the wiki. I expect it should be much more user-friendly than compiling the information yourself, and is already used by &lt;a href="https://codeberg.org/Booteille/Invidition"&gt;Invidition&lt;/a&gt; to provide a list of instances for users to choose from.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The site itself is licensed under the AGPLv3 and the source is available &lt;a href="https://github.com/omarroth/instances.invidio.us"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Video unavailable &lt;a href="https://github.com/omarroth/invidious/issues/811"&gt;#811&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many users have likely noticed this error message if using Invidious directly or through another service, such as FreeTube. This issue is caused by rate-limiting by Google, and is not a new issuee for projects like Invidious (notably &lt;a href="https://github.com/ytdl-org/youtube-dl#http-error-429-too-many-requests-or-402-payment-required"&gt;youtube-dl&lt;/a&gt;) and appears to be affecting smaller, private instances as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is not a permanent fix for administrators currently, however there is some information available &lt;a href="https://github.com/omarroth/invidious/issues/811#issuecomment-540017772"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; that may provide a temporary solution. Unfortanately, in most cases the best option is to wait for the instance to be unbanned or to move the instance to a different IP. A more informative error message is also now provided, which should help an administrator more quickly diagnose the problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For those interested, I would recommend following &lt;a href="https://github.com/omarroth/invidious/issues/811"&gt;#811&lt;/a&gt; for any future progress on the issue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;BAT verified publisher&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm quite late to this announcement, however I'm pleased to mention that Invidious is now a BAT verified publisher! I would recommend looking &lt;a href="https://basicattentiontoken.org/about/"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/BATProject/comments/7cr7yc/new_to_bat_read_this_introduction_to_basic/"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; for learning more about what it is and how it works. Overall I think it makes an interesting substitute for services like Liberapay, and a (hopefully) much less-intrusive alternative to direct advertising.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BAT is combined under other cryptocurrencies below. Currently there's a fairly significant delay in payout, which is the reason for the large fluctuation in crypto donations between September and October (and also the reason for the late announcement).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Release schedule&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently I'm quite pleased with the current state of the project. There's plenty of things I'd still like to add, however at this point I expect the rate of most new additions will slow down a bit, with more focus on stabililty and any long-standing bugs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because of this, I'm planning on releasing a new version quarterly, with any necessary hotfixes being pushed as a new patch release as necessary. As always it will be possible to run Invidious directly from &lt;a href="https://github.com/omarroth/invidious/wiki/Updating"&gt;master&lt;/a&gt; if you'd still like to have the lastest version.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'll plan on providing finances each release, with a similar monthly breakdown as below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Finances for September 2019&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Donations&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.patreon.com/omarroth"&gt;Patreon&lt;/a&gt; : \$64.37&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://liberapay.com/omarroth"&gt;Liberapay&lt;/a&gt; : \$76.04&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Crypto : ~\$99.89 (converted from BAT, BCH, BTC)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Total : \$240.30&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Expenses&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;invidious-lb1 (nyc1) : \$10.00 (load balancer)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;invidious-update1 (s-1vcpu-1gb) : \$5.00 (updates feeds)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;invidious-node1 (s-1vcpu-1gb) : \$5.00 (web server)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;invidious-node2 (s-1vcpu-1gb) : \$5.00 (web server)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;invidious-node3 (s-1vcpu-1gb) : \$5.00 (web server)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;invidious-node4 (s-1vcpu-1gb) : \$5.00 (web server)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;invidious-node5 (s-1vcpu-1gb) : \$5.00 (web server)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;invidious-node6 (s-1vcpu-1gb) : \$5.00 (web server)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;invidious-node7 (s-1vcpu-1gb) : \$5.00 (web server)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;invidious-node8 (s-1vcpu-1gb) : \$5.00 (web server)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;invidious-node9 (s-1vcpu-1gb) : \$5.00 (web server)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;invidious-node10 (s-1vcpu-1gb) : \$5.00 (web server)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;invidious-node11 (s-1vcpu-1gb) : \$5.00 (web server)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;invidious-node12 (s-1vcpu-1gb) : \$5.00 (web server)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;invidious-node13 (s-1vcpu-1gb) : \$5.00 (web server)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;invidious-node14 (s-1vcpu-1gb) : \$5.00 (web server)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;invidious-node15 (s-1vcpu-1gb) : \$5.00 (web server)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;invidious-node16 (s-1vcpu-1gb) : \$5.00 (web server)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;invidious-db1 (s-4vcpu-8gb) : \$40.00 (database)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Total : \$135.00&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Finances for October 2019&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://liberapay.com/omarroth"&gt;Liberapay&lt;/a&gt; : \$134.40&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Crypto : ~\$8.29 (converted from BAT, BCH, BTC)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Total : \$142.69&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Expenses&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;invidious-lb1 (nyc1) : \$5.00 (load balancer)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;invidious-lb2 (nyc1) : \$5.00 (load balancer)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;invidious-lb3 (nyc1) : \$5.00 (load balancer)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;invidious-lb4 (nyc1) : \$5.00 (load balancer)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;invidious-update1 (s-1vcpu-1gb) : \$5.00 (updates feeds)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;invidious-node1 (s-1vcpu-1gb) : \$5.00 (web server)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;invidious-node2 (s-1vcpu-1gb) : \$5.00 (web server)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;invidious-node3 (s-1vcpu-1gb) : \$5.00 (web server)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;invidious-node4 (s-1vcpu-1gb) : \$5.00 (web server)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;invidious-node5 (s-1vcpu-1gb) : \$5.00 (web server)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;invidious-node6 (s-1vcpu-1gb) : \$5.00 (web server)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;invidious-node7 (s-1vcpu-1gb) : \$5.00 (web server)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;invidious-node8 (s-1vcpu-1gb) : \$5.00 (web server)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;invidious-node9 (s-1vcpu-1gb) : \$5.00 (web server)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;invidious-node10 (s-1vcpu-1gb) : \$5.00 (web server)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;invidious-node11 (s-1vcpu-1gb) : \$5.00 (web server)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;invidious-node12 (s-1vcpu-1gb) : \$5.00 (web server)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;invidious-node13 (s-1vcpu-1gb) : \$5.00 (web server)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;invidious-node14 (s-1vcpu-1gb) : \$5.00 (web server)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;invidious-node15 (s-1vcpu-1gb) : \$5.00 (web server)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;invidious-node16 (s-1vcpu-1gb) : \$5.00 (web server)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;invidious-node17 (s-1vcpu-1gb) : \$5.00 (web server)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;invidious-node18 (s-1vcpu-1gb) : \$5.00 (web server)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;invidious-db1 (s-4vcpu-8gb) : \$40.00 (database)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Total : \$155.00&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/iv-org/invidious/releases/tag/0.20.0" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/iv-org/invidious/releases/tag/0.20.1</id>
    <title>New release for Invidious: Hotfix 0.20.1</title>
    <updated>2019-11-18T20:50:55-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>iv-org/invidious</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;! IMPORTANT !&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Releases are deprecated, build directly from master&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This adds support for QUIC as a workaround to #811.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is recommended to update to this version immediately.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/iv-org/invidious/releases/tag/0.20.1" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
