<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://selfh.st/apps</id>
  <title>Kapowarr Releases</title>
  <updated>2024-03-29T02:30:39.327137-04:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>selfh.st</name>
    <email>contact@selfh.st</email>
  </author>
  <link href="https://selfh.st/apps" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>Self-hosted software releases generated by selfh.st</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/Casvt/Kapowarr/releases/tag/V1.0.0-beta-1</id>
    <title>New release for Kapowarr: V1.0.0-beta-1</title>
    <updated>2023-05-24T11:33:34-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Casvt/Kapowarr</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;The first beta release of Kapowarr!&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/Casvt/Kapowarr/releases/tag/V1.0.0-beta-1" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/Casvt/Kapowarr/releases/tag/V1.0.0-beta-2</id>
    <title>New release for Kapowarr: V1.0.0-beta-2</title>
    <updated>2023-07-27T16:17:37-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Casvt/Kapowarr</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h2&gt;What's Changed&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Added&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Only download TPB's for TPB releases (#27)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Support for issue- and volume number padding (e.g. 7, 07 or 007) (#31)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added support for custom volume folders (#20)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added support for files, search results and downloads having the release year as the volume number&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added dark mode (#42)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Library sorting sticks cross-sessions per client&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added option to filter away translated versions when adding volumes (#25)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added proper handling of errors that arise in tasks (you don't have to restart anymore when a task errors out)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added ability to disable renaming downloaded files (#63)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added &lt;code&gt;{issue_release_year}&lt;/code&gt; to available file naming variables (#66)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added special file naming format for issues that don't have a title (#78)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When the volume folder is renamed (root folder changed, folder renamed), the old volume folder is deleted if empty&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The rename proposals (the list of suggested renames before actually applying them) are now sorted&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added a table library view (#44)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When a proxy is used, the IP of the original client is shown in the logs instead of the IP of the proxy (#80)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Changed&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed "database is locked" by implementing WAL journal mode for the database (#58)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improvements and some fixed bugs for the algorithm that extract data from filenames and search results (among other things, #41)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed deleting volume with "Delete folder" set to "Yes" when folder is already deleted (#54)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;After adding a volume, you now stay on the "Add Volume" page instead of getting redirected to the "View Volume" page (#74)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed downloading from some Media Fire links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved matching downloads on a GC page by using the available year as an extra check&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed using enter or search button for various search bars (#65)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed searching for issues that don't have a release date (#76)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed adding root folders that contain the &lt;code&gt;+&lt;/code&gt; character&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed using the &lt;code&gt;#&lt;/code&gt; character in the login password (#29)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed image file naming being year if no page number was found (#69)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed covers being seen as TPB's (#69)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Requests fetching the covers of volumes won't be logged, even in DEBUG mode&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed discord link at System -&amp;gt; Status&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Full Changelog&lt;/strong&gt;: https://github.com/Casvt/Kapowarr/compare/V1.0.0-beta-1...V1.0.0-beta-2&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/Casvt/Kapowarr/releases/tag/V1.0.0-beta-2" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/Casvt/Kapowarr/releases/tag/V1.0.0-beta-3</id>
    <title>New release for Kapowarr: V1.0.0-beta-3</title>
    <updated>2023-09-04T17:51:36-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Casvt/Kapowarr</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h2&gt;What's Changed&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Added&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added support for one-shots&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added support for hard covers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kapowarr avoids all download links from shorte.st&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved searching by adding extra search terms&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added logo in UI and docs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Downloads aren't added to the queue if they're already in it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added support for PWA (adding the web-UI to your home screen as if it was an app) (#28)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added check for CV token to see if it's valid and working when it's entered in the settings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Changed&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed/Improved some things regarding downloading from GC (among other things, #82)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed Kapowarr fetching new issues for volumes (see note below)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved matching files when scanning for them&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved matching search results that contained the 'and' word&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed deleting a volume when there is a download for it in the queue.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Show "Unknown" instead of "0TB" in the download queue for downloads with unknown size&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed Kapowarr adding download links to the blocklist when adding them on start-up&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The backend has been refactored to: reduce the "database locked" error, fix various small bugs, make some things faster and get Kapowarr ready for more features.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed the colour of links in the settings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Note&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you upgrade from beta-2 to beta-3, please run an "Update All" after upgrading. Kapowarr had a bug where it wouldn't fetch new issues of volumes. That is now fixed, which means that after upgrading, loads of new issues (depending on how many ongoing volumes you have) will appear for volumes, which will also be downloaded (if the volume and issue are monitored and a download is available). This bug has been in Kapowarr for quite some time, so there could be multiple new issues &lt;em&gt;per ongoing volume&lt;/em&gt; (depending on how often the publisher releases new issues for the volume).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;details&gt;
&lt;summary&gt;Technical explanation&lt;/summary&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
ComicVine supplies a "date_last_updated" key which gives the date that the metadata was changed for the last time. Kapowarr made use of this value by only fetching all metadata for a volume if the value had changed since the last fetch. This way, metadata would only be fetched if it was changed compared to the local version.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
It turns out that this value doesn't change when an issue is added to the volume (or removed/edited). So Kapowarr wouldn't update the metadata, even when new issues were released. Kapowarr would only update the metadata (and sync the issue list) when the metadata of the volume was changed, which doesn't happen very often. Because this is faulty behaviour, the system is removed and Kapowarr now always fetches all metadata. That means that suddenly all new issues that weren't fetched before, now will, and thus loads of new ones could appear.
&lt;/details&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Full Changelog&lt;/strong&gt;: https://github.com/Casvt/Kapowarr/compare/V1.0.0-beta-2...V1.0.0-beta-3&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/Casvt/Kapowarr/releases/tag/V1.0.0-beta-3" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/Casvt/Kapowarr/releases/tag/V1.0.0-beta-4</id>
    <title>New release for Kapowarr: V1.0.0-beta-4</title>
    <updated>2024-01-03T12:21:21-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Casvt/Kapowarr</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h2&gt;What's Changed&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Added&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added Library Import (#22)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added support for downloading torrents supplied by GetComics, using qBittorrent (#48)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added conversion support (#67) (See note)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added support for volumes as issues (#23)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added Mass Editor (#51)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added toggle for items in rename (#45)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added filters for library view&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added 000x issue padding option&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added support for issues as a series of image files&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Changed&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed adding root folder on a Windows manual install&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Volume progress (on library view) is now based only on monitored issues (#98)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Login sustains for 1 hour instead of for duration of browser session&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed special version not updating after new issues (#108)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed moving files on NFS mounts (#117)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed having volume number after issue number (#94)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed download importer locking up the database (#92)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed downloading from GetComics when last issue doesn't have a date&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed extension being zip instead of cbz for certain downloads&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed handling of files when they have non-lowercase extensions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved translation detection for volume search results&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;List of files is now sorted&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved filter when extracting archive files (prev. 'unzipping')&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Note&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new 'conversion' feature allows you to change the format of files (e.g. from 'cbr' to 'cbz'). This replaces the 'unzipping' feature.  To recreate the unzipping feature:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Go to Settings -&amp;gt; Media Management -&amp;gt; Converting.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enable 'Extract archives covering multiple issues'&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; add 'folder' to the format preference.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enable 'Convert Files' if you want to 'unzip' automatically after downloading.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Click 'Save' at the top.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Full Changelog&lt;/strong&gt;: https://github.com/Casvt/Kapowarr/compare/V1.0.0-beta-3...V1.0.0-beta-4&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/Casvt/Kapowarr/releases/tag/V1.0.0-beta-4" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
