<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://selfh.st/apps</id>
  <title>Karakeep Releases</title>
  <updated>2025-07-03T02:32:33.240751-04:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>selfh.st</name>
    <email>contact@selfh.st</email>
  </author>
  <link href="https://selfh.st/apps" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>Self-hosted software releases generated by selfh.st</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/karakeep-app/karakeep/releases/tag/v0.23.1</id>
    <title>New release for Karakeep: 0.23.1</title>
    <updated>2025-04-05T11:37:45-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>karakeep-app/karakeep</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h1&gt;0.23.1 (Hoarder is rebranding to Karakeep)&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is not a typical release. Hoarder is rebranding to Karakeep. For context about the rebranding, check out the reddit announcement &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1js667o/hoarder_is_rebranding_to_karakeep/"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The name Karakeep is inspired by the Arabic word "كراكيب" (karakeeb), a colloquial term commonly used to refer to miscellaneous clutter, odds and ends, or items that may seem disorganized but often hold personal value or hidden usefulness. It evokes the image of a messy drawer or forgotten box, full of stuff you can't quite throw away—because somehow, it matters (or more likely, because you're a hoarder!).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, we also have a couple of new contributors to this minor version. Welcome @ekambains, @Summon528, @jaworek, @jferch, @denysdovhan to the contributors list!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you enjoy using Karakeep, consider supporting the project &lt;a href="https://buymeacoffee.com/mbassem"&gt;here ☕️&lt;/a&gt; or via GitHub &lt;a href="https://github.com/sponsors/MohamedBassem"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;New Features 🚀&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Well, we're rebranding!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This release shows a banner in the admin panel about the rebranding. It's still unclear whether I'll be able to continue updating the hoarder docker image after the repo name change, so I wanted what might potentially be the last stable release on this image to inform the people about the change in the image name. If it turns out that I can continue updating the image, I'll drop the banner.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Please note that the new docker image will not yet be available until I execute the repo transfer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can now store the assets in a separate directory by setting the &lt;code&gt;ASSETS_DIR&lt;/code&gt; env variable. This allows people to offload the assets that can potentially grow larger into a network-mounted directory for example.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hoarder now stores and indexes the author and publisher attributes of links. In a future release, we'll start showing them in the UI. (by @erik-nilcoast).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;UX Improvements ✨&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clicking view original now opens in a blank tab (by @ekambains).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Link to Github release page in web sidebar (by @aworek).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Drop the font weight from sidebar items which makes the sidebar slightly nicer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Fixes 🐛&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixes issue where hoarder was running out of memory when uploading a large archive with SingleFile.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added a configurable crawler screenshot time &lt;code&gt;CRAWLER_SCREENSHOT_TIMEOUT_SEC&lt;/code&gt; (by @Summon528)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Upgrading 📦&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To upgrade:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you're using &lt;code&gt;HOARDER_VERSION=release&lt;/code&gt;, run &lt;code&gt;docker compose pull &amp;amp;&amp;amp; docker compose up -d&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you're pinning it to a specific version, upgrade the version and then run &lt;code&gt;docker compose pull &amp;amp;&amp;amp; docker compose up -d&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;All Commits&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;chore: Hoarder to Karakeep rebranding (#1199) - @MohamedBassem in 16866d8&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feat(web): link to Github release page in web sidebar (#1192) - @jaworek in 55ae679&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;i18n: Enable ukrainian language (#1195) - @denysdovhan in 4650ecc&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ui(web): Clicking view original now opens in a blank tab. Fixes #1114 (#1196) - @ekambains in f187e5e&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ui(web): Drop the font weight attribute from sidebar items - @MohamedBassem in e38be87&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feat: Allow storing assets in a separate directory. Fixes #1091 - @MohamedBassem in d86f601&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix: Dont buffer uploaded files in memory. Fixes #1173 - @MohamedBassem in 453f2dd&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feat(workers): Add CRAWLER_SCREENSHOT_TIMEOUT_SEC (#1155) - @Summon528 in c193c6e&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;docs: Fixed missing semicolon in update admin password section (#1169) - @jferch in 41067ee&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feat(workers): Adds publisher and author og:meta tags to Bookmark (#1141) - @erik-nilcoast in b3417d8&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/karakeep-app/karakeep/releases/tag/v0.23.1" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/karakeep-app/karakeep/releases/tag/v0.23.2</id>
    <title>New release for Karakeep: 0.23.2</title>
    <updated>2025-04-06T03:14:36-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>karakeep-app/karakeep</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;This is a dummy release to retrigger the generation of the ARM builds. Refer to the releases notes of &lt;a href="https://github.com/karakeep-app/karakeep/releases/tag/v0.23.1"&gt;0.23.1&lt;/a&gt; instead.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/karakeep-app/karakeep/releases/tag/v0.23.2" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/karakeep-app/karakeep/releases/tag/v0.24.0</id>
    <title>New release for Karakeep: 0.24.0</title>
    <updated>2025-04-27T14:55:48-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>karakeep-app/karakeep</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h1&gt;0.24.0 – Riding the MCP hype&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the 0.24.0 release of Karakeep! This release packs a ton of new stuff (we're back to shipping folks!). This release introduces a new MCP server for interacting with Karakeep through LLMs, a new rule generic rule engine for more control over organizing your bookmarks, new search qualifiers for feeds and bookmark age, overdue edit dialog for bookmark details, some UI polishing and more! This release also welcomes a TON of new contributors, @brandonw3612, @yorch, @Summon528, @dotvhs, @YTKme, @hasansino, @gomnitrix, @adripo, @meysam81, @SteffoSpieler, @jkywalker (And I probably missed some).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you enjoy using Karakeep, consider supporting the project &lt;a href="https://buymeacoffee.com/mbassem"&gt;here ☕️&lt;/a&gt; or via GitHub &lt;a href="https://github.com/sponsors/MohamedBassem"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;New Features 🚀&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;✨ MCP Server ✨&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unless you've been living under a rock recently, you've heard about the recent explosion of MCP servers all over the internet.
We're not going to miss the hype. This release ships a new MCP server (&lt;a href="https://docs.karakeep.app/mcp"&gt;docs&lt;/a&gt;) that allows you to interact with your Karakeep instance and bookmarks through extrenal LLMs.
You can ask the LLM to summarize your bookmarks, search the web and send what it finds to Karakeep, or archive your recent chat as a text note in karakeep.
It can create new lists, attach tags and more to help you organize your bookmarks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="CleanShot 2025-04-27 at 7  39 35@2x" src="https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/837fb6f6-2878-49e2-af92-a5526687b94a" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More demos in the screenshot section.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Generic Rule Engine ⚙️&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Karakeep was born because I don't want to spend time organizing what I hoard. I just throw stuff in there and karakeep's tagging and search will help me retrieve it later.
However, turns out that not everyone is in the same camp. If you're one of those people who enjoy organizing their bookmarks, this feature is for you.
This release introduces a new generic rule engine that allows you to define arbitrary processing rules for organizing your bookmarks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some examples:
1. If a bookmark is added, and it's coming from youtube, tag it with "#youtube" and "#video".
2. If a bookmark is favourited, download an offline archive for it.
3. If the tag "#fashion" is added to a bookmark, and this bookmark is an image, then add it my "Inspiration" list (You're better off using a smart list for this though).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="CleanShot 2025-04-27 at 7  35 55@2x" src="https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/b052451b-4a8e-4042-83e8-90abf657332d" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;⚠️ The firefox extension is back under a new name (Action Required) ⚠️&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the rebranding unfortunatly we couldn't get the old Firefox extension back, so we had to publish a new one (&lt;a href="https://addons.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/addon/karakeep/"&gt;link&lt;/a&gt;).
If you're using the old "firefox" extension, you MUST migrate to the new one manually otherwise you won't be getting future updates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;And more!&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;gpt-4.1-mini is the new default text model&lt;/strong&gt;: The default OpenAI text model changed to the new 4.1-mini. It's slightly more expensive than 4o-mini, but is supposed to be much smarter. The image model remains as 4o-mini as 4.1-mini is more expensive for images.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;New Search &amp;amp; Smart list Qualifiers&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New “age:” search qualifier to show bookmarks older or newer than a given duration (by @brandonw3612).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New "feed:" search qualifier to find bookmarks imported from certain RSS feeds.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can find the full query language &lt;a href="https://docs.karakeep.app/Guides/search-query-language"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Edit Bookmark Details&lt;/strong&gt;: You can now edit almost all the details of bookmarks. The URL, summary, creation date, everything. This is obviously very overdue.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;List Merging&lt;/strong&gt;: You can now merge lists together thanks to @gomnitrix.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Import Tab Session Manager Sessions&lt;/strong&gt;: Bulk-import your Chrome/Firefox Tab Session Manager session files as Karakeep bookmarks by @yorch.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Configuring other AI providers&lt;/strong&gt;: We added documentations for how to configure other AI providers beside OpenAI (&lt;a href="https://docs.karakeep.app/next/Guides/different-ai-providers"&gt;link&lt;/a&gt;). This includes providers like Google AI Studio, OpenRouter, Perplexity, etc. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Karakeep on TrueNAS&lt;/strong&gt;: People using TrueNAS can now find Karakeep in TrueNAS' app store thanks to @stavros-k.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;UX Improvements ✨&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some UI polish
  – Reduced shadows, lighter font weights, smaller editor box following the suggestions of @dotvhs in #1261!
  – Removed focus rings where they don't matter much, fix popovers to the emoji picker (by @Mxrk), and list items in the sidebar now get truncated if they're long.
  – Fixed margins of the “New List” button, and fixed spinner visibility during AI summarization&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cached content is now called “Reader Mode” content.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There's now a nice looking "No bookmarks" banner for search and empty smart lists.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lists now can have a short description beside their name (by @ekambains).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A new monochrome icon for android builds by @SteffoSpieler.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Copy link button now gets greyed out when on a non-secure context by @ekambains.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The github link in the sidebar now works correctly for people on the nightly build thanks to @hasansino.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;For Developers 🛠️&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added &lt;code&gt;includeContent&lt;/code&gt; to the API endpoints that return bookmarks (Listing, search, etc) to control whether the endpoint should include the content of the bookmark (which can be huge or not).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;⚠️ For backward compatibility, this defaults to &lt;code&gt;true&lt;/code&gt;, but starting from the next release, this will default to &lt;code&gt;false&lt;/code&gt;. So if your tool relies on the content of the bookmarks, start passing this to &lt;code&gt;true&lt;/code&gt; now.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The API docs have a new look. The new look also fixes the enum-like requests types (like the one in createBookmark).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Fixes 🐛&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Smart lists in search&lt;/strong&gt;: Smart lists are now correctly resolved in the search qualifiers &lt;code&gt;list:&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;is:inlist&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A much faster homepage loading times&lt;/strong&gt;: If you've been a user for the SingleFile extension, Karakeep's homepage might have started getting slower recently. The UI was accidently downloading a big chunk of the archive in the homepage when it's not needed. This is now fixed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Faster Imports&lt;/strong&gt;: Importing bookmarks used to be extremely slow, now it's done with much higher parallelism and should be significantly faster.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dark-mode icons for the firefox extension @L-K-M&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed the list getting opened when editing it from the sidebar.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added a new &lt;code&gt;INFERENCE_OUTPUT_SCHEMA&lt;/code&gt; configuration to restore support for models that only works with JSON mode (instead of the newer structured output mode).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Passwords stored in the database are now &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Salt_(cryptography)"&gt;salted&lt;/a&gt;. For backward compatibility, existing users will continue using an empty salt until they change their password.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Karakeep now closes the browser after it's done crawling in "on demand" mode by @Summon528.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed a bug in content extraction that might result in a suboptimal "cached content" being shown.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Triggering a search re-index now drops all the documents first to avoid dangling documents.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Community Projects 💡&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Github 2 Karakeep Importer&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;By @hasansino&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Exports your github stars automatically to Karakeep! Get it &lt;a href="https://github.com/hasansino/github2karakeep"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Screenshots 📸&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;MCP Demo&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="CleanShot 2025-04-27 at 6  57 47" src="https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/2a3e90f0-6ffe-4154-9cbf-0d56c5c9fd25" /&gt;
&lt;img alt="CleanShot 2025-04-27 at 6  59 25" src="https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/599138ad-ebf0-41d0-b544-874769e67675" /&gt;
&lt;img alt="CleanShot 2025-04-27 at 7  08 38" src="https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/df34efc9-d6a3-44ff-9cdd-195fcd87f773" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The new "No Bookmarks banner"&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="CleanShot 2025-04-27 at 7  41 54@2x" src="https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/9b503698-9b3c-41e1-b01d-9ce76eb4644b" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Bookmark Editing Dialog&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="CleanShot 2025-04-27 at 7  42 52@2x" src="https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/1c562229-8c15-44a9-b653-980521132a81" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Upgrading 📦&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re using &lt;code&gt;KARAKEEP_VERSION=release&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;docker compose pull &amp;amp;&amp;amp; docker compose up -d&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you pin to a specific version, update &lt;code&gt;KARAKEEP_VERSION&lt;/code&gt;, then:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;docker compose pull &amp;amp;&amp;amp; docker compose up -d&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;All Commits&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix: Fix smart lists not working in list search qualifiers. Fixes #845 - @MohamedBassem in 6178736d&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;docs: Update the API docs - @MohamedBassem in 28ca9d5f&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix: When triggering a re-index, drop all the documents first - @MohamedBassem in 3dd98b47&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix(mcp): Remove extra new line in bookmark listing - @MohamedBassem in b63366a4&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix(mcp): Fix spacing around the bookmarks - @MohamedBassem in 1568fe90&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix(mcp): Ditch JSON and respond in plain text - @MohamedBassem in 1a24eb69&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix(web): Hide smart lists from list selectors - @MohamedBassem in d3cf3e4d&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feat: Implement generic rule engine (#1318) - @MohamedBassem in 136f1262&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;tests: Run trpc tests in CI - @MohamedBassem in ca47be7f&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;build: Provide a docker container for the MCP server - @MohamedBassem in c239634d&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;landing: Update Homepage and Hero Image (#1304) - @YTKme in 1880a59f&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix(landing): all external links open in new tab (#1292) - @ekambains in 5ff470b4&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;chore: rename missing files/conf from Hoarder to Karakeep (#1280) - @adripo in 4296e7f4&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix(workers): Fix dompurify to run on readability's input not output - @MohamedBassem in 86728d7f&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;deps: Upgrade readability to 0.6 &amp;amp; adblocker to 2.5.1 - @MohamedBassem in f257a5ba&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix(web): Fix margins of the new list button - @MohamedBassem in 2870332d&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix(web): Fix the spinner getting hidden during AI summarization - @MohamedBassem in 6310d456&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix(web): Fix sidebar lists getting opened on edit - @MohamedBassem in 1e2b2df4&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix: Rename cached content into reader mode - @MohamedBassem in c42c2c3d&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ui(web): Reduce shadows, lighten some fonts, and a smaller editor. #1261 - @MohamedBassem in cd632f29&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;docs: Add a small doc about truenas installation - @MohamedBassem in ca58d68f&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix: Take 2: Attempt to fix darkmode icon for extensions - @MohamedBassem in 1ff9d1db&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix: Attempt to fix darkmode icon for extensions - @MohamedBassem in 1d9fc9bb&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix: Fix server side error on clipboard check - @MohamedBassem in 8c4df0ff&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;docs: Add docs for how to configure differnt AI providers - @MohamedBassem in bd5f85f5&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix: FIxed sidebar link to github for nightly builds (#1274) - @hasansino in 06284d28&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;docs: Add robots.txt to prevent indexing versioned docs - @MohamedBassem in 40085413&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix(mcp): Reduce number of MCP tools and add support for pagination - @MohamedBassem in 6bae1196&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix(mcp): Fix mixed es module issue - @MohamedBassem in 293a4a0d&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;release(mcp): Release mcp 0.23.5 - @MohamedBassem in 7584c1f4&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;tests: Add some simple crawler tests - @MohamedBassem in d732acd4&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;tests: Add tests for various trpc endpoints - @MohamedBassem in 1d780485&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;docs: Refresh the API docs - @MohamedBassem in 812354de&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix: Add includeContent to search endpoint and document it in the docs - @MohamedBassem in ba89a864&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feat: Add import support for Tab Session Manager (#1246) - @yorch in 5e0f4de1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;build: Take over the build command in the installation script - @MohamedBassem in 2328dc34&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feat(web): Add support for merging lists (#1231) - @gomnitrix in 71a47426&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix(workers): Close browser if connect on demand (#1151) - @Summon528 in dd990b51&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;docs: Fix docs build - @MohamedBassem in 209573ee&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feat: Change default text model to 4.1-mini - @MohamedBassem in adc22a76&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix: Add password salt to the user table - @MohamedBassem in 7e39afa2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;docs: Add documentation for the new rss feed search qualifier - @MohamedBassem in d7244978&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feat: add support for filtering by bookmark age (#1228) - @brandonw3612 in 95f504c0&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix: Dont download html content by default in the bookmark grid. Fixes #1198 - @MohamedBassem in 5bdb2d94&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix: Allow using JSON mode for ollama users. Fixes #1160 - @MohamedBassem in 1373a7b2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;docs: Revert 0.23.2 docs and just update 0.23.1 instead - @MohamedBassem in f3c525b7&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;docs: Release the new API docs - @MohamedBassem in ae76f946&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;docs: Replace the OpenAPI rendering library - @MohamedBassem in 969e774a&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix(landing): Add missing title tag - @MohamedBassem in 98ac31c3&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;chore: hoarder-linux.sh &amp;gt; karakeep-linux.sh v2.1 (#1219) - @vhsdream in f0726635&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;build: Allow auto deployment of MCP package to npm - @MohamedBassem in bc5c1a1b&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix(mcp): Allow accessing asset extracted content in MCP - @MohamedBassem in 7853096c&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feat: Allow editing the extracted content of an asset bookmark - @MohamedBassem in a4d5be3a&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix(mcp): compact the response of get bookmark lists - @MohamedBassem in 8c6cfc8f&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ui(web): Copy link button greyed out when clipboard not available (#1209) - @ekambains in 46277c74&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix(mcp): Reduce token usage of the MCP server - @MohamedBassem in e5bacda6&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feat(mobile/android): Add monochrome app icon (#1258) - @SteffoSpieler in 1f92ced3&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;docs: replace hoarder with karakeep in CONTRIBUTING.md and FAQ (#1256) - @Mxrk in eeff55f8&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix(web): fit popover content box to emoji picker size (#1257) - @Mxrk in 6c0638be&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feat: Add an MCP server for karakeep - @MohamedBassem in cf97bace&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feat(web): Optionally add short description to lists (#1225) - @ekambains in a39cd5f3&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;docs: add Arch Linux karakeep migration instructions (#1218) - @devome in 56e67956&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix(landing): Made the year in footer dynamic (#1223) - @ekambains in 33641489&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;chore: Replace hoarder with karakeep in github issue templates (#1247) - @Mxrk in 8ffef681&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;chore: Rename hoarder packages to karakeep - @MohamedBassem in 755fc36e&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;chrore: Update meilisearch version to 13.3 in both docker compose files (#1244) - @Mxrk in 7f569042&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;i18n: Add Korean language (#1239) - @jkywalker in 60a0df0b&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;docs: Remove hoarder references for docusaurus config preventing the indexing - @MohamedBassem in 1608804f&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;build: Regenerate the openapi specs and sdk - @MohamedBassem in a013a338&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix: Deprecate the updateBookmarkText trpc endpoint and replace it with updateBookmark - @MohamedBassem in 0b769c35&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feat: Allow editing bookmark details - @MohamedBassem in 3207264f&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;docs: update Arch Linux installation (#1216) - @devome in 817eb588&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;chore: update repo release url to karakeep (#1210) - @meysam81 in d1a814fb&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix: Do clientside import dedup and parallelize import calls - @MohamedBassem in af631eb2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feat: Add a search matcher for rss feed bookmarks - @MohamedBassem in af6774fa&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feat(web): A slightly better looking banner when no bookmarks are found - @MohamedBassem in d86628df&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix(web): Get rid of focus rings for ghost buttons - @MohamedBassem in b17bf7d5&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;refactor: Migrate the landing page from nextjs to vite - @MohamedBassem in 3f2d3560&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix(web): Line clamp sidebar items to a single line - @MohamedBassem in 4e32b409&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix(installation): Fix the baremetal installation script after the rebrand - @MohamedBassem in 27e5693a&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;release(extension): Release version 1.2.4 - @MohamedBassem in d17eb8c5&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix(extenion): Added white icon for dark mode users (#1176) - @L-K-M in 2753b822&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix(extension): Update extension logo and name - @MohamedBassem in 4ab5a189&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix(mobile): Revert mobile app slug name - @MohamedBassem in 019c1353&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix(mobile): Update karakeep logo and splash screen - @MohamedBassem in 49efe141&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;docs: Release the 0.23.1 docs - @MohamedBassem in 27324a96&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;chore: Rename mobile and pwa manifests to karakeep - @MohamedBassem in 8a2b8902&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;docs: Update installation docs with karakeep - @MohamedBassem in 4e6d3142&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;build: Update image source label in the dockerfile - @MohamedBassem in abcb9f26&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix: Drop the rebranding banner - @MohamedBassem in 8f470b32&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;build: Build the new karakeep docker images - @MohamedBassem in a5c3db1e&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;readme: More readme fixes for the new name - @MohamedBassem in 14b85a3b&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;readme: Update readme and docs for the new name - @MohamedBassem in a3864065&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/karakeep-app/karakeep/releases/tag/v0.24.0" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/karakeep-app/karakeep/releases/tag/v0.24.1</id>
    <title>New release for Karakeep: 0.24.1</title>
    <updated>2025-04-28T04:21:37-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>karakeep-app/karakeep</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;This is a hotfix release for &lt;a href="https://github.com/karakeep-app/karakeep/releases/tag/v0.24.0"&gt;0.24.0&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;🐞 Fixes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reverts the smart list expansion in &lt;code&gt;list:&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;is:inlist&lt;/code&gt; qualifiers as it can cause Karakeep's server to OOM (#1321).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Adds missing translations for the new features released in &lt;code&gt;0.24.0&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/karakeep-app/karakeep/releases/tag/v0.24.1" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/karakeep-app/karakeep/releases/tag/v0.25.0</id>
    <title>New release for Karakeep: 0.25.0</title>
    <updated>2025-06-08T05:57:57-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>karakeep-app/karakeep</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h1&gt;0.25.0&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the 0.25.0 release of Karakeep! This release addresses a lot of the top most upvoted feature requests. You can now share lists publicly, generate RSS feeds from your lists, reader view &amp;amp; pdf support in the mobile app, bi-directional browser bookmark sync using floccus, maintaining list structure on imports and a lot more. As usual, we have a lot of contributors in this release: @xuatz, @digithree, @thiswillbeyourgithub, @codelove77, @SConaway, @vhsdream, @AdrianAcala, @spasche, @SalGnt, @haappi, @yuikisaito, @jk, @jakeasmith, @Mxrk,  @WilliamAGH, and @SteffoSpieler!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you enjoy using Karakeep, consider supporting the project &lt;a href="https://buymeacoffee.com/mbassem"&gt;here ☕️&lt;/a&gt; or via GitHub &lt;a href="https://github.com/sponsors/MohamedBassem"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.buymeacoffee.com/mbassem" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;img src="https://cdn.buymeacoffee.com/buttons/v2/default-yellow.png" alt="Buy Me A Coffee" width="auto" height="50" &gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;New Features 🚀&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Public Lists are here:&lt;/strong&gt; You can now share your curated lists publicly! (#1511). Example list &lt;a href="https://try.karakeep.app/public/lists/f9ot2k3ogai51gvm3v6k0aoq"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;RSS Feed Generation:&lt;/strong&gt; Create and share RSS feeds directly for your lists (#1507)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Overdue Mobile Improvements&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added reader mode/screenshot/archive views to bookmark previews on mobile (pending app release) (#1509) - @digithree&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;View PDFs directly in the mobile app and share them to karakeep from the share sheet as well (#1519, #1494) - @codelove77&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Import / Export improvements&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added NETSCAPE file export format support (#1374) - @yuikisaito &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When importing netscape style bookmarks into karakeep, your lists will be re-created on karakeep. Preserving lists from other sources is planned.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Preserve archived status when importing from omnivore or pocket (RIP).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AI Auto-Summarization:&lt;/strong&gt; Automatic summarization for new bookmarks can be now be enabled with &lt;code&gt;INFERENCE_ENABLE_AUTO_SUMMARIZATION=true&lt;/code&gt; (#1163)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Floccus Integration:&lt;/strong&gt; Karakeep &lt;a href="https://github.com/floccusaddon/floccus/pull/1953"&gt;now supports&lt;/a&gt; bi-directional sync with browser bookmarks using &lt;a href="https://floccus.org/"&gt;Floccus&lt;/a&gt;. This will be available in the next Floccus release within a week or two.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;UX Improvements ✨&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The user setting page got fully redesigned to look nicer given that we're starting to have more user settings.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tab-based layout for bookmark previews on small screens - @thiswillbeyourgithub &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Save pages faster with a dedicated extension shortcut (#1532) - @SConaway&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Configure the default behavior when clicking on a bookmark. Either go to source, or expand the details.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Restored ability to properly sort by creation date for search pages (#1392) - @xuatz&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can now decide what you want to do when using the &lt;code&gt;singlefile&lt;/code&gt; extension on an existing bookmark. Check out how to customize it &lt;a href="https://docs.karakeep.app/next/Guides/singlefile#handling-existing-bookmarks"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Configure whether you want to see archived bookmarks in lists or tags or not (#1505) - @xuatz&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added Algolia-based search to docs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added "deleted" webhook event (#1464) - @SalGnt&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;code&gt;Summarize with AI&lt;/code&gt; button no longer shows up if you don't have AI configured&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can now disable auto AI tagging if not needed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Allow enabling/disabling RSS feeds collection&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added US English to folks who can't stand the British English - @WilliamAGH &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved the positioning of the highlights menu on mobile devices - @Mxrk&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Moved delete button in bookmark menu in the app for better ergonomics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Fixes 🐛&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Started using proper tokenizer for content truncation before inference. This should prevent the truncation of the model prompt leading to better accuracy and instruction adherence.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Preserve unsaved changes during tag modifications while editing bookmarks (#1515) - @AdrianAcala&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed tag drag-and-drop issues on Firefox (#1016) - @haappi&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added log rotation for linux installations (#1471) - @vhsdream&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can now run Karakeep container as a non-root user for better security.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;For Developers 🛠️&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added &lt;code&gt;?sortOrder&lt;/code&gt; parameter for resource sorting (#1398) - @xuatz  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New endpoint for tag creation  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PUT operations for bookmarks are now idempotent (e.g. adding to list) (#1427) - @xuatz&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added PATCH method support to CORS headers (#1489) - @spasche&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Documentation:&lt;/strong&gt;  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added documentation for the asset upload APIs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed JSON examples in MCP documentation (#1400, #1419) - @jk, @jakeasmith&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Expanded Meilisearch upgrade guides (#1436) - @thiswillbeyourgithub&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Community Projects 💡&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Python-based SDK for Karakeep:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://github.com/thiswillbeyourgithub/karakeep_python_api"&gt;karakeep-python-api&lt;/a&gt; - @thiswillbeyourgithub&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Freshrss Importer:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://github.com/thiswillbeyourgithub/freshrss_to_karakeep"&gt;freshrss-to-karakeep&lt;/a&gt; - @thiswillbeyourgithub &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Screenshots 📸&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Share List Modal&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/688d2389-65c1-4e0e-87ba-233d5b0ffaae" alt="Screenshot 2025-06-08 at 10 35 45@2x" width="500" height="auto"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Tabbed Layout on smaller screens&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/affc1426-fe1f-46df-9567-196c25d13107" alt="Screenshot 2025-06-08 at 10 37 11@2x" width="500" height="auto"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Reader Mode in the app&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/14f438ea-d558-40eb-8d05-84d017d46a89" alt="simulator_screenshot_1322546F-62F2-4129-89F7-7D77366179B6" width="300" height="auto"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Upgrading 📦&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To upgrade:
* If you're using KARAKEEP_VERSION=release, run &lt;code&gt;docker compose pull &amp;amp;&amp;amp; docker compose up -d&lt;/code&gt;.
* If you're pinning it to a specific version, upgrade the version and then run &lt;code&gt;docker compose pull &amp;amp;&amp;amp; docker compose up -d&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;All Commits&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;release(extension): Bump extension version to 1.2.6 - @MohamedBassem in 5b520667&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;release(mobile): Bump mobile version to 1.7.0 - @MohamedBassem in 3c48bb8d&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ci: Fix manifest formatting - @MohamedBassem in b93f3a4a&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feat(mobile): Add support for viewing PDFs (#1519) - @codelove77 in 0fde1087&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix(mobile): Move the delete button to the end in the bookmark menu - @MohamedBassem in 421e3e86&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feat(mobile): add reader/screenshot/archive view to bookmark preview (#1509) - @digithree in ec31a971&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix(build): karakeep-linux.sh fix use 'append' instead of 'file' for log (#1471) - @vhsdream in 09e5dd65&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feat(extension): add a keyboard shortcut to save page (#1532) - @SConaway in ee517456&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feat(ui): Improve the look of the public bookmarks page - @MohamedBassem in 3a0f5fa0&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix: Use a new public list metadata endpoint for metadata generation - @MohamedBassem in bc65a738&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;docs: Add asset APIs to the openapi spec - @MohamedBassem in a98f0236&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix(web): Smaller card titles in the user info page - @MohamedBassem in 4e481f4b&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix: preserve unsaved title changes when modifying bookmark tags in the edit dialog (#1515) - @AdrianAcala in f53ad0a1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feat(web): Redesign the user settings page - @MohamedBassem in 090c0d1c&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;readme: Small readme fixes - @MohamedBassem in 39feafe7&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix(web): Drop the experimental icon from rss feeds - @MohamedBassem in bf4cbd12&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feat: Drop corepack dep in prod and allow running as non-root. Fixes #606 - @MohamedBassem in 169e14d3&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;i18n: Sync weblate translations - 22460836&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Merge remote-tracking branch 'weblate/main' - @MohamedBassem in 7c245aa7&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feat: Maintain list structure when importing from netscape. Fixes #538 - @MohamedBassem in 1bae66f7&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feat: Allow specifying the overwrite mode for singlefile archives. Fixes #1125 - @MohamedBassem in e59be245&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feat: Add support for public lists (#1511) - @MohamedBassem in ea1d0023&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feat: add user customisable default archive display behaviour (#1505) - @xuatz in 3afe1e21&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;docs: mention the list of example scripts for the community api (#1484) - @thiswillbeyourgithub in 8784c73c&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feat(mobile): Add PDF support to share extension (#1494) - @codelove77 in 5f473401&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feat: Generate RSS feeds from lists (#1507) - @MohamedBassem in 9695bba2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;refactor: Move bookmark utils from shared-react to shared - @MohamedBassem in b218118b&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;docs: Add agolia based search - @MohamedBassem in 3e860b79&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;doc: mention meilisearch in the updating section (#1472) - @thiswillbeyourgithub in 7f04bd13&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feat: Allow PATCH method in CORS headers (#1489) - @spasche in 915aeb36&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix: Fix end icon in smart list input overlapping with text. Fixes #1379 - @MohamedBassem in d903c7f9&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix: Show list options menu on list sidebar hover - @MohamedBassem in a1f77075&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix: Truncate the RSS feed url - @MohamedBassem in e0ed727c&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;chore: Add localhost labs to README and landing - @MohamedBassem in e13809fb&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix(landing): Fix the favicon location for the landing page - @MohamedBassem in 96bce30c&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feat: Add "deleted" webhook event (#1464) - @SalGnt in 8a927e96&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;docs: Update the privacy policy - @MohamedBassem in 37c18b89&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feat: Allow defaulting to reader mode when clicking on bookmarks. Fixes #662 - @MohamedBassem in 09652176&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;docs: Update database docs (#1451) - @haappi in 5f3fe5d1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feat: Read the archive status from omnivore and pocket. Fixes #703 - @MohamedBassem in c6d21afa&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;build: Regen openAPI spec - @MohamedBassem in 6af14e9d&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feat: Disable the AI summary button if AI is not configured. Fixes #649 - @MohamedBassem in 85929850&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feat: Add AI auto summarization. Fixes #1163 - @MohamedBassem in 2743d9e3&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feat(api): Expose the endpoint to create a new tag - @MohamedBassem in a5ae67c2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix(web): Switch to a tab view in small screens for bookmark previews - @thiswillbeyourgithub in 053d1a90&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;build: Fix format error - @MohamedBassem in 0e734b6b&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix(web): Fix tag drag and drop merging on firefox .Fixes #1016 (#1309) - @haappi in c2e26f9f&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;refactor: Migrate from NextJs's API routes to Hono based routes for the API (#1432) - @MohamedBassem in 3505cb7d&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;doc: document how to upgrade meilisearch / migrate meilisearch db (#1436) - @thiswillbeyourgithub in 74e74fa6&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;doc: new comunity project: freshrss to karakeep (#1435) - @thiswillbeyourgithub in 3a592931&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feat(api): enable ?sortOrder= for relevant resources (#1398) - @xuatz in 4e06ea7b&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix: Use proper tokenizer when truncating for inference. Fixes #1405 - @MohamedBassem in 70d57209&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feat: position highlight menu based on device type (#1348) - @Mxrk :) in 523a251b&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix(search): add new relevance sort order (#1392) - @xuatz in dbd0fd19&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix(api): make PUT bookmark to a list idempotent (#1427) - @xuatz in f338f7b1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;build(Debian): update yt-dlp on karakeep's update and add a service check function (#1329) - @vhsdream in 4ae5857a&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;doc: Mention karakeep-python-api in community projects (#1424) - @thiswillbeyourgithub in 60f47122&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;docs: minor update to dev setup instructions (#1421) - @thiswillbeyourgithub in 65d7096b&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix(landing): Fix the responsiveness of the landing page - @MohamedBassem in d44cd235&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;docs: Update pikapods docs after the rename - @MohamedBassem in 6f6c9872&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feat: Allow enabling/disabling RSS feeds - @MohamedBassem in 370db082&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feat: Add karakeep metadata to openai calls - @MohamedBassem in 2a8d4b88&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;doc: Fixed json syntax error in mcp docs (#1419) - @jakeasmith in 2082f87e&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;docs: Fix JSON in MCP documentation (#1400) - @jk in 3ececfcc&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feat: Add NETSCAPE-Bookmark-file-1 export format support (#1374) - @yuikisaito in c03dcfdb&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix(mcp): Correct description for get-lists tool. Fixes #1332 (#1388) - @MohamedBassem in 8b05515b&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;i18n: Add US English as option in User Settings (#1327) - @WilliamAGH in 3d802db4&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;docs: Update the docs about admin password reset to include the salt - @MohamedBassem in 3b246a88&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix(docker): Fix build only docker compose file - @MohamedBassem in f4a31563&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/karakeep-app/karakeep/releases/tag/v0.25.0" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
