<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://selfh.st/apps</id>
  <title>Kavita Releases</title>
  <updated>2025-04-18T05:31:00.049999-04:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>selfh.st</name>
    <email>contact@selfh.st</email>
  </author>
  <link href="https://selfh.st/apps" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>Self-hosted software releases generated by selfh.st</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/Kareadita/Kavita/releases/tag/v0.8.4.2</id>
    <title>New release for Kavita: v0.8.4.2 - Hotfix + Migration Script</title>
    <updated>2024-11-27T15:11:39-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Kareadita/Kavita</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;A few small things slipped past. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to take this space to first apologize to our users that manually tag their metadata in Kavita. Post release has been an eye opener to the different ways uses of Kavita and a lesson learned to work harder to preserve data between releases. I always try, but sometimes big lift and shifts like this are needed and aren't easy to preserve data. I will take it on myself to strive for excellence and do what is feasible to preserve data. I don't foresee many major refactors like this happening in the near future. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On more positive news, MetronInfo.xml has become stabilized. This is a step towards advancing the metadata format for Comics and Manga (and potentially books in the future). I have worked closely with Brian (the creator) to include Manga into the format. Kavita is dedicated towards supporting the format, that work is planned for next year. Read up more about it &lt;a href="https://metron-project.github.io/blog/metroninfo-v1"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have a lot of metadata that was tagged just via the UI, you can try this &lt;a href="https://pastebin.com/RPmfSSYq"&gt;script&lt;/a&gt; a user wrote to migrate the data. Grab a backup from v0.8.3 and run this against it. You need to update &lt;code&gt;oldDb&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;newDb&lt;/code&gt;. I cannot offer support for this script. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did convert this to python via ChatGPT and added instructions, it will be much easier but I did not test it. You can find the script &lt;a href="https://pastebin.com/BR0GxaXB"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Fixed&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Send to on mobile was still broken&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Changed On Deck to use a workaround as a temp fix&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bug where on non-English locales parsing numbers would throw an exception and cause files to not be ingested. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Bulk library delete wasn't hooked up&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bug where updating chapter metadata with a new person, the normalized name was saved&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Potentially fixed a bug where adding multiple people on a series via UI will throw an exception (Was not able to reproduce, but added extra safety logic)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/Kareadita/Kavita/releases/tag/v0.8.4.2" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/Kareadita/Kavita/releases/tag/v0.8.5</id>
    <title>New release for Kavita: v0.8.5 - Metadata Downloading &amp; PDF Metadata!</title>
    <updated>2025-03-07T14:36:21-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Kareadita/Kavita</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;It's been some time since the last release and this one is hefty! The goal of this release is to overhaul Kavita+ experience within Kavita, but I sneaked in metadata downloading, something I originally envisioned for Kavita, as well. This release is packed with a lot of goodies, from the ability to download metadata, greatly improving the PDF experience, to decreasing the scrobble window from 4 hours to 1 hour, and much more. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Metadata Downloading (Kavita+)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I first started Kavita, I talked about wanting to build a plugin system to support metadata downloading, so I could have a true Plex experience. As the application and user base grew, the Plugin system was too much scope for me to handle and I said goodbye to the idea. Luckily, Kavita+ is here to provide that opportunity to build it out and all of last year, I have been slowly laying the foundation to make it a reality. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kavita can now automatically download metadata and apply it to your Series. It currently supports 12 different fields, including Cover Image, People, Genres, Tags, Age Ratings, and Relationships to name a few. I wanted to build a system that was functional but simple. Kavita offers a few controls that should allow enough flexibility to work for most users. I want to also thank the community for the overwhelming testing and feedback. The nightly testers and community really brought a lot of great ideas to polish this feature off. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With that said, I want to set expectations. I'm not looking to build a komf replacement. This will currently just use metadata from AniList/MAL and Hardcover once I get around to it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So how does it work? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;PDF Metadata&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The pains of PDF may finally be over! Kavita now can read PDF metadata when tagged with Calibre (there is no real metadata format). Thanks to @microtherion writing a custom PDF parser, Kavita can now extract Series, title, volume, genres, etc from your files and bring a good experience for people forced to use PDFs. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;New Stats API&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This release also sees the release of an overhauled stat system. The Stats API is mainly for understanding how many servers are running Kavita, but there is also a lot of benefit in collecting anonymous data about the users of Kavita. On multiple occasions, I base decisions for features or bugs based on that data. However, the original stats API was quite out of date with what was important, so I overhauled it drastically. Like always, the code is Open source and nothing is logged that can identify you. You can take a look at the stat record &lt;a href="https://github.com/Kareadita/KavitaStats/pull/67"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. Thank you to all that continue to report statistics. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Misc&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wanted to shout out a few extra features that are included in this release. First off, Automatic Webtoon mode switching. This is a very common issue for users that read by comics and webtoons and also a discovery issue for new users. While I had architected out a grand solution for this, due to time constraints it never came. This is a good hold over until that time comes. When Kavita opens a comic that is likely a webtoon, it will switch into the mode for you automatically. It's not 100%, but a best guess. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another new feature is bringing Bionic Reading mode to Kavita's epub reader via a new font. A few users asked for this and thankfully a font made it possible. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Docker Fix&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the last release, docker users reported the scanner breaking. You can fix this with the following. The wiki reflects this as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Add &lt;code&gt;DOTNET_SYSTEM_GLOBALIZATION_INVARIANT=true&lt;/code&gt; to your docker compose&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;This Year&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With that said, let's talk about what I want to deliver this year. I have to preface this by saying that this year my time is extremely constrained. But as always, I have lots of ideas that I want to try and accomplish. Since my time is limited, I've scaled down my goals to 2 main features:
1. &lt;strong&gt;Journal-style Progress&lt;/strong&gt; will allow for a much richer stats experience and allow for some new functionalities in reading history. I've already validated this architecture in another project so it shouldn't be too complex porting back to Kavita. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kobo Sync&lt;/strong&gt; was on my list last year but due to the new scanner, got pushed away. With the news of Kindle, it seems like a great time to prioritize it to the front of the list. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These two features are a blend of user wants and my own wants to enable much richer statistics in the application. I'm sure I'll get side tracked along the way and deliver something cool. As always, a big thank you to our users and community. Kavita would not be where it is without your comments, feedback, and ideas. I'm really grateful that I have a great community, looking forward to working with you this year. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note: AniList API is currently degraded and stuck at 30 requests / min. I've tried to build out the cache to avoid having to hit them for the release. Please be patient, I will be continuing my work on Kavita+ to work around these API limits.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;With metadata being available for PDF, you may loose progress. When v0.8.5 starts, it will export all progress to config/progress_export-v0.8.5.csv&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/942d0640-eb36-4523-93bc-d3f882ae29cc" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/7b6ade48-8036-4d0b-b473-bddaf6b10bc2" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/419955c1-9557-44e2-b329-dba43fb2b050" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/4133c843-cc74-4cb6-96b0-5d1c43fa1d61" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Added&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: Added Fast Font to Book Reader. Fast Font is an open source Bionic Font alternative (FR #1268)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: Added the ability to read embedded metadata from PDFs that conform to Calibre's embedding. (FR #3103)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: Added a new stat for if the server uses metadata matching&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: (Manga Reader) When most of the file dimensions look like webtoon images, switch into the Webtoon reader on behalf of the user.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: Series related tab will now show if there are bookmarks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: Added the ability to see release notes of nightly releases in the changelog/announcements screens.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: The UI will now check for new versions of Kavita (server-level) and prompt the user with the changelog and force them to refresh to get the latest UI code. This also takes care of any transloco hacks to clear the cache. This should help on update day for non-admin users to get the latest UI code files.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: Added a new long term cache directory (cache-long). Currently storing Github release history information.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: (Kavita+) Complete overhaul to the Kavita+ license page. Not only will you have the main license flow, but Kavita will pull down information about your subscription, including the registered email, total sub length, when the expiration will be, and if you're on a valid Kavita install version. Surfaced some of the actionable buttons with descriptions to hopefully help drive more management through the software instead of emailing me.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: Added long term caching for Publisher/Favicon fallback so CoversDb doesn't have to service more requests than needed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: (Kavita+) There is now a manual match flow in Kavita to match a series (or fix a match) to AniList (currently the only upstream provider till Hardcover). Kavita still tries to match automatically, but via this new action from Series detail page, you can either provide another search name or Anilist/Mal urls directly to direct match. Likewise, you can select 'Do Not Match' which will delete any previously matched data, drop all scrobble events, and prevent matching/scrobbling in the future.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: (Kavita+) Removed the previous error/matched bar from license screen and broke into it's own page called Matched Metadata. You can now filter by matched state (either not yet matched, needs manual match, don't match) and perform said flows from this screen. This should result in a much easier time navigating your metadata.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: (Kavita+) New screen to see your users and if their AniList tokens are set or expired.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: (Kavita+) Kavita will now email you (assuming email is setup and using a real email) whenever your scrobble tokens are about to expire (5 days out) and the day of, urging you to renew them to avoid scrobbling issues.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: Kavita now has an email history table for admins to see which emails were sent out&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: (Kavita+) Kavita now implements the feature request to sync your 'planned' read lists from AniList/MAL into Kavita's Want to Read (FR #3153)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: New button to download a person's image from CoverDB. I am still working out how to approach an automated solution. CoverDB is open for new entries.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: (Kavita+) Added the ability for individual users to turn on/off scrobbling to anilist and the want to read sync.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: (Kavita+) Kavita can now download metadata upon add and via the Match action. Metadata includes series cover image, summary, age rating, publication status, relationships (assuming already owned), release year, people (writer, artist, character) - including cover images, genres, and tags. Provides a flexible system to customize to your needs or disable altogether.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: (Kavita+) New Library setting to opt a whole library out of being matched.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: (Kavita+) Ability to override locked fields when performing a match to update metadata&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: Users can now press enter to close (and save) the setting items that are text inputs &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Changed&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Changed the maximum line length of text inside of expandable blocks of text to a readable value (Thanks @heyhippari)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Allow admins to change non-admin's email accounts on file. Will automatically assume it's valid.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Docker builds will now have extra metadata (Thanks @halkeye)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed:  Cleaned up the person image components to be a better experience in different states (Thanks @heyhippari )&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Known for on person page shouldn't show for Translator/Team/Location.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Updated docker build scripts to include docker labels&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Massive overhaul to the data collection aspect of Kavita to ship more helpful information that is more up to date with the functionalities of Kavita. Stat collection can still be disabled and will still run after the first 12 hours to give time to opt-out.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: ReadOnly role is now more inline with the name. Any user with this role will only be able to rate series and update their want to read.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Added a new mix mode for Colorscape to darken the colors&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Reworked handling of an exception for there being 2 progress entries for a given chapter. This previously would take the first and set as the new progress, but now it will take the newest and also take the highest page.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Don't show the number of images under a chapter card for images.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Rewrote the changelog/announcement to now be limited to 10 releases and have a better rendering experience.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: [TIME] profiling logs from last release is now on Trace as it's no longer needed anymore.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Updated to .NET 9 which brings performance improvements and patches some security vulnerabilities&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: (Kavita+) When registering a license that was previously bound to another instance, Kavita will now prompt you to override that old binding. This is usually the case and thus Kavita can perform the reset and registration in one flow for you (rather than you using Reset button then Saving again).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: (Kavita+) After registering your license a popup will open to inform you of how Scrobbling works and the next steps you should take.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: (Kavita+) After adding your Anilist token, Kavita now prompts you if you want to backfill scrobble events now or later (from Scrobbling page). This first time generation is important to sync your history/want to read/ratings from before you added the token. Giving the user time to setup Series Holds will ensure only data they want exposed is.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: (Kavita+) Scrobbling window is decreased from 4 hours to 1 hour&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: If anilist id is set, will add an AL weblink on person page&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: (Kavita+) Age Rating mappings from Kavita+ Metadata settings will apply when scanning in series.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: (Kavita+) When using edit series modal, also recalculate age rating based on tags/genres&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: (Kavita+) Characters are now ordered based on their role in the Series (Main, Supporting, Background)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: (Kavita+) Sleep a little longer for background fetching to respect AL's new rate limit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: (Kavita+) Reset all blacklisted external series metadata to allow fresh start with the much upgraded code. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Fixed&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed the way the sidebar closes (both on large screens and on mobile) to prevent text and icons jumping around during the animation. (Thanks @heyhippari)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bug where if an age restricted user tried to load a person that they have partial access to, the backend would restrict the load &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bug where double tap on an image in manga reader no longer triggers the bookmark flow. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed the UI using the wrong localization key for On Deck descriptions &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bug where updating Team, it would actually write to Characters for edit series modal.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a typo in the event widget error message that shows up when the scan returns an empty root folder for the particular library. (Thanks @midhun3301 )&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: (Kavita+) Fixed a long standing bug where background series processing (fetching metadata for K+) wasn't pulling anything more than the first 25 series over and over.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed add device button being broken&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bug where an admin editing a user was unable to save the form without a valid email, even though non-valid emails are allowed. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bug where person links wouldn't be url encoded&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bug where characters weren't being saved on the backend&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bug where progress tooltips would be behind the card title overlay &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bug where when the filename and the series name/localized name are the same, Kavita would get confused and skip the file.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bug where reading a pdf on Kavita then switching to reading over OPDS, the cache wouldn't work as the images weren't cached, only the pdf. (Thanks @m-amazirh for the help)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: When downloading image series/chapters, zip them up and use the folder names on disk for inside the archive&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: (Manga Reader) Fixed up/down arrow key not scrolling on manga reader with original layout &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Sanitize OPDS feeds in case the user has characters that are invalid&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: (Epub Reader) White book theme was unnecessarily overriding some book styles (Thanks @Redst0neFlux)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Don't darken images on white/paper book themes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bug when bulk selecting cards, the read button overlay shouldn't be present&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Confirmation modals didn't have localized strings.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: (Kavita+) Fixed a bug where want to read was scrobbling from libraries where AllowScrobbling is off. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: (Kavita+) Fixed a bug where Want to Read scrobbling was not respecting library rules &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed Characters field not being wired up in the Save API.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed location locked field not being wired up in the Save API.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a weird issue where Host name would eat keys when typing on General settings.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bug where clicking a person from Volume/Chapter detail pages wouldn't load the person profile&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bug that was calling unneeded checks on Kavita+ license validation each refresh&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed spacing issue on the edit chapter modal (and aligned all modals to have the same spacing)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bug where a progress check on the DB was being handled which logged a warning to logger.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed the overlay title on cards extending past the card boundary when in a carousel (Thanks @Zeoic)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bug where the background job to fill out metadata was constantly pulling the same blacklisted series over and over again, thus making no progress.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bug where epub images that were hotlinked weren't loading correctly in the reader.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed removing web links behaving wrongly when removing links in a specific order  (Thanks @Fesaa)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed default cache being 50MB when it should be 75MB&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bug when a metadata refresh event comes int, the active tab could get stuck on series detail&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed not being able to update general server settings &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: (Kavita+) New migration to cleanup super old scrobble events that might be side-effects of version updates. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Feature Requests&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added Fast Font to Book Reader. Fast Font is an open source Bionic Font alternative (FR #1268)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added the ability to read embedded metadata from PDFs that conform to Calibre's embedding. (FR #3103)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(Kavita+) Kavita now implements the feature request to sync your 'planned' read lists from AniList/MAL into Kavita's Want to Read (FR #3153)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Known Issues&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some covers will disappear after being added to Kavita (rare). If I can reproduce, I will hotfix.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Match modal may sometimes appear like there are no results but there should be. This is due to rate issues, this will be addressed in v0.8.6. You just need to wait a few minutes for it to be searchable again. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don't fall behind (Out of date)  modal is popping when it shouldn't (a hotfix will be issued in a few days)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/Kareadita/Kavita/releases/tag/v0.8.5" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/Kareadita/Kavita/releases/tag/v0.8.5.3</id>
    <title>New release for Kavita: v0.8.5.3 - Hotfix</title>
    <updated>2025-03-09T13:13:19-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Kareadita/Kavita</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;A small hotfix is needed due to the Don't fall behind modal showing incorrectly. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The known issue of covers disappearing seems to be related to multi-root libraries and thus is likely to require a full release cycle to tackle. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Fixed&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bug where the Don't fall behind modal was opening constantly&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a wiki link being wrong&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/Kareadita/Kavita/releases/tag/v0.8.5.3" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/Kareadita/Kavita/releases/tag/v0.8.5.11</id>
    <title>New release for Kavita: v0.8.5.11 - Hotfix 2</title>
    <updated>2025-03-17T15:25:25-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Kareadita/Kavita</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;I decided to do one more hotfix as there was an annoying bug for multi-root libraries that causes flip-flopping (the same issue as covers disappearing). This also contains some fixes around scrobbling and misc other bugs reported that are a good fit. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;v0.8.6 is still planned to focus on the Scanner and finishing off the Kavita+ Polish. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Changed&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Locale selection now shows the total percentage of completion of the locale.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Cleaned up some code around localization as a way to hopefully fight the keys showing in the UI on new versions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: (Kavita+) When a user removes the Kavita+ license from their instance, stop doing all K+ Background tasks instead of waiting for the next restart.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: (Kavita+) Kavita will now clean up old scrobble events for users that don't have an anilist token on their account, so that events that will never get processed get cleaned up.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: (Kavita+) When sourcing descriptions from Kavita+, remove the (Source: X).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Fixed&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bug where a signature on an API was wrong &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: (Kavita+) Fixed a length issue for reviews from Kavita+ that could break metadata matching &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: (Kavita+) Fixed some edge case handling of want to read scrobbling and potentially some issues around events that never get processed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed unable to start Kavita for the first time on DD/MM/YYYY locales (Thanks @Fesaa )&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bug where multi-root libraries would delete and recreate series in one of non-first folders&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed reading list not respecting age restrictions (Thanks @Fesaa )&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;API&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Updated the ReadHistoryEvent to expose ReadDateUtc instead of just the server timezone date. (Thanks @0xGingi)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Known Issues&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Docker images aren't showing Locale names correctly (this will be fixed v0.8.6)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/Kareadita/Kavita/releases/tag/v0.8.5.11" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/Kareadita/Kavita/releases/tag/v0.8.6</id>
    <title>New release for Kavita: v0.8.6 - Spring Cleaning</title>
    <updated>2025-04-14T18:09:30-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Kareadita/Kavita</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;v0.8.6 is here and it's only fair to call this the Spring-Cleaning release as over the past 3 weeks, Amelia (@Fesaa) and I have closed out 65 issues from Github and polished a ton of the app. This release is packed with a lot of OLD issues finally being tackled and a few of them are quite annoying, so let's get started with the breakdown. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, let's talk about the few enhancements that made it into the release. One of these enhancements was around Smart Filters and removing them from your customize list or renaming them. Both are features that weren't thought about in the initial implementation and just kept slipping through the cracks. Amelia took it upon herself to not only implement but also add some drag and drop reordering on the side nav for those that don't want to go into customize screen. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another nice enhancement is around Media Errors. I implemented Media Errors after being inspired by Komga feature, but never gave it much more thought after that. You know what's annoying? Having 300 media errors that aren't actually reflective of the state of your media. The original thought was manually clearing the alerts, but why can't Kavita just do most of those checks for you? So that's what this feature brings. Kavita will check if files were successfully imported with at least 1 page or 1 word and clear out the issue for you. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last big enhancement is around Reading Lists. I'm not a huge reading list user, but the folks over in CBL project have been discussing some polish that is needed and raised a great &lt;a href="https://github.com/Kareadita/Kavita/discussions/3671"&gt;Feature Request&lt;/a&gt;. Some of these were no-brainers, so I took a few days and implemented some much-needed polish and exposed more metadata around the reading list. My favorite is not being in edit mode by default. If you have ideas on how to make the Reading List experience better, please add your ideas to the Feature Request. I have already confirmed I will be doing a big overhaul once I have a good picture of the features user's want and need. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the enhancements out of the way, let's focus on the meat of this release, the bugfixes and polish. I'll open with one I know many readers are going to enjoy--the webtoon reader finally tracks the last page read when using the continuous reader 100% of the time. The nightly users and I tested this by reading a combined 700 chapters (500 of those were just @duplaja, go figures). Shoutout to @reinar for providing some code that helped me get the needed fix. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another major fix, with the help yet again of Amelia, is the localization fix. Non-English locales have been having issues with Kavita for the last few releases and due to me not being able to reproduce the issues, I used a shotgun approach to fixing the issue. Luckily Amelia has such a setup and was able to fix it. Docker users can now remove the &lt;code&gt;DOTNET_SYSTEM_GLOBALIZATION_INVARIANT=true&lt;/code&gt; from their compose file and Kavita should work across the board. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Docker users&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remove &lt;code&gt;DOTNET_SYSTEM_GLOBALIZATION_INVARIANT=true&lt;/code&gt; from your compose files. It is no longer needed. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lastly, Amelia polished a lot of the UI for the epub reader, closing out some annoying issues around scrolling, especially on iOS (which I cannot test against) and I focused on the backend, allowing for loosened parsing requirements, but still reporting the issue to Media Errors (Thanks to @vers-one for enhancing their library). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This overall feels like a great release with a lot of polish and stability. Many other issues were fixed, and I feel very confident in this release. The next release is planned to focus on the Scanner and see if some more instability can be ironed out and apply some more performance improvements. Amelia and I have been brainstorming and doing some research to see what overhauls we can make. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lastly I want to end with an update that my time is still extremely constrained and will likely be this way going forward, so expect longer windows between releases. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Added&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: Ability to delete Smart filter steams from Customize Side Nav and Dashboard&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: Ability to rename Smart Filters in Customize settings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: Added the ability to reorder the side nav without using customize screen by clicking the actionable on Home -&amp;gt; Reorder (Thanks @Fesaa)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: Added a new cleanup task that scans media errors and clears them out if they are ingested fine into Kavita &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: Added a new preference option for allowing Kavita to automatically switch into webtoon reader mode based on image resolution. Defaults to on.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: Added the ability to see all people across a reading list, the time it would take to read, and age rating.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: Updated many areas of Kavita to bring even better localization support. Everything in the UI should be fully localized now &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: Added support for partial (0.5) volumes for Korean filename parsing &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Changed&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Allow volume title card overlay for more than just book libraries&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Updated hostname tooltip text to be more clear&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Added a toast message for backfilling events on scrobble page.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: (Kavita+) Changed button on Scrobbling Errors to a match button which can directly fix the issue, rather than the old edit and add weblink.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Improved the tooltip for the scrobbling button to be clearer if it is on/off.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Overhauled the reading list detail page to be more aligned with series detail page&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Reading lists will be in non-edit mode by default. A new edit button can toggle edit mode and bring drag handles and other controls.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Added a warning when in edit mode about when drag handles are suppressed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: PDFs will now fall back to the Title in metadata for series&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Updated Angular to 19 &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: (Kavita+) Don't create scrobble events for specials as they will never match on AniList&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Updated wording and some styling to make the first impression better&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Changed how series downloads work to include the individual archives instead of unpacking them first (for non-image based series) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Reworked the version update logic so that we don't pop the new version update so often. It will now pop once and if no action is taken, it will wait a week to pop again. The same logic applies to the you are X releases behind, etc (but longer windows).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Updated dependencies and Security issues from downstream libraries&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Enhanced parsing code for (back cover) falsely being recognized as a cover image. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Cleaned up how specials are parsed to allow supporting periods in the Title name &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: (Epub Reader) When reading in Double Column mode, Kavita will now prevent seeing the same text twice by added an empty page when needed &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Allow users to type both localized name and series name to find a match on Related Series &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Made Library type and Sort options dropdowns alphabetical (localized)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Removed the analyze task as it shouldn't be needed anymore&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Renamed Comic -&amp;gt; Comic (Legacy) and Comic (Comic Vine) -&amp;gt; Comic. The new comic library should be the primary.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Moved the reset button for API Key to the right side, which renders much nicer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Aligned and corrected some styling for the Edit/Close button on setting items to be consistent&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Setting items that are not editable won't show the pointer cursor&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Setting switch items have the label appropriately wired and thus when you click the label, the switch will update.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Details tab will show genre/tags expanded by default&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: (Kavita+) Updated how JWT looks at expiration time for AniList Token.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Moved Skipped scheduling ScanFolder log message to Trace as it's noisy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Tweaked how localization cache busting is handled to try and get Transloco to respect cache busting&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: For Admins (or users with access to all libraries), under Manage Users, sharing now shows 'All Libraries'&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Changed how epubs are parsed. Now, Kavita will try to open it expecting a valid epub structure (which isn't common without user intervention) then allow falling back to a non-correct epub (with degraded experience within Kavita). Kavita will record issue in the Media Issues tab.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Ensure all switch elements link up with a label element for accessibility.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: (Kavita+) Switched Last modified to Created for when the scrobble reading event took place.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Reading lists' age rating will now update when a series age rating is updated via the UI&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Moved Gmail/Outlook auto fill buttons from Host Name to Host setting&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Setting items will auto focus when switching into edit mode&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Fixed&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed an issue with non-American date and number parsing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed an initial blank page on settings due to a slow locale cache load&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixes the environment variable for invariant globalization still being set in the Dockerfile&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bug where cbl import wouldn't allow importing due to the name clashing with another user, when it should have only checked your account&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a lot of styling across the app and overall polish&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bug when updating email settings, it can error out after 2 changes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed an issue where chapter ranges (1-3) could get an incorrect sort order &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed an issue with Mihon over-extracting image files (Thanks @arition)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a missing action handler for delete chapter from series detail page.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed issues with selection on mobile devices in the epub reader causing pages to skip &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed TitleSort being used instead of SeriesSort for Series Sort field  (Thanks @joshuaavalon for the help)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Moved loading icon up so it's visible even when having a lot of cards on library detail page&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Improved the webtoon reader's ability to ensure chapters are marked as read from continuous reader which caused the last page to not get marked as read. (Thanks @reinar for the spur)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bug in edit list that would break the UI when any comma separated values were used.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed read more for chinese text &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed tooltips on series card getting overlapped (Thanks @therobbiedavis )&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: (Kavita+) Fixed an issue where some people's metadata could have broken urls due to an @ symbol in the url for their description&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed up the webtoon detection algorithm to be more robust &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed the scrobbling page not having working sorting &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed locale response being empty on first load (Thanks @nevivurn)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed PDF specials using filename instead of embedded metadata as title&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Stats charts shouldn't overlap anymore&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed the changelog for API/Removed having an extra -&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bug in the update series metadata where you wouldn't be able to clear out people field.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Updated chapter update API to allow ability to clear out people fields, genres, and tags.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed reading list items overflowing (Thanks @therobbiedavis )&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed missing scrollbars in some dropdowns&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed an out-of-bounds from a reading list when reordering&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed Epub table of contents, when all under one node didn't show as active. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed the inability to update server settings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed release date not displaying correctly in the edit chapter model &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed 'never' being displayed in a bunch of places on certain locales&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed the incorrect date layout being used on certain locales&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bug where Top Readers on Stats page wasn't rendering the numbers correctly&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: (Epub Reader) Fixed chapter not always scrolling to the top. Was not able to reproduce but used a community fed fix. (Thanks @joonhuiwong)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Don't throw an exception when downloading a theme that is already downloaded but just let the user re-download it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed some padding on a few setting screens that got missed last release.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed flashing no result message during loading of MAL Stacks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed an issue on edit series/chapter detail page where language input would not show the language reliably.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed issues with selection on mobile devices in the epub reader causing pages to skip&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bad url to the wiki page&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed an issue where search could not be selectable and would also close the pdf reader on ESC. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bug where some fields weren't being ingested from ComicInfo due to a bug from last release &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed edit chapter modal, tag options weren't rendering&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed edit chapter modal not being able to have some metadata fields persist&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed an issue on edit series/chapter modal where adding data to a typeahead field, then switching to another tab would blank out the field.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bug where Send to Email/Kindle was not properly sending the filename of the file.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: (Kavita+) Fixed a missing blacklist path for Kavita+ background fetch&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed 'add to reading list' not working in volume detail&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed users being unable to open promoted reading lists via OPDS&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed reading lists, adding an unnecessary volume marker for EPUB specials&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bug where registration form was telling the user the email was required when it wasn't.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed change email so that multiple toasts don't popup telling the user that email was updated successfully but also wasn't and link needed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed change email and change password not switching to view mode after save.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bug where UI was not reflecting that an Admin cannot change their age restriction settings.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bug where filter IsEmpty wasn't hiding the value input.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: IsEmpty wasn't working for Collection Tags and Tags&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bug where Genres/Tags from ComicInfo.xml were being normalized &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Detail page actionables were being hidden on mobile.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/Kareadita/Kavita/releases/tag/v0.8.6" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
