<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://selfh.st/apps</id>
  <title>Kavita Releases</title>
  <updated>2024-04-05T22:30:38.975721-04:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>selfh.st</name>
    <email>contact@selfh.st</email>
  </author>
  <link href="https://selfh.st/apps" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>Self-hosted software releases generated by selfh.st</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/Kareadita/Kavita/releases/tag/v0.7.11.1</id>
    <title>New release for Kavita: v0.7.11.1 - Hotfix</title>
    <updated>2023-12-05T09:05:02-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Kareadita/Kavita</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;An unfortunate bug slipped in last minute with the release which would cause LastModified fields to be updated at night when a cleanup task ran to cap progress to 100% (in cases where a user reads 10 pages, swaps the file for one with only 8 pages). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This hotfix will fix that skewing, however, it is likely the task has already ran. You can restore your DB backup from prior to updating (Dec 3rd). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm sorry about the data loss.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Fixed&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a critical bug where the cleanup task would break ordering of progress events. This would cause your On Deck to skew.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/Kareadita/Kavita/releases/tag/v0.7.11.1" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/Kareadita/Kavita/releases/tag/v0.7.11.2</id>
    <title>New release for Kavita: v0.7.11.2 - Hotfix 2</title>
    <updated>2023-12-11T16:42:59-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Kareadita/Kavita</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately a few more bugs surfaced after the last hotfix, one being a problem with extracting weblink id's for Kavita+ matching along with an annoying bug with side nav being wiped out for fresh install admins. This is the last release for the year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Remember to use the new &lt;a href="https://hub.docker.com/r/jvmilazz0/kavita"&gt;Docker Central Repo&lt;/a&gt;! Updates are not going to the old one.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Changed&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Backups now show the version of Kavita in the filename&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Moved some cleanup tasks within another task to ensure everything is processed at the same time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Changed the readme to point to the correct type of projects.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: (Kavita+) When sending requests to Kavita+, MangaDex Ids will be sent as well to prepare for a potential enhancement next year.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Fixed&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed unneeded slowness in the image api as some debug code got left in there&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed invalid date showing on tasks screen&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a long standing parser bug where series would parse as Love Hina Vol. 30 Chapter 22 when the file was Love Hina Vol. 30 Chapter 22 - Vol 30 Omakes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: (Kavita+) Fixed a bug where Kavita+ wasn't being sent the ids from Weblinks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a loader showing on the webtoon reader when it shouldn't have&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a critical issue where fresh installs that invite a user have their own admin account's side nav and dashboard streams wiped out&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bug where Smart filters would always evaluate to descending sort&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bug where some progress bars wouldn't report series progress correctly&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Known Issue&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some users on iOS are reporting issues with the webtoon reader. I spent a week working with one user but unfortunately unable to reproduce. I will look into buying an iOS device next year. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/Kareadita/Kavita/releases/tag/v0.7.11.2" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/Kareadita/Kavita/releases/tag/v0.7.12</id>
    <title>New release for Kavita: v0.7.12 - Happy New Year</title>
    <updated>2024-01-07T15:51:59-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Kareadita/Kavita</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;Happy New Year! A new year and a new set of plans for the year. I wanted to get this first release out quickly so I can share my plans as I'm bursting with excitement. The release is pretty small and mainly focused on bugs I found during my holiday. With that out of the way, let's talk about Kavita this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Process Change&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First off, I will be changing how feature requests are handled. Going forward, Kavita will solely use &lt;a href="https://github.com/Kareadita/Kavita/discussions/2529"&gt;Github Discussions&lt;/a&gt; for feature requests. Normal support will be done still via Issues and Discord and bugs of course via Issues. I tried many different things over the last 3 years. Given the scope of the application, I need something a bit more robust. The current feature site, while is nice, doesn't send alerts to users, leaving me without a means to communicate when I'm actually ready to start a feature. Discord is just too chaotic and we lack visibility. All feature requests over 10 votes have been migrated over to Discussions already. Please go visit and engage so we can drive some of these home. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next, let's talk about shaping features. Once a feature is on discussions and I agree, I will be taking this feature to my Kavita+ discord users to help shape the feature into the final solution. I usually rely on a few users for advice, but going forward, Kavita+ users (which many would consider power users) will have a strong say in shaping features going forward. Feedback is always welcome from non-Kavita+ users, but I want to utilize power users to drive features going forward. You can go to Kavita+ tab to link your Discord User Id with your Kavita+ license, which will grant you access to the hidden channels. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lastly, the subreddit will be shutdown this year. I no longer use Reddit and unfortunately have to keep it as the subreddit needs questions answered. I hope you all can respect my decision and can migrate to discord for future discussions/support. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Website/Wiki&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The website is drastically out of date and quite bad. Originally I copied it from Lidarr, which I was one of the original developers, and meant to update it to a new look and feel, but never got around to it. This is finally the year to take action. A new design and stack has already been chosen and @therobbiedavis is taking lead on driving the effort. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to the new website, I will be creating a blog. I need a centralized place to post updates that may not be tied to a release (like this post). The new website will host the blog and I will post releases there as well. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The wiki is also in need of some love. It's quite difficult keeping it up to date myself. @DieselTech and @ThePromidius have helped a ton in that regard to updating, but we are in need of a deep redesign of the information and a new technology to allow better searching. We are investigating new software and are planning a complete revamp over this year. If anyone is knowledgeable about Kavita and wants to contribute, please reach out in discord. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Features&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Kavita+&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have a few key features for Kavita+ that I want to test and if successful, deliver to you all. The first up is &lt;strong&gt;Metadata&lt;/strong&gt;. Komf is a great tool that already exists, but some users want something a bit simpler and that is where Kavita+ comes in. When I first started Kavita, I always had the goal of metadata integration but soon I learned how disjointed everything is and it seemed like adding it would become a full time job instead of letting me build out Kavita. As Kavita+ already has metadata from AniList, I see an opportunity to trial metadata integration. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the end of 2023, Robbie mentioned to me Hardcover, a potential integration point for Kavita+ that has similar features as AniList -- reviews, ratings, scrobblings, and metadata for books (and some limited comics). After speaking with their development team, this seems feasible to build out. I will be doing a deep dive later this year to bring these features into Kavita+. This also means if metadata support is built out, it will benefit from Hardcover.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lastly, as mentioned above, Kavita+ users will become critical to shaping and expanding on community ideas once accepted. Link your discord user id via Kavita and you will be granted access into the hidden channels to participate in defining the scope of an idea and provide feedback post implementation before it ships to stable users. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;PDF&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PDF as many of you know has always been Kavita's weakest point. PDFs have no tools existing for metadata, have the worst and most inconsistent naming patterns out there and overall have just not been a good fit within Kavita. I want to change that this year. First off I want to polish the reader. I've been using a reader that doesn't have many hooks nor does it have the ability to save the reading preferences. I had originally opened an issue for information on how people use Kavita, but the comments were underwhelming. I will be looking to my Kavita+ users to help shape this feature and deliver a good experience. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many users also collect magazines and I think it's high time a separate library type with different parsing is built out. Like I did with the image library last year, I will be adding a new library type explicitly for Magazines with a limited set of metadata and some UI differences. PDF parsing overall will be updated to be more robust and work better overall. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Comics&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comics are quite complicated and work differently than I had thought when users asked me many years to add comic support. This year I will be trialing a new library type that mimics ComicVine's format, which is the standard for Mylar and comics in general. As is the theme, my Kavita+ users, including @DieselTech  will be helping me drive the end solution. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Kobo Sync&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last major feature is Kobo sync. I bought a Kobo and am excited to reverse engineer the protocol to allow native sync with Kavita, much like calibre-web has. Originally this was planned as a Kavita+ feature, but after looking more into it, Kavita can service it without problem. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are more items on my list as well, but let's leave a bit to surprise. I'm sure everyone can tell these are huge items with that will take tons of time. I'm really excited for this year and what I can achieve. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Remember to use the new &lt;a href="https://hub.docker.com/r/jvmilazz0/kavita"&gt;Docker Central Repo&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Added&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: (Kavita+) Added the ability to view the provider of a recommendation on the card itself and in the preview drawer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: (Kavita+) Added the ability to reset your Kavita+ license key without having to reach out to me.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: (Kavita+) Added the ability to add your Discord UserId during Kavita+ license registration which will grant access to hidden channels for feature curtailing. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Changed&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: When opening up an external series review, show the source of the review.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Streamlined the design slightly for a user's personal review&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: There is now inline form validation on the User Review Modal&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Removed the tagline from user/external reviews. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: (Scanner) When a series has a single special and a total count of 1 or less, assume it's completed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Lots of love around the messaging when interacting with users that do not use real emails.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Enhanced the messaging around users without valid emails interacting with change email flow. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Validation messaging added on change username flow, including showing the valid characters.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Don't log apikey in logs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Updated the donate link to point to a wiki explaining the donation options and that Kavita+ is the only way to remove the donate button.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Fixed&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bug where user reviews wouldn't be rendered on the UI if they didn't have a tagline, even though it's optional.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Ensure my own review orders in front of other local user reviews&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: When a user resets the API key, tell connected clients to refresh their account details&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Moved bulk operations bar back to the top of the page where it belongs on series detail&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: When using back on side nav after having a filter applied, clear the filter.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Cleaned up the error handling around Kavita+ registering of a license. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fix the issue of an extra space appearing after the end of the series detail page. (Thanks @charles7668 )&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bug with email link generation when using a base url, where too many characters could be trimmed  (Thanks @charles7668 )&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Change username wouldn't update the correct field which was used in login flow &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bug where when filtering was disabled (reading list page), the jumpbar also got disabled.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bug where library watching was trying to be turned on before we had saved the new value from server settings.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bug where the check email button success message was missing a space before the version number.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a delay in the UI after a bookmark is created/deleted (Thanks @charles7668 )&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed webtoon mode not allowing bookmarking (Thanks @charles7668 )&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a config issue where not all of Weblate's language codes would show up&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Removed&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Removed: (Kavita+) Removed the ability to scrobble reviews as the conditions are strict and doesn't make much sense to do it from Kavita.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/Kareadita/Kavita/releases/tag/v0.7.12" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/Kareadita/Kavita/releases/tag/v0.7.13</id>
    <title>New release for Kavita: v0.7.13 - Downloading Improvments</title>
    <updated>2024-01-18T18:08:32-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Kareadita/Kavita</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;A quick and small update for you all with a focus on Kavita+ and a regression that appeared from NetVips, which is responsible for generating cover images, causing black and white covers. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A word to all Kavita+ users, many of you have user's with AniList tokens that have expired. Your users need to go to &lt;code&gt;User settings &amp;gt; Account&lt;/code&gt; and generate a new one to continue scrobbling. Also don't forget to register your discord user id and gain access to the exclusive channels. We have been sharing some of the progress on the big items and I would love more feedback. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have over 10K active installs on old versions. If you're running Kavita, please update! You're missing out on the good stuff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Make sure you know that the docker repo has CHANGED.&lt;/strong&gt;
New repo here: https://hub.docker.com/r/jvmilazz0/kavita - You just need to switch your image to jvmilazz0/kavita:latest&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are on 0.7.6+ you can update directly to 0.7.13 otherwise you need to update incrementally to prevent data loss (v0.5.6 &amp;gt; v0.7.1.4 &amp;gt; v0.7.3.1 &amp;gt; v0.7.6 &amp;gt; v0.7.13)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Added&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: Added the ability to delete a library from side nav menu&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: (Kavita+) Kavita now alerts the user on visiting their homepage that their AniList token needs rotating to continue scrobbling&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Changed&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: (Kavita+) Kavita will now clear out existing, non-processed scrobbling events when a Series is put on hold.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Lots of dependency updates&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Downloading a Volume (consisting of multiple chapter archives) or a Full Series will not auto extract and re-zip for you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Enhanced the messaging around events widget for downloading/preparing a download.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Min length for a user review is now only 5 characters&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Downloads will download as cbz&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Under User settings &amp;gt; Account tab, Email and AniList token will now inform user if the email is not validated or if AniList token needs to be regenerated (as they expire every few months)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: (Kavita+) Kavita will quit faster during scrobbling events whenever rate limit is hit or token is expired.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: (Kavita+) Switched Kavita to use a new dedicated API to allow data to load on the screen faster and all at once leading to less page shift.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: (Kavita+) If a license is still on disk, but the subscription is not active, Kavita will not schedule Kavita+ tasks at all.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Streamlined some code around downloading for upcoming enhancements&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Updated dependencies, including NetVips for some regressions around cover generation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Major improvement to messaging when a series collides with another series in a parallel folder to library root. Explicitly give more information.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Localization files now have cache busting to help on new releases not reflecting all keys&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Removed XFrameOptions and replaced with AllowIFraming as true/false. This will control multiple headers for Organizer &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Shortened the time in which Kavita will check for an update an inform user. Originally 5-6 hours, now 1-2. We have over 10k users on old installs that haven't updated.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Fixed&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: On non-authenticated flows, the nav bar will no longer flash on refresh.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed inablity to right click highlighted text in the book reader&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed reading activity graphic not taking the full width like it should&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed some spacing on the Continue/Read button on reading list page&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed an issue where download indicators on cards would should on different series &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Don't have validations on the login screen&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed More in Genre not using a localized string for title&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: When a series updates to completed and there was a next estimated chapter card, make sure it gets cleared.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed bookmarks having + in the filename when not needed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed bookmarks not showing the download indicator&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed bookmarks not showing page count in card&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bad localization string for chapter actions from within the card detail drawer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Restore PDF layout menu (Thanks @tjarls)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed an issue where tab could flash on user preferences due to some delay waiting for a license check.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Ensure only admins can see files when searching &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bug where Edit Series Modal made it look like the language tag was set, but it wasn't &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/Kareadita/Kavita/releases/tag/v0.7.13" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/Kareadita/Kavita/releases/tag/v0.7.14</id>
    <title>New release for Kavita: v0.7.14 - iOS Webtoon Fixes, Built-in Email, and a new Wiki!</title>
    <updated>2024-02-08T08:52:31-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Kareadita/Kavita</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;A small on the surface, large under the hood release for everyone. This release first off fixes the webtoon reader for our iOS users. Many have validated and want to thank the community for helping me test and @thundernerd for doing some basic POC to help me drive it home. In addition to this, Want to Read had a critical bug in the architecture (that somehow slipped noticed for over a year now) where if one user adds a series to want to read, then another does, it will override the other. And lastly, for Kavita+ users, this is foundational release for the upcoming Basic Metadata feature. All data, like reviews, recommendations, and ratings are now stored in your DB. This leads to very quick response times and sets up the system for future data synchronization. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another big feature in this release is KavitaEmail is no longer required for those that want to use email (and me hosting an email service for everyone is no more). All email settings are built into the application and this has allowed me to streamline how Kavita works around email. Before, it was a mess of having to call an external system, check if the system was accessible externally, etc. Now, you MUST setup a host name (reverse proxy domain) and the email settings to use any email functionality. Due to this, all the flows got polished and should be much more consistent for users. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lastly, while it looks so small, it was over 3K lines of code, but volume numbers are now float-based, meaning if a volume is &amp;lt; 1, it will now properly show on book library series detail page. In addition to this, Omnibus (Volume 1-2) is now much better supported and Kavita+ will get Volume 2 when you read an Omnibus vs Volume 1 previously.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That wraps the v0.7.x series of releases. Next release series (v0.8.x) will be focusing mainly on the new Magazine library type, PDF parsing enhancements, and likely the new comic library.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;New Wiki&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lastly I want to call out a massive thanks to @DieselTech who has been leading a redesign of our wiki. Safe to say, at least 100 hours have been poured into re-organizing and updating a ton of the content from our old wiki into a brand new system. It looks slick and should be much easier to understand and search against. While we aren't yet ready to roll out, be on the look out next release for the full release. For those that want a sneak peak, you can check it out &lt;a href="https://wiki2.kavitareader.com"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Old Email Service&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As mentioned, this release contains built-in email functionality. The old emailer will remain on for 1 week after this release to give time for people to update. If you are stuck on an old version, please reach out so we can help understand why and get you updated. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Kavita+&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kavita+ is designed to work with the latest - 2 releases. If you are further than that out of date, it may no longer work appropriately. It is important to stay up to date.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Added&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: Added limited parsing support for c01-c04. Normally, c01-04 is used. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: Admins can now write custom cron notation for Scans, Backup, and Cleanup tasks. Cleanup cannot be disabled as it is required for Kavita to function smoothly. Ideal to always leave at midnight.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: (Kavita+) New filter for Average Rating. This will allow you to filter on series that have an external average rating. Note: This only applies to series that have metadata pulled down from Kavita+.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: (Kavita+) Kavita will now store Kavita+ external ratings, reviews, and recommendations in your Database. This will increase performance and lays the foundation for the upcoming basic metadata from Kavita+. Data is refreshed ad-hoc after 2 weeks and cached in memory for 48 hours. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: (Kavita+) New button in Edit Series modal that allows the series to be invalidated (or removed from blocklist) and force refresh from Kavita+ on next series detail page view.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: (Kavita+) User's can now see error messages and a different icon on Scrobbling History when a series fails to scrobble.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: (Kavita+) Sort by Average Rating&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: Added a new role that makes a user account read only. This means they cannot change anything themselves (Age Restriction, Email, Password, Forgot Password, API Key). This is not intended for users to use, but for the demo instance.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: Added a popup that will tell users that are over 3 releases behind to update. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: New setting in Email settings to let you use Customized Template files. If this is true, Kavita will pick templates from config/templates rather than internal storage. Fallback is available. You then own the onset to stay up to date with email template changes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: Added back the ability to delete your own review&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: Added the ability to delete collection tags via actionables on collection detail page. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: Added buttons that allows users to quickly autofill gmail/outlook email settings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: Added the changelog to the Admin System tab (in case users don't see it in the announcements page).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Changed&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: (Kavita+) Changed how Series Detail api works to drastically reduce memory needs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: (Kavita+) Removed Bust Kavita+ cache button from Admin -&amp;gt; Tasks screen as it's no longer needed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: (Kavita+) Series that don't match against Kavita+ will now be stored in a table and not be retried again.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: (Kavita+) When scrobbling, check if a series is blacklisted or not before trying. When an unknown series comes back, add it to the blacklist (so we don't waste time trying when it will never match)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Updated system tab with a link to localization and new feature request site&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Massive refactor to change how Volume numbers are represented within Kavita to support volumes that are &amp;lt; 1 on the UI. This means 0.5 books will now work going forward.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Lots of autocomplete hints added to help password managers and browsers autofill login/registration/passwords.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Adjusted OPDS-PS lastReadDate to adhere to ISO 8061 as per the spec and what Panels expects for proper sync.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Supressed image requests on the logs as they are quite noisy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Hostname setting is in general admin settings as well as email, as it's not 100% tied to email functionality&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Kavita will now confirm before you delete a device&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Email is now baked into Kavita. If email is not setup then all flows will now just work. The extra security measures will only work with email being setup (and HostName set). Kavita will no longer try to identify if the server is accessible externally. You will have to set HostName and setup the emailer going forward.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Series detail title (series title) now shows a loading indicator showcasing all the important apis that are loading&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: If Kavita+ license check throws an exception, just assume license is invalid and let the scheduled task check again (or the user manually)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Changelog now shows if you're on a nightly and which stable it's based off.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Split the main email template into base.html and fixed some bad closing tags. This should make customizing email templates easier.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Removed the up/down arrow keys on webtoon reader moving full pages. Use up/down for scroll and space for a bit at a time. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Updated the Kavita templates to be more modern (in terms of the code) and easier to customize.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Fixed&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed UI not being able to render search for non-admin users &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Remove from On Deck wasn't refreshing the dashboard&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed up the display and logic around when there is a series collision, to help the user understand more&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bug where the UI filter could send out of date information to the backend which threw an error.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: (Kavita+) Fixed a bug where external reviews would show as local&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed webtoon reader being unusable on iOS (Thanks @thundernerd for the help)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Series detail page was making a ton of api calls that weren't needed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bug where scrobbling tab could duplicate&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bunch of warnings about ordering and take with search queries&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Want to Read had a critical issue where a user could undo your want to read.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed bulk select of chapters leaving the last one off.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: On non-authenticated flows, the nav bar will no longer flash on refresh.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed inability to right click highlighted text in the book reader &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed reading activity graphic not taking the full width like it should&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed some spacing on the Continue/Read button on reading list page&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed an issue where download indicators on cards would should on different series &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Don't have validations on the login screen&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Support for the 'pageNumber' parameter in OPDS API smart-filter/{Id}.  (Thanks @charles7668 )&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed and polished a lot of the email flows.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bug where send to device didn't properly send the correct end event&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: LSIO dockers weren't properly recognized as Docker, Kavita now checks for LSIO_FIRST_PARTY environment variable &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed an issue with // being generated for some invite links (&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed an issue where a new library could render as blank in the UI &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed an issue when creating a new library, that new library wouldn't be included in folder watching&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bad encoding of dates for lastReadDate on OPDS-PS streams. Panels has already updated implemenation to help progress sync work more smoothly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bug where non Kavita+ users wouldn't see reviews.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Handled a rare case where a cover image wouldn't exist when creating a merged image for a reading list/collection.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bad comparison on code that pushes update notification users to admins. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed an issue where continue point for a totally unread series would start on the special and not chapter 1.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed an issue in webtoon reader where it would load the next chapter and be all black.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;API&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Volume Number field is deprecated in favor of MinNumber and MaxNumber (if the volume is a range). You can switch to MinNumber and ignore MaxNumber. (Volume Number will not be removed for at least 6 months to give time for apps to update)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/Kareadita/Kavita/releases/tag/v0.7.14" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
