<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://selfh.st/apps</id>
  <title>Kavita Releases</title>
  <updated>2024-11-12T22:30:34.477322-05:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>selfh.st</name>
    <email>contact@selfh.st</email>
  </author>
  <link href="https://selfh.st/apps" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>Self-hosted software releases generated by selfh.st</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/Kareadita/Kavita/releases/tag/v0.8.0</id>
    <title>New release for Kavita: v0.8.0 - Comic &amp; Collection Overhaul and PDF Settings Finally!</title>
    <updated>2024-04-12T18:26:31-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Kareadita/Kavita</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;Have you ever thought to yourself that you'd like to switch the foundation of your house from slab to pier and beam? Well, that's essentially what I've done with this release, and not only that, I had to do it without a single picture falling off the walls. This release comprises a whopping 48K lines of code added and 5.5K removed throughout 400 files.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order for me to achieve my vision of Kavita being the best software out there for reading, sometimes sacrifices have to be made. When I started building Kavita, I had never thought of what it would be today nor the part it would take in my life. It was simply a tool for me to consume and collect Manga since Ubooquity didn't have support for rich metadata. As users came along, so did the scope. Some features were added with limited knowledge, like comics, and that lack of knowledge in the beginning became a problem for heavy comic collectors. In order to build towards my vision of being the best, I had to rewrite large portions of how Kavita functions, work closely with the community, and deliver the best product I could. I want to first and foremost thank @DieselTech, who has been a key component in this. He has been pushing me relentlessly over the past year and has had a major hand in shaping the features, working with hardcore collectors from other servers (Mylar, Komga, and the CBL initiative).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, let's get into the meat and potatoes. What is new in this release?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Comic Overhaul&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to support these hardcore users, Kavita needs to align with the tools already in the space, primarily Mylar and CBL. Mylar serves as the collection tool, aligning with Comic Vine for standards of naming and tagging, while CBL provides a rich repository of reading lists to make navigating comics easier. One of the most important differences between the old 'Comic' library and the new 'Comic Vine' library is that the Volume number is always the year and is used in the generation of the Series title. The new library type is strictly for those who abide by the rules laid out by Comic Vine and CBL. CBL works around these assumptions for linking up issues from many series into one reading list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But that's not all. Comics are unique; they can have Issue Ω, which should be between Issues 8 and 9, or how about issue 18.HU? These are unique situations that didn't particularly go well with Kavita's number-based system. Through a feat of engineering, Kavita can now support these situations and, not only that, will soon allow the admins to actually change the sort order, a feature which, to my knowledge, no other software supports. This also means that Issue 0 (which can happen in Manga too) is now supported.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From the massive amount of testing, users have reported that this new library meets their needs perfectly. There are other small things, like Annual Series relationships, updates to CBL Import flows, etc., but the major points are above. This feature took 30K lines of code and 3 weeks of development for me to deliver to the testers (plus 2 weeks more of testing).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Collection Overhaul&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While we are on the topic of reworking major code, let's talk about collections. When I first coded these, I made a really bad call and tied them with Series (so a series belongs to a collection), but as I started working on new collection-related features, I realized how bad of a call this was. I needed collections to be user-based, like want-to-read or reading lists. While this isn't really needed now, it will be with a future update.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, yet again, I had to plan on how to migrate user data to the new collections without data loss and rework a ton of code. These new collections are user-based, and through a new Role, non-admins can even promote their own collections and share them with the server. While I was in there, I also made bulk promote/demote easier. Another easy 5K lines of code added and just over 1K removed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Misc&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, the large, foundational features are over, and we can talk about some of the smaller things, like finally adding PDF settings a year after adding a PDF reader. Yikes. That's right, I finally got around to it and added PDF settings, along with also adding tap-to-paginate to the PDF reader.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another area that has been receiving attention is Themes. Kavita saw an influx of new themes recently (and a few bug fixes too). Quite a few users are using these themes, and they look pretty good. Check them out on our Theme Repo. It's really easy to build your own, so if you have an interest, I highly encourage you to give it a go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another thing you might have noticed is Kavita+ enhancements. Quite a few small things were updated, but the most important is that Kavita+ will now auto-fetch data when you add new series and slowly work in the background to fetch external metadata. I have more planned around reporting on the data and managing bad matches against Kavita+, especially as I am still planning on basic metadata fetching, but I have found that this drastically improves load times on new series and makes the experience much better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lastly, I mentioned this last release, but Diesel has been hard at work on a complete revamp of the wiki. As of v0.8, we have moved over to the new wiki. Older installs wiki links will no longer work. Thanks again to @DieselTech for yet another monumental add to Kavita. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Important&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Important!&lt;/strong&gt; Once you update to this release there are manually steps needed! You MUST perform a forced library scan on all libraries to migrate properly to the new foundation. Failure to do so may result in data loss. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a massive update, all progress data will be exported on the first run to config/progress_export.csv. The migrations may take up to 10 minutes to migrate. Do not stop midway, you will break your db and need to restore from a backup. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kavita+ users: As mentioned last release, you are expected to stay up to date - 2 releases. Old Kavita+ APIs will be shutdown shortly after v0.8. You can update to v0.7.14 as the minimum.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The default emailer was supposed to be turned off last release. I held it longer to give time. The emailer will be turned off after the v0.8 release.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a MASSIVE update, some data loss can be expected. I spent weeks trying to minimize any data loss and have provided an export. I apologize ahead of time if any occurs. If you are running into issues, do not hesitate to reach out to support on discord. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Added&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: Added a new library type aimed at Light Novels. This will use card list layout by default (overriding user preferences) and is eligible for Kavita+ metadata/scrobbling. The regular book library no longer is Kavita+ eligible.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: Added a label on Library settings modal to help admins know which libraries are eligible for Kavita+ scrobbling/metadata pull.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: (Kavita+) Implemented a background prefetch task that will slowly refresh series from Kavita+ (reviews, recs, ratings).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: (Kavita+) Kavita will now prefetch data from Kavita+ on new series. This and the prefetch background task is limited to 50 series per 12 hours. Loading on-demand will still work as normal and is not restricted.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: Chapters now sort by SortOrder. SortOrder is generated from chapter number, but can be overridden (in a future update). This allows for custom sorting for issues that aren't purely numerical. SortOrder will handle cases like 19, 19.HU, 19.BD, 20 without any user intervention.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: You can now have Chapter 0, -1, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: This fully supports chapters with non-numeric issue numbers, like Alpha, 19.HU, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: Added a new library type: Comic Vine which is aimed at users of Mylar or have well tagged libraries following Comic Vine. This library works different and can support multiple folders with the same series parallel to library root.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: New Series Relationship of Annual.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: Imprints are now read from ComicInfo, will display on the UI and can be filtered.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: (Scanner) Added a new LowestFolderPath. This is the lowest path that contains all the series files and is used by ScanFolder/Series to avoid extra work.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: Added support for Locations and Teams, including the filtering for them&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: There is a one-time progress export to config/progress_export.csv in case of data loss.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: Added Sort order to be visible on chapter detail drawer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: (Kavita+) Added Mal Username/ClientId integration into Kavita for upcoming Kavita+ integrations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: Added the ability to view (your) or all users (if admin) progress for that given chapter via the chapter detail drawer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: (Kavita+) Added a pie chart to Server Stats that shows how many eligible series have metadata fetched from Kavita+. This pairs well with the background job that fills out your server over time. (This will be expanded upon in a future update)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: (Parser) Added parser support for Thai language volume and chapters (Thanks @gozilla-paradise)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: Finally added PDF Reader Settings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: (PDF Reader) Added tap to paginate to the pdf reader.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: Collections can now be created by non-admins&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: Collections can now be promoted by non-admins (given they have the Promote role).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: Added bulk flows for Promotion and Deletion. If you select cards that are not owned by you, nothing will happen to those cards.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: OPDS feeds will now send description information when applicable for underlying volume/chapters.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Changed&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: (Kavita+) Removed Book library from Scrobbling/Metadata pull. Books being in Google Books was far and few in-between. This is a temporary solution until Hardcover support is implemented, which has good Book (and some Comic) support. If you have light novels, change to the LN library type. The scanner works the same.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Allow users to send files to their devices without having host name set for Email settings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: (Theme) side-nav-color is now side-nav-text-color&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: (Theme) Added carousel-btn-color (for carousel buttons) and badge-text-color (for badge text)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: When iOS users are trying to download files greater than 200MB, they will be given an additional warning that iOS may fail to download due to arbitrary limits each device has.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Specials will now order by SP marker numbers, else fallback to natural sort&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Loose Leaf volumes are now encoded with the number -100000 instead of 0. This now means users can have a Volume 0 without issue.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Search will now search against a chapter range and will also fallback if there is no title (comicinfo title) to the range.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Clean up a log message when no files found, to ensure the admin checks the Library settings as well.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Image Library is now more aligned to reported usage&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Changed chapter title format to Chapter {number} - {title} (assuming title exists), else Chapter {number}. For Books, nothing has changed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Series Detail metadata area will collapse automatically on desktop if there are too many tags.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Comic/Comic Vine libraries will never show Storyline or Volumes (unless there are no issues/specials or multiple volumes exist)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Minor changes to how PDFs parse to make them a tad more smart. Nothing major, will do the overhaul later.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Trim strings from ComicInfo more aggressively to prevent weird parsing for things like Number.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Optimized a lot of the scanner and cleaned up the code deeply.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: (Parser) Adjusted the special parsing for Annuals to account for 'Series Annual \d'&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Dependency and security updates&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Added a flag to the CBL import to use Comic Vine parsing for CBL Import (and set to true as all CBLs to my knowledge are using this new library).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Kavita now handles non-float numbers from CBL Imports (including special cases for comics)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: (Kavita+) During library setting modal, changing type will now automatically change the Allow Scrobbling control, if the underlying library type is not Kavita+ applicable.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Normalize all paths during the scanner to ensure everything is always the same.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Added the csv files to the backup as those are used in manual migrations and likely good to have.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: (Kavita+) When a rate limit error comes in after the pre-check, retry after the wait window instead of waiting for the next scrobble window.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Some epubs have incorrect metadata where the series is parsing with a volume. To help users, Kavita will override this on Light Novel library type to merge into the correct series.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Added a bit of a loader when deleting a lot of series with bulk actions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Tweaked some wording about the changelog component to better indicate to nightly users that are not on the latest stable-based nightlies.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: When using Force Scan on library settings, automatically close the modal.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: (Scanner) Change pdf parser so if it's a library type book, we override chapters as chapter number is RARELY used and mainly results in false positives.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: (Scanner) Fixed up the parsing so that book parser will coerced when the series in the metadata is wrong but there is a volume tag in said series, it will override.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Added a fallback to the series detail page to handle bad pdf parses (until the upcoming pdf parser rewrite comes) to avoid no cards showing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Turned down the amount of debug logging from the library watcher and moved them to trace.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Added some code so that while the device is offline, the UI wont try to refresh JWT and likewise, when turned back online, a JWT Refresh will be called to hopefully extend the session. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Collections will show who created them under the card. For the time being, actionables (...) will show for all cards. This system will be getting an overhaul in the future. You still wont be able to interact with another user's collections.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Changed some of the format icons to some better looking icons&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Added a filter in Edit Collections &amp;gt; Series tab to quickly find series to remove in large collections&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Updated all email templates to have rel noopener noreferrer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: When checking Kavita+ license, show a loading spinner first.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Reduced amount of Kavita+ license checks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Send to Device now works without Hostname set.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Switched all links over to the new wiki&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Fixed&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a security bug from .NET (CVE-2024-21409)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed an issue around being able to delete series with external recommendations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed up the delete series flow so that the boolean returned is used in the UI to pop the correct toaster.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed an oversight where emailers without authentication wouldn't work&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bug with looping around to volume 1 at the end of a reading session when it shouldn't &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a case where an exception was thrown, scanner wasn't existing and instead invoked metadata service with bad entities&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed some bad styling on Chapter metadata (drawer)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bad localization on edit reading list modal.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed another check around rescheduling Kavita+ tasks once a valid check came through. There was a lack of a checking mechanism and Kavita was doing more than needed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: I believe the Foreign Key constraint issue is solved once and for all &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a rendering bug on CBL validation where the UI reports success but also a warning message appears&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bug where Translators couldn't be updated in Edit Series Modal.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a manual migration that had to run before the db was migrated and it didn't check if the db even existed yet.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Scanner was clearing temp directory when it shouldn't have been, which could replace db migration backup.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Added an argument exception when reording a list has a number that's less than 0, throw. This usually happens with bad metadata in ComicInfo's. Perhaps when there is a -1 chapter, it's using number instead of order.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Stats and Tasks were missing localization &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed an issue where the new downloading code would unzip epubs on volume/series download &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bug where opening library settings from ... on library detail page wouldn't have library type. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bug where the UI wasn't properly sending the custom cron data to the backend. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bug where weblink's in a card detail drawer wasn't rendering the favicon&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed an issue where progress bar css variable was being overridden by bootstrap&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bug where selecting bulk mode on in customize side nav wouldn't allow you to ever enable order numbers again.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: (Parser) Fixed a parsing case for 'Cynthia The Mission - c000 - c006 (v06)'&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed an issue where uploading a custom cover wasn't respecting Cover Size setting (Thanks Elry)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bug where an epub with an empty link element could break Kavita's epub reader (Thanks @YodaDaCoda)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: (Kavita+) Fixed External reviews not showing the Go to Review due to an API change.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed an issue where applying a custom theme was not working immediately or consistently&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed bad messaging around test email failing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed an issue when changing email address, after validating, it wouldn't mark as confirmed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Panels wasn't properly showing images on Series due to a bug on their app (Thanks Dani)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Panels wasn't properly syncing read status with Kavita (Thanks Dani)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Avoid possible username enumeration in login or reset-password endpoints due to message translations (Thanks @YodaDaCoda)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Ensure we cannot create multiple collections in bulk flow if we use ENTER Key &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: When clicking Gmail/Outlook buttons on email form, the form wasn't allowing saving even though fields changed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: (Panels) Panels has fixed a few bugs with Kavita. v3.4.1 (beta) and above should be used&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Removed&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Removed: Removed .kavitaignore file support as Library Exclude patterns are much easier to use and flexible enough.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;API&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NOTE&lt;/strong&gt; CDisplayEx, Panels, Tachiyomi, and Komf have all been tested with v0.8. Aidoku and Kavya (Paperback) are in progress. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;VolumeDto reverted the float on Number field back to int&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ChapterDto Range will be the chapter number. If a special, will be the special name. MinNumber can always be checked for the special encoding&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Encoding: Special (100000), Loose Leaf Volume (-100000).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;stats/user/reading-history has a dto change, making ChapterNumber a float instead of a string.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tachiyomi routes now use their own Dto to avoid having to break apis there.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added SortOrder on the ChapterDto. This is a float that can be used to order the chapters within the Volume. By default, all APIs will already order by this.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SeriesMetadataDto (for updating series metadata) now has Teams, Locations, Imprints and their lock fields: teamLocked, locationLocked, imprintLocked.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed library/ -&amp;gt; library/libraries for getting all libraries&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All Collection apis were updated, however most of the underlying DTO is the same.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SeriesMetadata DTO no longer has Collections or needs them for the POST (as they are no longer tied with this entity)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;series/ (deprecated) no longer handles filtering for collections. Use v2 api.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/Kareadita/Kavita/releases/tag/v0.8.0" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/Kareadita/Kavita/releases/tag/v0.8.1</id>
    <title>New release for Kavita: v0.8.1 - A bit more than a Hotfix</title>
    <updated>2024-04-22T16:20:48-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Kareadita/Kavita</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;This is just a bit more than a hotfix, but mainly focused on some polish after more users got their hands on the v0.8 along with the updated Image library. From the community support, v0.8 looks to have gone off really well with only a few users reporting minor data loss. Thanks to everyone joining support and bringing up edge cases that were missed. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would also like to remind users that you can upvote and comment (or create your own) feature requests on out &lt;a href="https://github.com/Kareadita/Kavita/discussions"&gt;Github Discussions&lt;/a&gt; page. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Added&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: Added SortOrderLocked field for upcoming ability to set it in the UI, allowing customization of sort order on Series Detail page. (This is not yet in the UI, just in the DB and code)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Changed&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Changed how often the 1 version out of date check occurs to be every 4-6 hours instead of 1-2 hours.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Allow jumpbar to function on pages as long as there is no custom sort &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: When refusing OPDS download due to lack of role, use 403 Forbid.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Don't show any of the internal information on publication status tooltip when the total items is set to 0 (or unset)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Updated Comic Vine library when falling back to taking Series name from directory because no Volume tag exists, don't clean specials from the directory name.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Fixed&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bug where some series detail pages have a ton of extra space&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bug where series folders with nested specials would get a bad LowestSeriesFolder meaning series scans wouldn't do anything important.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bug with default ordering failing when a series has a special&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bug where the very out of date modal wouldn't have the correct number of version out of date.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bug where stacked image chapters wouldn't move all the files over to cache&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed an oversight where brightness control in manga reader wasn't applying to webtoon reader&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Drastically sped up switching between card/list mode on series detail for large series&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed Continue -100000 when a series is read on series detail page&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: When parsing from fallback libraries, use comic parsing only for Comic/Comic Vine library types.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bug where weblinks remove would not work well. Now it works more like you would assume.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bug where active tab wouldn't default to volumes on comic libraries when there were no issues or specials.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bug where progress bar on kavita+ metadata progress wasn't showing red.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bug where on Chrome bootstrap sliders were blue and not the primary color.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bug where chapters could duplicate due to some regions using ',' as a decimal separator. Now in Kavita, whenever we stringify any numbers, it will always choose English's way as that is how it was designed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a case where non-English locales wouldn't parse floats correctly for x.x chapters.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed an exception being thrown on startup for fresh users&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;API&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deprecated series/chapter-metadata API in favor of just including the metadata with all chapter entities.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/Kareadita/Kavita/releases/tag/v0.8.1" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/Kareadita/Kavita/releases/tag/v0.8.2</id>
    <title>New release for Kavita: v0.8.2 - Theme Overhaul, Smart Collections, &amp; a lot of Scanner work</title>
    <updated>2024-07-07T08:38:32-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Kareadita/Kavita</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;A new stable release is here and it is yet again another big one. Initially I set out to focus on 3 items: Scanner, Smart Collections, and CBL v2 (new schema), but here I am delivering 3 massive improvements and a ton of smaller changes. This release includes a bit of everything spread about. Let's get into it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Built-in Theme Explorer&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing I wanted since day one of adding theme support into Kavita was the ability for users you just browse a list of themes and download what they want to use. It's not easy when the admin has to add the theme for you and hit scan, dealing with the underlying filesystem. I finally got around to setting up the initial version of this (open to feedback to expand on this system) with v0.8.2. All users will have the ability to browse themes uploaded to the theme repo, preview the images and description, and download and apply theme. This currently does not have any role permission and I didn't hear much from nightly users thinking it's needed. If you feel otherwise, raise a discussion. If you don't want to use a theme on the repo, you can upload your own file via the interface. Existing theme users should delete their themes and re-acquire them. This will allow them to be updated for you automatically (assuming the supported version matches yours). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="https://github.com/Kareadita/Kavita/assets/735851/b40e1284-8c30-4f3b-968c-73227abb65f3" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Smart Collections for Kavita+&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is another one I've wanted for a while and is part of the theme of introducing more synchronization systems into Kavita. Smart Collections allow for you to import any Interest Stacks/Restacks from your MAL account into Kavita. Every 2 days, Kavita will resync with upstream and add any Series that you own to the collection. The collection is otherwise read-only and promotable, so if you want to setup a few best of X and promote them for your server, you can. These features are also not admin-specific. Any user can import their interest stacks into the server (and if they have the promotion role, can promote them). I hope you all enjoy this feature as much as I am. Another level of bringing a top notch experience for my users. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Scanner Changes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've been working a lot with our users that have larger libraries, ranging from 100k files to 10k series. One of the major problems is that when you have a library of 10k, it's going to take a long time as expected. These users are mainly new users coming from the comic rework and have folder structures Kavita wasn't originally built around. I spent a good chunk of time building optimizations to reduce the amount of processing work Kavita does for these folder layouts (not restrictive to comic libraries) and fixing some bugs around parsing and whatnot that surfaced thanks to the numerous bug reports. If you aren't finding good results after this update, please do reach out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Misc Changes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few other big changes come with this release. The first is WAL is now on by default. You can always turn this off manually in the DB, but fresh installs (and existing) will turn WAL on. WAL fixes the common &lt;code&gt;database is locked&lt;/code&gt; issue due to Kavita writing too much data too fast. Another big one is double scrollbar on mobile. This was an annoying bug on some mobile browsers on some pages. Robbie took this up and fixed it everywhere to my knowledge. A great QoL enhancement. OPDS has gotten a lot of love in this release thanks to some great reports by @MnsieurJF around reading lists and missing metadata in the feeds. Lastly, the Manga Reader has had some tweaking to how fit to height/width works. It's not easy to put into words, but I find the fitting to be MUCH better. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have loose plans for what the next release is going to be. The PDF rework will need to come after v0.8.3 to allow people who upgrade into the v0.8.x series not to loose data from the massive changes. I have a lot of holiday coming up as well, so the release may be longer or shorter depending. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lastly, I want to mention (as I keep forgetting) that @DieselTech has joined the Kavita team a few months ago. His name should be well known as he's very active in most of the reading and comic discords as well as being a core member in the CBL Reading Order group. He's already driven a lot of great changes in Kavita for hardcore comic users and I have no doubt he will continue to be a great resource for me to rely on in the future. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Added&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: Kavita+ users can now import their MAL interest stacks/restacks into Kavita as Smart Collections. These collections will synchronize back with MAL to update with new series and summary information every 2 days. Smart Collections work just as normal collections except are non-editable as the MAL stack controls the data. They can be promoted given the user has promotion role. They are not admin-specific. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: Added the ability for any user to download themes from the Theme Repo directly via Kavita. Kavita will keep these themes up to data automatically (unless the reported version from the Repo is greater than the server version).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: Book series can now have specials. In order to be classified as a Special, the SP marker must be in the filename, the calibre:series must be set to the Series name and &lt;code&gt;calibre:series_index&lt;/code&gt; must be 0. (Feature Request: 3 upvotes)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: OPDS-PS on PDF files is now possible. Kavita will convert to images.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: Added a create link to create a new smart filter in case it's not clear for first time users exploring the software.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: Added first install version and date to the DB so admin's can look back at it. This data is available in System tab.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: Added new Random sort option to allow a stream like 'Top Unread in X' (Thanks @Fesaa)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: Added the following css variables --event-widget-activity-bg-color, --event-widget-update-bg-color, --event-widget-error-bg-color&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: Implemented the ability to click download on any file extension from stats page (formats table) and download a report of all files that are of that extension.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: Added the ability to manually override the width in the manga/webtoon reader when using Width scaling (Thanks @Marsimplodation) (Feature Request: 19 upvotes)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: Added bulk promote/demote/delete for reading lists to align with collections.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Changed&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: On forgot password, even if email isn't setup or user doesn't have email setup, still allow the reset link to log. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Reduced memory for adding a set of series to a collection.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Scan button no longer exists on themes tab. Now, admin's can upload their custom css files via the UI.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Admin's can no longer delete themes and force users with that theme active off.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Changed how scaling works in the manga reader to be more inline with the expected behavior. Height will scale to viewport height even if it is beyond the image's original dimensions. Width will scale to viewport width even if it is beyond the image's original dimensions. Original will show the image at its intrinsic dimensions, no scaling is applied (Thanks @therobbiedavis)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Enable WAL journal mode by default in all Kavita installs. Users can turn it off after the first run if needed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Show a warning on dirty email setting form to inform the user they need to save before testing settings.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Ensure users know that Scrobbling providers will always keep the highest number from kavita.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: On &amp;lt; tablet viewports, reading list page should use order numbers rather than drag and drop, as there isn't enough real estate.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Series Detail page will now show people/genre/tags as collapsed even on desktop, but summary will have same code to be expanded up to 1000 characters on desktop.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: (Scanner) Refactored Scan Loop to avoid doing extra work on lower folders in a folder map path, so that users that group by publisher or another arbitrary folder, can avoid a lot of scanning on lower level folders just because the highest level changed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: (Performance) Applied some performance optimizations on Series OPDS route which should help speed up heavier Series.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: (Performance) Small optimization to image reader to make finding the next/prev page faster.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Search will no longer search against Chapter titles and Files by default. Instead, there is a new link in the search window to perform with those included. This should help users with larger libraries find their files faster.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: (Kavita+) Kavita+ scrobbling will now take AniList/Mal ids from External metadata (which is prefetched from Kavita+ for the external metadata) whenever possible. This can help with matching when there are no weblinks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Updates dependencies which includes a fix for nav items in epub toc that are more loose. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Added a few full-wdith characters for normalization: ＊！＋&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: All smart filters page now uses the same design as the flow from Customize modal.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Disable the first remove button for weblinks/exclude pattern component as it isn't removable&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Updated ScanFolder to be more aggressive in finding the underlying series by also checking against a partial match on lowest folder path to find a series. This should result in less work for well structured libraries.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: (Performance) Cleaned up some extra db calls that aren't needed in the OPDS apis.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Reading Lists in both OPDS/UI now have the underlying issue's summary.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Smart Filter OPDS feeds are now smart-filters/{id} instead of smart-filter/{id}&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Updated the cover generation logic to handle webtoons better. The new code will now check if the image scales well or not and if not, use a more attention focused scaling/cropping method. (Thanks @arition for the &lt;a href="https://github.com/Kareadita/Kavita/pull/2612"&gt;initial PR&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: For OPDS Reading Lists, when there is only one underlying file (common), send an acquisition link rather than a subsection. This allows the removal of one of the clicks for nearly all users. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: When a scan is enqueued or in progress, have the scanner aware and reschedule tasks mins into the future (except scan series which is 1 min)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Added more logging into scanner service and ensure folder watching isn't over triggering the scan loop.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Redesigned the loading indicators on the events widget to be cleaner and more expressive. Added the online user count to the nav bar like Plex has. Added an update icon like error/info to help users know when there are updates.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: (Performance) Converted series detail to control flow syntax to hopefully speed up change detection when there is a large amount of chapters.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: (Performance) Don't render all tabs by default on series detail. When switching tabs, it will destroy the DOM. This helps a lot with change detection on first load and later changes. First load on big series can take over 30 seconds to process. This means you will incur the long load when activating the tab with a lot of cards.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Tweaked how jobs are queued and what messages we send to the UI. First, Scan tasks invoked via the UI will now send reschedule alerts when a scan is in progress and another is about to be kicked off. Scan Series now will retry 200 times instead of 3 given new rescheduling code.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Fixed&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bug where Hangfire could be accessible when it wasn't supposed to. (Thanks @theGEBIRGE)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bug where Update Preferences API was taking SiteTheme instead of SiteThemeDto&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bug where multiple extractions of the same archive would start concurrently and create file system problems. This caused out of order reading in Mihon (Thanks @SamuelBMartins)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed an issue where one some screens images would stack instead of being side by side while using the double setting in the manga reader. (Thanks @therobbiedavis)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed an issue where the cover and last page would not be positioned correctly when using the double (Manga) setting in the manga reader. (Thanks @therobbiedavis)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed the issue with review cards provider and score extending outside it's card boundary. (Thanks @therobbiedavis)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed an issue with double scrollbar when viewing saved smart filters (Thanks @therobbiedavis)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed up the info icon cards on series detail to be better with responsiveness on some breakpoints.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed an issue where one-shot/specials in Scrobble History would show internal encoding&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bug with Image series where caching the images for reading could create a ton of folders with the same files inside. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Word count analysis will now handle missing manifest items gracefully and report media errors around said file.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed bcmap files not loading in the pdf reader &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bug when adding items to a reading list in bulk, sorting order of those chapters was not being respected.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bug when a file of Chapter 0.2 first scanned in, Kavita would render the card as 'Chapter 0.2 - .2' then on another scan, Kavita would correctly render out 'Chapter 0.2'.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Loading indicator wasn't properly wired up in the search component &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed an edge case bug when performing a series scan, it wouldn't respect the exclude patterns of the library.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a case where specials in the manga reader weren't giving the special name &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a case where there could be no storyline chapters but just normal chapters and OPDS feed wouldn't render correctly. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a case where content type could fail, for example with avif. Now a failsafe is in place.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed some OPDS feeds where author (writer) wasn't being sent. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a parser case where a file was marked as special but also had an issue number, the issue number would un-specialize it. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Added a migration to nullify LowestFolderPaths that did not start with a library root. This was caused by an old bug likely that has hence been fixed, yet old records break the new scan loop.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bug where LowestSeriesFolder was not a full rooted path on linux&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed an issue where metadata apis could return genres/tags/people coming from libraries a user doesn't have access to.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bug with publication status when there is a set number of volumes but that series also has a special in it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bug where OPDS urls could have api/opds//api/opds instead of just api/opds/&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed up the code in the system tab where users may be on a revision of 0 but the Github release doesn't have a revision, causing the page to always show as nightly, even though it's a stable. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixes the pdf search button not displaying (Thanks @Zackaree)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed double scrollbar &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bug where continue from title was not taking library type into consideration nor was localized&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Cleaned up the event widget showing nothing going on here when it shouldn't. Fixed a missing localization.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bug where some events weren't sending their name and event widget wasn't clearing them after opening their detail modal.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a case where when mass deleting series from library detail page, the page could refresh a lot more than needed. Now, each call is debounced by 100ms.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bug where on mobile devices the continuous scroller wouldn't trigger when scrolling on webtoon mode (Thanks @Zackareee)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed an annoying parse case for 'Giant Ojou-sama - Ch. 33.5 - Volume 04 Bonus Chapter' parsing as 'Giant Ojou-sama - Ch. 33.5' instead of 'Giant Ojou-sama'&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Updated some rendering of tags to not be people tags, like teams&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bug where series-level imprint tags weren't showing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/Kareadita/Kavita/releases/tag/v0.8.2" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/Kareadita/Kavita/releases/tag/v0.8.3</id>
    <title>New release for Kavita: v0.8.3 - The UX Refresh</title>
    <updated>2024-09-18T09:25:09-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Kareadita/Kavita</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;It's finally here, the UX Refresh. Robbie and I have been dreaming and planning this for over a year now and we've grinded for 2 months (with my trip to Norway/Finland between) to bring it to you. The feedback from the nightly testers has been fantastic! Everyone is in love. We have poured over the UX, both on mobile and on desktop, to bring what we think is a consistent and killer experience. We took a lot of inspiration from Plex and if anyone knows, I'm trying to make Kavita the Plex for reading. So let's get into the nitty gritty of what makes this release. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Colorscape&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I browse Plex, I'm always blown away by the accent colors on movie detail pages. Contrast that to Kavita, I felt it was sorely lacking. So I brought it to Kavita and let me tell you, it was no easy feat. Hours wasted on css gradients before realizing the complex system Plex has. Kavita now will show a nice gradient in the background of any page that has a cover (except reading lists and collections, these will likely follow in the future). What's even cooler is the system is able to be turned on/off with a custom theme or even customized by theme creators. This is the feature I'm most proud of with this release. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/25b81beb-1333-4e82-b22f-8f41e3c9c72d" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Individual Pages&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a big thing for Book and Comic users, the ability to view individual volume/chapter metadata. This not only brings dedicated pages (and the ability to update metadata for individual chapters/books), but also the ability to read a series/chapter/volume from any card. No longer do you need to open the series detail page. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/954050d9-184e-46b6-8cbf-1985844aef8d" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Settings Overhaul&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Again taking inspiration from Plex, we updated the settings pages to bring tooltip information front and center and make changes to any field instant (no more pressing save).  All settings, from admin to user preferences, are now on one screen. Some flows have been moved to dedicated pages, like CBL Import or MAL Interest Stack import. This should help with bringing visibility to some of the features Kavita has. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/aa330cb2-ae1b-442a-a109-3c568104e8e8" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Publisher Images&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lastly, we added a new system similar to favicons for publisher images. This new system allows for users to submit or edit publisher images on our &lt;a href="https://github.com/Kareadita/kareadita.github.io?tab=readme-ov-file#publishers"&gt;kavita repo&lt;/a&gt; and these images will be downloaded dynamically and displayed on the detail pages. Some images may not look good. I am counting on the community to add new or edit images to bring the best UX to all users. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/21791599-0956-49fb-b817-f3117e4defba" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All in all, I'm really proud of this release. Next up is an overhaul to the UX surrounding Kavita+ including reworking some of the systems and laying more foundation for future feature releases. I am also working on building out the test cases for the Scanner to allow me to continue working on the elusive Foreign Key constraint issue still plaguing us and working on bringing more optimizations into the Scan Loop to make Kavita faster. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lastly, I want to make a big thank you to those that contribute on Weblate. This release was massive and many localization strings were changed. The localizers were on top of it and as of this release, we are shipping Kavita in 10 languages with full support. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Refresh your browser after updating&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Added&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: Added ability to upload a volume cover for Komf users&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: Added a lot of ability to theme the login screen, including the background image.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: Added ColorScapes. ColorScapes is a new dynamic tinting system for Kavita. During cover generation, Kavita will pick primary colors from the image and apply them to the background on pages where the image is a primary element (series detail for now). These are configurable via the theming system. (Light themes do not look good with this system, it should be disabled)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: Added a new actionable for Library to generate colorscapes (which is a soft refresh covers)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: Library Settings and Edit Series Modal now has a tasks tab that shows appropriate tasks that can be done on the library/series along with information about what the task does.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: Added a Volume/Chapter detail page. From any card you can click and open the detail page.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: Added the ability to directly read a card/volume/series/readinglist from the card or open their details page.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: Added the ability to edit chapter metadata directly within Kavita, lock the fields, This includes Sort order which will allow comic users with unique issue numbers to be ordered on the series detail in any order and the readers will respect it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: Added a new API and UI to allow setting just a volume cover (and locking it). Komf has already updated with support. (Thanks @Snd-R)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: Added the ability to have publisher images (that are managed on Kavita's site, like favicons). There is no extra styling, this is pretty rough but I want to see from users if there is any interest.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: Added a new metadata filter called 'is empty'. This will check against fields like Writers, Tags, Genres, etc to explicitly see if there are no links. (Feature Request)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: .yacreaderlibrary directories will be ignored by the scanner&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: Made it so when a new version of Kavita is released, the UI will automatically refresh and bust locale cache since non-admins can't actually run the bust cache task.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: Admins can now trigger Sync Theme job from Tasks page&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: Added a link to the CBL Repo from CBL Import for those that are unaware of the project&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Changed&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Passwords can now be up to 256 characters long&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Changed some headers, spacing, and positioning to make things more uniform across the app.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Revamped how settings/preferences work in the app. Following Plex' style, they are all on one page (RBS applies) with a dedicated left nav menu that groups based on functionality. (Sorry localizers, lots of string updates)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: When navigating away from library/collection/bookmark/etc-detail, instead of just restoring position when interacting with a jumpkey, Kavita will now restore position down to the location of jump point in all cases.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Jump keys now show an animation instead of a tooltip to show number of series&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Filter icon now shows an animation when actively configuring it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Moved some screens around to dedicated sections and most of Kavita+ screens are now on a new Scrobbling page&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Moved the customize modal into a dedicated settings item to make discovery of the feature easier.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Lots of small consistency issues and QoL tweaks on different pages to bring a better UX and interaction. A lot of functionality has been moved to drive a consistent experience and discovery of features.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Cast and Reviews are in their own tab &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Tabs on Series Detail now report card count&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: All preferences (except those in account) now just save automatically after interaction&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Removed library setting 'Include in Recommendations' as Kavita no longer has those flows&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: On mobile view ports, remove the dropdown button and scroll to top. Dropdown button links are now visible in a modal to make clicking much easier.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Added a customize button on the Side nav when you move into 'More', so you know you can tweak it if you haven't visited settings yet.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Series cards will now show the localized name on hover if present&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Chapter cards will now show the title on hover if present.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Cover Artists is now Artists in the application.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: After selecting a tab, a refresh of the browser will resume you back on the same tab on series/volume/chapter detail pages.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Folder watching is now moved to a separate background thread so it doesn't block startup for users with massive libraries &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: After we update a metadata filter, rescroll to the top as results change&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Cleaned up some registration error output to look nicer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Reorganized edit user modal to better handle users with large amounts of libraries.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: When mass creating libraries, ensure we enqueue the scans. Also don't restart folder watching if folder watching isn't on.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Tweaked some backend code around when we restart library watching and make sure it's always done in a background thread.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Sync Themes job now runs daily instead of weekly&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Lots of small improvements to the UX of theme manager&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Actionable menu (...) on mobile will now load a modal, rather than the normal desktop view. From testing, the menu was easy to misclick on mobile.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Fixed&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed an issue where long passwords would truncate on autofill. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a side-nav css var that was inappropriately assigned. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bug in theme manager where the active pill wouldn't have the correct color for non-dark themes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bug where reading list cards wouldn't promote/unpromote from actionables&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bug where OPDS reading list feeds were missing pagination&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed an edge case where busting Kavita+ cache in edit series then hitting close wasn't refreshing screen.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: A ton of localization changes across the board (Thank you to the Translators for promptly updating language support to 100%)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed a bug where busting locale cache wouldn't refresh the new translations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed some logic around disabling scrobbling on the UI side for library type selections&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bug where pinned smart filters on the side nav would all show an active highlight (Thanks @Fesaa for the help fixing)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bug where there could be a duplicate key in OPDS for some unique configurations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Don't allow users to add series to smart collections &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed CBL Import flow and a bad localization string when the reading list already exists&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: (Kavita+) MAL Interest stacks didn't handle pagination correctly, but now it does. You can now import all your stacks. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed duplicate Dark theme issue&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bug with utc to local time not respecting null date&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bug where user was unable to save manga reader preferences due to a missing field&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Ensure that any smart filter bound to the dashboard load in the correct Context and respect libraries that have opted out of showing on the Dashboard. (FR #3149)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed duplicate Dark theme issue &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bug where user was unable to save manga reader preferences due to a missing field&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Ensure that any smart filter bound to the dashboard load in the correct Context and respect libraries that have opted out of showing on the Dashboard.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed an issue where user rating was using a float (0-1) but users were expecting to put in a percentage given that's always how the UI shows it. Now, Kavita will translate from percentage to float behind the scenes. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed CBL import breaking again due to swagger&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed an issue where a user with no reading progress would throw an exception on loading stats page&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed an issue where after downloading a theme, the theme would be unselected.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed some exceptions being thrown when downloading or fetching themes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed an error when trying to save settings from the manga reader&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bug where the manga reader could prefetch all files in the archive &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a weird state where a book series with a volume 0 and being marked as special would trick series detail into rendering 0 out on card title instead of title.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Theme&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tables are now themeable&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There were a ton of changes and new css variables. Wiki has been updated with extra documentation around colorscape system.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;API&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Updated how resetting cover image field works on the API. All update APIs now accept a LockCover field which will force the lock or not. Defaults to true. Can still reset the cover by passing an empty string and false. In addition, the code is more streamlined to ensure after a reset, a regeneration task is queued.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/Kareadita/Kavita/releases/tag/v0.8.3" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/Kareadita/Kavita/releases/tag/v0.8.3.2</id>
    <title>New release for Kavita: v0.8.3.2 - A Small Hotfix</title>
    <updated>2024-09-20T17:24:03-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Kareadita/Kavita</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;The UX refresh release has been great, a lot of great feedback has come in, along with a few bugs that got missed during testing. I knew there would be some, especially when the new UX was 50K lines of code difference. I picked up as many as I could that didn't require large periods of time for testing. Unless there is anything major that comes, this should be the last hotfix and I will start work on v0.8.4. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Changed&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Instead of showing 'Special' on chapter cards that aren't real, show a dash instead&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Changed how the warning about Email settings and the Test flow worked to be less intrusive&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: (Performance) Small memory improvement when returning reading list items over OPDS&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Changed 'Edit Series Information' tooltip to 'Edit Information' as it's now generic for other entities&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Adjusted the logic for displaying chapter information when the chapter belongs to a single volume. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Fixed&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bug where all chapter cards would always say chapter, instead of issue&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed some edge case styling issues on cards&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed the wording for the edit tooltip to be more generic since used on other pages, not just series&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed Cover Artists still showing instead of Artist in Search&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bug where task settings weren't saving&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bug where when highlighting text in a setting item, the setting would close. Now it will only close if you click outside the item and there is no selection. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed an issue where validators would reject payload when password was over 32 characters &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Genres/Tags margins on details tab wasn't aligned well with People information&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed an issue where Cover Image Size wasn't displaying on the UI&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bug when changing the bookmark directory would throw an error and not function&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a few issues around smart filter loading for base url reverse proxy setups (aka domain.com/kavita) (Thanks @Fesaa for the issue and helping validate the fixes)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/Kareadita/Kavita/releases/tag/v0.8.3.2" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
