<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://selfh.st/apps</id>
  <title>Kavita Releases</title>
  <updated>2025-03-17T20:30:40.224917-04:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>selfh.st</name>
    <email>contact@selfh.st</email>
  </author>
  <link href="https://selfh.st/apps" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>Self-hosted software releases generated by selfh.st</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/Kareadita/Kavita/releases/tag/v0.8.4</id>
    <title>New release for Kavita: v0.8.4 - New Scanner + Browse Authors/Artists + Tons of Bugfixes</title>
    <updated>2024-11-22T19:12:26-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Kareadita/Kavita</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;After rewriting 50K lines of code last release, I decided it was best to take a break and focus on the bugs that resulted and a few that had piled up. This release is bug focused, but of course I stuck a few big features in with it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Scanner&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One issue that has been cropping up as we attract more users with larger libraries or libraries laid out in the Publisher/Series style is the scanner. Users with large libraries modify their library quite a bit and the old scanner had issues with change detection. v0.8.3 had quite a nasty bug which required forced library scans to ingest new data. There was also the notorious FK issue that was more common for larger libraries. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To fix these issues, I rewrote the scanner from the ground up to be more reliable. This was a (painful) 3 week effort working closely with a dedicated set of testers on a canary release to be nightly and stable ready. &lt;strong&gt;The new scanner will be slower than the old one.&lt;/strong&gt; As of now, I feel that once the main slow first scan is done, it's actually performing much better. With this new scanner, there were some other major changes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;People Re-architecture&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to reduce the FK issue in the scanner, I also needed to tackle the 80+ hour re-architecture of how people work within Kavita. When I started, with my limited knowledge of the scene or what Kavita would grow to become, I implemented people as tags, much like how ComicInfo does. This is constrained when you want to make people more entity-focused, like having a dedicated page for them. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With this release, you can now view individual details of a person, set a cover and description about the person and see their works and individual issues they worked on. You can also browse authors and artists, like other software has. This is just the start, please leave feedback for me via Feature Requests, so I can build this feature out more and make it a richer experience. &lt;strong&gt;Note: Any Smart Filters that relied on people will need manual intervention to correct. A force scan will be required to regenerate writer information.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/992c5451-08c3-45c5-81ce-4426967d3127" /&gt;
&lt;img alt="image" src="https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/b1a06eb8-ddde-44f6-98c2-98315b252494" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Special Keyword Removal&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last thing with the scanner was removing Kavita's ability to detect and classify certain keywords as Special. Like &lt;code&gt;Omake&lt;/code&gt;  or &lt;code&gt;Annual&lt;/code&gt; would classify a file as a special. While this is extremely handy in the Manga scene, there were numerous reports over the years that required manual workarounds by users. In order to behave more reliably, I opened a discussion this year for removal and made the final call. &lt;strong&gt;Specials going forward will need the SP marker on the filename (or tagged internally).&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;CoversDB&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kavita has had the ability to download and display favicon and publisher images with a fallback repository being hosted on the main Kavita website. In this release, I've moved all that functionality and those images over to a new CoversDB &lt;a href="https://github.com/Kareadita/CoversDB"&gt;repo&lt;/a&gt;. This repo will be the home for anything related to pulling images for Kavita instances. I plan to enhance this further as new features come to Kavita.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Small QoL Features&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Last Read Filter&lt;/strong&gt; is a new feature that allows you to pass a number that will be subtracted from TODAY, upping the dynamic function and allowing users to build Smart Filters like "Haven't read in a month". &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Colorscape Polish&lt;/strong&gt; The colorscape system has been polished even further. I spent a good amount of time adding some randomness, fixed a bug with colorscape resetting between navigation, and tried to tweak where colors go to avoid harsh contrasts. It's not perfect, but it's a step in the right direction. If you're passionate about the colorscape system, I welcome collaboration. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bulk Library Actions&lt;/strong&gt; This is something @DieselTech has been pushing me to add and the time is finally here. For users that have a lot of libraries (like Diesel and his 200+), sometimes it's quite a pain to update the settings of them all or perform some actions. Now in Kavita there are some limited bulk options, like refreshing covers or copying settings from one library to another (Scan currently disabled). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/2517e6f1-4548-4d30-ae23-17dc80688771" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Recap&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This release has been a ton of work on my part, but I felt it was important to squash the bugs first and ensure Kavita remains stable while I continue to add more features and bring a richer experience to users. My next release is still aimed at finishing the UX Overhaul with attention on Kavita+. With the holidays coming up, it is expected that this will take longer than most releases. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For those that have seen, we have hit over 65K active installs. It's absolutely amazing that a small project I started due to Ubooquity not having metadata has turned into such a massive project with a huge userbase. I want to give my thanks again to those in the community that have raised bugs, feature requests, give support in the discord/reddit, those who give me donations via OC/Kavita+, the translators, and of course my wife that helps support me pouring so much time into the project. &lt;strong&gt;I'm excited to continue building Kavita and bring about more of our visions into the software and see what is possible.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;People metadata will be removed on update. A force scan is required to repopulate in the new system. A force scan/first scan will be much slower than before.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Added&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: Manage Libraries now has bulk actions. You can trigger multiple scans (not file scans, but refresh covers or colorscapes, etc) or copy settings from one library to multiple. Shift+select works as well.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: Added a new page for all People within Kavita. From this page, you can see their works across Kavita.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: Ability to see individual chapters/issues (limited to 20) a person has.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: Ability to add images to the person via UI/API. A more automated method is planned in the future.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: Added the ability to browse all Writers and Artists (cover artist) in one page. This should help book users that like to browse by author. (Feature Request: #2556 - 23 votes) (Thanks @MrRobotjs for some css on the Person detail page)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: Added the ability to trigger the general cleanup (which normally runs at midnight) manually in case you need to clear unlinked people, covers, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: Reading List and Collection cards now show a badge showing the number of series/items underneath.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: New Filter option called Last Read which allows a number to be passed in and will dynamically calculate a date from TODAY() matched against reading time. This allows for users to build even more dynamic smart filters to find things not read in a month or read within the past 7 days.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: Added back a lot of the metadata that had to be removed from the top of the series detail page in the UX overhaul, like Language, Release Year, Format, and Reading Time &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: Added Details tab to volume details page&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: (Kavita+) New Sync Details button on smart collections that shows an easier to digest view of Series and missing series.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: Bulk send to is now available for chapters/volumes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: Added bulk deletion for chapters/volumes &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Changed&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Optimized a number of methods within the Scanner to reduce memory and CPU time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Moved a lot of the chapter scanner logging to Trace.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Scanner can now choose to parallel parse files when there are over 100 in a directory&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Changed how detection and scanning of dirty directories works. The scanner will now parse bottom-up to reduce any potential misses and avoid different layouts working differently. This has extra I/O checks but much greater reliability and should reduce the amount of work needed to ingest changes after the first scan.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: LocalizedSeries merging with Series is now done at a higher level and performs much better (in terms of reliability)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: People are now entity based which allows for a richer experience in Kavita.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Clicking on any person in Kavita will now open their dedicated page which showcases their different works.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: (Performance) Some large refactors to the scanner to help with the FK bug. The scanner should be slower but consume much less memory, especially for well tagged systems.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Kavita no longer parses keywords from filenames and groups as a Special. The way to mark a special going forward will be explicitly with SP01, SP02, etc. Specials can be flat in the series folder or ideally in Specials/ folder. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Changed logging level on some of the loggers that could become noisy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Refactored some of the post-series work to a separate thread.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Ensure mobile actionable modal is fullscreen and centered vertically&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Update to Angular 18 and other backend dependencies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: When a setting is invalid, clicking outside the setting item will not close and edit is disabled.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Changed the smart filters page to open in the same window (but still available to open in new tab)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: (Performance) Made the pipe that turns the language codes into full names use a dedicated API which is faster&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Improved the wording for Single Volume chapters on Series detail page (and person detail page)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Kavita now uses a different repo for publisher images and favicons (https://github.com/Kareadita/CoversDB). Any changes should be made here.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: You can now edit the person name in the UI. If not corrected in the metadata, a duplicate person will be created. This will be tweaked in the future once Alias support is added.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Significantly improved the feel of the colorscape experience. When transitioning between colorscapes, locations of accent points will randomize. Lighter colors will try to avoid the bottom right where there could be bad contrast.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Changed Colorscape to use non-linear animation for transitioning between 2 colorscapes. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: If the user somehow wrote bad cron notation for custom jobs, on startup, Kavita will detect and default to daily&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Changed the overall look and feel of the preference side nav and main side nav (Thanks @MrRobotjs)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Moved Test email settings to the top to align with the UX patterns&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Moved Reset to Defaults to the top to align with UX patterns and removed a few instances since it resets everything.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Changed a lot of modals to be more consistent in how they open and their size to be slightly larger.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: When failing to get a page count on an archive, report it in media issues&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Improved memory consumption on some filtering conditions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Tweaked some logging messages to be more clear when using logs to debug&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Fixed&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bug where the UnauthorizedAccessException is not correctly ignored when using the docker container as non-root. (Thanks @Fesaa)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bug where any media that was less than an hour in length wouldn't be included in stats. This requires Analyze Files to be ran on all libraries to retroactively fix&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bug where chapter order wasn't properly sorting on Volume Detail page&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed an issue where bookmarking wouldn't check if the source file was already in the target encoding and thus had issue when trying to convert. Also added another check to not do anything if target encoding is PNG (aka Kavita doesn't convert webp -&amp;gt; png). &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bug where Series Cover image could choose a Volume 0 instead of Volume 1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bug where teams and locations wouldn't trigger updating people on update series metadata api&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bug where calculating the Lowest Folder for a Series could be incorrect when there are nested folders. This includes a migration to clear out existing entries to avoid scan series not seeing files.
Example:
/ &amp;lt;- Lib root assume
/love hina/love hina/v01.cbz
/love hina/specials/sp01.cbz
The lowest series folder was /love hina/love hina/ for some reason, meaning series scan wasn't getting the full series (all folders) scanned in.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed up a check for using lowest folder path to lookup from a Folder Watcher task. This should find series much better from a lower file path.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bug where teams and locations wouldn't trigger updating people on update series metadata api&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bug where users could change their age rating when they didn't have the permission&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bug where download wasn't functioning from the on deck cards&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a typo on the localization string for Create Multiple Reading List/Collection pages&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed Promote/Unpromote not working from reading list detail page and collection detail page &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Ensure we show details page when weblinks are present, including chapter detail page&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed related tab not having enough bottom padding &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a few different combinations where IsEmpty was not working &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed broken Send To on mobile and Send To not actually functioning for chapter/volume cards.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Tweaked read-time-left pipe to have better control on how we present the now decimal number.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bug where continue from was choosing ch instead of vol &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed read-more text not displaying newlines correctly in some situations (Thanks @Fesaa)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed the search bar closing when toggling show chapters and files toggle (Thanks @Fesaa)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bug where validation wasn't showing on Hostname &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Next expected card had layout issues and missing localization&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Don't close a modal when a typeahead is open and pressing Escape key&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed tooltips not rendering on some cards, like reading list/collection cards&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a missing case to show storyline tab on Light Novel libraries when users use chapters (not common) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Ensure the edit series modal is showing the localized publication status &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Updated a lot of missing localization keys&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed the fade between colorscape so there isn't a reset to default anymore&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed an issue with how specials render on reading list detail page &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed the duplicate Dark theme issue once and for all&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed custom tasks not being possible &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed Irish not working when selected as locale &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed edit chapter modal failing to save when setting Age Rating &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bug where when a card doesn't have a format, 22px was still beating taken up. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Ensure More In Genre doesn't choose from a Genre that's not exposed to the dashboard&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bug where bulk mode on customize side nav wasn't laying out the bulk update well. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed delete chapter not being hooked up from Volume details page &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed user rating filter not working at all. It was accepting a percentage, but should have been a number 0-5 for the star rating. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed the bulk actions bar laying out in the wrong position&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: In the rare occasion someone turns off all the file types for a library, the scanner will now respect that.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed Delete and Analyze Files on the library detail actionables not being hooked up&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed an issue with doujin filenames causing series to all parse as ( &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: (Kavita+) Fixed a bug where old Book libraries could be stuck in Scrobbling On state&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed age rating icon not updating upon series metadata changes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Ensure Jumpkeys are grouped non-case sensitive&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bug where want to read page was using a custom query passed through the filtering pipeline, thus breaking some combos.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bug where manage email settings was spamming the backend due to an infinite loop&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed select all on edit user modal affecting the role/library control as well.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: On Age Rating filter, the comparisons could be duplicated&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bug with bulk selection not pruning submenu actions when there are no children left. (aka empty send to)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;API&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Search now returns a list of PersonDto instead of strings for People results.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Removed metadata/chapter-summary api since it hasn't been used in years&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Theme&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Side nav selected tab now uses --side-nav-item-active-text-color on the text instead of just being white&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added --side-nav-width variable to control side nav bar width&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added --navbar-header-margin, set it to 8px and --nav-offset to 56px to get the Plex floating navbar.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added --navbar-border-radius to fix the navbar but let users customize for that Plex look.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added --navbar-header-mobile-x-margin and --navbar-header-mobile-y-margin to allow for the Plex navbar on mobile&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Feature Requests&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added the ability to browse all Writers and Artists (cover artist) in one page. This should help book users that like to browse by author. (FR #2556 - 23 votes)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Known Issues&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(Kavita+) MAL Stack imports/Smart Collection total series count is not correct. This will be fixed with v0.8.5. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Uploading some dimensions for person cover can cause the image to be squished. This will be fixed with v0.8.5.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When using multiple reading progress filters, some series with 100% reading progress will show (clicking On Deck). After 14 hours, I can't solve it. I will loop around in v0.8.5.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/Kareadita/Kavita/releases/tag/v0.8.4" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/Kareadita/Kavita/releases/tag/v0.8.4.2</id>
    <title>New release for Kavita: v0.8.4.2 - Hotfix + Migration Script</title>
    <updated>2024-11-27T15:11:39-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Kareadita/Kavita</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;A few small things slipped past. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to take this space to first apologize to our users that manually tag their metadata in Kavita. Post release has been an eye opener to the different ways uses of Kavita and a lesson learned to work harder to preserve data between releases. I always try, but sometimes big lift and shifts like this are needed and aren't easy to preserve data. I will take it on myself to strive for excellence and do what is feasible to preserve data. I don't foresee many major refactors like this happening in the near future. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On more positive news, MetronInfo.xml has become stabilized. This is a step towards advancing the metadata format for Comics and Manga (and potentially books in the future). I have worked closely with Brian (the creator) to include Manga into the format. Kavita is dedicated towards supporting the format, that work is planned for next year. Read up more about it &lt;a href="https://metron-project.github.io/blog/metroninfo-v1"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have a lot of metadata that was tagged just via the UI, you can try this &lt;a href="https://pastebin.com/RPmfSSYq"&gt;script&lt;/a&gt; a user wrote to migrate the data. Grab a backup from v0.8.3 and run this against it. You need to update &lt;code&gt;oldDb&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;newDb&lt;/code&gt;. I cannot offer support for this script. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did convert this to python via ChatGPT and added instructions, it will be much easier but I did not test it. You can find the script &lt;a href="https://pastebin.com/BR0GxaXB"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Fixed&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Send to on mobile was still broken&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Changed On Deck to use a workaround as a temp fix&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bug where on non-English locales parsing numbers would throw an exception and cause files to not be ingested. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Bulk library delete wasn't hooked up&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bug where updating chapter metadata with a new person, the normalized name was saved&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Potentially fixed a bug where adding multiple people on a series via UI will throw an exception (Was not able to reproduce, but added extra safety logic)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/Kareadita/Kavita/releases/tag/v0.8.4.2" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/Kareadita/Kavita/releases/tag/v0.8.5</id>
    <title>New release for Kavita: v0.8.5 - Metadata Downloading &amp; PDF Metadata!</title>
    <updated>2025-03-07T14:36:21-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Kareadita/Kavita</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;It's been some time since the last release and this one is hefty! The goal of this release is to overhaul Kavita+ experience within Kavita, but I sneaked in metadata downloading, something I originally envisioned for Kavita, as well. This release is packed with a lot of goodies, from the ability to download metadata, greatly improving the PDF experience, to decreasing the scrobble window from 4 hours to 1 hour, and much more. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Metadata Downloading (Kavita+)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I first started Kavita, I talked about wanting to build a plugin system to support metadata downloading, so I could have a true Plex experience. As the application and user base grew, the Plugin system was too much scope for me to handle and I said goodbye to the idea. Luckily, Kavita+ is here to provide that opportunity to build it out and all of last year, I have been slowly laying the foundation to make it a reality. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kavita can now automatically download metadata and apply it to your Series. It currently supports 12 different fields, including Cover Image, People, Genres, Tags, Age Ratings, and Relationships to name a few. I wanted to build a system that was functional but simple. Kavita offers a few controls that should allow enough flexibility to work for most users. I want to also thank the community for the overwhelming testing and feedback. The nightly testers and community really brought a lot of great ideas to polish this feature off. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With that said, I want to set expectations. I'm not looking to build a komf replacement. This will currently just use metadata from AniList/MAL and Hardcover once I get around to it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So how does it work? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;PDF Metadata&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The pains of PDF may finally be over! Kavita now can read PDF metadata when tagged with Calibre (there is no real metadata format). Thanks to @microtherion writing a custom PDF parser, Kavita can now extract Series, title, volume, genres, etc from your files and bring a good experience for people forced to use PDFs. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;New Stats API&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This release also sees the release of an overhauled stat system. The Stats API is mainly for understanding how many servers are running Kavita, but there is also a lot of benefit in collecting anonymous data about the users of Kavita. On multiple occasions, I base decisions for features or bugs based on that data. However, the original stats API was quite out of date with what was important, so I overhauled it drastically. Like always, the code is Open source and nothing is logged that can identify you. You can take a look at the stat record &lt;a href="https://github.com/Kareadita/KavitaStats/pull/67"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. Thank you to all that continue to report statistics. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Misc&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wanted to shout out a few extra features that are included in this release. First off, Automatic Webtoon mode switching. This is a very common issue for users that read by comics and webtoons and also a discovery issue for new users. While I had architected out a grand solution for this, due to time constraints it never came. This is a good hold over until that time comes. When Kavita opens a comic that is likely a webtoon, it will switch into the mode for you automatically. It's not 100%, but a best guess. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another new feature is bringing Bionic Reading mode to Kavita's epub reader via a new font. A few users asked for this and thankfully a font made it possible. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Docker Fix&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the last release, docker users reported the scanner breaking. You can fix this with the following. The wiki reflects this as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Add &lt;code&gt;DOTNET_SYSTEM_GLOBALIZATION_INVARIANT=true&lt;/code&gt; to your docker compose&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;This Year&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With that said, let's talk about what I want to deliver this year. I have to preface this by saying that this year my time is extremely constrained. But as always, I have lots of ideas that I want to try and accomplish. Since my time is limited, I've scaled down my goals to 2 main features:
1. &lt;strong&gt;Journal-style Progress&lt;/strong&gt; will allow for a much richer stats experience and allow for some new functionalities in reading history. I've already validated this architecture in another project so it shouldn't be too complex porting back to Kavita. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kobo Sync&lt;/strong&gt; was on my list last year but due to the new scanner, got pushed away. With the news of Kindle, it seems like a great time to prioritize it to the front of the list. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These two features are a blend of user wants and my own wants to enable much richer statistics in the application. I'm sure I'll get side tracked along the way and deliver something cool. As always, a big thank you to our users and community. Kavita would not be where it is without your comments, feedback, and ideas. I'm really grateful that I have a great community, looking forward to working with you this year. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note: AniList API is currently degraded and stuck at 30 requests / min. I've tried to build out the cache to avoid having to hit them for the release. Please be patient, I will be continuing my work on Kavita+ to work around these API limits.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;With metadata being available for PDF, you may loose progress. When v0.8.5 starts, it will export all progress to config/progress_export-v0.8.5.csv&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/942d0640-eb36-4523-93bc-d3f882ae29cc" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/7b6ade48-8036-4d0b-b473-bddaf6b10bc2" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/419955c1-9557-44e2-b329-dba43fb2b050" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/4133c843-cc74-4cb6-96b0-5d1c43fa1d61" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Added&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: Added Fast Font to Book Reader. Fast Font is an open source Bionic Font alternative (FR #1268)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: Added the ability to read embedded metadata from PDFs that conform to Calibre's embedding. (FR #3103)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: Added a new stat for if the server uses metadata matching&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: (Manga Reader) When most of the file dimensions look like webtoon images, switch into the Webtoon reader on behalf of the user.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: Series related tab will now show if there are bookmarks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: Added the ability to see release notes of nightly releases in the changelog/announcements screens.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: The UI will now check for new versions of Kavita (server-level) and prompt the user with the changelog and force them to refresh to get the latest UI code. This also takes care of any transloco hacks to clear the cache. This should help on update day for non-admin users to get the latest UI code files.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: Added a new long term cache directory (cache-long). Currently storing Github release history information.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: (Kavita+) Complete overhaul to the Kavita+ license page. Not only will you have the main license flow, but Kavita will pull down information about your subscription, including the registered email, total sub length, when the expiration will be, and if you're on a valid Kavita install version. Surfaced some of the actionable buttons with descriptions to hopefully help drive more management through the software instead of emailing me.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: Added long term caching for Publisher/Favicon fallback so CoversDb doesn't have to service more requests than needed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: (Kavita+) There is now a manual match flow in Kavita to match a series (or fix a match) to AniList (currently the only upstream provider till Hardcover). Kavita still tries to match automatically, but via this new action from Series detail page, you can either provide another search name or Anilist/Mal urls directly to direct match. Likewise, you can select 'Do Not Match' which will delete any previously matched data, drop all scrobble events, and prevent matching/scrobbling in the future.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: (Kavita+) Removed the previous error/matched bar from license screen and broke into it's own page called Matched Metadata. You can now filter by matched state (either not yet matched, needs manual match, don't match) and perform said flows from this screen. This should result in a much easier time navigating your metadata.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: (Kavita+) New screen to see your users and if their AniList tokens are set or expired.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: (Kavita+) Kavita will now email you (assuming email is setup and using a real email) whenever your scrobble tokens are about to expire (5 days out) and the day of, urging you to renew them to avoid scrobbling issues.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: Kavita now has an email history table for admins to see which emails were sent out&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: (Kavita+) Kavita now implements the feature request to sync your 'planned' read lists from AniList/MAL into Kavita's Want to Read (FR #3153)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: New button to download a person's image from CoverDB. I am still working out how to approach an automated solution. CoverDB is open for new entries.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: (Kavita+) Added the ability for individual users to turn on/off scrobbling to anilist and the want to read sync.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: (Kavita+) Kavita can now download metadata upon add and via the Match action. Metadata includes series cover image, summary, age rating, publication status, relationships (assuming already owned), release year, people (writer, artist, character) - including cover images, genres, and tags. Provides a flexible system to customize to your needs or disable altogether.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: (Kavita+) New Library setting to opt a whole library out of being matched.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: (Kavita+) Ability to override locked fields when performing a match to update metadata&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: Users can now press enter to close (and save) the setting items that are text inputs &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Changed&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Changed the maximum line length of text inside of expandable blocks of text to a readable value (Thanks @heyhippari)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Allow admins to change non-admin's email accounts on file. Will automatically assume it's valid.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Docker builds will now have extra metadata (Thanks @halkeye)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed:  Cleaned up the person image components to be a better experience in different states (Thanks @heyhippari )&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Known for on person page shouldn't show for Translator/Team/Location.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Updated docker build scripts to include docker labels&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Massive overhaul to the data collection aspect of Kavita to ship more helpful information that is more up to date with the functionalities of Kavita. Stat collection can still be disabled and will still run after the first 12 hours to give time to opt-out.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: ReadOnly role is now more inline with the name. Any user with this role will only be able to rate series and update their want to read.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Added a new mix mode for Colorscape to darken the colors&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Reworked handling of an exception for there being 2 progress entries for a given chapter. This previously would take the first and set as the new progress, but now it will take the newest and also take the highest page.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Don't show the number of images under a chapter card for images.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Rewrote the changelog/announcement to now be limited to 10 releases and have a better rendering experience.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: [TIME] profiling logs from last release is now on Trace as it's no longer needed anymore.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Updated to .NET 9 which brings performance improvements and patches some security vulnerabilities&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: (Kavita+) When registering a license that was previously bound to another instance, Kavita will now prompt you to override that old binding. This is usually the case and thus Kavita can perform the reset and registration in one flow for you (rather than you using Reset button then Saving again).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: (Kavita+) After registering your license a popup will open to inform you of how Scrobbling works and the next steps you should take.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: (Kavita+) After adding your Anilist token, Kavita now prompts you if you want to backfill scrobble events now or later (from Scrobbling page). This first time generation is important to sync your history/want to read/ratings from before you added the token. Giving the user time to setup Series Holds will ensure only data they want exposed is.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: (Kavita+) Scrobbling window is decreased from 4 hours to 1 hour&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: If anilist id is set, will add an AL weblink on person page&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: (Kavita+) Age Rating mappings from Kavita+ Metadata settings will apply when scanning in series.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: (Kavita+) When using edit series modal, also recalculate age rating based on tags/genres&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: (Kavita+) Characters are now ordered based on their role in the Series (Main, Supporting, Background)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: (Kavita+) Sleep a little longer for background fetching to respect AL's new rate limit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: (Kavita+) Reset all blacklisted external series metadata to allow fresh start with the much upgraded code. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Fixed&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed the way the sidebar closes (both on large screens and on mobile) to prevent text and icons jumping around during the animation. (Thanks @heyhippari)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bug where if an age restricted user tried to load a person that they have partial access to, the backend would restrict the load &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bug where double tap on an image in manga reader no longer triggers the bookmark flow. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed the UI using the wrong localization key for On Deck descriptions &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bug where updating Team, it would actually write to Characters for edit series modal.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a typo in the event widget error message that shows up when the scan returns an empty root folder for the particular library. (Thanks @midhun3301 )&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: (Kavita+) Fixed a long standing bug where background series processing (fetching metadata for K+) wasn't pulling anything more than the first 25 series over and over.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed add device button being broken&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bug where an admin editing a user was unable to save the form without a valid email, even though non-valid emails are allowed. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bug where person links wouldn't be url encoded&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bug where characters weren't being saved on the backend&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bug where progress tooltips would be behind the card title overlay &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bug where when the filename and the series name/localized name are the same, Kavita would get confused and skip the file.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bug where reading a pdf on Kavita then switching to reading over OPDS, the cache wouldn't work as the images weren't cached, only the pdf. (Thanks @m-amazirh for the help)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: When downloading image series/chapters, zip them up and use the folder names on disk for inside the archive&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: (Manga Reader) Fixed up/down arrow key not scrolling on manga reader with original layout &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Sanitize OPDS feeds in case the user has characters that are invalid&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: (Epub Reader) White book theme was unnecessarily overriding some book styles (Thanks @Redst0neFlux)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Don't darken images on white/paper book themes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bug when bulk selecting cards, the read button overlay shouldn't be present&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Confirmation modals didn't have localized strings.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: (Kavita+) Fixed a bug where want to read was scrobbling from libraries where AllowScrobbling is off. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: (Kavita+) Fixed a bug where Want to Read scrobbling was not respecting library rules &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed Characters field not being wired up in the Save API.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed location locked field not being wired up in the Save API.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a weird issue where Host name would eat keys when typing on General settings.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bug where clicking a person from Volume/Chapter detail pages wouldn't load the person profile&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bug that was calling unneeded checks on Kavita+ license validation each refresh&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed spacing issue on the edit chapter modal (and aligned all modals to have the same spacing)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bug where a progress check on the DB was being handled which logged a warning to logger.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed the overlay title on cards extending past the card boundary when in a carousel (Thanks @Zeoic)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bug where the background job to fill out metadata was constantly pulling the same blacklisted series over and over again, thus making no progress.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bug where epub images that were hotlinked weren't loading correctly in the reader.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed removing web links behaving wrongly when removing links in a specific order  (Thanks @Fesaa)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed default cache being 50MB when it should be 75MB&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bug when a metadata refresh event comes int, the active tab could get stuck on series detail&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed not being able to update general server settings &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: (Kavita+) New migration to cleanup super old scrobble events that might be side-effects of version updates. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Feature Requests&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added Fast Font to Book Reader. Fast Font is an open source Bionic Font alternative (FR #1268)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added the ability to read embedded metadata from PDFs that conform to Calibre's embedding. (FR #3103)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(Kavita+) Kavita now implements the feature request to sync your 'planned' read lists from AniList/MAL into Kavita's Want to Read (FR #3153)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Known Issues&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some covers will disappear after being added to Kavita (rare). If I can reproduce, I will hotfix.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Match modal may sometimes appear like there are no results but there should be. This is due to rate issues, this will be addressed in v0.8.6. You just need to wait a few minutes for it to be searchable again. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don't fall behind (Out of date)  modal is popping when it shouldn't (a hotfix will be issued in a few days)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/Kareadita/Kavita/releases/tag/v0.8.5" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/Kareadita/Kavita/releases/tag/v0.8.5.3</id>
    <title>New release for Kavita: v0.8.5.3 - Hotfix</title>
    <updated>2025-03-09T13:13:19-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Kareadita/Kavita</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;A small hotfix is needed due to the Don't fall behind modal showing incorrectly. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The known issue of covers disappearing seems to be related to multi-root libraries and thus is likely to require a full release cycle to tackle. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Fixed&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bug where the Don't fall behind modal was opening constantly&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a wiki link being wrong&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/Kareadita/Kavita/releases/tag/v0.8.5.3" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/Kareadita/Kavita/releases/tag/v0.8.5.11</id>
    <title>New release for Kavita: v0.8.5.11 - Hotfix 2</title>
    <updated>2025-03-17T15:25:25-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Kareadita/Kavita</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;I decided to do one more hotfix as there was an annoying bug for multi-root libraries that causes flip-flopping (the same issue as covers disappearing). This also contains some fixes around scrobbling and misc other bugs reported that are a good fit. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;v0.8.6 is still planned to focus on the Scanner and finishing off the Kavita+ Polish. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Changed&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Locale selection now shows the total percentage of completion of the locale.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Cleaned up some code around localization as a way to hopefully fight the keys showing in the UI on new versions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: (Kavita+) When a user removes the Kavita+ license from their instance, stop doing all K+ Background tasks instead of waiting for the next restart.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: (Kavita+) Kavita will now clean up old scrobble events for users that don't have an anilist token on their account, so that events that will never get processed get cleaned up.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: (Kavita+) When sourcing descriptions from Kavita+, remove the (Source: X).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Fixed&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bug where a signature on an API was wrong &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: (Kavita+) Fixed a length issue for reviews from Kavita+ that could break metadata matching &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: (Kavita+) Fixed some edge case handling of want to read scrobbling and potentially some issues around events that never get processed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed unable to start Kavita for the first time on DD/MM/YYYY locales (Thanks @Fesaa )&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bug where multi-root libraries would delete and recreate series in one of non-first folders&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed reading list not respecting age restrictions (Thanks @Fesaa )&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;API&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Updated the ReadHistoryEvent to expose ReadDateUtc instead of just the server timezone date. (Thanks @0xGingi)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Known Issues&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Docker images aren't showing Locale names correctly (this will be fixed v0.8.6)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/Kareadita/Kavita/releases/tag/v0.8.5.11" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
