<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://selfh.st/apps</id>
  <title>Kavita Releases</title>
  <updated>2025-01-14T12:30:56.863162-05:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>selfh.st</name>
    <email>contact@selfh.st</email>
  </author>
  <link href="https://selfh.st/apps" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>Self-hosted software releases generated by selfh.st</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/Kareadita/Kavita/releases/tag/v0.8.2</id>
    <title>New release for Kavita: v0.8.2 - Theme Overhaul, Smart Collections, &amp; a lot of Scanner work</title>
    <updated>2024-07-07T08:38:32-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Kareadita/Kavita</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;A new stable release is here and it is yet again another big one. Initially I set out to focus on 3 items: Scanner, Smart Collections, and CBL v2 (new schema), but here I am delivering 3 massive improvements and a ton of smaller changes. This release includes a bit of everything spread about. Let's get into it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Built-in Theme Explorer&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing I wanted since day one of adding theme support into Kavita was the ability for users you just browse a list of themes and download what they want to use. It's not easy when the admin has to add the theme for you and hit scan, dealing with the underlying filesystem. I finally got around to setting up the initial version of this (open to feedback to expand on this system) with v0.8.2. All users will have the ability to browse themes uploaded to the theme repo, preview the images and description, and download and apply theme. This currently does not have any role permission and I didn't hear much from nightly users thinking it's needed. If you feel otherwise, raise a discussion. If you don't want to use a theme on the repo, you can upload your own file via the interface. Existing theme users should delete their themes and re-acquire them. This will allow them to be updated for you automatically (assuming the supported version matches yours). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="https://github.com/Kareadita/Kavita/assets/735851/b40e1284-8c30-4f3b-968c-73227abb65f3" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Smart Collections for Kavita+&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is another one I've wanted for a while and is part of the theme of introducing more synchronization systems into Kavita. Smart Collections allow for you to import any Interest Stacks/Restacks from your MAL account into Kavita. Every 2 days, Kavita will resync with upstream and add any Series that you own to the collection. The collection is otherwise read-only and promotable, so if you want to setup a few best of X and promote them for your server, you can. These features are also not admin-specific. Any user can import their interest stacks into the server (and if they have the promotion role, can promote them). I hope you all enjoy this feature as much as I am. Another level of bringing a top notch experience for my users. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Scanner Changes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've been working a lot with our users that have larger libraries, ranging from 100k files to 10k series. One of the major problems is that when you have a library of 10k, it's going to take a long time as expected. These users are mainly new users coming from the comic rework and have folder structures Kavita wasn't originally built around. I spent a good chunk of time building optimizations to reduce the amount of processing work Kavita does for these folder layouts (not restrictive to comic libraries) and fixing some bugs around parsing and whatnot that surfaced thanks to the numerous bug reports. If you aren't finding good results after this update, please do reach out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Misc Changes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few other big changes come with this release. The first is WAL is now on by default. You can always turn this off manually in the DB, but fresh installs (and existing) will turn WAL on. WAL fixes the common &lt;code&gt;database is locked&lt;/code&gt; issue due to Kavita writing too much data too fast. Another big one is double scrollbar on mobile. This was an annoying bug on some mobile browsers on some pages. Robbie took this up and fixed it everywhere to my knowledge. A great QoL enhancement. OPDS has gotten a lot of love in this release thanks to some great reports by @MnsieurJF around reading lists and missing metadata in the feeds. Lastly, the Manga Reader has had some tweaking to how fit to height/width works. It's not easy to put into words, but I find the fitting to be MUCH better. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have loose plans for what the next release is going to be. The PDF rework will need to come after v0.8.3 to allow people who upgrade into the v0.8.x series not to loose data from the massive changes. I have a lot of holiday coming up as well, so the release may be longer or shorter depending. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lastly, I want to mention (as I keep forgetting) that @DieselTech has joined the Kavita team a few months ago. His name should be well known as he's very active in most of the reading and comic discords as well as being a core member in the CBL Reading Order group. He's already driven a lot of great changes in Kavita for hardcore comic users and I have no doubt he will continue to be a great resource for me to rely on in the future. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Added&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: Kavita+ users can now import their MAL interest stacks/restacks into Kavita as Smart Collections. These collections will synchronize back with MAL to update with new series and summary information every 2 days. Smart Collections work just as normal collections except are non-editable as the MAL stack controls the data. They can be promoted given the user has promotion role. They are not admin-specific. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: Added the ability for any user to download themes from the Theme Repo directly via Kavita. Kavita will keep these themes up to data automatically (unless the reported version from the Repo is greater than the server version).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: Book series can now have specials. In order to be classified as a Special, the SP marker must be in the filename, the calibre:series must be set to the Series name and &lt;code&gt;calibre:series_index&lt;/code&gt; must be 0. (Feature Request: 3 upvotes)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: OPDS-PS on PDF files is now possible. Kavita will convert to images.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: Added a create link to create a new smart filter in case it's not clear for first time users exploring the software.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: Added first install version and date to the DB so admin's can look back at it. This data is available in System tab.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: Added new Random sort option to allow a stream like 'Top Unread in X' (Thanks @Fesaa)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: Added the following css variables --event-widget-activity-bg-color, --event-widget-update-bg-color, --event-widget-error-bg-color&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: Implemented the ability to click download on any file extension from stats page (formats table) and download a report of all files that are of that extension.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: Added the ability to manually override the width in the manga/webtoon reader when using Width scaling (Thanks @Marsimplodation) (Feature Request: 19 upvotes)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: Added bulk promote/demote/delete for reading lists to align with collections.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Changed&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: On forgot password, even if email isn't setup or user doesn't have email setup, still allow the reset link to log. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Reduced memory for adding a set of series to a collection.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Scan button no longer exists on themes tab. Now, admin's can upload their custom css files via the UI.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Admin's can no longer delete themes and force users with that theme active off.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Changed how scaling works in the manga reader to be more inline with the expected behavior. Height will scale to viewport height even if it is beyond the image's original dimensions. Width will scale to viewport width even if it is beyond the image's original dimensions. Original will show the image at its intrinsic dimensions, no scaling is applied (Thanks @therobbiedavis)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Enable WAL journal mode by default in all Kavita installs. Users can turn it off after the first run if needed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Show a warning on dirty email setting form to inform the user they need to save before testing settings.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Ensure users know that Scrobbling providers will always keep the highest number from kavita.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: On &amp;lt; tablet viewports, reading list page should use order numbers rather than drag and drop, as there isn't enough real estate.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Series Detail page will now show people/genre/tags as collapsed even on desktop, but summary will have same code to be expanded up to 1000 characters on desktop.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: (Scanner) Refactored Scan Loop to avoid doing extra work on lower folders in a folder map path, so that users that group by publisher or another arbitrary folder, can avoid a lot of scanning on lower level folders just because the highest level changed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: (Performance) Applied some performance optimizations on Series OPDS route which should help speed up heavier Series.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: (Performance) Small optimization to image reader to make finding the next/prev page faster.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Search will no longer search against Chapter titles and Files by default. Instead, there is a new link in the search window to perform with those included. This should help users with larger libraries find their files faster.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: (Kavita+) Kavita+ scrobbling will now take AniList/Mal ids from External metadata (which is prefetched from Kavita+ for the external metadata) whenever possible. This can help with matching when there are no weblinks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Updates dependencies which includes a fix for nav items in epub toc that are more loose. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Added a few full-wdith characters for normalization: ＊！＋&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: All smart filters page now uses the same design as the flow from Customize modal.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Disable the first remove button for weblinks/exclude pattern component as it isn't removable&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Updated ScanFolder to be more aggressive in finding the underlying series by also checking against a partial match on lowest folder path to find a series. This should result in less work for well structured libraries.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: (Performance) Cleaned up some extra db calls that aren't needed in the OPDS apis.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Reading Lists in both OPDS/UI now have the underlying issue's summary.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Smart Filter OPDS feeds are now smart-filters/{id} instead of smart-filter/{id}&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Updated the cover generation logic to handle webtoons better. The new code will now check if the image scales well or not and if not, use a more attention focused scaling/cropping method. (Thanks @arition for the &lt;a href="https://github.com/Kareadita/Kavita/pull/2612"&gt;initial PR&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: For OPDS Reading Lists, when there is only one underlying file (common), send an acquisition link rather than a subsection. This allows the removal of one of the clicks for nearly all users. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: When a scan is enqueued or in progress, have the scanner aware and reschedule tasks mins into the future (except scan series which is 1 min)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Added more logging into scanner service and ensure folder watching isn't over triggering the scan loop.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Redesigned the loading indicators on the events widget to be cleaner and more expressive. Added the online user count to the nav bar like Plex has. Added an update icon like error/info to help users know when there are updates.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: (Performance) Converted series detail to control flow syntax to hopefully speed up change detection when there is a large amount of chapters.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: (Performance) Don't render all tabs by default on series detail. When switching tabs, it will destroy the DOM. This helps a lot with change detection on first load and later changes. First load on big series can take over 30 seconds to process. This means you will incur the long load when activating the tab with a lot of cards.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Tweaked how jobs are queued and what messages we send to the UI. First, Scan tasks invoked via the UI will now send reschedule alerts when a scan is in progress and another is about to be kicked off. Scan Series now will retry 200 times instead of 3 given new rescheduling code.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Fixed&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bug where Hangfire could be accessible when it wasn't supposed to. (Thanks @theGEBIRGE)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bug where Update Preferences API was taking SiteTheme instead of SiteThemeDto&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bug where multiple extractions of the same archive would start concurrently and create file system problems. This caused out of order reading in Mihon (Thanks @SamuelBMartins)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed an issue where one some screens images would stack instead of being side by side while using the double setting in the manga reader. (Thanks @therobbiedavis)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed an issue where the cover and last page would not be positioned correctly when using the double (Manga) setting in the manga reader. (Thanks @therobbiedavis)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed the issue with review cards provider and score extending outside it's card boundary. (Thanks @therobbiedavis)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed an issue with double scrollbar when viewing saved smart filters (Thanks @therobbiedavis)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed up the info icon cards on series detail to be better with responsiveness on some breakpoints.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed an issue where one-shot/specials in Scrobble History would show internal encoding&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bug with Image series where caching the images for reading could create a ton of folders with the same files inside. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Word count analysis will now handle missing manifest items gracefully and report media errors around said file.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed bcmap files not loading in the pdf reader &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bug when adding items to a reading list in bulk, sorting order of those chapters was not being respected.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bug when a file of Chapter 0.2 first scanned in, Kavita would render the card as 'Chapter 0.2 - .2' then on another scan, Kavita would correctly render out 'Chapter 0.2'.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Loading indicator wasn't properly wired up in the search component &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed an edge case bug when performing a series scan, it wouldn't respect the exclude patterns of the library.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a case where specials in the manga reader weren't giving the special name &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a case where there could be no storyline chapters but just normal chapters and OPDS feed wouldn't render correctly. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a case where content type could fail, for example with avif. Now a failsafe is in place.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed some OPDS feeds where author (writer) wasn't being sent. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a parser case where a file was marked as special but also had an issue number, the issue number would un-specialize it. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Added a migration to nullify LowestFolderPaths that did not start with a library root. This was caused by an old bug likely that has hence been fixed, yet old records break the new scan loop.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bug where LowestSeriesFolder was not a full rooted path on linux&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed an issue where metadata apis could return genres/tags/people coming from libraries a user doesn't have access to.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bug with publication status when there is a set number of volumes but that series also has a special in it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bug where OPDS urls could have api/opds//api/opds instead of just api/opds/&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed up the code in the system tab where users may be on a revision of 0 but the Github release doesn't have a revision, causing the page to always show as nightly, even though it's a stable. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixes the pdf search button not displaying (Thanks @Zackaree)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed double scrollbar &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bug where continue from title was not taking library type into consideration nor was localized&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Cleaned up the event widget showing nothing going on here when it shouldn't. Fixed a missing localization.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bug where some events weren't sending their name and event widget wasn't clearing them after opening their detail modal.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a case where when mass deleting series from library detail page, the page could refresh a lot more than needed. Now, each call is debounced by 100ms.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bug where on mobile devices the continuous scroller wouldn't trigger when scrolling on webtoon mode (Thanks @Zackareee)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed an annoying parse case for 'Giant Ojou-sama - Ch. 33.5 - Volume 04 Bonus Chapter' parsing as 'Giant Ojou-sama - Ch. 33.5' instead of 'Giant Ojou-sama'&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Updated some rendering of tags to not be people tags, like teams&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bug where series-level imprint tags weren't showing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/Kareadita/Kavita/releases/tag/v0.8.2" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/Kareadita/Kavita/releases/tag/v0.8.3</id>
    <title>New release for Kavita: v0.8.3 - The UX Refresh</title>
    <updated>2024-09-18T09:25:09-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Kareadita/Kavita</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;It's finally here, the UX Refresh. Robbie and I have been dreaming and planning this for over a year now and we've grinded for 2 months (with my trip to Norway/Finland between) to bring it to you. The feedback from the nightly testers has been fantastic! Everyone is in love. We have poured over the UX, both on mobile and on desktop, to bring what we think is a consistent and killer experience. We took a lot of inspiration from Plex and if anyone knows, I'm trying to make Kavita the Plex for reading. So let's get into the nitty gritty of what makes this release. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Colorscape&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I browse Plex, I'm always blown away by the accent colors on movie detail pages. Contrast that to Kavita, I felt it was sorely lacking. So I brought it to Kavita and let me tell you, it was no easy feat. Hours wasted on css gradients before realizing the complex system Plex has. Kavita now will show a nice gradient in the background of any page that has a cover (except reading lists and collections, these will likely follow in the future). What's even cooler is the system is able to be turned on/off with a custom theme or even customized by theme creators. This is the feature I'm most proud of with this release. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/25b81beb-1333-4e82-b22f-8f41e3c9c72d" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Individual Pages&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a big thing for Book and Comic users, the ability to view individual volume/chapter metadata. This not only brings dedicated pages (and the ability to update metadata for individual chapters/books), but also the ability to read a series/chapter/volume from any card. No longer do you need to open the series detail page. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/954050d9-184e-46b6-8cbf-1985844aef8d" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Settings Overhaul&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Again taking inspiration from Plex, we updated the settings pages to bring tooltip information front and center and make changes to any field instant (no more pressing save).  All settings, from admin to user preferences, are now on one screen. Some flows have been moved to dedicated pages, like CBL Import or MAL Interest Stack import. This should help with bringing visibility to some of the features Kavita has. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/aa330cb2-ae1b-442a-a109-3c568104e8e8" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Publisher Images&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lastly, we added a new system similar to favicons for publisher images. This new system allows for users to submit or edit publisher images on our &lt;a href="https://github.com/Kareadita/kareadita.github.io?tab=readme-ov-file#publishers"&gt;kavita repo&lt;/a&gt; and these images will be downloaded dynamically and displayed on the detail pages. Some images may not look good. I am counting on the community to add new or edit images to bring the best UX to all users. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/21791599-0956-49fb-b817-f3117e4defba" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All in all, I'm really proud of this release. Next up is an overhaul to the UX surrounding Kavita+ including reworking some of the systems and laying more foundation for future feature releases. I am also working on building out the test cases for the Scanner to allow me to continue working on the elusive Foreign Key constraint issue still plaguing us and working on bringing more optimizations into the Scan Loop to make Kavita faster. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lastly, I want to make a big thank you to those that contribute on Weblate. This release was massive and many localization strings were changed. The localizers were on top of it and as of this release, we are shipping Kavita in 10 languages with full support. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Refresh your browser after updating&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Added&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: Added ability to upload a volume cover for Komf users&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: Added a lot of ability to theme the login screen, including the background image.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: Added ColorScapes. ColorScapes is a new dynamic tinting system for Kavita. During cover generation, Kavita will pick primary colors from the image and apply them to the background on pages where the image is a primary element (series detail for now). These are configurable via the theming system. (Light themes do not look good with this system, it should be disabled)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: Added a new actionable for Library to generate colorscapes (which is a soft refresh covers)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: Library Settings and Edit Series Modal now has a tasks tab that shows appropriate tasks that can be done on the library/series along with information about what the task does.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: Added a Volume/Chapter detail page. From any card you can click and open the detail page.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: Added the ability to directly read a card/volume/series/readinglist from the card or open their details page.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: Added the ability to edit chapter metadata directly within Kavita, lock the fields, This includes Sort order which will allow comic users with unique issue numbers to be ordered on the series detail in any order and the readers will respect it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: Added a new API and UI to allow setting just a volume cover (and locking it). Komf has already updated with support. (Thanks @Snd-R)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: Added the ability to have publisher images (that are managed on Kavita's site, like favicons). There is no extra styling, this is pretty rough but I want to see from users if there is any interest.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: Added a new metadata filter called 'is empty'. This will check against fields like Writers, Tags, Genres, etc to explicitly see if there are no links. (Feature Request)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: .yacreaderlibrary directories will be ignored by the scanner&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: Made it so when a new version of Kavita is released, the UI will automatically refresh and bust locale cache since non-admins can't actually run the bust cache task.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: Admins can now trigger Sync Theme job from Tasks page&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: Added a link to the CBL Repo from CBL Import for those that are unaware of the project&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Changed&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Passwords can now be up to 256 characters long&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Changed some headers, spacing, and positioning to make things more uniform across the app.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Revamped how settings/preferences work in the app. Following Plex' style, they are all on one page (RBS applies) with a dedicated left nav menu that groups based on functionality. (Sorry localizers, lots of string updates)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: When navigating away from library/collection/bookmark/etc-detail, instead of just restoring position when interacting with a jumpkey, Kavita will now restore position down to the location of jump point in all cases.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Jump keys now show an animation instead of a tooltip to show number of series&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Filter icon now shows an animation when actively configuring it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Moved some screens around to dedicated sections and most of Kavita+ screens are now on a new Scrobbling page&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Moved the customize modal into a dedicated settings item to make discovery of the feature easier.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Lots of small consistency issues and QoL tweaks on different pages to bring a better UX and interaction. A lot of functionality has been moved to drive a consistent experience and discovery of features.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Cast and Reviews are in their own tab &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Tabs on Series Detail now report card count&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: All preferences (except those in account) now just save automatically after interaction&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Removed library setting 'Include in Recommendations' as Kavita no longer has those flows&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: On mobile view ports, remove the dropdown button and scroll to top. Dropdown button links are now visible in a modal to make clicking much easier.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Added a customize button on the Side nav when you move into 'More', so you know you can tweak it if you haven't visited settings yet.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Series cards will now show the localized name on hover if present&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Chapter cards will now show the title on hover if present.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Cover Artists is now Artists in the application.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: After selecting a tab, a refresh of the browser will resume you back on the same tab on series/volume/chapter detail pages.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Folder watching is now moved to a separate background thread so it doesn't block startup for users with massive libraries &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: After we update a metadata filter, rescroll to the top as results change&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Cleaned up some registration error output to look nicer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Reorganized edit user modal to better handle users with large amounts of libraries.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: When mass creating libraries, ensure we enqueue the scans. Also don't restart folder watching if folder watching isn't on.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Tweaked some backend code around when we restart library watching and make sure it's always done in a background thread.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Sync Themes job now runs daily instead of weekly&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Lots of small improvements to the UX of theme manager&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Actionable menu (...) on mobile will now load a modal, rather than the normal desktop view. From testing, the menu was easy to misclick on mobile.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Fixed&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed an issue where long passwords would truncate on autofill. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a side-nav css var that was inappropriately assigned. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bug in theme manager where the active pill wouldn't have the correct color for non-dark themes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bug where reading list cards wouldn't promote/unpromote from actionables&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bug where OPDS reading list feeds were missing pagination&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed an edge case where busting Kavita+ cache in edit series then hitting close wasn't refreshing screen.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: A ton of localization changes across the board (Thank you to the Translators for promptly updating language support to 100%)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed a bug where busting locale cache wouldn't refresh the new translations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed some logic around disabling scrobbling on the UI side for library type selections&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bug where pinned smart filters on the side nav would all show an active highlight (Thanks @Fesaa for the help fixing)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bug where there could be a duplicate key in OPDS for some unique configurations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Don't allow users to add series to smart collections &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed CBL Import flow and a bad localization string when the reading list already exists&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: (Kavita+) MAL Interest stacks didn't handle pagination correctly, but now it does. You can now import all your stacks. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed duplicate Dark theme issue&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bug with utc to local time not respecting null date&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bug where user was unable to save manga reader preferences due to a missing field&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Ensure that any smart filter bound to the dashboard load in the correct Context and respect libraries that have opted out of showing on the Dashboard. (FR #3149)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed duplicate Dark theme issue &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bug where user was unable to save manga reader preferences due to a missing field&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Ensure that any smart filter bound to the dashboard load in the correct Context and respect libraries that have opted out of showing on the Dashboard.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed an issue where user rating was using a float (0-1) but users were expecting to put in a percentage given that's always how the UI shows it. Now, Kavita will translate from percentage to float behind the scenes. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed CBL import breaking again due to swagger&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed an issue where a user with no reading progress would throw an exception on loading stats page&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed an issue where after downloading a theme, the theme would be unselected.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed some exceptions being thrown when downloading or fetching themes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed an error when trying to save settings from the manga reader&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bug where the manga reader could prefetch all files in the archive &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a weird state where a book series with a volume 0 and being marked as special would trick series detail into rendering 0 out on card title instead of title.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Theme&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tables are now themeable&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There were a ton of changes and new css variables. Wiki has been updated with extra documentation around colorscape system.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;API&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Updated how resetting cover image field works on the API. All update APIs now accept a LockCover field which will force the lock or not. Defaults to true. Can still reset the cover by passing an empty string and false. In addition, the code is more streamlined to ensure after a reset, a regeneration task is queued.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/Kareadita/Kavita/releases/tag/v0.8.3" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/Kareadita/Kavita/releases/tag/v0.8.3.2</id>
    <title>New release for Kavita: v0.8.3.2 - A Small Hotfix</title>
    <updated>2024-09-20T17:24:03-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Kareadita/Kavita</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;The UX refresh release has been great, a lot of great feedback has come in, along with a few bugs that got missed during testing. I knew there would be some, especially when the new UX was 50K lines of code difference. I picked up as many as I could that didn't require large periods of time for testing. Unless there is anything major that comes, this should be the last hotfix and I will start work on v0.8.4. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Changed&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Instead of showing 'Special' on chapter cards that aren't real, show a dash instead&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Changed how the warning about Email settings and the Test flow worked to be less intrusive&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: (Performance) Small memory improvement when returning reading list items over OPDS&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Changed 'Edit Series Information' tooltip to 'Edit Information' as it's now generic for other entities&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Adjusted the logic for displaying chapter information when the chapter belongs to a single volume. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Fixed&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bug where all chapter cards would always say chapter, instead of issue&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed some edge case styling issues on cards&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed the wording for the edit tooltip to be more generic since used on other pages, not just series&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed Cover Artists still showing instead of Artist in Search&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bug where task settings weren't saving&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bug where when highlighting text in a setting item, the setting would close. Now it will only close if you click outside the item and there is no selection. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed an issue where validators would reject payload when password was over 32 characters &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Genres/Tags margins on details tab wasn't aligned well with People information&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed an issue where Cover Image Size wasn't displaying on the UI&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bug when changing the bookmark directory would throw an error and not function&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a few issues around smart filter loading for base url reverse proxy setups (aka domain.com/kavita) (Thanks @Fesaa for the issue and helping validate the fixes)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/Kareadita/Kavita/releases/tag/v0.8.3.2" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/Kareadita/Kavita/releases/tag/v0.8.4</id>
    <title>New release for Kavita: v0.8.4 - New Scanner + Browse Authors/Artists + Tons of Bugfixes</title>
    <updated>2024-11-22T19:12:26-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Kareadita/Kavita</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;After rewriting 50K lines of code last release, I decided it was best to take a break and focus on the bugs that resulted and a few that had piled up. This release is bug focused, but of course I stuck a few big features in with it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Scanner&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One issue that has been cropping up as we attract more users with larger libraries or libraries laid out in the Publisher/Series style is the scanner. Users with large libraries modify their library quite a bit and the old scanner had issues with change detection. v0.8.3 had quite a nasty bug which required forced library scans to ingest new data. There was also the notorious FK issue that was more common for larger libraries. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To fix these issues, I rewrote the scanner from the ground up to be more reliable. This was a (painful) 3 week effort working closely with a dedicated set of testers on a canary release to be nightly and stable ready. &lt;strong&gt;The new scanner will be slower than the old one.&lt;/strong&gt; As of now, I feel that once the main slow first scan is done, it's actually performing much better. With this new scanner, there were some other major changes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;People Re-architecture&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to reduce the FK issue in the scanner, I also needed to tackle the 80+ hour re-architecture of how people work within Kavita. When I started, with my limited knowledge of the scene or what Kavita would grow to become, I implemented people as tags, much like how ComicInfo does. This is constrained when you want to make people more entity-focused, like having a dedicated page for them. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With this release, you can now view individual details of a person, set a cover and description about the person and see their works and individual issues they worked on. You can also browse authors and artists, like other software has. This is just the start, please leave feedback for me via Feature Requests, so I can build this feature out more and make it a richer experience. &lt;strong&gt;Note: Any Smart Filters that relied on people will need manual intervention to correct. A force scan will be required to regenerate writer information.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/992c5451-08c3-45c5-81ce-4426967d3127" /&gt;
&lt;img alt="image" src="https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/b1a06eb8-ddde-44f6-98c2-98315b252494" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Special Keyword Removal&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last thing with the scanner was removing Kavita's ability to detect and classify certain keywords as Special. Like &lt;code&gt;Omake&lt;/code&gt;  or &lt;code&gt;Annual&lt;/code&gt; would classify a file as a special. While this is extremely handy in the Manga scene, there were numerous reports over the years that required manual workarounds by users. In order to behave more reliably, I opened a discussion this year for removal and made the final call. &lt;strong&gt;Specials going forward will need the SP marker on the filename (or tagged internally).&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;CoversDB&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kavita has had the ability to download and display favicon and publisher images with a fallback repository being hosted on the main Kavita website. In this release, I've moved all that functionality and those images over to a new CoversDB &lt;a href="https://github.com/Kareadita/CoversDB"&gt;repo&lt;/a&gt;. This repo will be the home for anything related to pulling images for Kavita instances. I plan to enhance this further as new features come to Kavita.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Small QoL Features&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Last Read Filter&lt;/strong&gt; is a new feature that allows you to pass a number that will be subtracted from TODAY, upping the dynamic function and allowing users to build Smart Filters like "Haven't read in a month". &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Colorscape Polish&lt;/strong&gt; The colorscape system has been polished even further. I spent a good amount of time adding some randomness, fixed a bug with colorscape resetting between navigation, and tried to tweak where colors go to avoid harsh contrasts. It's not perfect, but it's a step in the right direction. If you're passionate about the colorscape system, I welcome collaboration. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bulk Library Actions&lt;/strong&gt; This is something @DieselTech has been pushing me to add and the time is finally here. For users that have a lot of libraries (like Diesel and his 200+), sometimes it's quite a pain to update the settings of them all or perform some actions. Now in Kavita there are some limited bulk options, like refreshing covers or copying settings from one library to another (Scan currently disabled). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/2517e6f1-4548-4d30-ae23-17dc80688771" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Recap&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This release has been a ton of work on my part, but I felt it was important to squash the bugs first and ensure Kavita remains stable while I continue to add more features and bring a richer experience to users. My next release is still aimed at finishing the UX Overhaul with attention on Kavita+. With the holidays coming up, it is expected that this will take longer than most releases. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For those that have seen, we have hit over 65K active installs. It's absolutely amazing that a small project I started due to Ubooquity not having metadata has turned into such a massive project with a huge userbase. I want to give my thanks again to those in the community that have raised bugs, feature requests, give support in the discord/reddit, those who give me donations via OC/Kavita+, the translators, and of course my wife that helps support me pouring so much time into the project. &lt;strong&gt;I'm excited to continue building Kavita and bring about more of our visions into the software and see what is possible.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;People metadata will be removed on update. A force scan is required to repopulate in the new system. A force scan/first scan will be much slower than before.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Added&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: Manage Libraries now has bulk actions. You can trigger multiple scans (not file scans, but refresh covers or colorscapes, etc) or copy settings from one library to multiple. Shift+select works as well.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: Added a new page for all People within Kavita. From this page, you can see their works across Kavita.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: Ability to see individual chapters/issues (limited to 20) a person has.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: Ability to add images to the person via UI/API. A more automated method is planned in the future.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: Added the ability to browse all Writers and Artists (cover artist) in one page. This should help book users that like to browse by author. (Feature Request: #2556 - 23 votes) (Thanks @MrRobotjs for some css on the Person detail page)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: Added the ability to trigger the general cleanup (which normally runs at midnight) manually in case you need to clear unlinked people, covers, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: Reading List and Collection cards now show a badge showing the number of series/items underneath.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: New Filter option called Last Read which allows a number to be passed in and will dynamically calculate a date from TODAY() matched against reading time. This allows for users to build even more dynamic smart filters to find things not read in a month or read within the past 7 days.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: Added back a lot of the metadata that had to be removed from the top of the series detail page in the UX overhaul, like Language, Release Year, Format, and Reading Time &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: Added Details tab to volume details page&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: (Kavita+) New Sync Details button on smart collections that shows an easier to digest view of Series and missing series.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: Bulk send to is now available for chapters/volumes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: Added bulk deletion for chapters/volumes &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Changed&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Optimized a number of methods within the Scanner to reduce memory and CPU time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Moved a lot of the chapter scanner logging to Trace.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Scanner can now choose to parallel parse files when there are over 100 in a directory&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Changed how detection and scanning of dirty directories works. The scanner will now parse bottom-up to reduce any potential misses and avoid different layouts working differently. This has extra I/O checks but much greater reliability and should reduce the amount of work needed to ingest changes after the first scan.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: LocalizedSeries merging with Series is now done at a higher level and performs much better (in terms of reliability)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: People are now entity based which allows for a richer experience in Kavita.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Clicking on any person in Kavita will now open their dedicated page which showcases their different works.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: (Performance) Some large refactors to the scanner to help with the FK bug. The scanner should be slower but consume much less memory, especially for well tagged systems.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Kavita no longer parses keywords from filenames and groups as a Special. The way to mark a special going forward will be explicitly with SP01, SP02, etc. Specials can be flat in the series folder or ideally in Specials/ folder. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Changed logging level on some of the loggers that could become noisy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Refactored some of the post-series work to a separate thread.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Ensure mobile actionable modal is fullscreen and centered vertically&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Update to Angular 18 and other backend dependencies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: When a setting is invalid, clicking outside the setting item will not close and edit is disabled.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Changed the smart filters page to open in the same window (but still available to open in new tab)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: (Performance) Made the pipe that turns the language codes into full names use a dedicated API which is faster&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Improved the wording for Single Volume chapters on Series detail page (and person detail page)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Kavita now uses a different repo for publisher images and favicons (https://github.com/Kareadita/CoversDB). Any changes should be made here.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: You can now edit the person name in the UI. If not corrected in the metadata, a duplicate person will be created. This will be tweaked in the future once Alias support is added.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Significantly improved the feel of the colorscape experience. When transitioning between colorscapes, locations of accent points will randomize. Lighter colors will try to avoid the bottom right where there could be bad contrast.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Changed Colorscape to use non-linear animation for transitioning between 2 colorscapes. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: If the user somehow wrote bad cron notation for custom jobs, on startup, Kavita will detect and default to daily&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Changed the overall look and feel of the preference side nav and main side nav (Thanks @MrRobotjs)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Moved Test email settings to the top to align with the UX patterns&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Moved Reset to Defaults to the top to align with UX patterns and removed a few instances since it resets everything.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Changed a lot of modals to be more consistent in how they open and their size to be slightly larger.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: When failing to get a page count on an archive, report it in media issues&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Improved memory consumption on some filtering conditions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Tweaked some logging messages to be more clear when using logs to debug&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Fixed&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bug where the UnauthorizedAccessException is not correctly ignored when using the docker container as non-root. (Thanks @Fesaa)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bug where any media that was less than an hour in length wouldn't be included in stats. This requires Analyze Files to be ran on all libraries to retroactively fix&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bug where chapter order wasn't properly sorting on Volume Detail page&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed an issue where bookmarking wouldn't check if the source file was already in the target encoding and thus had issue when trying to convert. Also added another check to not do anything if target encoding is PNG (aka Kavita doesn't convert webp -&amp;gt; png). &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bug where Series Cover image could choose a Volume 0 instead of Volume 1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bug where teams and locations wouldn't trigger updating people on update series metadata api&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bug where calculating the Lowest Folder for a Series could be incorrect when there are nested folders. This includes a migration to clear out existing entries to avoid scan series not seeing files.
Example:
/ &amp;lt;- Lib root assume
/love hina/love hina/v01.cbz
/love hina/specials/sp01.cbz
The lowest series folder was /love hina/love hina/ for some reason, meaning series scan wasn't getting the full series (all folders) scanned in.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed up a check for using lowest folder path to lookup from a Folder Watcher task. This should find series much better from a lower file path.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bug where teams and locations wouldn't trigger updating people on update series metadata api&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bug where users could change their age rating when they didn't have the permission&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bug where download wasn't functioning from the on deck cards&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a typo on the localization string for Create Multiple Reading List/Collection pages&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed Promote/Unpromote not working from reading list detail page and collection detail page &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Ensure we show details page when weblinks are present, including chapter detail page&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed related tab not having enough bottom padding &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a few different combinations where IsEmpty was not working &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed broken Send To on mobile and Send To not actually functioning for chapter/volume cards.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Tweaked read-time-left pipe to have better control on how we present the now decimal number.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bug where continue from was choosing ch instead of vol &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed read-more text not displaying newlines correctly in some situations (Thanks @Fesaa)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed the search bar closing when toggling show chapters and files toggle (Thanks @Fesaa)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bug where validation wasn't showing on Hostname &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Next expected card had layout issues and missing localization&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Don't close a modal when a typeahead is open and pressing Escape key&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed tooltips not rendering on some cards, like reading list/collection cards&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a missing case to show storyline tab on Light Novel libraries when users use chapters (not common) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Ensure the edit series modal is showing the localized publication status &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Updated a lot of missing localization keys&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed the fade between colorscape so there isn't a reset to default anymore&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed an issue with how specials render on reading list detail page &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed the duplicate Dark theme issue once and for all&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed custom tasks not being possible &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed Irish not working when selected as locale &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed edit chapter modal failing to save when setting Age Rating &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bug where when a card doesn't have a format, 22px was still beating taken up. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Ensure More In Genre doesn't choose from a Genre that's not exposed to the dashboard&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bug where bulk mode on customize side nav wasn't laying out the bulk update well. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed delete chapter not being hooked up from Volume details page &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed user rating filter not working at all. It was accepting a percentage, but should have been a number 0-5 for the star rating. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed the bulk actions bar laying out in the wrong position&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: In the rare occasion someone turns off all the file types for a library, the scanner will now respect that.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed Delete and Analyze Files on the library detail actionables not being hooked up&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed an issue with doujin filenames causing series to all parse as ( &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: (Kavita+) Fixed a bug where old Book libraries could be stuck in Scrobbling On state&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed age rating icon not updating upon series metadata changes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Ensure Jumpkeys are grouped non-case sensitive&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bug where want to read page was using a custom query passed through the filtering pipeline, thus breaking some combos.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bug where manage email settings was spamming the backend due to an infinite loop&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed select all on edit user modal affecting the role/library control as well.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: On Age Rating filter, the comparisons could be duplicated&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bug with bulk selection not pruning submenu actions when there are no children left. (aka empty send to)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;API&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Search now returns a list of PersonDto instead of strings for People results.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Removed metadata/chapter-summary api since it hasn't been used in years&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Theme&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Side nav selected tab now uses --side-nav-item-active-text-color on the text instead of just being white&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added --side-nav-width variable to control side nav bar width&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added --navbar-header-margin, set it to 8px and --nav-offset to 56px to get the Plex floating navbar.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added --navbar-border-radius to fix the navbar but let users customize for that Plex look.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added --navbar-header-mobile-x-margin and --navbar-header-mobile-y-margin to allow for the Plex navbar on mobile&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Known Issues&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(Kavita+) MAL Stack imports/Smart Collection total series count is not correct. This will be fixed with v0.8.5. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Uploading some dimensions for person cover can cause the image to be squished. This will be fixed with v0.8.5.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When using multiple reading progress filters, some series with 100% reading progress will show (clicking On Deck). After 14 hours, I can't solve it. I will loop around in v0.8.5.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/Kareadita/Kavita/releases/tag/v0.8.4" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/Kareadita/Kavita/releases/tag/v0.8.4.2</id>
    <title>New release for Kavita: v0.8.4.2 - Hotfix + Migration Script</title>
    <updated>2024-11-27T15:11:39-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Kareadita/Kavita</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;A few small things slipped past. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to take this space to first apologize to our users that manually tag their metadata in Kavita. Post release has been an eye opener to the different ways uses of Kavita and a lesson learned to work harder to preserve data between releases. I always try, but sometimes big lift and shifts like this are needed and aren't easy to preserve data. I will take it on myself to strive for excellence and do what is feasible to preserve data. I don't foresee many major refactors like this happening in the near future. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On more positive news, MetronInfo.xml has become stabilized. This is a step towards advancing the metadata format for Comics and Manga (and potentially books in the future). I have worked closely with Brian (the creator) to include Manga into the format. Kavita is dedicated towards supporting the format, that work is planned for next year. Read up more about it &lt;a href="https://metron-project.github.io/blog/metroninfo-v1"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have a lot of metadata that was tagged just via the UI, you can try this &lt;a href="https://pastebin.com/RPmfSSYq"&gt;script&lt;/a&gt; a user wrote to migrate the data. Grab a backup from v0.8.3 and run this against it. You need to update &lt;code&gt;oldDb&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;newDb&lt;/code&gt;. I cannot offer support for this script. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did convert this to python via ChatGPT and added instructions, it will be much easier but I did not test it. You can find the script &lt;a href="https://pastebin.com/BR0GxaXB"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Fixed&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Send to on mobile was still broken&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Changed On Deck to use a workaround as a temp fix&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bug where on non-English locales parsing numbers would throw an exception and cause files to not be ingested. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Bulk library delete wasn't hooked up&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Fixed a bug where updating chapter metadata with a new person, the normalized name was saved&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Potentially fixed a bug where adding multiple people on a series via UI will throw an exception (Was not able to reproduce, but added extra safety logic)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/Kareadita/Kavita/releases/tag/v0.8.4.2" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
