<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://selfh.st/apps</id>
  <title>Koel Releases</title>
  <updated>2025-06-28T02:36:14.374336-04:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>selfh.st</name>
    <email>contact@selfh.st</email>
  </author>
  <link href="https://selfh.st/apps" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>Self-hosted software releases generated by selfh.st</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/koel/koel/releases/tag/v7.5.1</id>
    <title>New release for Koel: v7.5.1</title>
    <updated>2025-05-28T12:12:29-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>koel/koel</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;removed a debug call hehe&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/koel/koel/releases/tag/v7.5.1" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/koel/koel/releases/tag/v7.5.2</id>
    <title>New release for Koel: v7.5.2</title>
    <updated>2025-06-01T18:49:19-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>koel/koel</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h2&gt;What's Changed&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feat: separate states between playlists by @phanan in https://github.com/koel/koel/pull/1935&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Full Changelog&lt;/strong&gt;: https://github.com/koel/koel/compare/v7.5.1...v7.5.2&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/koel/koel/releases/tag/v7.5.2" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/koel/koel/releases/tag/v7.6.1</id>
    <title>New release for Koel: v7.6.1</title>
    <updated>2025-06-23T08:38:48-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>koel/koel</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h1&gt;v7.6.1&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[!NOTE]&lt;br /&gt;
There was never a v7.6.0 because my dumb ass screwed it up as always. Sorry!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[!CAUTION]
Though a minor version, v7.6.1 brings some breaking changes (SemVer? What's SemVer?), so please &lt;strong&gt;read this release note carefully&lt;/strong&gt; before attempting an upgrade.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This new version of Koel comes with these improvements and changes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Most importantly, the media scanner received the biggest overhaul since the project's conception. As a result: &lt;strong&gt;Koel now supports perhaps every music format you've heard of&lt;/strong&gt;, both lossy and lossless — I'm talking about mp3 (duh), mp4, m4a, aac, ogg, flac, aiff, ape, wma, wav, opus, ra, ac3, dts… Admittedly, I've not tested them all myself, but in theory, since &lt;a href="https://www.getid3.org/"&gt;getId3&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://ffmpeg.org/"&gt;FFmpeg&lt;/a&gt; do all the hard work, I don't even have to. Of course, if you want to stream those lossless files, make sure &lt;a href="https://docs.koel.dev/usage/streaming#transcoding"&gt;FFmpeg is installed and configured&lt;/a&gt;, you audiophile.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The second biggest improvement is in how Koel handles lossless streaming (transcoding). &lt;strong&gt;The functionality has been completely rewritten to support all storage drivers (local, SFTP, S3, and Dropbox)&lt;/strong&gt;, as opposed to only local as before. Now, for example, if you're using S3 as your storage driver, a transcoded version will be generated on the fly and cached for subsequent plays.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now to think about it, why am I tagging a minor version? This should be some major shit goddamnit. Anyways…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An &lt;code&gt;ARTIFACTS_PATH&lt;/code&gt; .env config has been added. This is the local path to store artifacts like local transcodes, temporarily downloaded and uploaded files, etc. This is useful, for example, if you have a mounted disk and want to use it instead of relying on the app server's tmp directory.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The concepts of the playlist owner and collaborators are now consolidated (#1938). TL;DR: Better database design, more open for future functionalities.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Album/artist info views now display loading skeletons during, well, loading (6a8959cebe18208ec0cc32e7fa5055c7872c8fec)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The play button on the artist/album thumbnail in the sidesheet (you know, where the lyrics and stuff are) is restored. It was gone due to some smartass "mobile-first" code (d6bb32cf9631cf08baedbb62a6a859867652244d)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use public ID for users, albums, and artists.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The content of the sidesheet (you know, where the lyrics and stuff are) is now lazy-loaded (77d0b27bbdc524cbffb030d0a7463e459ca3070f). Meaning, a request is only made now if you activate the corresponding tab (Album Info, Artist Info, YouTube…)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can now toggle and sort by Genre and Year columns, too (e43dfd1d250fa8e14041a771275d660289dbf95a)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Last but not least, Laravel's been upgraded to version 11 to make use of new features and mitigate all security issues.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Upgrade&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[!IMPORTANT]
Since Laravel 11 requires PHP &amp;gt;= 8.2, make sure your PHP version meets this prerequisite before upgrading.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Back up your database. I know, I sound like a broken record now, but this version comes with a few database changes, so you want to do it, trust me.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Back up your database again. You can't be too careful, can you?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Check out v7.6.1 tag or extract the downloaded archive. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If installing from source, run &lt;code&gt;composer install&lt;/code&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Run &lt;code&gt;php artisan koel:init&lt;/code&gt; as the webserver user. Note: &lt;strong&gt;The database migration step may take a while&lt;/strong&gt; as Koel will have to do some magic moves behind the scene. Be patient!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If every goes well, enjoy the shiny v7.6.1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;"Oh shoot" you say?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Look at &lt;code&gt;storge/logs/laravel.log&lt;/code&gt; to hopefully find out what went wrong and fix it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If all hope is lost: restore the database, restore the files, etc., you know the drill, and &lt;a href="https://github.com/koel/koel/issues/new?template=1-bug-report.yml"&gt;let me know&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/koel/koel/releases/tag/v7.6.1" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/koel/koel/releases/tag/v7.6.2</id>
    <title>New release for Koel: v7.6.2</title>
    <updated>2025-06-23T11:28:57-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>koel/koel</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;What's a new release without some bugs?&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/koel/koel/releases/tag/v7.6.2" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/koel/koel/releases/tag/v7.6.3</id>
    <title>New release for Koel: v7.6.3</title>
    <updated>2025-06-25T03:40:22-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>koel/koel</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;This version fixes an issue with MySQL migration (#1969).&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/koel/koel/releases/tag/v7.6.3" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
