<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://selfh.st/apps</id>
  <title>Komodo Releases</title>
  <updated>2025-08-02T04:33:46.387552-04:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>selfh.st</name>
    <email>contact@selfh.st</email>
  </author>
  <link href="https://selfh.st/apps" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>Self-hosted software releases generated by selfh.st</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/moghtech/komodo/releases/tag/v1.18.0</id>
    <title>New release for Komodo: Komodo v1.18.0</title>
    <updated>2025-05-30T16:12:54-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>moghtech/komodo</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h1&gt;Changelog&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🚨 This release moves &lt;strong&gt;official support to FerretDB v2&lt;/strong&gt;. Users who deployed v1.17.5 or before using Postgres / Sqlite option are using FerretDB v1 and should &lt;strong&gt;eventually&lt;/strong&gt; migrate using the &lt;a href="https://github.com/moghtech/komodo/blob/main/bin/util/docs/copy-database.md#ferretdb-v2-update-guide"&gt;FerretDB v2 Update Guide&lt;/a&gt;. Note that this is &lt;strong&gt;not a change to Komodo itself&lt;/strong&gt;, only to the list of supported Mongo stand-ins. Users can update to 1.18.0 and continue to use FerretDB v1 if they wish.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🚨 Admins managing user permissions may need to modify the user access rules. In particular, &lt;strong&gt;container logs&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;docker inspect&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; on containers, and &lt;strong&gt;terminal access&lt;/strong&gt; are now gated behind additional permissions (for non admin users).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Specific Permissions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main purpose of this release is to refine the access control / permissions system in Komodo. In 1.17.5 and before, access to resources was controlled only via access level (&lt;code&gt;Read&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;Execute&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;Write&lt;/code&gt;). These levels provide access to the associated &lt;code&gt;/read&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;/execute&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code&gt;/write&lt;/code&gt; methods on resources, and it worked pretty well to provide RBAC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now with more potentially sensitive features, this is not quite enough to provide granular access control. To address this, &lt;code&gt;specific&lt;/code&gt; permissions have been introduced &lt;em&gt;in addition&lt;/em&gt; to &lt;code&gt;Read&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;Execute&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code&gt;Write&lt;/code&gt; levels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;Logs&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: User can retrieve docker / docker compose logs on the associated resource.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Valid on &lt;code&gt;Server&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;Stack&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;Deployment&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For admins wanting this permission by default for all users with read permissions, see below on default user groups.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;Inspect&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;:  User can "inspect" docker containers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Valid on &lt;code&gt;Server&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;Stack&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;Deployment&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;On Servers&lt;/strong&gt;: Access to this api will expose all container environments on the given server,
  and can easily lead to secrets being leaked to unintended users if not protected.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;Terminal&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: User can access the associated resource's terminal.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If given on a &lt;code&gt;Server&lt;/code&gt;, this allows server level terminal access, and all container exec priviledges (Including attached &lt;code&gt;Stacks&lt;/code&gt; / &lt;code&gt;Deployments&lt;/code&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If given on a &lt;code&gt;Stack&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;Deployment&lt;/code&gt;, this allows container exec terminal (even without &lt;code&gt;Terminal&lt;/code&gt; on &lt;code&gt;Server&lt;/code&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;Attach&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: User can "attach" &lt;em&gt;other resources&lt;/em&gt; to the resource.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If given on a &lt;code&gt;Server&lt;/code&gt;, allows users to attach &lt;code&gt;Stacks&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;Deployments&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;Repos&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code&gt;Builders&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If given on &lt;code&gt;Build&lt;/code&gt;, allows users to attach the Build to Deployments&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If given on a &lt;code&gt;Builder&lt;/code&gt;, allows users to attach &lt;code&gt;Builds&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;Processes&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: User can retrieve the full running process list on the &lt;code&gt;Server&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The above &lt;code&gt;specific&lt;/code&gt; permissions are defined in a list alongside their &lt;code&gt;level&lt;/code&gt;. This list is open for future expansion / and the associated implementations may be refined in future releases as well. The list is also given here: https://komo.do/docs/permissioning#specific-permissions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Default User Groups&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes you will want to set a "baseline" set of permissions that all users will have on the Komodo instance. Previously this could only be done in very barebones way, by setting &lt;code&gt;KOMODO_TRANSPARENT_MODE=true&lt;/code&gt; on the Komodo Core container. This would give all users a base level of "Read" on all resources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to the above permissions features, this release also adds an &lt;code&gt;everyone&lt;/code&gt; mode to User Groups. If you enable this mode on a User Group, then all users will inherit those permissions as a base.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;TOML Examples&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As before, you are able to manage User Groups in Resource Syncs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;```toml&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Can define default rules in the Everyone group&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[[user_group]]
name = "Everyone"
everyone = true
 # Can see servers, but no Logs / Inspect / Terminal permission
all.Server = "Read"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;This doesn't elevate specific stacks from None permissions,&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;but if the user gets greater than Read from another permission,&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;they will inherit the specific permissions&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;all.Stack = { level = "None", specific = ["Inspect", "Logs", "Terminal"] }
all.Deployment = { level = "None", specific = ["Inspect", "Logs", "Terminal"] }&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Allow users to see all Builders, and attach builds to them.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;all.Builder = { level = "Read", specific = ["Attach"] }&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[[user_group]]
name = "Stack Read"
users = ["user1", "user2"]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Because of the "Everyone" group, don't need to redefine&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;the specific permissions. User will have "Inspect", "Logs", etc.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;all.Stack = "Read"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[[user_group]]
name = "Immich Manager"
users = ["user1", "user2"]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Give per-service management to select users&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;permissions = [
  { target.type = "Server", target.id = "immich-server", level = "Write", specific = ["Logs", "Inspect", "Terminal"] },
  { target.type = "Stack", target.id = "immich", level = "Write"  }
]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[[user_group]]
name = "Dev Manager"
users = ["user1", "user2"]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Manage wildcard access to specific resources, in this case with the &lt;code&gt;dev-&lt;/code&gt; name prefix.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Note. Doesn't work with Sync "Commit". Only "Execute" direction.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;permissions = [
  { target.type = "Server", target.id = "dev-&lt;em&gt;", level = "Read" },
  { target.type = "Deployment", target.id = "dev-&lt;/em&gt;", level = "Write"  },
  { target.type = "Build", target.id = "dev-*", level = "Write"  },
]
```&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Misc.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Server&lt;/strong&gt;: Remove limitations on &lt;strong&gt;name&lt;/strong&gt;. Names can now include Capital letters and spaces. They still have to be unique.&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Also can use any name for &lt;strong&gt;Procedures&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Actions&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Resource Syncs&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Builders&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Alerters&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stacks / Deployments / Builds / Repos &lt;strong&gt;still have the same naming restrictions&lt;/strong&gt; (no capitals / spaces)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Alerter&lt;/strong&gt;: Ntfy endpoints now support configuring email. Note that you must also make sure SMTP is configured on the Ntfy server. By @FelixBreitweiser in #493 &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Resource Sync&lt;/strong&gt;: Fix issue with User Groups showing "Pending" repeatedly / eroneously.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;UI&lt;/strong&gt;: Fix the inline rename behavior when renaming multiple resources in a row.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Startup log&lt;/strong&gt;: Specify &lt;code&gt;pretty_startup_config = true&lt;/code&gt; to get more human readable initial config log.&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Core Env: &lt;code&gt;KOMODO_PRETTY_STARTUP_CONFIG=true&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Periphery Env: &lt;code&gt;PERIPHERY_PRETTY_STARTUP_CONFIG=true&lt;/code&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Screenshot 2025-05-30 at 12 25 55 PM" src="https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/c05dbb81-3db6-4a90-bb4b-f86bf8fcadb8" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/moghtech/komodo/releases/tag/v1.18.0" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/moghtech/komodo/releases/tag/v1.18.1</id>
    <title>New release for Komodo: Komodo v1.18.1</title>
    <updated>2025-06-07T02:25:20-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>moghtech/komodo</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h1&gt;Changelog&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Schedules Page&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added a dedicated &lt;strong&gt;Schedules page&lt;/strong&gt; to provide an overview of all your scheduled actions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Server Alerting&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Server health alerts will now only be opened after &lt;strong&gt;2 consecutive out-of-bounds conditions&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This helps a lot to reduce noise, like intermittent unreachable alerts and short CPU usage spikes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you turned off alerts to reduce noise, you can try turning them back on and see how it is now.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Commits&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Commits made by Komodo &lt;strong&gt;no longer use &lt;code&gt;--force&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; in the push command.&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This should prevent any more issues like #501&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you run into issues pushing, it depends on the resource type.&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For Stacks, can temporarily enable the Reclone option, and Deploy. Afterwards can try commit again.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For Syncs / Builds, you should be able to use the refresh button in header and try again. Otherwise you can recreate the repo cache volume.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Resources&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stack / Build / Repo / Sync&lt;/strong&gt;: Add &lt;strong&gt;url links&lt;/strong&gt; for attached repos in the resource headers / tables.&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Github only&lt;/strong&gt;: links to correct branch&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stack / Deployment&lt;/strong&gt;: Add dedicated "Deploying" state to improve the feedback&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Server&lt;/strong&gt;: Add Core / Periphery version mismatch indicator&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Repo&lt;/strong&gt;: Fix "On Pull" command during &lt;code&gt;PullRepo&lt;/code&gt; operation re #580 &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stack&lt;/strong&gt;: Run "Pre Deploy" command &lt;em&gt;before&lt;/em&gt; &lt;code&gt;docker compose config&lt;/code&gt; in #584 by @undaunt &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Allows for easier integrations re #324&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;UI&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clean up headers / quick links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improve frontend loading time re dependency loading&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Move &lt;strong&gt;Builders / Alerters out of sidebar&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;into settings&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width="1649" alt="Screenshot 2025-06-06 at 11 03 54 PM" src="https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/35e7734f-f467-4c52-88f0-bc1cb986988f" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/moghtech/komodo/releases/tag/v1.18.1" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/moghtech/komodo/releases/tag/v1.18.2</id>
    <title>New release for Komodo: Komodo v1.18.2</title>
    <updated>2025-06-15T20:02:01-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>moghtech/komodo</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h1&gt;Changelog&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The two main features of this release are &lt;strong&gt;Linked Repos&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Alert Maintenance Windows&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Repo Linking&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Repo linking, this means you can link Repos that you configure once in Komodo to &lt;em&gt;multiple resources&lt;/em&gt;. This avoids having to configure your repo provider, name, and account multiple times (you can just select it in the dropdown), and also keeps things in sync if you change the underlying repo provider, name, branch, or account. This is available on all Resources that use git repos (&lt;code&gt;Stacks&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;Builds&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code&gt;Resource Syncs&lt;/code&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Stacks, this means that multiple Stacks attached to the same Repo will &lt;strong&gt;share the same repo clone on individual hosts&lt;/strong&gt;. You can migrate your Stacks to used the linked Repo in place, just note that it won't deal with any data mounted inside the clone folders. Those would need to be moved to the new Repo clone path (as specified in the Repo config). Ideally all your data mounts are outside of the repo. Config files which are committed inside the repo are fine to keep mounted in using relative path however.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note that you can but don't need to attach a Server / Builder to the Repo. If you do configure an attachment on the Repo, the Repo can still be attached to eg Stacks on other Servers. The Repo server / builder attachments aren't considered by Resources depending on the Repo. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Alert Maintenance Windows&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These allow you to configure time periods to suppress alerts when downtime is expected, such as for system updates. You can schedule either Daily, Weekly, or One Time maintenance windows, and configure them on individual &lt;code&gt;Servers&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;Alerters&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Resource&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Server&lt;/strong&gt;: Add docker lists search re #548 &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Server&lt;/strong&gt;: Add Periphery version indicator to Server tables&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Deployment / All containers&lt;/strong&gt;: Support capitals and &lt;code&gt;.&lt;/code&gt; in the names re #563 &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Actions&lt;/strong&gt;: Add &lt;code&gt;komodo.execute_container_exec&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;komodo.execute_deployment_exec&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;komodo.execute_stack_exec&lt;/code&gt; methods&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Similar to &lt;code&gt;komodo.execute_terminal&lt;/code&gt;, but set up to connect directly to container exec&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Only requires &lt;code&gt;disable_container_exec = false&lt;/code&gt; in Periphery config. Direct terminals can be disabled.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stack, Build, Resource Sync&lt;/strong&gt;: Can now link &lt;strong&gt;Komodo Repos&lt;/strong&gt; (in the sidebar) directly to these resources&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stacks&lt;/strong&gt;: Have them share a single repo clone on your hosts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Don't&lt;/em&gt; need to attach Repo to any Server / Builder, but you can if you would like, to manually pull / reclone.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note&lt;/em&gt;: Non admin users need &lt;code&gt;Attach&lt;/code&gt; permission on the Repo to be able to link Resources to it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Server / Alerter&lt;/strong&gt;: Add per-server and per-alerter maintenance window configuration to suppress alerts during planned time periods. #550 by @R3D2 and @mbecker20 &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Misc&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Failed OIDC provider initialization just error logs, doesn't crash core. Can still login with other providers. Re. #567 &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;OIDC login gets username using the standard &lt;code&gt;userinfo&lt;/code&gt; endpoint, instead of token claims. Does not affect already created users in Komodo, only new users. Re. #557 &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/moghtech/komodo/releases/tag/v1.18.2" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/moghtech/komodo/releases/tag/v1.18.3</id>
    <title>New release for Komodo: Komodo v1.18.3</title>
    <updated>2025-06-16T03:03:46-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>moghtech/komodo</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h1&gt;Changelog&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Quick fix for an issue found shortly after releasing 1.18.2&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Builds were failing when after changing the repo branch due to change in 1.18.2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This adds a &lt;code&gt;git fetch&lt;/code&gt; call before the branch checkout to make sure all latest remote branches are known, fixing the issue.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;User Group: Allow admin to add &lt;code&gt;Attach&lt;/code&gt; permission to Repo / Build from the UI &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/moghtech/komodo/releases/tag/v1.18.3" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/moghtech/komodo/releases/tag/v1.18.4</id>
    <title>New release for Komodo: Komodo v1.18.4</title>
    <updated>2025-06-24T20:06:56-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>moghtech/komodo</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h1&gt;Changelog&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This release includes support for two repeatedly requested features.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are also changes to the Periphery agent, remember to update both Core and Periphery to 1.18.4 so everything works correctly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Template support&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Resources can now be &lt;strong&gt;marked as templates&lt;/strong&gt;, and they will be suggested as a the starting point when creating a new resource. You can control the inclusion of templates in the tables, and you can control the template inclusion behavior in the ListResources apis. The behavior is similar to the Gitea repo templates feature. This allows you to configure multiple "defaults" to use as starting points when creating more Resources like Stacks, satisfying requests such as #579.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Container port display / link&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If a container defines port mappings, the host ports used will now be displayed in the container tables, as well as the container headers, Stack service tables / headers, and Deployment headers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hovering over the port will reveal additional information about the port binding, such as which network interfaces / protocols are involved. Clicking on the port will link to &lt;code&gt;$server_address:$port&lt;/code&gt;, using the server address which Core uses to connect to the server.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Resource&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stack / Build&lt;/strong&gt;: When using a Linked Repo, will now correctly write the environment configured on Repo, and also run Repo On Clone / On Pull commands. Interpolation is now correctly applied.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Server&lt;/strong&gt;: The Server Stats tab now displays current Docker container stats table.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Misc&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Includes pretty extensive refactors standardizing interpolation and log sanitization, making the code simpler and avoiding errors and inconsistencies.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Refactored internal git library and usage, separating out library level handling of environment / on clone / on pull execution out for more modular implementation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix &lt;code&gt;/GetUser&lt;/code&gt; endpoint spam on token expiry in #618 by @huzky-v &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/moghtech/komodo/releases/tag/v1.18.4" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
