<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://selfh.st/apps</id>
  <title>LANCommander Releases</title>
  <updated>2025-01-09T17:32:51.639293-05:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>selfh.st</name>
    <email>contact@selfh.st</email>
  </author>
  <link href="https://selfh.st/apps" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>Self-hosted software releases generated by selfh.st</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/LANCommander/LANCommander/releases/tag/v1.0.0</id>
    <title>New release for LANCommander: v1.0.0</title>
    <updated>2024-09-28T04:54:56-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>LANCommander/LANCommander</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h1&gt;Server&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: The "Archives" side menu option when editing a game has been moved towards the top&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Key allocation method (MAC address or user) can now be changed per-game, default value is user account&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: The underlying log engine has been swapped out and logging should be overall improved across the board&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: A new section called "Issues" can be used to track submitted issues with games&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: .ico files can now be uploaded as media&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: A new micro-CMS has been added and is available under "Pages"&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: User profiles can now contain custom fields that may be used in scripts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: User information can now be edited by administrators&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: Mods/expansions will now show nested under their base game in the main games list&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: A count of games that require a redistributable has now been added as a column in the redistributable list&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: Games that require a redistributable can now be selected in bulk when editing the redistributable&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: An issue that was affecting some games to not return any search results for media has been fixed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Titles when editing a game, server, or redistributable are now correct&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Mods/expansions with no base game set will now show in the main games list instead of being hidden away&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Removed: A hidden wiki functionality has been removed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Launcher&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: An issue where some metadata such as collections and genres was being improperly cached has been fixed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Name change scripts now run properly if &lt;code&gt;$NewPlayerAlias&lt;/code&gt; is equal to &lt;code&gt;$OldPlayerAlias&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: PowerShell scripts now execute in a bundled runtime. This should remove the requirement to set the ExecutionPolicy option in PowerShell in order for scripts to execute correctly&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Overall release size should be improved&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: The logging engine has been swapped out and should result in better logs across the board&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: When enabled in settings, debug mode now provides an in-app PowerShell terminal&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: A CLI interface has been added to the launcher with some basic verbs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: A "Report Issue" button has been added to report issues with a game back to the server&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: Games that use Steamworks lobbies will show extra actions in the action dialog if any lobbies are open. More documentation and details will be available in documentation soon&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: Multiple install locations can now be specified&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: A new "Discovered Servers" UI element has been added to the authentication form&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: Users can now register with a server directly from the launcher&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: The launcher's window position will now be retained between runs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Documentation&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Documentation has been revamped now lives over at:
https://docs.lancommander.app/&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Breaking Changes&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Detect install scripts for redistributables have been slightly reworked and thus has introduced a breaking change where you will need to update these scripts. Where an exit code was previously supplied, now the variable &lt;code&gt;$Return&lt;/code&gt; must be set. See the &lt;a href="https://docs.lancommander.app/en/Scripting/DetectInstallScripts"&gt;documentation&lt;/a&gt; for more details.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Full Changelog&lt;/strong&gt;: https://github.com/LANCommander/LANCommander/compare/v0.9.1...v1.0.0&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/LANCommander/LANCommander/releases/tag/v1.0.0" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/LANCommander/LANCommander/releases/tag/v1.0.1</id>
    <title>New release for LANCommander: v1.0.1</title>
    <updated>2024-10-04T02:01:15-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>LANCommander/LANCommander</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h1&gt;Server&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: Archives can now be uploaded via REST API&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: Redistributables and servers can now be exported/imported via REST API&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: /app permissions in Docker by @miketweaver (#95)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: New pages now get deleted properly (#113)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Page slug editor properly updates on save (#113)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Issue deletion popover no longer says redistributables (#116)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Issue add form now loads properly (#117)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: PCGamingWiki scraper for multiplayer modes no longer crashes metadata lookup (#119)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Dashboard now uses dark theme for charts in dark mode (#118)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: The autoupdater in this release should work as expected&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Slimmed the download a bit more&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Launcher&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: Uninstall scripts can now be called from the debug menu&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Removed media is now deleted on import (#114)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: Archives can now be uploaded via CLI&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: Redistributables and servers can now be exported/imported via CLI&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: The autoupdater in this release should work as expected&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Slimmed the download a bit more&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Autoupdater Issues&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note that in the last release there was an issue with how the autoupdating functionality worked. Any non-Docker users will have to update their install manually.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Full Changelog&lt;/strong&gt;: https://github.com/LANCommander/LANCommander/compare/v1.0.0...v1.0.1&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/LANCommander/LANCommander/releases/tag/v1.0.1" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/LANCommander/LANCommander/releases/tag/v1.0.2</id>
    <title>New release for LANCommander: v1.0.2</title>
    <updated>2024-10-09T19:20:41-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>LANCommander/LANCommander</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h1&gt;Server&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Getting a list of games from the API no longer filters out mods/expansions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Launcher&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Player's alias is now correctly populated in &lt;code&gt;$NewPlayerAlias&lt;/code&gt; when launching a game&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Profile avatar is now pulled on application start&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: The importer will attempt to reimport media if it's missing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Full Changelog&lt;/strong&gt;: https://github.com/LANCommander/LANCommander/compare/v1.0.1...v1.0.2&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/LANCommander/LANCommander/releases/tag/v1.0.2" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/LANCommander/LANCommander/releases/tag/v1.0.3</id>
    <title>New release for LANCommander: v1.0.3</title>
    <updated>2024-10-15T18:37:11-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>LANCommander/LANCommander</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h1&gt;Server&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: A bug that was causing servers to produce malformed LCX files on export has been fixed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: A bug that caused servers to fail on import when a console was defined has been fixed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Launcher&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Issues with application startup on new installs has been fixed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: When extracting save files, there was the potential for nested directories to not get extracted properly. This should be resolved now&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Full Changelog&lt;/strong&gt;: https://github.com/LANCommander/LANCommander/compare/v1.0.2...v1.0.3&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/LANCommander/LANCommander/releases/tag/v1.0.3" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/LANCommander/LANCommander/releases/tag/v1.0.4</id>
    <title>New release for LANCommander: v1.0.4</title>
    <updated>2024-10-28T18:15:18-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>LANCommander/LANCommander</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h1&gt;Launcher&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Downloads are now queued properly (#131)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Errors for password requirements and other validation issues are now displayed properly on the registration form (#132)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: A minor display issue with the loading indicator on the registration form has been fixed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Save files are now packaged with UTF-8 filenames&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: The launcher will no longer crash if an installed game has no actions available&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Full Changelog&lt;/strong&gt;: https://github.com/LANCommander/LANCommander/compare/v1.0.3...v1.0.4&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/LANCommander/LANCommander/releases/tag/v1.0.4" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
