<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://selfh.st/apps</id>
  <title>LANCommander Releases</title>
  <updated>2024-10-07T10:32:47.217763-04:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>selfh.st</name>
    <email>contact@selfh.st</email>
  </author>
  <link href="https://selfh.st/apps" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>Self-hosted software releases generated by selfh.st</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/LANCommander/LANCommander/releases/tag/v0.8.6</id>
    <title>New release for LANCommander: v0.8.6</title>
    <updated>2024-07-20T20:16:54-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>LANCommander/LANCommander</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h1&gt;Launcher&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: Offline mode&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: Scripts can be manually run on a game if debug mode is enabled&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: Logging now writes to file and some basic options have been added to &lt;code&gt;Settings.yml&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: BeforeStart and AfterStop scripts now execute properly on games&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Player names, allocated keys, and saves are now synced properly on game start mirroring Playnite extension functionality&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Full Changelog&lt;/strong&gt;: https://github.com/LANCommander/LANCommander/compare/v0.8.5...v0.8.6&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/LANCommander/LANCommander/releases/tag/v0.8.6" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/LANCommander/LANCommander/releases/tag/v0.9.0</id>
    <title>New release for LANCommander: v0.9.0</title>
    <updated>2024-08-05T01:33:20-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>LANCommander/LANCommander</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h1&gt;Server&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Robots.txt to block web scraping now loads correctly&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: API version check&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Renamed base project from &lt;code&gt;LANCommander&lt;/code&gt; to &lt;code&gt;LANCommander.Server&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: New &lt;code&gt;/Launcher&lt;/code&gt; page allows users to download the same version launcher from the server (or redirect to GitHub asset if server doesn't host client updates)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Playnite Extension&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: Basic validation to check that fields are not blank on the authentication dialog have been added&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Launcher&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: Autoupdater&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: Builds are now being provided for Linux x64/arm64, macOS arm64, and Windows x64/arm64, though only Windows x64 is supported at this time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: Installed date for game is now being tracked&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: Launcher version is now viewable in settings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: Library items can now be right clicked to access context menu&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Merged many of the required DLLs into the main launcher EXE&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Renamed from client to launcher&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: PowerShell module is now being imported properly&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Zone identifier is now being removed for all files in the launcher's directory on first start&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Saves are now pulled from the server on start of a game only if the save is newer than the last play session and newer than the game's installed on&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Games with no actions will now display error message when attempting to start instead of crashing the application&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Images no longer show broken image icon if image is missing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Other&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This release marks the full release of the official LANCommander launcher. This is also the last non-patch release that will support the Playnite extension. For more details about this development, please read the post over at our Patreon:
https://www.patreon.com/posts/v0-9-0-updates-109003781&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note, due to the changes of naming of the base assemblies and release files, this release cannot be updated using the autoupdater. You will have to download this release manually and extract its contents to your server directory. It's also recommended to start clean with this being the first official version of the launcher, if you have used the v0.8.x prerelease versions in the past.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As always, it's highly recommended to make proper backups before updating!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Full Changelog&lt;/strong&gt;: https://github.com/LANCommander/LANCommander/compare/v0.8.6...v0.9.0&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/LANCommander/LANCommander/releases/tag/v0.9.0" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/LANCommander/LANCommander/releases/tag/v0.9.1</id>
    <title>New release for LANCommander: v0.9.1</title>
    <updated>2024-08-09T19:41:25-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>LANCommander/LANCommander</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h1&gt;Server&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Navigation to login/register pages from launcher download page has been fixed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Port field is correctly set when importing a server LCX&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Importing a server LCX no longer fails if the "game" field was set on export&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Launcher&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Authentication now works correctly if a user doesn't have an avatar set on their profile&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: The overall download has been slimmed down and most dev files have been removed from final builds&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Games with inaccessible files (deleted or moved) will no longer crash the application when selected&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Authentication issues with servers behind Cloudflare have been fixed and should no longer show server out of date errors&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: The download queue no longer glitches out with its opened/closed state&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: The selected game's action button is now properly updated when the game is uninstalled&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Autoupdater Issues&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was a minor bug in v0.9.0's autoupdater that causes the updater to crash. This has been fixed, but upgrading from v0.9.0 to v0.9.1 will require a manual update. The files in the release ZIP for both the server and client can just be dragged over the existing files.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Full Changelog&lt;/strong&gt;: https://github.com/LANCommander/LANCommander/compare/v0.9.0...v0.9.1&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/LANCommander/LANCommander/releases/tag/v0.9.1" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/LANCommander/LANCommander/releases/tag/v1.0.0</id>
    <title>New release for LANCommander: v1.0.0</title>
    <updated>2024-09-28T04:54:56-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>LANCommander/LANCommander</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h1&gt;Server&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: The "Archives" side menu option when editing a game has been moved towards the top&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Key allocation method (MAC address or user) can now be changed per-game, default value is user account&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: The underlying log engine has been swapped out and logging should be overall improved across the board&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: A new section called "Issues" can be used to track submitted issues with games&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: .ico files can now be uploaded as media&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: A new micro-CMS has been added and is available under "Pages"&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: User profiles can now contain custom fields that may be used in scripts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: User information can now be edited by administrators&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: Mods/expansions will now show nested under their base game in the main games list&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: A count of games that require a redistributable has now been added as a column in the redistributable list&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: Games that require a redistributable can now be selected in bulk when editing the redistributable&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: An issue that was affecting some games to not return any search results for media has been fixed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Titles when editing a game, server, or redistributable are now correct&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Mods/expansions with no base game set will now show in the main games list instead of being hidden away&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Removed: A hidden wiki functionality has been removed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Launcher&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: An issue where some metadata such as collections and genres was being improperly cached has been fixed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Name change scripts now run properly if &lt;code&gt;$NewPlayerAlias&lt;/code&gt; is equal to &lt;code&gt;$OldPlayerAlias&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: PowerShell scripts now execute in a bundled runtime. This should remove the requirement to set the ExecutionPolicy option in PowerShell in order for scripts to execute correctly&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Overall release size should be improved&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: The logging engine has been swapped out and should result in better logs across the board&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: When enabled in settings, debug mode now provides an in-app PowerShell terminal&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: A CLI interface has been added to the launcher with some basic verbs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: A "Report Issue" button has been added to report issues with a game back to the server&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: Games that use Steamworks lobbies will show extra actions in the action dialog if any lobbies are open. More documentation and details will be available in documentation soon&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: Multiple install locations can now be specified&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: A new "Discovered Servers" UI element has been added to the authentication form&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: Users can now register with a server directly from the launcher&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: The launcher's window position will now be retained between runs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Documentation&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Documentation has been revamped now lives over at:
https://docs.lancommander.app/&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Breaking Changes&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Detect install scripts for redistributables have been slightly reworked and thus has introduced a breaking change where you will need to update these scripts. Where an exit code was previously supplied, now the variable &lt;code&gt;$Return&lt;/code&gt; must be set. See the &lt;a href="https://docs.lancommander.app/en/Scripting/DetectInstallScripts"&gt;documentation&lt;/a&gt; for more details.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Full Changelog&lt;/strong&gt;: https://github.com/LANCommander/LANCommander/compare/v0.9.1...v1.0.0&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/LANCommander/LANCommander/releases/tag/v1.0.0" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/LANCommander/LANCommander/releases/tag/v1.0.1</id>
    <title>New release for LANCommander: v1.0.1</title>
    <updated>2024-10-04T02:01:15-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>LANCommander/LANCommander</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h1&gt;Server&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: Archives can now be uploaded via REST API&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: Redistributables and servers can now be exported/imported via REST API&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: /app permissions in Docker by @miketweaver (#95)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: New pages now get deleted properly (#113)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Page slug editor properly updates on save (#113)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Issue deletion popover no longer says redistributables (#116)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Issue add form now loads properly (#117)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: PCGamingWiki scraper for multiplayer modes no longer crashes metadata lookup (#119)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Dashboard now uses dark theme for charts in dark mode (#118)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: The autoupdater in this release should work as expected&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Slimmed the download a bit more&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Launcher&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: Uninstall scripts can now be called from the debug menu&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Removed media is now deleted on import (#114)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: Archives can now be uploaded via CLI&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added: Redistributables and servers can now be exported/imported via CLI&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: The autoupdater in this release should work as expected&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Slimmed the download a bit more&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Autoupdater Issues&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note that in the last release there was an issue with how the autoupdating functionality worked. Any non-Docker users will have to update their install manually.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Full Changelog&lt;/strong&gt;: https://github.com/LANCommander/LANCommander/compare/v1.0.0...v1.0.1&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/LANCommander/LANCommander/releases/tag/v1.0.1" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
