<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://selfh.st/apps</id>
  <title>Lingarr Releases</title>
  <updated>2025-04-12T19:34:48.203554-04:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>selfh.st</name>
    <email>contact@selfh.st</email>
  </author>
  <link href="https://selfh.st/apps" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>Self-hosted software releases generated by selfh.st</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/lingarr-translate/lingarr/releases/tag/0.9.2</id>
    <title>New release for Lingarr: 0.9.2</title>
    <updated>2024-10-12T07:38:59-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>lingarr-translate/lingarr</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;Release 0.9.2&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am happy to announce version 0.9.2, this release addressed volume mapping issues and added additional support for AI and free translation services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;New Features &amp;amp; Enhancements:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Volume Mapping Fix: Resolved volume mapping issues. (9de7785)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Additional Translation Services: Added initial support for additional translation services. (8020c9d, 1373908)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;AI Translation Settings: Added settings for AI translation. (6d2a632)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Case-Insensitive Search: Made search queries case insensitive. (61f2c14)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;System Enhancements:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Documentation Update: Refactored instructions on how to add LibreTranslate within the Readme.MD. (186635b)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Input Component Refactor: Refactored input component and moved validation to a composable. (ea2fea6)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SignalR Refactor: Refactored SignalR to allow for more WebSocket connections and improved storing and retrieving settings. (3670a90)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Translation Service Improvements: Improved translation services and restructured responsibilities. (12fc995)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Miscellaneous Fixes and Improvements:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Documentation updates and other improvements. (4719eb2, 4281a49, 91ac164, 1eb57cf)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/lingarr-translate/lingarr/releases/tag/0.9.2" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/lingarr-translate/lingarr/releases/tag/0.9.3</id>
    <title>New release for Lingarr: 0.9.3</title>
    <updated>2024-10-13T06:10:27-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>lingarr-translate/lingarr</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added initial support for local AI (5846bcd)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added reindex option, improved navigation indication, added api to call the automation instantly (d001f07)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed mapping bug on auto translation (4e07998)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Updated readme, simplified docker compose with the minimum requirements, removed usage of root user (4719eb2)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/lingarr-translate/lingarr/releases/tag/0.9.3" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/lingarr-translate/lingarr/releases/tag/0.9.4</id>
    <title>New release for Lingarr: 0.9.4</title>
    <updated>2024-10-30T15:50:38-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>lingarr-translate/lingarr</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[!WARNING]&lt;br /&gt;
This release contains a breaking change. When upgrading, you need to remap your volumes and resynchronize your libraries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a few releases to improve the overal functionality I am happy to announce version 0.9.4 which has made significant steps in performance, stability, and quality. With this release with over 23 commits and 183 files changed, I’ve enhanced notifications, improved automation, and introduced my first breaking change (oops, apologies!).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed volume mapping and removed &lt;code&gt;/app/media&lt;/code&gt; which is a &lt;code&gt;BREAKING CHANGE&lt;/code&gt;  make sure you map the new volumes and synchronise your libraries via the settings.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added a new notification system which displays automated and manually instantiated translations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved automated volume mapping and added support for manual in-application mapping.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved services, made them thread-safe, and ensured one-time initialization of service dependencies.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added language definition per service, languages now need to be reconfigured when selecting a new service to match the definition.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sonarr and Radarr images are now optional.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Set input fields to password on API key fields.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Numerous other bug fixes and improvements.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you all for your positivity and feedback! I hope this release makes it easier to enjoy and discover new movies and series.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/lingarr-translate/lingarr/releases/tag/0.9.4" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/lingarr-translate/lingarr/releases/tag/0.9.5</id>
    <title>New release for Lingarr: 0.9.5</title>
    <updated>2025-01-20T07:23:36-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>lingarr-translate/lingarr</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;I am excited to share a nice set of new features and improvements in this update! With over 33 commits and 162 files changed, this release introduces personal statistics to enhance your dashboard experience, along with support for the &lt;code&gt;SubStation Alpha (SSA/ASS)&lt;/code&gt; subtitle format. A dedicated release is now available for our ARM users, and the app has been localized in English and Dutch, with support for additional languages. Last but not least, I've implemented a tasks page that provides clearer insights and better management of scheduled tasks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Features&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Introduced personal statistics, which also improve the dashboard experience.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added support for the &lt;code&gt;SubStation Alpha (SSA/ASS)&lt;/code&gt; subtitle format. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Introduced an ARM build. Use &lt;code&gt;latest-arm64&lt;/code&gt; instead of &lt;code&gt;latest&lt;/code&gt; to access this version.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The app is now localized and available in English and Dutch. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added a tasks page where users can manage scheduled tasks. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added support for settings via environment variables. More details &lt;a href="https://github.com/lingarr-translate/lingarr/blob/main/Settings.MD"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added support for &lt;code&gt;PUID&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;PGID&lt;/code&gt;. This feature is experimental, so please ensure you fully understand its functionality before using it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Bug fixes and Improvements&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gracefully handle missing media &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved foreign key support and record removal functionality within SQLite.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Subtitle collection now supports accessibility features and language codes like &lt;code&gt;es-MX&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;pt-BR&lt;/code&gt;. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved overal subtitle collection of splintered directories.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Introduced rate limiting to handle &lt;code&gt;429 Too Many Requests&lt;/code&gt; errors gracefully.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Merged subtitle lines for better translation quality. &lt;em&gt;Special thanks to Jaspu for the suggestion!&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Resolved an issue where scheduled updates wouldn’t occur without restarting the application.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added &lt;code&gt;/api/generate&lt;/code&gt; endpoint for &lt;strong&gt;Ollama/local AI&lt;/strong&gt; integrations. &lt;em&gt;Thank you, Tem, for the idea!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;WebSockets now correctly close when the user exits the application.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Removed the mapping screen due to its limited utility and confusion among users.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/lingarr-translate/lingarr/releases/tag/0.9.5" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/lingarr-translate/lingarr/releases/tag/0.9.6</id>
    <title>New release for Lingarr: 0.9.6</title>
    <updated>2025-02-26T12:45:42-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>lingarr-translate/lingarr</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;I'm excited to bring you another update packed with new features, improvements, and fixes! This release focuses on enhancing subtitle handling, improving accessibility, refining translation management, and making backend operations more reliable. With key upgrades like support for overlapping subtitle fixes, new AI services, exclusions and thresholds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Features&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added new AI services: DeepSeek and Gemini&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added support for fixing overlapping subtitles&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Introduced file age delay configuration per media type&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added options to exclude media or set a file age delay for translation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Implemented delete functionality for translation requests&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Implemented resuming translation requests on restart&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enhanced translation request status handling and updates&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added option to store Hangfire jobs in MySQL&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Bug fixes and Improvements&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Major refactor of SRT parsing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed active translation count&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed display of language chart statistics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed episode number handling&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed language selection errors caused by filtered results&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed API changes for Anthropic integration&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Removed sync button from integrations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved accessibility with updated navigation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cleaned up statistics chart code&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Upgraded frontend packages&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Applied new code formatting&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/lingarr-translate/lingarr/releases/tag/0.9.6" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
