<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://selfh.st/apps</id>
  <title>LinguaCafe Releases</title>
  <updated>2024-07-15T11:30:49.272837-04:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>selfh.st</name>
    <email>contact@selfh.st</email>
  </author>
  <link href="https://selfh.st/apps" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>Self-hosted software releases generated by selfh.st</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/simjanos-dev/LinguaCafe/releases/tag/v0.12.3</id>
    <title>New release for LinguaCafe: v0.12.3</title>
    <updated>2024-05-22T04:02:38-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>simjanos-dev/LinguaCafe</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;Please backup LinguaCafe before updating, otherwise you can lose your data if anything goes wrong. You can read more about backups in the &lt;a href="https://github.com/simjanos-dev/LinguaCafe/wiki/2.-Setup#backup"&gt;user manual&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bug fixes:&lt;/strong&gt;
- Fixed Polish font file name, which did not load previously.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Thank you for everyone who contributed for the release!&lt;/h2&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/simjanos-dev/LinguaCafe/releases/tag/v0.12.3" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/simjanos-dev/LinguaCafe/releases/tag/v0.12.4</id>
    <title>New release for LinguaCafe: v0.12.4</title>
    <updated>2024-05-29T14:29:13-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>simjanos-dev/LinguaCafe</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;Please backup LinguaCafe before updating, otherwise you can lose your data if anything goes wrong. You can read more about backups in the &lt;a href="https://github.com/simjanos-dev/LinguaCafe/wiki/2.-Setup#backup"&gt;user manual&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This update is not necessary for existing users. If you already started using linguacafe after April 25 and never changed your selected language from Spanish, you can fix this bug by selecting an other language, then selecting Spanish again. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bug fixes:&lt;/strong&gt;
- Fixed unusable Spanish goals after creating the first user.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Thank you for everyone who contributed for the release!&lt;/h2&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/simjanos-dev/LinguaCafe/releases/tag/v0.12.4" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/simjanos-dev/LinguaCafe/releases/tag/v0.12.5</id>
    <title>New release for LinguaCafe: v0.12.5</title>
    <updated>2024-06-01T13:21:22-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>simjanos-dev/LinguaCafe</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;Please backup LinguaCafe before updating, otherwise you can lose your data if anything goes wrong. You can read more about backups in the &lt;a href="https://github.com/simjanos-dev/LinguaCafe/wiki/2.-Setup#backup"&gt;user manual&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This issue only affects servers that have a user other than the admin who manages the server.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bug fixes:&lt;/strong&gt;
- Fixed a serious security issue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Thank you for everyone who contributed for the release!&lt;/h2&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/simjanos-dev/LinguaCafe/releases/tag/v0.12.5" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/simjanos-dev/LinguaCafe/releases/tag/v0.12.6</id>
    <title>New release for LinguaCafe: v0.12.6</title>
    <updated>2024-06-05T12:26:17-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>simjanos-dev/LinguaCafe</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;Please backup LinguaCafe before updating, otherwise you can lose your data if anything goes wrong. You can read more about backups in the &lt;a href="https://github.com/simjanos-dev/LinguaCafe/wiki/2.-Setup#backup"&gt;user manual&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bug fixes:&lt;/strong&gt;
- Using the same LinguaCafe user on multiple devices with multiple languages caused database corruption in some very rare edge cases. Now whenever a user logs in on a device, other devices will be logged out to avoid this issue. This is a temporary solution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Thank you for everyone who contributed for the release!&lt;/h2&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/simjanos-dev/LinguaCafe/releases/tag/v0.12.6" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/simjanos-dev/LinguaCafe/releases/tag/v0.13</id>
    <title>New release for LinguaCafe: v0.13</title>
    <updated>2024-06-26T12:06:04-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>simjanos-dev/LinguaCafe</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;Please backup LinguaCafe before updating, otherwise you can lose your data if anything goes wrong. You can read more about backups in the &lt;a href="https://github.com/simjanos-dev/LinguaCafe/wiki/2.-Setup#backup"&gt;user manual&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;New features:&lt;/strong&gt;
-Added support for using remote MySQL server.
-Added an icon.
-Added support for multiple users.
-Added an import option for e-books that lets users order the chapters based on the e-book's spine metadata. In some rare cases, this will fix incorrect chapter order for imported e-books.
-Added an option to set preferred hover vocabulary position. Now it can appear both above or below the hovered words based on the selected setting.
-Added filtering, sorting and pagination to the user settings, dictionary settings, font settings, library and chapters pages.
-Replaced the dictionary import process. Now users can import dictionaries by file upload, instead of having to copy files into the storage directory.
-Users now can delete and create DeepL dictionaries.
-Added support for DeepL translation into multiple languages.
-Added an option for % display of word counts on the chapters page.
-Added tabs to the text reader's settings dialog.
-Added an auto level words option, which automatically levels up words which the user did not click on while reading.
-Added a hotkey to the text reader to toggle plain text mode.
-Added settings to hide the subtitle timestamps and to change the space between subtitles.
-Added a setting to change the speed of the text to speech.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bug fixes:&lt;/strong&gt;
-Login page sometimes showed an error despite a successful login, mostly after creating the first user.
-Review page displayed no text after the user finished reviewing if it only had one card in total.
-Fixed and enabled Thai import options.
-Added missing created_at and updated_at fields to imported words in the database.
-Fixed multi word touch selection with Apple pencils.
-Hover vocabulary now will move if there's not enough space for it to be displayed inside the reading area.
-Admin settings cannot be saved anymore if a field is left empty.
-Removed whitespace from the beginning of the tab selector UI element on mobile.
-Removed furigana from text on plain text mode.
-Fixed a problem when a user selected a long phrase, and the search result overflowed its box. I hid the whole search result if it was too long, and users now can see the whole search result by hovering over the shortened form. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Other changes:&lt;/strong&gt;
-Hover vocabulary's dictionary search results have been limited to 9 instead of 15. I'll add a setting for this in the future.
-JMDict dictionary files have been replaced with a single .zip file that contains them. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Thank you for everyone who contributed for the release!&lt;/h2&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/simjanos-dev/LinguaCafe/releases/tag/v0.13" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
