<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://selfh.st/apps</id>
  <title>LinguaCafe Releases</title>
  <updated>2024-05-30T06:30:50.272619-04:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>selfh.st</name>
    <email>contact@selfh.st</email>
  </author>
  <link href="https://selfh.st/apps" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>Self-hosted software releases generated by selfh.st</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/simjanos-dev/LinguaCafe/releases/tag/v0.12</id>
    <title>New release for LinguaCafe: v0.12</title>
    <updated>2024-05-17T04:03:42-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>simjanos-dev/LinguaCafe</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;There was in issue with the Windows update process. I updated the readme with an extra step, it should work now. Sadly I have no way of testing it currently, but it worked for an other user.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please backup LinguaCafe before updating, otherwise you can lose your data if anything goes wrong. You can read more about backups in the &lt;a href="https://github.com/simjanos-dev/LinguaCafe/wiki/2.-Setup#backup"&gt;user manual&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;New features:&lt;/strong&gt;
- Docker installation and update process has been improved. It does not require git and chmod commands anymore (except once for already existing users).
- Added book length to the library list view.
- Added word inflections table for Japanese.
- Added text to speech option for the text reader.
- Added bottom sheet vocabulary for mobile view.
- Added progressive web app support. Now users can use LinguaCafe as a full screen mobile app.
- Added font type management system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bug fixes:&lt;/strong&gt;
- Added missing kanji images. Now users can see the kanji stroke order and writing animation on the kanji info pages.
- Book word counts now update after importing something.
- Hover vocabulary now disappears when the user moves their mouse pointer to empty space.
- Importing texts now skips too long words instead of throwing an error.
- Importing dictionaries now skips records that contain a word or a definition that is too long instead of throwing an error.
- Fixed highlighted word colors that were displayed incorrectly at several places.
- Interactive text is not selectable anymore on the review page natively like other texts in the browser.
- Previous example sentences are not visible anymore on the review page while the new one is loading.
- Users cannot open a chapter in the text reader anymore that does not belong to their selected language.
- JMDict's source language is not editable anymore.
- Copying a selected word with ctrl+c won't set the word's level to new anymore.
- It is now impossible to create a phrase without any words, which would corrupt the database.
- Fixed light theme's warning color, because it was too yellow and lacking in contrast. For devices that already opened LinguaCafe, users must click on the reset color button to update it.
- Fixed plain text mode copy-paste in Firefox.
- Symbols won't be combined anymore with words in Japanese. This only applies to texts that are imported after this update.
- Fixed a bug that caused text importing to fail in Japanese, if the last word was combined with the previous word during post processing.
- Polish language had a font type that displayed incorrect letters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Other changes:&lt;/strong&gt;
- The import dialog won't close by itself anymore after importing has finished.
- Laravel now produces more detailed logs, and logs both to the log file and the docker terminal.
- Disabled Thai import options temporarily, because they did not work. Will fix and re-enable them in v0.13. Users can still use it by manually importing text.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Thank you for everyone who contributed for the release!&lt;/h2&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/simjanos-dev/LinguaCafe/releases/tag/v0.12" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/simjanos-dev/LinguaCafe/releases/tag/v0.12.1</id>
    <title>New release for LinguaCafe: v0.12.1</title>
    <updated>2024-05-17T12:30:57-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>simjanos-dev/LinguaCafe</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;Please backup LinguaCafe before updating, otherwise you can lose your data if anything goes wrong. You can read more about backups in the &lt;a href="https://github.com/simjanos-dev/LinguaCafe/wiki/2.-Setup#backup"&gt;user manual&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bug fixes:&lt;/strong&gt;
- Example sentence text overflowed the review card.
- Added missing folder creation for linguacafe/storage/app/temp. Not having it caused ebook file imports, and Japanese language install to fail.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Thank you for everyone who contributed for the release!&lt;/h2&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/simjanos-dev/LinguaCafe/releases/tag/v0.12.1" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/simjanos-dev/LinguaCafe/releases/tag/v0.12.2</id>
    <title>New release for LinguaCafe: v0.12.2</title>
    <updated>2024-05-19T16:13:23-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>simjanos-dev/LinguaCafe</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;Please backup LinguaCafe before updating, otherwise you can lose your data if anything goes wrong. You can read more about backups in the &lt;a href="https://github.com/simjanos-dev/LinguaCafe/wiki/2.-Setup#backup"&gt;user manual&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bug fixes:&lt;/strong&gt;
- Disabled touch scrolling while selecting text.
- Fixed a bug that prevented reading and reviewing in browsers that do not support TTS, like Opera.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Thank you for everyone who contributed for the release!&lt;/h2&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/simjanos-dev/LinguaCafe/releases/tag/v0.12.2" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/simjanos-dev/LinguaCafe/releases/tag/v0.12.3</id>
    <title>New release for LinguaCafe: v0.12.3</title>
    <updated>2024-05-22T04:02:38-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>simjanos-dev/LinguaCafe</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;Please backup LinguaCafe before updating, otherwise you can lose your data if anything goes wrong. You can read more about backups in the &lt;a href="https://github.com/simjanos-dev/LinguaCafe/wiki/2.-Setup#backup"&gt;user manual&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bug fixes:&lt;/strong&gt;
- Fixed Polish font file name, which did not load previously.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Thank you for everyone who contributed for the release!&lt;/h2&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/simjanos-dev/LinguaCafe/releases/tag/v0.12.3" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/simjanos-dev/LinguaCafe/releases/tag/v0.12.4</id>
    <title>New release for LinguaCafe: v0.12.4</title>
    <updated>2024-05-29T14:29:13-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>simjanos-dev/LinguaCafe</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;Please backup LinguaCafe before updating, otherwise you can lose your data if anything goes wrong. You can read more about backups in the &lt;a href="https://github.com/simjanos-dev/LinguaCafe/wiki/2.-Setup#backup"&gt;user manual&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This update is not necessary for existing users. If you already started using linguacafe after April 25 and never changed your selected language from Spanish, you can fix this bug by selecting an other language, then selecting Spanish again. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bug fixes:&lt;/strong&gt;
- Fixed unusable Spanish goals after creating the first user.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Thank you for everyone who contributed for the release!&lt;/h2&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/simjanos-dev/LinguaCafe/releases/tag/v0.12.4" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
