<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://selfh.st/apps</id>
  <title>LinguaCafe Releases</title>
  <updated>2024-04-27T02:30:46.160313-04:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>selfh.st</name>
    <email>contact@selfh.st</email>
  </author>
  <link href="https://selfh.st/apps" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>Self-hosted software releases generated by selfh.st</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/simjanos-dev/LinguaCafe/releases/tag/v0.8</id>
    <title>New release for LinguaCafe: v0.8</title>
    <updated>2024-03-20T23:39:42-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>simjanos-dev/LinguaCafe</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h1&gt;Please create a backup before updating to prevent any possible data loss. A lot of server code has been refactored, and there always can be unexpected problems. There is a page on backups in the user manual.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new user manual can be viewed on the GitHub &lt;a href="https://simjanos-dev.github.io/LinguaCafeHome/#user-manual"&gt;overview page&lt;/a&gt; as well. It is lacking many pages currently, but it will be expanded regularly. English is not my native language, and I think my phrasing is not great, so please feel free to improve and modify it. I recognized that many things in LinguaCafe are not explained anywhere, and I'll try to work on those pages first.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;New features:&lt;/strong&gt;
- Added "website" import option.
- Added vocabulary word import from .csv.
- Added start review dialog for the review button in the navigation sidebar.
- Added review finished information cards, instead of redirecting the user to the homepage.
- Word counts now load automatically when you open a book.
- Added a setting for hover vocabulary's delay.
- Added user manual. Will be extended and updated regularly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bug fixes:&lt;/strong&gt;
- Review cards' content overflowed the buttons.
- Books with long titles hid their open button.
- Daily read words goal was not updating while reviewing phrases if the sentence mode was not selected.
- Vocabulary sidebar had a minor visual problem with its edges.
- Text reader had an error if the opened chapter had no text.
- Renamed label "stage" to "level" on vocabulary page to make it consistent.
- Non Chinese and Japanese phrases were only searchable on the vocabulary page without spaces. This fix only applies to phrases created after this update.
- Non Chinese and Japanese phrases were displayed incorrectly on the vocabulary sidebar.
- Phrases were displayed incorrectly on the vocabulary export dialog.
- Reading fields were visible on vocabulary search page's edit dialog for languages that had no readings.
- Numpad hotkeys were not working.
- Hover vocabulary's search dictionary setting was not working when it was turned off.
- Hover vocabulary sent a request to the server even if you took the mouse off from the hovered word before the delay ended.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Other changes:&lt;/strong&gt;
- If DeepL is disabled for a language, the dictionaries will not show a DeepL error message anymore, and they also won't make a request to retrieve the DeepL translations.
- For better performance and to avoid accidentaly opening hover vocabulary on words, a slight delay was added before the hover vocabulary box becomes visible. The dictionary and DeepL searches already had this delay, it just has been applied to the visibility of the hover vocabulary box as well. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Thank you for everyone who contributed for the release!&lt;/h2&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/simjanos-dev/LinguaCafe/releases/tag/v0.8" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/simjanos-dev/LinguaCafe/releases/tag/v0.9</id>
    <title>New release for LinguaCafe: v0.9</title>
    <updated>2024-03-28T12:57:02-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>simjanos-dev/LinguaCafe</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;Please &lt;strong&gt;backup&lt;/strong&gt; LinguaCafe before updating, otherwise you can lose your data if anything goes wrong. You can read more about backups in the &lt;a href="https://simjanos-dev.github.io/LinguaCafeHome/#user-manual"&gt;user manual&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Mac changes&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a small change for Mac users with Apple silicon processors in the install/update process. Please follow the &lt;a href="https://github.com/simjanos-dev/LinguaCafe?tab=readme-ov-file#updating-to-the-latest-version"&gt;instructions&lt;/a&gt;  in the readme before updating.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;New features:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added new supported languages: English, Greek and Latin.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Made text editable when importing a website.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added settings dialog for the review page.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Expanded example sentence mode on the review page. Now it has 3 options: disabled, plain text and interactive text.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added hover vocabulary on the review page.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added dictionary edit dialog for the admin page.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;DeepL translator's target language now can be changed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added support for HanDeDict dictionary.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added support for every dict cc dictionary. Now you can import multiple of them for the same language.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Other changes:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MacOS users have a new, simpler install and update process.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Thank you for everyone who contributed for the release!&lt;/h2&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/simjanos-dev/LinguaCafe/releases/tag/v0.9" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/simjanos-dev/LinguaCafe/releases/tag/v0.10</id>
    <title>New release for LinguaCafe: v0.10</title>
    <updated>2024-04-19T09:31:00-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>simjanos-dev/LinguaCafe</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;Please backup LinguaCafe before updating, otherwise you can lose your data if anything goes wrong. You can read more about backups in the &lt;a href="https://github.com/simjanos-dev/LinguaCafe/wiki/2.-Setup#backup"&gt;user manual&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The interactive text's code has been reworked, it may come with a small performance increase. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a few UI elements that do not look good if you change the background or foreground colors, they will be fixed in a future update.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;New features:&lt;/strong&gt; 
- Added a new default list layout for the library page.
- Added a logout confirmation dialog.
- Added theme customization.
- Added different background colors for different word levels.
- Added a separate color for ignored words' text color.
- Added a hotkey to set words' level back to new.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bug fixes:&lt;/strong&gt;
- There will be no error message anymore due to empty book name when you click on "Create book" button.
- While creating a book, the save button won't be grayed out anymore if you type in a name. Previously it only turned active after you removed the focus from the name input field.
- While creating or editing a book and uploading an image, clicking on the cancel button will now revert the image to the default or previous image, instead of showing an error message.
- Fixed a bug that caused words imported on the vocabulary page to not be added to the review system.
- Pressing the enter key when creating or editing a book or a chapter now will act the same as clicking on the Save button. Pressing the enter key when importing something now will act as the Continue or Import button.
- Fixed a bug that caused hover vocabulary box to appear even when plain text mode was active&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Other changes:&lt;/strong&gt;
- Improved dictionary search UI: made dictionary colors less distracting and vocabulary sidebar more compact and uniform.
- The online user manual has been moved from the GitHub Page to the GitHub Wiki. It also moved from a Vuetify format to Markdown.
- DeepL API key error will not appear on the admin page anymore if it set to the default value.
- Added a warning on how hover vocabulary box works in review settings.
- Lightened default dark mode text color to make it more readable.
- Made navigation sidebar more compact.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Thank you for everyone who contributed for the release!&lt;/h2&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/simjanos-dev/LinguaCafe/releases/tag/v0.10" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/simjanos-dev/LinguaCafe/releases/tag/v0.10.1</id>
    <title>New release for LinguaCafe: v0.10.1</title>
    <updated>2024-04-21T15:37:22-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>simjanos-dev/LinguaCafe</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;Please backup LinguaCafe before updating, otherwise you can lose your data if anything goes wrong. You can read more about backups in the &lt;a href="https://github.com/simjanos-dev/LinguaCafe/wiki/2.-Setup#backup"&gt;user manual&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bug fixes:&lt;/strong&gt;
- Fixed a bug that disabled some hotkeys.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Thank you for everyone who contributed for the release!&lt;/h2&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/simjanos-dev/LinguaCafe/releases/tag/v0.10.1" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/simjanos-dev/LinguaCafe/releases/tag/v0.11</id>
    <title>New release for LinguaCafe: v0.11</title>
    <updated>2024-04-25T06:04:22-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>simjanos-dev/LinguaCafe</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;Please backup LinguaCafe before updating, otherwise you can lose your data if anything goes wrong. You can read more about backups in the &lt;a href="https://github.com/simjanos-dev/LinguaCafe/wiki/2.-Setup#backup"&gt;user manual&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This update will change your selected language to Spanish to avoid having selected languages that are not installed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;New features:&lt;/strong&gt; 
- Language installation. Some languages have been removed from the docker image to reduce its size, and became installable on the admin page.
- Added new languages: Croatian, Danish, Macedonian, Polish, Portuguese, Romanian, Slovenian, Thai and Turkish.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Other changes:&lt;/strong&gt;
- The default language has been changed to Spanish.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Thank you for everyone who contributed for the release!&lt;/h2&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/simjanos-dev/LinguaCafe/releases/tag/v0.11" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
