<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://selfh.st/apps</id>
  <title>Logto Releases</title>
  <updated>2025-02-12T05:32:46.227211-05:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>selfh.st</name>
    <email>contact@selfh.st</email>
  </author>
  <link href="https://selfh.st/apps" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>Self-hosted software releases generated by selfh.st</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/logto-io/logto/releases/tag/v1.21.0</id>
    <title>New release for Logto: v1.21.0</title>
    <updated>2024-10-28T00:48:54-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>logto-io/logto</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/7d961d02-e7de-484d-b0d1-59f4f9c72dbb" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;GatewayAPI SMS connector&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can now send SMS messages via GatewayAPI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Australia region&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Australia region is now available in Logto Cloud.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Improvements and fixes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;6734 update Google Connector default &lt;code&gt;prompts&lt;/code&gt; to be &lt;code&gt;select_account&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;6630 fix an issue that prevent mp4 video from playing in custom sign-in pages on Safari browser&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;6674 add environment variable to override default database connection timeout&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;New Contributors&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;@michaelgiraldo made their first contribution in https://github.com/logto-io/logto/pull/6615&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;@bpow made their first contribution in https://github.com/logto-io/logto/pull/6328&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;@GeisonPiegas made their first contribution in https://github.com/logto-io/logto/pull/6642&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;@buchen made their first contribution in https://github.com/logto-io/logto/pull/6655&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;@luis815 made their first contribution in https://github.com/logto-io/logto/pull/6674&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Coming Soon: Account API&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new Account API is on its way, designed to give end users direct API access without needing to go through the Management API. Here’s a sneak peek of what you can expect:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Direct access: The Account API empowers end users to directly access and manage their own account profile without requiring the relay of Management API.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;User profile and identities management: Users can fully manage their profiles and security settings, including the ability to update identity information like email, phone, and password, as well as manage social link connections. May also support MFA and SSO in the future.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Global access control: Admin will have full, global control over access settings, can customize each fields.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Seamless authorization: Authorizing is easier than ever! Simply use &lt;code&gt;client.getAccessToken()&lt;/code&gt; to obtain an access token and attach it to the Authorization header.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/logto-io/logto/releases/tag/v1.21.0" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/logto-io/logto/releases/tag/v1.22.0</id>
    <title>New release for Logto: v1.22.0</title>
    <updated>2024-11-22T04:34:00-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>logto-io/logto</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Cover-changelog 2024 11" src="https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/7f810eb3-28ba-4976-b36e-d5ae9c67854e" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Account API&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new Account API is now available, giving end users direct API access without needing to go through the Management API. With this new API:
- Users can directly manage their profiles, including basic information, password, email, and phone
- Admins have full control over access settings for each field
- Integration is simple with &lt;code&gt;client.getAccessToken()&lt;/code&gt; for authorization
- Social identities management is supported out of the box&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check out the &lt;a href="https://docs.logto.io/docs/recipes/interact-with-account-api/"&gt;Interact with Account API&lt;/a&gt; for more details.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Microsoft EntraID SSO connector enhancement&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Added &lt;code&gt;trustUnverifiedEmail&lt;/code&gt; setting for Microsoft EntraID OIDC SSO connector.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This addresses a common issue where email addresses from EntraID weren't being synced to Logto because they lacked explicit verification.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Organizations can now choose to trust these email addresses, enabling smoother user onboarding through EntraID SSO.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can configure this setting in the &lt;strong&gt;EntraID OIDC SSO connector&lt;/strong&gt; settings page in the Logto console or through the management API.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Sign-in experience improvements&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Support contact information&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Added support email and website information display on error pages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When users encounter issues (like 404 errors or social callback failures), they can now easily find ways to contact support for assistance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You may configure the support email and website info in the &lt;strong&gt;Sign-in experience &amp;gt; Content &amp;gt; Support&lt;/strong&gt; settings in the Logto Console or through the management API.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Unknown session handling&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Introduced unknown session redirect URL configuration.
This helps users who land on sign-in pages with expired sessions or through bookmarked URLs - instead of seeing a 404 error, they can be automatically redirected to a specified URL to restart their authentication process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You may configure the unknown session redirect URL in the &lt;strong&gt;Sign-in experience &amp;gt; Sign-up and sign-in &amp;gt; Advanced options&lt;/strong&gt; settings in the Logto Console or through the management API.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/logto-io/logto/releases/tag/v1.22.0" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/logto-io/logto/releases/tag/v1.23.0</id>
    <title>New release for Logto: v1.23.0</title>
    <updated>2025-01-02T01:57:53-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>logto-io/logto</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="logto-changelog-2025-01" src="https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/b35196c7-3a33-4e22-bcbb-543a195201f6" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Customizable MFA prompt policy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can now customize the MFA prompt policy in the Console.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, choose if you want to enable &lt;strong&gt;Require MFA&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Enable&lt;/strong&gt;: Users will be prompted to set up MFA during the sign-in process, which cannot be skipped. If the user fails to set up MFA or deletes their MFA settings, they will be locked out of their account until they set up MFA again.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disable&lt;/strong&gt;: Users can skip the MFA setup process during the sign-up or sign-in flow.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you choose to &lt;strong&gt;Disable&lt;/strong&gt;, you can continue to choose the MFA setup prompt:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do not ask users to set up MFA.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ask users to set up MFA during registration (skippable, one-time prompt). &lt;strong&gt;The same prompt as the previous policy (UserControlled)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ask users to set up MFA on their next sign-in attempt after registration (skippable, one-time prompt).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Relaxed redirect URI restrictions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have been following the industry best practices for OAuth2.0 and OIDC from the start. However, in the real world, there are things we cannot control, like third-party services or operation systems like Windows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This update relaxes restrictions on redirect URIs to allow the following:
- A mix of native and HTTP(S) redirect URIs. For example, a native app can now use a redirect URI like &lt;code&gt;https://example.com/&lt;/code&gt;.
- Native schemes without a period (&lt;code&gt;.&lt;/code&gt;). For example, &lt;code&gt;myapp://callback&lt;/code&gt; is now allowed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When such URIs are configured, Logto Console will display a prominent warning. This change is backward-compatible and will not affect existing applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We hope this change will make it easier for you to integrate Logto with your applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;New connectors&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3fa2b796e Added Xiaomi social connector (credit @u0x01 ).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3004ae9a6 Added YunPian SMS connector (credit @u0x01 ).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Bug fixes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;217858950 Fixed the CLI command for fetching official connectors by updating the npm registry API integration.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/logto-io/logto/releases/tag/v1.23.0" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/logto-io/logto/releases/tag/v1.23.1</id>
    <title>New release for Logto: v1.23.1</title>
    <updated>2025-01-23T03:03:14-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>logto-io/logto</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h2&gt;Support custom endpoint and addressing style for S3&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Add support for configurable S3 endpoint and addressing style (path-style/virtual-hosted)
to improve compatibility with S3-compatible storage services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add forcePathStyle option to control URL addressing style&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix custom endpoint support implementation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improve URL generation logic for different configurations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Bug fixes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Fix the broken image on Logto console sign-in page&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remove the image element's &lt;code&gt;cross-origin="anonymous"&lt;/code&gt; attribute.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some public image resources may not have the proper cross-origin headers configured, those images may fail to load when the &lt;code&gt;cross-origin="anonymous" attribute is present.&lt;/code&gt;
Since sign-in page image elements are only used for display purposes, Logto does not need to access the image data, so the &lt;code&gt;cross-origin="anonymous"&lt;/code&gt; attribute is not necessary.To make the image elements more compatible with public image resources, remove the attribute from the image elements.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/logto-io/logto/releases/tag/v1.23.1" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/logto-io/logto/releases/tag/v1.24.0</id>
    <title>New release for Logto: v1.24.0</title>
    <updated>2025-02-07T02:18:44-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>logto-io/logto</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="logto-changelog-2025-02" src="https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/9b88d729-b8f9-49d5-8af4-7c33771518be" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Support SAML applications&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Logto now supports acting as a SAML identity provider (IdP), enabling enterprise users to achieve secure Single Sign-On (SSO) through the standardized SAML protocol. Key features include:
&lt;img alt="saml-app-demo" src="https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/ed134fc2-979c-47c8-99f8-c766698964c9" /&gt;
- Full support for SAML 2.0 protocol
- Flexible attribute mapping configuration
- Metadata auto-configuration support
- Enterprise-grade encryption and signing&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://docs.logto.io/integrate-logto/saml-app"&gt;View full documentation&lt;/a&gt; for more details.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Add HTTP email connector&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Users can now use HTTP email connector for sending emails.
The HTTP email connector allows you to send emails via HTTP call. To use the HTTP email connector, you'll need to have your own email service that expose an HTTP API for sending emails. Logto will call this API when it needs to send an email. For example, when a user registers, Logto will call the HTTP API to send a verification email.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Bug fixes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;62eb8ed Fixed the issue where the CLI could not correctly initialize the Logto instance or deploy database alterations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;bf2d300 Fixed the bug that a user accepts an invitation and join an organization does not trigger the &lt;code&gt;Organization.Membership.Updated&lt;/code&gt; webhook.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/logto-io/logto/releases/tag/v1.24.0" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
