<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://selfh.st/apps</id>
  <title>Logto Releases</title>
  <updated>2024-06-21T00:33:06.848904-04:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>selfh.st</name>
    <email>contact@selfh.st</email>
  </author>
  <link href="https://selfh.st/apps" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>Self-hosted software releases generated by selfh.st</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/logto-io/logto/releases/tag/v1.13.1</id>
    <title>New release for Logto: v1.13.1</title>
    <updated>2024-02-26T05:22:18-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>logto-io/logto</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h2&gt;Console application guides&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add Angular, Nuxt, SvelteKit, Expo (React Native) guides&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Update Next.js guide&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/logto-io/logto/releases/tag/v1.13.1" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/logto-io/logto/releases/tag/v1.14.0</id>
    <title>New release for Logto: v1.14.0</title>
    <updated>2024-03-01T02:10:09-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>logto-io/logto</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h2&gt;New features&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Support form post callback for social connectors&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add the POST /callback/:connectorId endpoint to handle the form post callback for social connectors. This is useful for the connectors that require a form post callback to complete the authentication process, such as Apple.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SMTP connector: Always show TLS configurations in Logto Console&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Apple connector: Support &lt;code&gt;scope&lt;/code&gt; parameter&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Now you can request for email and name during Sign in with Apple&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/logto-io/logto/releases/tag/v1.14.0" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/logto-io/logto/releases/tag/v1.15.0</id>
    <title>New release for Logto: v1.15.0</title>
    <updated>2024-04-10T10:00:25-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>logto-io/logto</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h2&gt;Direct sign-in&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can now directly invoke a sign-in method by skipping the first screen. This is useful when you have a direct link to a sign-in method, for instance, when you have a "Sign in with Google" button on your website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To use this feature, you need to pass the &lt;code&gt;direct_sign_in&lt;/code&gt; parameter to the authentication request. It supports the following methods:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A social connector&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An enterprise SSO connector&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To learn more, see the &lt;a href="https://docs.logto.io/docs/recipes/openid-connect/authentication-parameters/#direct-sign-in"&gt;Direct sign-in&lt;/a&gt; documentation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;First screen parameter&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sign-in experience can be initiated with a specific screen by setting the &lt;code&gt;first_screen&lt;/code&gt; parameter in the OIDC authentication request. This parameter is intended to replace the &lt;code&gt;interaction_mode&lt;/code&gt; parameter, which is now deprecated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See the &lt;a href="https://docs.logto.io/docs/recipes/openid-connect/authentication-parameters/#first-screen"&gt;First screen&lt;/a&gt; documentation for more information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Full OpenID Connect standard claims support&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have added support for the remaining &lt;a href="https://openid.net/specs/openid-connect-core-1_0.html#StandardClaims"&gt;OpenID Connect standard claims&lt;/a&gt;. Now, these claims are accessible in both ID tokens and the response from the &lt;code&gt;/me&lt;/code&gt; endpoint.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additionally, we adhere to the standard scopes - claims mapping. This means that you can retrieve most of the profile claims using the &lt;code&gt;profile&lt;/code&gt; scope, and the &lt;code&gt;address&lt;/code&gt; claim can be obtained by using the &lt;code&gt;address&lt;/code&gt; scope.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For all newly introduced claims, we store them in the &lt;code&gt;user.profile&lt;/code&gt; field.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[!Note]
Unlike other database fields (e.g. &lt;code&gt;name&lt;/code&gt;), the claims stored in the &lt;code&gt;profile&lt;/code&gt; field will fall back to &lt;code&gt;undefined&lt;/code&gt; rather than &lt;code&gt;null&lt;/code&gt;. We refrain from using &lt;code&gt;?? null&lt;/code&gt; here to reduce the size of ID tokens, since &lt;code&gt;undefined&lt;/code&gt; fields will be stripped in tokens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Social data&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to the claims that Logto recognizes, all social connectors now also store the raw data returned by the social provider in the &lt;code&gt;rawData&lt;/code&gt; field.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To access this data in a user object, you can use the &lt;code&gt;user.identities.[idp-name].details.rawData&lt;/code&gt; field.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Lazy password migration&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When migrating users from a legacy system to Logto, you can now use the &lt;code&gt;passwordAlgorithm&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;passwordDigest&lt;/code&gt; fields in the &lt;code&gt;POST /users&lt;/code&gt; API to store the user's original password hash.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently supported algorithms are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bcrypt&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MD5&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SHA1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SHA256&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Argon2i&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the user logs in, Logto will use the provided algorithm and digest to verify the password; if the verification succeeds, Logto will automatically migrate the password to the new Argon2 hash.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See &lt;a href="https://openapi.logto.io/operation/operation-post-api-users"&gt;API reference&lt;/a&gt; for more information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Improvements&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Support &lt;code&gt;avatar&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;customData&lt;/code&gt; fields in the &lt;code&gt;POST /users&lt;/code&gt; API.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Support signing key rotation in Logto OSS Console.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Carry over search params to the authentication request in the live preview (demo app).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When entering the Logto demo app with search parameters, if the user is not authenticated, the search parameters are now carried over to the authentication request. This allows manual testing of the OIDC authentication flow with specific parameters.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;GET /organization-roles&lt;/code&gt; can now be called with the &lt;code&gt;q&lt;/code&gt; query parameter to filter the results by the role id, name, or description.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Fixes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Console: Fixed issues in the Microsoft social connector integration guide.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Console: To create a new API resource, the indicator must be a valid absolute URI.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Experience: Resolved third-party app's &lt;code&gt;/interaction/consent&lt;/code&gt; endpoint 500 error.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Experience: Skip non-object messages in the native environment. This fixes an issue in the &lt;code&gt;WKWebView&lt;/code&gt; of new iOS versions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Development&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;@logto/connector-kit&lt;/code&gt;: [BREAKING] update &lt;code&gt;SocialUserInfo&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;GetUserInfo&lt;/code&gt; types&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;@logto/connector-kit&lt;/code&gt;: [BREAKING] guard results of &lt;code&gt;parseJson&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;parseJsonObject&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/logto-io/logto/releases/tag/v1.15.0" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/logto-io/logto/releases/tag/v1.16.0</id>
    <title>New release for Logto: v1.16.0</title>
    <updated>2024-05-14T23:04:58-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>logto-io/logto</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h2&gt;Custom JWT&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;JWT access tokens can now be customized with additional claims using custom JavaScript code snippets. This feature is useful when you need to include custom data in the token for compatibility with other systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To use this feature, navigate to the "Custom JWT" tab in the Console. Both user and machine-to-machine (M2M) tokens can be customized.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width="1373" alt="image" src="https://github.com/logto-io/logto/assets/14722250/be46e384-1b9d-4ba3-b052-37ba29c51a6b"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before deploying the changes, you can use the "Run test" button to see how the token will look with the custom claims.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See &lt;a href="https://docs.logto.io/docs/recipes/custom-jwt/"&gt;🎫 Custom JWT claims&lt;/a&gt; for more information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[!Warning]
In the open-source version, the code for custom JWT will run in the same environment as the rest of the Logto code. Be careful when adding custom code to the JWT, as it can introduce security vulnerabilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;API resources for organization roles&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can now assign permissions (scopes) from the API resources to organization roles. Like other permissions in the organization template, these permissions are organization-level, meaning that they only apply to a specific organization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width="600" alt="image" src="https://github.com/logto-io/logto/assets/14722250/d9f783a4-4661-42b8-b92a-3a60f07e8b51"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let's see an example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There is an API resource called &lt;code&gt;https://shopping.api/&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The API resource has two scopes: &lt;code&gt;read&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;write&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There are two organization roles: &lt;code&gt;admin&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;user&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;code&gt;admin&lt;/code&gt; role has both &lt;code&gt;read&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;write&lt;/code&gt; scopes; the &lt;code&gt;user&lt;/code&gt; role has only the &lt;code&gt;read&lt;/code&gt; scope.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A user Alice is assigned the &lt;code&gt;admin&lt;/code&gt; role in the organization &lt;code&gt;foo&lt;/code&gt;, and the &lt;code&gt;user&lt;/code&gt; role in the organization &lt;code&gt;bar&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When Alice tries to exchange an &lt;strong&gt;organization token&lt;/strong&gt; for the &lt;code&gt;https://shopping.api/&lt;/code&gt; resource, she will receive a token with scopes based on which organization she is requesting the token for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the &lt;code&gt;foo&lt;/code&gt; organization, Alice will receive a token with both &lt;code&gt;read&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;write&lt;/code&gt; scopes. For the &lt;code&gt;bar&lt;/code&gt; organization, she will receive a token with only the &lt;code&gt;read&lt;/code&gt; scope.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See &lt;a href="https://docs.logto.io/docs/recipes/organizations/"&gt;🏢 Organizations (Multi-tenancy)&lt;/a&gt; for a comprehensive introduction to organizations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Third-party app permissions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Organizational API resources can also be used when configuring permissions for third-party apps. User will be prompted to select an organization when configuring permissions for a third-party app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width="480" alt="image" src="https://github.com/logto-io/logto/assets/14722250/a7b16b10-9e87-4b04-8fc1-762ab1daa47a" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Organization custom data&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now you can save additional data associated with the organization with the organization-level &lt;code&gt;customData&lt;/code&gt; field by:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Editing in the Console organization details page.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Specifying the &lt;code&gt;customData&lt;/code&gt; field when using organization Management APIs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Connectors&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added Hugging Face connector.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GitHub connector now has the &lt;code&gt;user:email&lt;/code&gt; as part of default scope to fetch GitHub account's private email address list.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It now picks the verified primary email among private email address list as a fallback if the user does not set a public email for GitHub account.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Removed the plus sign in front of the phone number in the feishu connector (#5801). Credit @kamto7.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Improvements&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added support for Redis Cluster and extra TLS options for Redis connections (#5619). Credit @alekitto.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;OIDC and OAuth 2 connectors now support &lt;code&gt;client_secret_basic&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;client_secret_jwt&lt;/code&gt; client authentication methods for the token endpoint.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When a user is deleted or suspended through Management API, they will be signed out in Logto and their sessions will be invalidated immediately.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Support comma separated &lt;code&gt;resource&lt;/code&gt; parameter as some libraries do not support array of resources.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added an API to fetch user organization scopes based on user organization roles (&lt;code&gt;GET /api/organizations/:id/users/:userId/scopes&lt;/code&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added Java Spring Boot web integration guide.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added &lt;code&gt;zh-cn&lt;/code&gt; phrases in OIDC consent page (#5606). Credit @the-pawn-2017.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Fixes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Organization invitation APIs should handle invitee emails case insensitively.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Management API will not return 500 in production for status codes that are not listed in the OpenAPI spec.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Return 403 instead of 400 when Logto tries to grant an access token to a user lacking the required permissions, especially when granting for organization related resources.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed the wrong social sign-in callback that posts to the native container (e.g. WKWebView in iOS).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed the new user from SSO register hook event not triggering bug.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed a bug that API resource indicator does not work if the indicator is not followed by a trailing slash or a pathname.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/logto-io/logto/releases/tag/v1.16.0" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/logto-io/logto/releases/tag/v1.17.0</id>
    <title>New release for Logto: v1.17.0</title>
    <updated>2024-05-31T12:00:09-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>logto-io/logto</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[!Note]
The US region is now available in Logto Cloud.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;New webhook events&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are introducing a series of new webhook events triggered by data updates, mostly through the Management API, which are useful for various automation scenarios. These include user events, role events, organization events, etc. For the full list of events, please see &lt;a href="https://docs.logto.io/docs/recipes/webhooks/webhook-events/"&gt;Webhook events&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width="1027" alt="image" src="https://github.com/logto-io/logto/assets/14722250/2b4a211d-a622-47ea-97a3-9529b5eee5ed"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To improve clarity, the Console now displays the raw event key instead of the translated text for webhooks. For example, "Create new account" is now displayed as "PostRegister".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;User default roles&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can now set default roles for users by visiting the role details page, clicking on the "General" tab, and then enabling the "Default role" switch. Once activated, all new users will automatically be assigned all the default roles upon account creation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This enables you to configure Logto apps with resources and scopes associated with a default role, ensuring new users receive the necessary scopes right after registration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width="648" alt="image" src="https://github.com/logto-io/logto/assets/14722250/5f7abe90-51ed-43e3-8ed3-a1e774c5698d"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[!Note]
All existing users will not be affected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Improvements&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;5915 Added DingTalk web connector (credit @anyidea).&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;5908 A pre-configured role with Management API access will be created when seeding the database.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;5955 Added &lt;code&gt;sso_identities&lt;/code&gt; ID token claim to the userinfo endpoint response. It is an array of objects that stores the current user's SSO identities.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To request this claim, you can use the &lt;code&gt;identities&lt;/code&gt; scope which is shared with social identities.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;5950 In OSS, show the current version number in the top right corner.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved error handling and deleted item display on Console.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Show global loading state on page redirects to prevent user interactions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Updated documentation reference links.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Fixes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;5925 GitHub connector: Fix a potential blocking error in when &lt;code&gt;GET /users/emails&lt;/code&gt; responds 403&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;5912 Fixed Microsoft EntraID OIDC SSO connector invalid authorization code response issue&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/logto-io/logto/releases/tag/v1.17.0" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
