<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://selfh.st/apps</id>
  <title>Logto Releases</title>
  <updated>2025-03-25T14:33:14.629592-04:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>selfh.st</name>
    <email>contact@selfh.st</email>
  </author>
  <link href="https://selfh.st/apps" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>Self-hosted software releases generated by selfh.st</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/logto-io/logto/releases/tag/v1.23.0</id>
    <title>New release for Logto: v1.23.0</title>
    <updated>2025-01-02T01:57:53-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>logto-io/logto</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="logto-changelog-2025-01" src="https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/b35196c7-3a33-4e22-bcbb-543a195201f6" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Customizable MFA prompt policy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can now customize the MFA prompt policy in the Console.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, choose if you want to enable &lt;strong&gt;Require MFA&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Enable&lt;/strong&gt;: Users will be prompted to set up MFA during the sign-in process, which cannot be skipped. If the user fails to set up MFA or deletes their MFA settings, they will be locked out of their account until they set up MFA again.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disable&lt;/strong&gt;: Users can skip the MFA setup process during the sign-up or sign-in flow.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you choose to &lt;strong&gt;Disable&lt;/strong&gt;, you can continue to choose the MFA setup prompt:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do not ask users to set up MFA.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ask users to set up MFA during registration (skippable, one-time prompt). &lt;strong&gt;The same prompt as the previous policy (UserControlled)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ask users to set up MFA on their next sign-in attempt after registration (skippable, one-time prompt).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Relaxed redirect URI restrictions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have been following the industry best practices for OAuth2.0 and OIDC from the start. However, in the real world, there are things we cannot control, like third-party services or operation systems like Windows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This update relaxes restrictions on redirect URIs to allow the following:
- A mix of native and HTTP(S) redirect URIs. For example, a native app can now use a redirect URI like &lt;code&gt;https://example.com/&lt;/code&gt;.
- Native schemes without a period (&lt;code&gt;.&lt;/code&gt;). For example, &lt;code&gt;myapp://callback&lt;/code&gt; is now allowed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When such URIs are configured, Logto Console will display a prominent warning. This change is backward-compatible and will not affect existing applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We hope this change will make it easier for you to integrate Logto with your applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;New connectors&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3fa2b796e Added Xiaomi social connector (credit @u0x01 ).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3004ae9a6 Added YunPian SMS connector (credit @u0x01 ).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Bug fixes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;217858950 Fixed the CLI command for fetching official connectors by updating the npm registry API integration.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/logto-io/logto/releases/tag/v1.23.0" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/logto-io/logto/releases/tag/v1.23.1</id>
    <title>New release for Logto: v1.23.1</title>
    <updated>2025-01-23T03:03:14-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>logto-io/logto</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h2&gt;Support custom endpoint and addressing style for S3&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Add support for configurable S3 endpoint and addressing style (path-style/virtual-hosted)
to improve compatibility with S3-compatible storage services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add forcePathStyle option to control URL addressing style&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix custom endpoint support implementation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improve URL generation logic for different configurations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Bug fixes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Fix the broken image on Logto console sign-in page&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remove the image element's &lt;code&gt;cross-origin="anonymous"&lt;/code&gt; attribute.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some public image resources may not have the proper cross-origin headers configured, those images may fail to load when the &lt;code&gt;cross-origin="anonymous" attribute is present.&lt;/code&gt;
Since sign-in page image elements are only used for display purposes, Logto does not need to access the image data, so the &lt;code&gt;cross-origin="anonymous"&lt;/code&gt; attribute is not necessary.To make the image elements more compatible with public image resources, remove the attribute from the image elements.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/logto-io/logto/releases/tag/v1.23.1" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/logto-io/logto/releases/tag/v1.24.0</id>
    <title>New release for Logto: v1.24.0</title>
    <updated>2025-02-07T02:18:44-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>logto-io/logto</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="logto-changelog-2025-02" src="https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/9b88d729-b8f9-49d5-8af4-7c33771518be" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Support SAML applications&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Logto now supports acting as a SAML identity provider (IdP), enabling enterprise users to achieve secure Single Sign-On (SSO) through the standardized SAML protocol. Key features include:
&lt;img alt="saml-app-demo" src="https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/ed134fc2-979c-47c8-99f8-c766698964c9" /&gt;
- Full support for SAML 2.0 protocol
- Flexible attribute mapping configuration
- Metadata auto-configuration support
- Enterprise-grade encryption and signing&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://docs.logto.io/integrate-logto/saml-app"&gt;View full documentation&lt;/a&gt; for more details.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Add HTTP email connector&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Users can now use HTTP email connector for sending emails.
The HTTP email connector allows you to send emails via HTTP call. To use the HTTP email connector, you'll need to have your own email service that expose an HTTP API for sending emails. Logto will call this API when it needs to send an email. For example, when a user registers, Logto will call the HTTP API to send a verification email.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Bug fixes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;62eb8ed Fixed the issue where the CLI could not correctly initialize the Logto instance or deploy database alterations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;bf2d300 Fixed the bug that a user accepts an invitation and join an organization does not trigger the &lt;code&gt;Organization.Membership.Updated&lt;/code&gt; webhook.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/logto-io/logto/releases/tag/v1.24.0" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/logto-io/logto/releases/tag/v1.24.1</id>
    <title>New release for Logto: v1.24.1</title>
    <updated>2025-02-21T02:50:20-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>logto-io/logto</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="logto-changelog-2025-02-v2 (1)" src="https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/becf45d6-54e6-486e-bb99-a284e43301d8" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;New connectors:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;X (Twitter) social connector&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Slack social connector&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;LinkedIn social connector&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Line social connector&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Amazon social connector&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Bug fixes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;https://github.com/logto-io/logto/commit/cb261024b6d8ce1a708d2359d8843aa052aaff01: fix cli add offical connectors command missing connectors bug
  Fix the bug when running the cli commend logto connectors add --official, only 8 connectors are fetched from npm registry.
  This fix update logic to query additional pages of results when fetching connectors from the npm registry.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;https://github.com/logto-io/logto/commit/0b785ee0d8e1156607f5185c51e9a21fbae76a4d: display JWKS URI on application details page&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;https://github.com/logto-io/logto/commit/e7accfdab9c646dfe60dd0728c9566823fe18188: prevent i18n context contamination by using request-scoped instances
  This bug fix resolves a concurrency issue in i18n handling by moving from a global i18next instance to request-scoped instances.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Problem&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When handling concurrent requests:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The shared global &lt;code&gt;i18next&lt;/code&gt; instance's language was being modified via &lt;code&gt;changeLanguage()&lt;/code&gt; calls.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This could lead to race conditions where requests might receive translations in unexpected languages.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Particularly problematic in multi-tenant environments with different language requirements.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Solution&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Updated &lt;code&gt;koaI18next&lt;/code&gt; middleware to create a cloned i18next instance for each request.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Attach the request-scoped instance to Koa context (&lt;code&gt;ctx.i18n&lt;/code&gt;) All subsequent middleware and handlers should now use &lt;code&gt;ctx.i18n&lt;/code&gt; instead of the global &lt;code&gt;i18next&lt;/code&gt; instance.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Maintains the global instance for initialization while preventing cross-request contamination&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a5990ec57: fixes an incorrect condition check in the verification code flow where &lt;code&gt;isNewIdentifier&lt;/code&gt; was using inverted logic for email and phone comparisons.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Changes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Corrected &lt;code&gt;isNewIdentifier&lt;/code&gt; boolean logic to use &lt;code&gt;identifier.value !== user.primaryEmail&lt;/code&gt; for email checks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed phone number comparison to properly use &lt;code&gt;identifier.value !== user.primaryPhone&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Impact&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This fixes a regression where:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Verification codes for existing emails/phones were incorrectly using the&lt;code&gt;BindNewIdentifier&lt;/code&gt; template&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New identifiers were mistakenly getting the &lt;code&gt;UserPermissionValidation&lt;/code&gt; template&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Affected both email and phone verification flows&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;28643c1f1: fix the email/phone identifier conflict handling logic during user registration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When a user attempts to register with an email/phone that already exists:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Previous Behavior&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"Sign in instead" modal will be shown when:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The email/phone identifier has been verified through a verification code validation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Identifier type (email/phone) was enabled in sign-in methods&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This caused an issue when:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Only password authentication method was enabled in the sign-in method settings.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When users clicked "Sign in instead" action button, the API call will throw an sign-in method not enabled error. Which is confusing for the user.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Expected behavior: Show the "Email/phone already exists" error modal directly. If only password authentication is enabled. User should not be able to sign in with email/phone directly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Fixed Behavior&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shows the "Sign in instead" modal if:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The email/phone identifier type is enabled in the sign-in method settings and the verification code is enabled for the identifier.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Otherwise, shows the "Email/phone already exists" error modal directly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;bd18da4cf: properly filter WeChat connectors by platform (Web | Native) in SSR sign-in experience settings&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Previously, platform-based social connector filtering was applied during the sign-in experience settings fetch process but not in the SSR sign-in experience data. As a result, platform-specific connectors were not correctly filtered when rendering the page using SSR data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This update ensures that the same filtering logic is applied to SSR sign-in experience data, resolving the issue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Affected connectors: WeChat Web and WeChat Native.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/logto-io/logto/releases/tag/v1.24.1" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/logto-io/logto/releases/tag/v1.25.0</id>
    <title>New release for Logto: v1.25.0</title>
    <updated>2025-02-28T02:22:39-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>logto-io/logto</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="logto-changelog-2025-02-03" src="https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/da32196e-e402-4591-9dc2-9e25eb9a6de5" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Support custom email templates in multiple languages via Management API&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Introduce localized email template customization capabilities. This update allows administrators to create and manage multiple email templates for different languages and template types (e.g., SignIn, ForgotPassword) via the management API.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Email connectors now support automatic template selection based on the user's preferred language. If a template is not available in the user's preferred language, the default template will be used.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For client-side API requests, like experience API and user account API, the user's preferred language is determined by the &lt;code&gt;Accept-Language&lt;/code&gt; header.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For server-side API requests, like organization invitation API, email language preference can be set by passing extra &lt;code&gt;locale&lt;/code&gt; parameter in the &lt;code&gt;messagePayload&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The email template selection logic is based on the following priority order:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Find the template that matches the user's preferred language detected from the request.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Find the template that matches the default language set in the sign-in experience settings.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use the default template set in the email connector settings.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Management API&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;PUT /email-templates&lt;/code&gt;: Bulk create or update email templates.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;GET /email-templates&lt;/code&gt;: List all email templates with filter by language and type support.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;DELETE /email-templates&lt;/code&gt;: Bulk delete email templates by language and type.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;GET /email-templates/{id}&lt;/code&gt;: Get a specific email template by ID.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;DELETE /email-templates/{id}&lt;/code&gt;: Delete a specific email template by ID.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;PATCH /email-templates/{id}/details&lt;/code&gt;: Update email template details by ID.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Supported email connectors&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;@logto/connector-aliyun-dm&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;@logto/connector-aws-ses&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;@logto/connector-mailgun&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;@logto/connector-sendgrid-email&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;@logto/connector-smtp&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Unsupported email connectors&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following email connectors have their templates managed at the provider side and do not support reading templates from Logto.
The user's preferred language will be passed to the provider as the &lt;code&gt;locale&lt;/code&gt; parameter in the email sending request payload. For i18n support, administrators must manage the template selection logic at the provider side.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;@logto/connector-postmark&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;@logto/connector-http-email&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Pass additional context variables to email templates&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enhanced email template customization by introducing additional context variables that developers can utilize in message templates. These new variables provide deeper contextual information about the authentication workflow, enabling more personalized and scenario-specific email content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;user&lt;/code&gt;: &lt;code&gt;UserInfo&lt;/code&gt; - Contains basic user profile data (name, primaryEmail, etc.) for personalization&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;application&lt;/code&gt;: &lt;code&gt;ApplicationInfo&lt;/code&gt; - Contains basic application-specific data (name, logo, etc.) for personalization&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;organization&lt;/code&gt;: &lt;code&gt;OrganizationInfo&lt;/code&gt; - Contains basic organization-specific data (name, logo, etc.) for personalization&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;inviter&lt;/code&gt;: &lt;code&gt;UserInfo&lt;/code&gt; - Contains basic inviter profile data (name, primaryEmail, etc.) for personalization&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;| usageType                | Scenario                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                      | Variables                                                                             |
| ------------------------ | ----------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------- | ------------------------------------------------------------------------------------- |
| SignIn                   | Users sign in using their email and verify by entering verification code instead of entering a password.                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                      | code: string&lt;br/&gt;application: &lt;code&gt;ApplicationInfo&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br/&gt;organization?: &lt;code&gt;OrganizationInfo&lt;/code&gt; |
| Register                 | Users create an account using their email and verify it by entering a verification code sent by Logto to their email.                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                         | code: string&lt;br/&gt;application: &lt;code&gt;ApplicationInfo&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br/&gt;organization?: &lt;code&gt;OrganizationInfo&lt;/code&gt; |
| ForgotPassword           | If users forget their password during login, they can choose to verify their identity using the email they've already verified with Logto.                                                                                                                                                                                                                                    | code: string&lt;br/&gt;application: &lt;code&gt;ApplicationInfo&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br/&gt;organization?: &lt;code&gt;OrganizationInfo&lt;/code&gt; |
| Generic                  | This template can be used as a general backup option for various scenarios, including testing connector configurations and so on.                                                                                                                                                                                                                                             | code: string                                                                          |
| OrganizationInvitation   | Use this template to send users an invitation link to join the organization.                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                  | link: string&lt;br/&gt;organization: &lt;code&gt;OrganizationInfo&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br/&gt;inviter?: &lt;code&gt;UserInfo&lt;/code&gt;            |
| UserPermissionValidation | During app usage, there may be some high-risk operations or operations with a relatively high risk level that require additional user verification, such as bank transfers, deleting resources in use, and canceling memberships. The &lt;code&gt;UserPermissionValidation&lt;/code&gt; template can be used to define the content of the email verification code users receive in these situations. | code: string&lt;br/&gt;user: &lt;code&gt;UserInfo&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br/&gt;application?: &lt;code&gt;ApplicationInfo&lt;/code&gt;                 |
| BindNewIdentifier        | When a user modifies their profile, they may bind an email address to their current account. In this case, the &lt;code&gt;BindNewIdentifier&lt;/code&gt; template can be used to customize the content of the verification email.                                                                                                                                                                   | code: string&lt;br/&gt;user: &lt;code&gt;UserInfo&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br/&gt;application?: &lt;code&gt;ApplicationInfo&lt;/code&gt;                 |&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check &lt;a href="https://docs.logto.io/connectors/email-connectors/email-templates"&gt;Email templates&lt;/a&gt; for more information on how to use these new context variables in your email templates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Improvements&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/logto-io/logto/commit/1c7bdf9ba53ab795e6ccb3e99a60b7be39d4f8d4"&gt;1c7bdf9ba&lt;/a&gt;: add legacy password type supporting custom hasing function, credits @fre2d0m&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can now set the type of &lt;code&gt;password_encryption_method&lt;/code&gt; to &lt;code&gt;legacy&lt;/code&gt;, and store info with a JSON string format (containing a hash algorithm, arguments, and an encrypted password) in the &lt;code&gt;password_encrypted&lt;/code&gt; field. By doing this, you can use any hash algorithm supported by Node.js, this is useful when migrating from other password hash algorithms, especially for the ones that include salt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The format of the JSON string is as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;json
  ["hash_algorithm", ["argument1", "argument2", ...], "expected_hashed_value"]&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And you can use &lt;code&gt;@&lt;/code&gt; as the input password in the arguments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, if you are using SHA256 with a salt, you can store the password in the following format:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;json
  [
    "sha256",
    ["salt123", "@"],
    "c465f66c6ac481a7a17e9ed5b4e2e7e7288d892f12bf1c95c140901e9a70436e"
  ]&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then when the user uses the password (&lt;code&gt;password123&lt;/code&gt;), the &lt;code&gt;legacyVerify&lt;/code&gt; function will use the &lt;code&gt;sha256&lt;/code&gt; algorithm with the &lt;code&gt;salt123&lt;/code&gt; and the input password to verify the password.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this case, &lt;code&gt;salt123&lt;/code&gt; is the first argument, &lt;code&gt;@&lt;/code&gt; is the input password, then the following code will be executed:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;ts
  const hash = crypto.createHash("sha256");
  hash.update("salt123" + "password123");
  const expectedHashedValue = hash.digest("hex");&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/logto-io/logto/commit/b0135bcd3c7385245ec3edc000ede8470b82b006"&gt;b0135bcd3&lt;/a&gt;: enhanced handlebars template processing in the connector to support nested property access in email template variables&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;### Updates&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Updated &lt;code&gt;replaceSendMessageHandlebars&lt;/code&gt; logic to handle nested property paths in template variables&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Latest template processing logic now supports:&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Direct replacement of primitive values (string/number/null/undefined)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deep property access using dot-notation (e.g., &lt;code&gt;organization.branding.logoUrl&lt;/code&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Graceful handling of missing properties (replaces with empty string)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Preservation of original handlebars when variables aren't provided in payload&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;### Examples&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Direct replacement&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;ts
  replaceSendMessageKeysWithPayload("Your verification code is {{code}}", {
    code: "123456",
  });
  // 'Your verification code is 123456'&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deep property access&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;ts
  replaceSendMessageKeysWithPayload(
    "Your logo is {{organization.branding.logoUrl}}",
    { organization: { branding: { logoUrl: "https://example.com/logo.png" } } }
  );
  // 'Your logo is https://example.com/logo.png'&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Missing properties&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;ts
  replaceSendMessageKeysWithPayload(
    "Your logo is {{organization.branding.logoUrl}}",
    { organization: { name: "foo" } }
  );
  // 'Your logo is '&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Preservation of missing variables&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;ts
  replaceSendMessageKeysWithPayload(
    "Your application is {{application.name}}",
    {}
  );
  // 'Your application is {{application.name}}'&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/logto-io/logto/commit/c874240258a36c6c46b690e2bce98cbd71265e85"&gt;c87424025&lt;/a&gt;: support role names alongside role IDs in organization user role assignment/replacement with merge capability&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This update enhances organization user role management APIs to support role assignment by both names and IDs, improving integration flexibility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added &lt;code&gt;organizationRoleNames&lt;/code&gt; parameter to:&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;POST &lt;code&gt;/api/organizations/{id}/users/{userId}/roles&lt;/code&gt; (assign roles)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PUT &lt;code&gt;/api/organizations/{id}/users/{userId}/roles&lt;/code&gt; (replace roles)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make both &lt;code&gt;organizationRoleNames&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;organizationRoleIds&lt;/code&gt; optional in the above APIs&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If both are not provided, or empty, an invalid data error will be thrown&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Merge logic when both parameters are provided:&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Combines roles from &lt;code&gt;organizationRoleNames&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;organizationRoleIds&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Automatically deduplicates entries&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Validates all names/IDs exist before applying changes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Maintains backward compatibility with existing integrations using role IDs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Fixes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/logto-io/logto/commit/edeb7cc8daabfbedb968513485d531f0a7a6c60d"&gt;edeb7cc8d&lt;/a&gt;: add &lt;code&gt;AuthnStatement&lt;/code&gt; to SAML app assertion response&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/logto-io/logto/commit/b2a77d79c1c9c56c1320c4954dd5099420605bb1"&gt;b2a77d79c&lt;/a&gt;: add &lt;code&gt;strictPhoneRegionNumberCheck&lt;/code&gt; to config with default value &lt;code&gt;false&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When this configuration is enabled, the connector will assume by default that all phone numbers include a valid region code and rely on this to determine whether the phone number belongs to mainland China. If your users' phone numbers do not include a region code due to historical reasons, their sign-in processes may be affected. Please enable this setting with caution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/logto-io/logto/commit/20b61e05e7c5b0e3f4ec7ed67bfff85a9845185d"&gt;20b61e05e&lt;/a&gt;: adjust TOTP secret length to 20 bytes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Update the TOTP secret generation to use 20 bytes (160 bits), following the recommendation in RFC 6238 (TOTP) and RFC 4226 (HOTP).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This aligns with the standard secret length used by most 2FA applications and provides better security while maintaining compatibility with existing TOTP validators.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reference:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RFC 6238 (TOTP) Section 5.1: https://www.rfc-editor.org/rfc/rfc6238#section-5.1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;RFC 4226 (HOTP) Section 4, Requirement 6: https://www.rfc-editor.org/rfc/rfc4226#section-4&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/logto-io/logto/commit/f15602f198f0dce049fec887ae6315a752263466"&gt;f15602f19&lt;/a&gt;: incorrect pagination behavior in organization role scopes APIs&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fix &lt;code&gt;/api/organization-roles/{id}/scopes&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;/api/organization-roles/{id}/resource-scopes&lt;/code&gt; endpoints to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Return all scopes when no pagination parameters are provided&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Support optional pagination when query parameters are present&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix Console to properly display all organization role scopes on the organization template page&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/logto-io/logto/releases/tag/v1.25.0" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
