<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://selfh.st/apps</id>
  <title>Mastonaut Releases</title>
  <updated>2024-12-14T00:33:41.787579-05:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>selfh.st</name>
    <email>contact@selfh.st</email>
  </author>
  <link href="https://selfh.st/apps" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>Self-hosted software releases generated by selfh.st</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/mastodon/mastodon-ios/releases/tag/2024.7</id>
    <title>New release for Mastodon: 2024.7</title>
    <updated>2024-07-02T11:11:37-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>mastodon/mastodon-ios</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h1&gt;App Store Release Notes&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Long time no see! Okay, joke's on us as it has been just a week or so since the last release. But we've been busy and this is why you can enjoy these rather short release notes for the latest and greatest 2024.7-release of Mastodon for iOS. It contains not one, but two improvements and bug fixes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We fixed a bug! In case you wanted to translate a reblogged status, this failed, but not anymore, as we fixed this! (IOS-271)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An improvement! If the author of a blogpost or a newspaper article or a video producer or any other content creator on the internet has a Mastodon-account (and did some configuration), you will see a small, additional button if someone posts a link to their written piece or video or content in general. This button leads you to the author's profile so that you can discover more of their content. (IOS-284)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We hope that these numerous changes help you discover more content you like, but: No pressure! Use Mastodon only as much as it feels good to you. We don't want to lurk you in as we all know: There are way more important things in life than social media. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As always: This release wouldn't have been possible without your ongoing support. Thank you so much for that and for using Mastodon. It sparks so much joy to see people using the stuff you built. Until next time!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Github-Release Notes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IOS-271: Fix translate functionality leads to empty status content by @kimar in https://github.com/mastodon/mastodon-ios/pull/1320&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Show author in Card (IOS-284) by @zeitschlag in https://github.com/mastodon/mastodon-ios/pull/1321&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New Crowdin updates by @Gargron in https://github.com/mastodon/mastodon-ios/pull/1318&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Full Changelog&lt;/strong&gt;: https://github.com/mastodon/mastodon-ios/compare/2024.6...2024.7&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/mastodon/mastodon-ios/releases/tag/2024.7" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/mastodon/mastodon-ios/releases/tag/2024.8</id>
    <title>New release for Mastodon: 2024.8</title>
    <updated>2024-08-08T05:53:09-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>mastodon/mastodon-ios</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h2&gt;App Store Release Notes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hey there! We’ve got some nifty updates for you in this release. Now you can check out your lists right in the app, because who doesn’t love a good list? If your server is feeling generous, you’ll enjoy our new notification filters. Filter away! We’ve sorted out the character counter on the compose screen, so you can add links without any counting mishaps. Crash fixes galore! The app is now more stable than your morning coffee routine. Widgets can finally retrieve data, and shortcuts are back to posting like champs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks for sticking with us and for all your feedback. We hope these tweaks make your app experience even better! Enjoy the update!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Github Release Notes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add authorization to custom emojis by @zeitschlag in https://github.com/mastodon/mastodon-ios/pull/1324&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Implement Lists and Hashtags Menu (and timeline) (IOS-102) by @kimar in https://github.com/mastodon/mastodon-ios/pull/1325&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix WidgetCrash and MastodonIntent not able to load data (IOS-262) by @kimar in https://github.com/mastodon/mastodon-ios/pull/1326&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix: Remove charset from application/json content type by @nikclayton in https://github.com/mastodon/mastodon-ios/pull/1327&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixes for empty list state and hashtags (IOS-287) by @kimar in https://github.com/mastodon/mastodon-ios/pull/1328&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Notification Filtering (IOS-241) by @zeitschlag in https://github.com/mastodon/mastodon-ios/pull/1319&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Align dismiss icon for notification filters with web by @kimar in https://github.com/mastodon/mastodon-ios/pull/1331&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New Crowdin updates by @Gargron in https://github.com/mastodon/mastodon-ios/pull/1323&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix notification filters touches plural string by @kimar in https://github.com/mastodon/mastodon-ios/pull/1334&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix link char count (IOS-285) by @kimar in https://github.com/mastodon/mastodon-ios/pull/1336&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;New Contributors&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;@nikclayton made their first contribution in https://github.com/mastodon/mastodon-ios/pull/1327&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Full Changelog&lt;/strong&gt;: https://github.com/mastodon/mastodon-ios/compare/2024.7...2024.8-6769&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/mastodon/mastodon-ios/releases/tag/2024.8" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/mastodon/mastodon-ios/releases/tag/2024.9</id>
    <title>New release for Mastodon: 2024.9</title>
    <updated>2024-09-12T03:16:53-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>mastodon/mastodon-ios</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h2&gt;App Store Release Notes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ve fixed bugs and improved stability with this release.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Github Release Notes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bump FaviconFinder to 4.5.0 (IOS-289) by @kimar in https://github.com/mastodon/mastodon-ios/pull/1343&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Full Changelog&lt;/strong&gt;: https://github.com/mastodon/mastodon-ios/compare/2024.8...2024.9&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/mastodon/mastodon-ios/releases/tag/2024.9" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/mastodon/mastodon-ios/releases/tag/2024.10</id>
    <title>New release for Mastodon: 2024.10</title>
    <updated>2024-10-23T11:17:57-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>mastodon/mastodon-ios</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h2&gt;App Store Release Notes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ve tweaked the app icon to make it perfectly integrate into the system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What's Changed&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New Crowdin updates by @Gargron in https://github.com/mastodon/mastodon-ios/pull/1337&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Implement new Icons (IOS-290) by @kimar in https://github.com/mastodon/mastodon-ios/pull/1347&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Full Changelog&lt;/strong&gt;: https://github.com/mastodon/mastodon-ios/compare/2024.9...2024.10&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/mastodon/mastodon-ios/releases/tag/2024.10" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/mastodon/mastodon-ios/releases/tag/2024.11</id>
    <title>New release for Mastodon: 2024.11</title>
    <updated>2024-12-02T10:00:56-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>mastodon/mastodon-ios</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;Just in time for Giving Tuesday, you may now see a banner at the bottom of your timeline inviting your support for Mastodon’s continued development (only when logged in to &lt;a href="http://mastodon.social"&gt;[mastodon.social](http://mastodon.social/)&lt;/a&gt; or mastodon.online). You’ll also see a bunch of improvements, small and large:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Filters work better!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Concealed posts no longer take up the full space of their content, which should make scrolling past them less arduous.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Filtered posts now tell you which filter they triggered!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Filters with the “hide” action should now actually remove posts from your feed completely, as intended.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Content warnings have also been updated slightly — as on the web, if the content warning text is empty, only the attached image will be hidden.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your privacy is better guarded…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When you log out of an account, logging in again will now require re-entering the username and password.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deleting the app from your device and reinstalling will now launch as if you had never logged in.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new user experience is a little better…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The “Find people to follow” view is now dismissable even after you’ve viewed a profile.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When you follow someone from the “Find people to follow” view, your blank feed will update immediately… and hopefully show you some cool stuff!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some small visual improvements…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Vertical-stacked layout of edit history labels, which fixes some spectacularly bad layouts when the localized strings are lengthy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dark Mode icon now has a dark ‘m’.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And finally…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fewer crashes! File this under the customarily bland description “stability improvements” because although the refactoring projects involved have all the drama of sword dancing with freshly honed blades for the developer involved, you will hopefully notice nothing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/mastodon/mastodon-ios/releases/tag/2024.11" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
