<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://selfh.st/apps</id>
  <title>Medialytics Releases</title>
  <updated>2024-06-03T12:31:00.351991-04:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>selfh.st</name>
    <email>contact@selfh.st</email>
  </author>
  <link href="https://selfh.st/apps" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>Self-hosted software releases generated by selfh.st</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/Drewpeifer/medialytics/releases/tag/v2.1.0</id>
    <title>New release for Medialytics: v2.1.0</title>
    <updated>2023-10-15T19:01:44-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Drewpeifer/medialytics</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;2.1 - Feedback + Docker Update
&lt;em&gt;This release includes some new user-requested features, most notably the publishing of a publicly hosted docker image.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Contributions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;github user heehoo98 contributed initial dockerization files, and user jzucker2 added more code (and valuable advice) on hosting a public docker image, latest can be found at &lt;code&gt;ghcr.io/drewpeifer/medialytics:latest&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;General&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lots of cleanup, organization, and inline comments&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Renamed many variables for consistency, hopefully it's a little easier to follow now&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Converted chart colors to variables in &lt;code&gt;scripts.js&lt;/code&gt; in case you want to change them or add additional colors&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Bugs Fixed&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Limits were returning 1 less than intended when rendering certain axes of charts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;New Features&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some charts can now toggle between bar and pie by clicking the bar/pie icon in the top of their card&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some charts now allow their limit (Top "X") value to be edited within the UI. If a limit longer than the list is entered, the total length of the list is used. Extremely large values may not display as intended (which is why there are limits by default, but they can be changed to any value, e.g. 999999, at  the top of &lt;code&gt;scripts.js&lt;/code&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Now tracking dateAdded (to library) and displaying "Earliest" and "Latest" addition&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Now tracking unmatched content and displaying it as a library statistic if any are found&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Known issues:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Some XML feed metadata is truncated (by Plex)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the last update, some users reported inconsistencies with some of the counts when compared to the plex web UI. I took a look and confirmed their suspicions, this is due to the plex XML feed being a truncated version of the full data. For example, movies only return a list of 2 genres (maximum), and it seems to choose the first 2 in the full list from the web UI. So if you have a movie like "Rocky" with genres [Sports, Drama, Action], the XML feed (which Medialytics parses) only returns [Sports, Drama] and does not count Rocky towards the Action genre. Similarly, the XML feed only returns the top 3 actors for any given movie. This is a limitation of the XML feed structure itself, but is kind of understandable given the high possible number of genres and cast members returned when you query a single entry directly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Server "added" dates can be inaccurate&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This update now tracks the earliest item added to your library, as well as the most recent. I only have my own Plex server to test on, and I see some unexpected dates returned for the earliest addition (Plex reports 1-1-2000 for several items). I am not sure how Plex actually tracks or calculates this number, but I assume its accuracy could be affected by the age of your server, or the number of times you have migrated your server, libraries, hard drive volumes, etc. I'll continue to look into it but I haven't figured it out yet, but I figured that value might be more accurate for other people (?) so I left it in the UI for now.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/Drewpeifer/medialytics/releases/tag/v2.1.0" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/Drewpeifer/medialytics/releases/tag/v.2.1.1</id>
    <title>New release for Medialytics: v2.1.1</title>
    <updated>2023-10-21T16:15:19-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Drewpeifer/medialytics</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h2&gt;What's Changed&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Update GitHub actions to latest versions and clean up the docs around the newly hosted images by @jzucker2 in https://github.com/Drewpeifer/medialytics/pull/16&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;New Contributors&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;@jzucker2 made their first contribution in https://github.com/Drewpeifer/medialytics/pull/16&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Full Changelog&lt;/strong&gt;: https://github.com/Drewpeifer/medialytics/compare/v2.1.0...v.2.1.1&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/Drewpeifer/medialytics/releases/tag/v.2.1.1" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/Drewpeifer/medialytics/releases/tag/v2.1.2</id>
    <title>New release for Medialytics: v2.1.2</title>
    <updated>2023-12-03T14:46:56-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Drewpeifer/medialytics</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h2&gt;What's Changed&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2.1.2 by @Drewpeifer in https://github.com/Drewpeifer/medialytics/pull/17&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed display of top actor and director in charts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Removed unnecessary components in recentlyAdded API call, bumped limit to 20, long lists now scroll properly&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Made more information visible in console with debug=true&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cleaned up readme and UI surrounding versions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Full Changelog&lt;/strong&gt;: https://github.com/Drewpeifer/medialytics/compare/v2.1.1...v2.1.2&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/Drewpeifer/medialytics/releases/tag/v2.1.2" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/Drewpeifer/medialytics/releases/tag/v2.2</id>
    <title>New release for Medialytics: v2.2</title>
    <updated>2024-04-26T04:15:53-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Drewpeifer/medialytics</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Now tracking watched/unwatched status across total library, as well as within genre, studio, country, and decades charts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Full Changelog&lt;/strong&gt;: https://github.com/Drewpeifer/medialytics/compare/v2.1.2...v2.2&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width="1215" alt="Screenshot 2024-04-26 at 3 36 25 AM" src="https://github.com/Drewpeifer/medialytics/assets/30933/c0c11eae-9a3e-4ba5-96c9-e00a656d4008"&gt;
&lt;img width="1646" alt="Screenshot 2024-04-26 at 3 36 45 AM" src="https://github.com/Drewpeifer/medialytics/assets/30933/05dfe2c8-cdaf-45f2-a6b1-03be5d37202e"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/Drewpeifer/medialytics/releases/tag/v2.2" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/Drewpeifer/medialytics/releases/tag/v2.2.1</id>
    <title>New release for Medialytics: v2.2.1</title>
    <updated>2024-04-27T13:56:02-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Drewpeifer/medialytics</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;Version bump to troubleshoot workflow actions, no changes from previous version&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Full Changelog&lt;/strong&gt;: https://github.com/Drewpeifer/medialytics/compare/v2.2...v2.2.1&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/Drewpeifer/medialytics/releases/tag/v2.2.1" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
