<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://selfh.st/apps</id>
  <title>Metabase Releases</title>
  <updated>2024-06-14T00:31:47.045793-04:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>selfh.st</name>
    <email>contact@selfh.st</email>
  </author>
  <link href="https://selfh.st/apps" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>Self-hosted software releases generated by selfh.st</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/metabase/metabase/releases/tag/v0.49.15</id>
    <title>New release for Metabase: Metabase v0.49.15</title>
    <updated>2024-06-11T08:37:03-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>metabase/metabase</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Upgrading&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can download a .jar of the release, or get the latest on Docker. Make sure to back up your Metabase
database before you upgrade! Need help? Check out our &lt;a href="https://metabase.com/docs/latest/operations-guide/upgrading-metabase.html"&gt;upgrading instructions&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Docker image: &lt;a href="https://hub.docker.com/r/metabase/metabase/tags"&gt;&lt;code&gt;metabase/metabase:v0.49.15&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
Download the JAR here: https://downloads.metabase.com/v0.49.15/metabase.jar&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Notes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SHA-256 checksum for the v0.49.15 JAR:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;8019f4fdc87d2661585bd4c49c554e7f1b4c89c6b73d24bf864e86d1c4ec8a72&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;details&gt;
&lt;summary&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Changelog&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;/summary&gt;

**Bug fixes**

- Parse naked JSON values (https://github.com/metabase/metabase/pull/43812)
- Database role is not respected when private key is used in Snowflake (https://github.com/metabase/metabase/issues/43600)
- Failed to save changes to the existing report/SQL query after latest version update (https://github.com/metabase/metabase/issues/40769)
- Cannot duplicate or save questions when moving from 42 to 49 (https://github.com/metabase/metabase/issues/40600)

&lt;/details&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/metabase/metabase/releases/tag/v0.49.15" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/metabase/metabase/releases/tag/v0.50.1</id>
    <title>New release for Metabase: Metabase v0.50.1</title>
    <updated>2024-06-12T12:51:56-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>metabase/metabase</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Upgrading&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you've encrypted your database connection info, avoid this version. Some customers are having trouble during the upgrade process and we'll have a fix for that soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you're using Clickhouse as a data warehouse, hold off on upgrading for now. The Clickhouse driver for Metabase 50 isn't quite ready yet, but we wanted to release 50 now so that others can upgrade in the meantime.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can download a .jar of the release, or get the latest on Docker. Make sure to back up your Metabase
database before you upgrade! Need help? Check out our &lt;a href="https://metabase.com/docs/latest/operations-guide/upgrading-metabase.html"&gt;upgrading instructions&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Docker image: &lt;a href="https://hub.docker.com/r/metabase/metabase/tags"&gt;&lt;code&gt;metabase/metabase:v0.50.1&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
Download the JAR here: https://downloads.metabase.com/v0.50.1/metabase.jar&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Notes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SHA-256 checksum for the v0.50.1 JAR:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;6804be983500fdc535095b40ac4d7986b31d34824fc47635d09e32096deaf495&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;details&gt;
&lt;summary&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Changelog&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;/summary&gt;

### Enhancements

**Better cache controls** (#41430, #41429, #41427, #41426, #41478)
    - Add cache config form to question sidebar (#42729)
    - Tweak appearance of cache page and form (#42856, #42958)
    - Move model caching UI to Admin &gt; Performance (#43019)
    - Only show "Adaptive" and "Don't cache" options on OSS page (#43122, #43121)
    - Config should be editable if entity is accessible (#43522)
    - Fix width of save button in cache sidebar (tiny PR) (#43755)
    - Update copy on cache invalidation configuration forms (#42815)
    - Remove cache-related field from database creation form (#42808)
    - Remove cache timestamp from Question info sidebar (#42788)
    - Reduce query runs before cache hit from 3 to 2 (#35630)
    - Invalid cache-keys used for query caching (#37702)
    - Implement advanced cache strategies (#38434)
    - Basic cache admin UI (#39234)
    - Implement webhook handlers to reset/refresh query cache (#40548)
    - Add "Invalidate cache now" button (#40972)
    - Add cache configuration form to dashboard sidebar (#42192)
    - Use DelayedLoadingAndErrorWrapper component in Admin &gt; Performance (#41103)
    - Rename and re-order TTL strategy (#41108)
    - In Admin &gt; Performance, display minimum query duration in seconds (#40970)
    - Add Schedule strategy to Admin &gt; Performance (#41424, #41230)
    - In Admin &gt; Performance Data caching settings, the Save button is inaccessible when pushed offscreen by a long list of databases (#43813)

**Split data access and query builder access and merge Query Builder and SQL permissions (#26918)**
    - Newly added databases should be created with "No self-service" permissions - default permissions risks in strict data isolation contexts (#6735)
    - Not possible to view Native question unless given ad-hoc native query permissions if another group has Block (#21695)
    - Block permissions behave strangely after losing advanced permissions feature flag or switching to OSS (#20813)
    - Native query editor offers data source a user does not have native write permissions for (#39053)
    - Configuring sandboxed permissions in schemaless databases removes tables from the list (#41490)
    - Refactor `cy.updatePermissionsGraph`, `cy.updatePermissionsSchemas` &amp; `cy.updateCollectionGraph` to TypeScript (#39675, #39614)
    - No Access to Our Analytics will break the "Add to Dashboard" in multiple ways (#38856)
    - Grant Collection-only access that respects data sandboxing (#21703)
    - Block access on a database prevents executing actions and uploading CSVs, even with unrestricted access (#36298)    

**Chart appearance in subscriptions the same as in Metabase (#41764)**
    - Trend lines are not generated in subscriptions (#29836)
    - "Abbreviate days and months" setting is not respected in subscriptions (#36850)
    - Metabase subscription email not correct graphs (#27963)
    - Stacked area charts with 100% stacking show up in alerts/subscriptions as regular stacking (#30551)
    - Pulse card render error when sending dashboard via email. (#33705)
    - Subscription report not similar on mail (#33798)
    - Dashboard subscription Y-axis don't match the custom range (#30807)
    - Static viz multi-series shows two Y-axis (#20559)
    - Line Style formatting doesn't stick on e-mail/slack subscription (#30142)
    - Y-axis is unnecessarily split in static visualizations (#29281)
    - Y-axis in static visualizations can get too cramped when X-axis is rotated 90 degrees (#28822)
    - Static viz and App disagree in bar charts (#23743)
    - Area graph stacked in dashboard subscription email but unstacked in question (#25896)
    - Subscription charts rendering in Outlook does not look correct (#6874)
    - Different chart rendered in pulse from question (#5493)
    - Stacked bar graph is rendered as unstacked bar graph in email and Slack subscription (#30315)
    - Pulse card render error when sending dashboard via email. (#33705)
    - Subscription report not similar on mail (#33798)
    - Stacked bar graph is rendered as unstacked bar graph in email and Slack subscription (#30315)
    - Pulse card render error when sending dashboard via e-mail. (#33705)
    - Charts that Render via GUI Fail to Render in Subscriptions (#39178)
    - Subscription report not similar on mail (#33798)
    - Incorrect Y-axis unit in subscription email for line chart (#27942)
    - Static visualization for simple stacked lines produces different result in Slack (#26769)
    - Scatter plot renders as a Table in Email/Slack subscription (#33586)
    - ‘Error occurred while displaying this card’ in email subscriptions (#36626)
    - Surface statistics about Pulse send status (#12084)

**Visualization improvements and fixes** (#33626)
    - Stacked bar - show data values for each bar within a stack (#13096)
    - Allow non-zero Y-axis auto range (#7196)
    - Smart number projected values (#9170)
    - Stacked combo charts (stacked bars with lines) (#12008)
    - Line settings for changing thickness and/or pattern (#9255)
    - Show percentage change in tooltips for funnel charts (#27236)
    - Row Chart x-axis formatting applies column metric scaling twice (#43779)

**Pivot tables look pivoted in export**
    - CSV downloads for pivot tables are missing header row when multiple measures exist (#43325)

**Browse Models (**#36368)
    - Remove Metabase analytics models from Browse models (#43778, #43251)
    - Use breadcrumbs to display collection paths in Browse models (#41960)
    - Ellipsify descriptions properly in Browse models (#42456)
    - Move createMockModelResult to browse folder (#42690)
    - Combine breadcrumbs into one link (#42951)
    - Remove dead Browse models sorting code (#42823)
    - Show Browse models link in nav only when there are models (#43286)
    - Filter toggle should be absent if there are no verified models (#43262)
    - Don't show browse models in sidebar when no models exist (#43253)
    - Add brand-colored dot to filter icon when the filter is active (#43350)
    - Add recents to Browse models table (#42138)
    - Linkify rows in Browse models table (#42111)
    - Use new icon for verified models (#42689)
    - Fix column widths in Browse models (#42601)
    - Tweak the Model explanation banner (#42413)
    - Add table of models to the Browse models page and make sortable (#41614, #41954, #41591, #41603, #43014, #42113, #42493)
    - Remove the tabs from Browse (#41955)
    - Restore Models in Browse data (#40633)
    - Add palette actions for Browse models and Browse databases (#41592)

**Command palette** (#39259, #43475)

**Suggest custom expressions (#41187)**
    - Add hover card column metadata on custom expressions (custom columns, aggregations) (#38869)

**Time-over-time comparisons - Cumulative and Offset Window functions (#40313,** #42751**)**
    - `Offset()` doesn't work after saving a question (#42323)
    - Do not suggest `Offset` in filters (#42753)
    - Waterfall charts with non-aggregated data improperly calculate y-offsets (#25597)
    - Bug fix - Cannot sort by aggregation that uses `Offset()` (#42554)
    - `diagnose-expression` throws when `Offset` is nested (#42377)Support `Offset()` in custom columns (#42318)
    - Disable offset() in custom columns (#43224)

**Data, Collection, and Menu picker improvements  (#40717, #41175,** #36411, #38315, #36376, #40207, #39869, #37833**)**
    - Data picker search shows tables in "Our Analytics" instead of in db/schema (#42978)
    - Empty collections shown in Data Picker (#42957)
    - Entity Picker Recents Tab (#39528)
    - Update Query Builder source picker dropdown to align more with other popovers (#38670)
    - Refactor types in CollectionPicker (#40377)
    - Add a type to collections returned by search (#42535)
    - Populate collection search results with effective parent (#43331)
    - Put bulk actions above popovers in collections (#42512)

**Smoother migration to Metabase Cloud  (#39654)**
    - Update copy and flow for Cloud Migration (#43116)
    - Cloud Migration RC1 issues (#43056)
    - Migrate to cloud copy (#42706)

**Allow changing data source in join (#40890)**
    - Make search surface columns when I’m working on joined tables (#41085)

**Make it easy to combine columns and extract from column headings (#39977, #38964)**
    - Support column addition / reordering (#39868)
    - Add `combine_via_column_header` analytics event (#41350)
    - Text column combination modal in the Query Builder (#41178)
    - "Combine columns" drill thru (#39980)
    - Allow duplicate combine column columns from column headers (#42314)
    - Fix broken test in column extraction drill (#42202)
    - Add plus icon to chill mode headers with extract column popover shortcut (#42151)
    - Add test for Extract action to column headings, URL and email columns (#39291, #42096)
    - Fix combine extract column drill icons (#42297)
    - Add combine column shortcut to the shortcut menu in the column header (#42172)
    - Regexextract option is not available anymore in GUI custom column (#43180)
    - Wrong columns shown in Extract/Combine expression when aggregation is present (#43222)
    - Add analytics events for extract via column header (#42093)
    - Add analytics events for combine shortcut in notebook editor (#41766)

**Remove Trash collection from 50 release**
    - Remove Trash from release v50 (#43159)
    - Make Trash Usable (#42339)
    - Questions within an archived collection shouldn't appear in the Archive list (#4013)
    - Allow deleting archived collections (#2783)
    - Make it clear that an archived collection is archived when navigating to its direct URL (#29229)
    - Archiving and unarchiving a collection leaves dashboards in the collection empty (#38646)
    - Make the delete button appear as default on the archive (#33180)
    - Unarchive question/dashboard/etc in one click from the "We're a little lost..." page (#10987)
    - Add filtering options to Archive page (#21341)
    - Add timestamp to archive items (#9555)

**Druid JDBC driver (#39938,** #43147)
**Let white-labeling customers customize illustrations (#39246)**
**Add license activation in the initial setup (#38867)**
    - Allow license tokens that start with `airgap_` (#42733)
**Remove global plain CSS styles (#39324, #40106, #40103, #40007, #40133, #38811, #41294)**
**Replace CSV data (#38788)**
    - CSV appends: integer columns should be convertable to float (#37069)
    - Auto-detect CSV separator on uploads (#34325)
    - Convert column to float when appending floats to an integer column (#39493)
    - CSV upload fails on rows with float type among mostly integer values (#38958)
    - Naive CSV Replacement (#40365)
    - Publish Snowplow events when appending to uploads (#39867)
**Embedding SDK**
    - Follow up work on SDK changelog automation (#43583)
    - Add types generation for embedding SDK package (#40975)
    - Integration commit (#40198)
    - CORS (#40394)
    - SDK plugins system proof of concept (#41560)
    - Fix SDK style overridden by CSS reset (#41891)
    - Fix table header styles calculation (#41449)
    - CI for Embedding SDK (#40629)

**Surface column info in places where it’d be most useful (#38394)**
    - Column info fixes (#39746)
    - Design update for column info (#42589)
    - Add hover card on visualization settings sidebar (#38918)
    - Add hover card column metadata on join column picker (#38863)
    - Add hover card column metadata on Notebook filters (#38845)
    - Add hover card column metadata on Summarize sidebar (#38812)
    - Add hover card on table picker (#39305)
    - Add info hover card on data reference in SQL query builder (#39114)
    - Add hover card on column picker (#38698)
    - Add hover card when picking a column to use for simple sandbox filtering (#39240)
    - Make info hover icons less intrusive (#40863)
    - Allow description columns to be dimensions of charts (#42539)

**Docs changes**
    - Note on locked filters (#43886)
    - Update env vars (#43885, #43612, #43150)
    - Update upload setting metadata (#43855)
    - Update list of releases (#43754)
    - Format SQL (#43753)
    - OpenAPI docs (#40162)
    - API change (#42975)
    - Druid JDBC and JSON unfolding (#43267)
    - Column heading options (#43409)
    - License step (#43534)
    - Models and caching (#43681)
    - Caching updates (#42857)
    - Automatically merge the doc PR (#43746)    

- **Let admins delete previous CSV uploads and their underlying table (#36369,** #41118**)**
- **Seed new instances with an example dashboard (#40066, #43190)**
- **Show generated SQL in a side bar automatically (#40254)**
- **Beef up Recents** 🥩 (#41957)
- **Preserve Dashboard Filter States (#39809)**
- **Selecting multiple values for all text filters (#41956)**
- **Capture more metadata: table count, field usage, last viewed/used_at (#38229,** #43603)
- **Enable drill-thru for single-row aggregates (#40174)**
- **Initial homepage experience for embedding admins (#40005)**
- **Appearance settings page polish (#38699)**
- **Change the default access of new added databases and groups (#36428)**

**Other stuff**
- [Flaky test] metabase.pulse.pulse-integration-test/skip-if-empty-test (#43912)
- Mark flaky tests for v50 Release Branch (#43839)
- 🤖 backported "[MBQL lib] Move the `field_ref` matching hack from #43848" (#43903)
- Fix unit test (#43895)
- Use the metric icon for metrics (#43893)
- Add line symbol on hover (#43887)
- [Flaky Test]: should correctly insert function suggestion with the opening parenthesis (#43872)
- Remove classnames (#43869)
- reset series displays when changing card display (#43868)
- Micro-edit: spaces not white spaces (#43860)
- Upgrade `@testing-library/cypress` to `v10.0.2` (#43842)
- Record Task History exception correctly during sync (#43821)
- Task history sorted by started at (#43809)
- Fix typo (#43808)
- Actually validate `view_log.context` matches `::view-log/context` on insert (#43801)
- Use RTK Query to obtain task/job information (#43798)
- Timeline events are on top of bars and data labels (#43738)
- [serdes] do not output exceptions used only for api tests (#43723)
- Instance Analytics content appears in add series modal without EE token (#42645)
- [Flaky Test]: sidebar should be resizable (#43696)
- Column metadata gets lost when connecting a filter to a model (#43799)
- Use "contains" and "between" as default filter operators for non-PK/FK/Category string and numeric columns (#40424)
- Add case for boolean columns in example (#41889)
- Enable customization of columns in ItemsTable (#41777)
- Expose `attached-dwh` token feature flag to frontend (#43657)
- Use a more obvious test error message (#43642)
- Run smaller smoke test suite for pre-release check (#43633)
- `/api/dataset/query_metadata` endpoint (#43629, #43628)
- Performance fix for getUrlWithParameters when there are no parameters (#43626)
- Loki CI improvements (#43607)
- E2E flake `e2e/test/scenarios/embedding/interactive-embedding.cy.spec.js` (#43587)
- Research handling changelog files in different branches. (#43582)
- Update dead jetty docs links (#43573)
- Amend stack values labels control copy (#43553)
- Using scaling on a question with multiple Y-axis columns breaks tool-tips and Y-axis label formatting (#43536)
- Temporarily remove the SameSite=None suggestion box (#43524)
- Batch fetch card__id table metadata (#43509)
- Demonstrate nesting dynamic redefines (#43496)
- Refactor public/embed reducers and related code (#43495)
- Measure auto compactness on correct values (#43477)
- Make compact formatting consistent across all series (#43472)
- Handle MySQL quotes when resolving analyzed fields (#43447)
- Don't throw an exception when a non-existent setting is in the config file (#43425)
- Move `isEditable` from query display info to a card property computed on the BE (#43386)
- Single metadata endpoint for cards (#43334)
- Multiple Measures Requires Additional Header Row in Pivot Exports (#43322)
- Rename `PublicDashboard` to `PublicOrEmbeddedDashboard` and isPublic to isPublicOrEmbed (#43289)
- Don't allow executing archived pivot-table cards in a public dashboard (#43206)
- 🤖 backported "Migrate uploads settings to the db-level behind the scenes, so the uploads DB can be set by the config file" (#43198)
- Update macaw for qualified rename support (#43195)
- Fix missing React key prop (#43179)
- Enable running tagged tests defined in TS (#43172)
- Make plus button less prominent (#43118)
- Provide Macaw with driver-based formatting options (#43096)
- Use table2 icon for questions (#43095)
- Update the design for custom expression shortcuts (#43064)
- Fix not being able to upload to a table if the uploads database has switched (#43026)
- Measure search performance (#43017)
- Drivers: Update the driver changelog with new features (#43004)
- Disable creating new items from the recents screen (#42976)
- Add UTM params to link (#42968)
- Fixes for InteractiveQuestion theming (#42932)
- Static embedding: Update link in "Powered by Metabase footer" (#42889)
- Restore default styles for subtle button (#42854)
- Optimize creating preview queries on the FE (#42831)
- Fix flaky BucketPickerPopover test (#42811)
- Update Metabase Analytics content for v50 (#42799)
- Make Metabot Cool Again (#42797)
- Remove Google Analytics driver and related special case stuff (#42792)
- [MBQL lib] Add `canPreview` and use it from the notebook (#42791)
- Don't explicitly set the dimensions of the verified model icon (#42702)
- Recents API Improvements (#42660)
- Embedding app origin setting should allow multiple origins for the `Access-Control-Allow-Origin` header (#42631)
- New modal after adding a database (#42592)
- Implement F&amp;R for native queries with references to other cards (#42582, #42580)
- Fix drill FK test flake by removing unneeded wait for /api/dataset (#42501)
- Fix pie chart display when switching from notebook editor (#42430)
- Remove dead API keys code (#42418)
- Port CollapseSection to ts (#42333)
- Remove snippets from search types (#42315)
- Backfill QueryField on Metabase startup (#42279)
- New Recents API Format (#42239)
- Use a Popover and user settings for filters (#41959)
- Move ItemsTable components to a higher-level folder (#41952)
- Port code relating to moderation to ts #41756 (#41903)
- Add Reset button for InteractiveQuestion (#41860)
- [dc.js migration] missing combined card in subscription (#41787)
- Add `collection.effective_ancestors` to model search results (#41746)
- Add console.trace() when capturing console error (#41657)
- Port six collection-related components to TypeScript (#41632)
- Fix Dispatch type (#41631)
- Store fields used in MBQL cards in QueryField (#41623)
- Bump dompurify in yarn.lock (#41583)
- Fix broken test in FilterPicker (#41523)
- Replace body with params for RTK Query GET requests (#41511)
- Bump mysql2 from 3.6.3 to 3.9.4 (#41398)
- Migrate dashboards to RTK (#41311)
- Localize text in AlertModals (#41254)
- Support parsing native queries with a {{#card-id}} ref in them (#41242)
- Add "Most used functions" to suggestion dropdown (#41237)
- Update suggestions to use Mantine components (#41198)
- Suggest the original question name for derived question in a "save question" modal (#41196)
- Add Danish Language Support (#41120, #43314)
- [ParseSQL] Catch mutation commands (#41115)
- [ParseSQL] Support `*` (#40247)
- Add interactive question component with drilldown (#41106)
- Add logging when something fails at Query Builder level (#41090)
- Do not print stacktrace when client closes connection too early (#40834)
- Migrate dashboards and alerts to RTK (#40791, #40789)
- Fix model card overflow bug (#40736)
- Fix some warnings in JS console (#40727)
- Hide Error Diagnostic modal + triggers in all embedding contexts (#40677)
- Deprecate entity hooks (#40666)
- Record field usage during query execution (#40494)
- Start of 50 Cycle Routine Clojure Dependency Bump (#40354)
- [E2E] Refactor question commands to function helpers (#40236)
- Improved pivot QP: use MLv2 and avoid recursive preprocessing (performance improvement) (#40141)
- Support parsing native queries with variables or a field filter in them (#39954, #39953)
- Provide a list of outdated native queries (#39950)
- Remove info icon on table (#39853)
- [MLv2] Introduce `swap-clauses` to reorder aggregations, etc. (#39850)
- [MLv2 × QP] Migrate pre-processing middleware `metabase.query-processor.middleware.upgrade-field-literals` (#39837)
- [E2E] Overload the existing E2E visitQuestion helper to make it work with the alias (#39683)
- Refactor `cy.archiveQuestion`, `cy.createQuestion` &amp; `cy.createNativeQuestion` to TypeScript ()
- Use arrow functions in e2e &amp; unit tests definitions (#39512)
- Ring-JSON already supports converting stuff to keywords (#39416)
- Use LLMs for autocompletion of Question, Dashboard Titles and Descriptions (#39112)
- Easy List Virtualization (#39074)
- Parameter field mapping (#39042)
- Migrate dataset flag - move changes to master (#39041)
- Fix availableDrillThrus typing (#38957)
- Align paths in Prettier &amp; ESLint scripts (#38951)
- Include e2e directory in prettier scripts (#38948)
- Detect tables, fields, and columns used in which query (#38926, #38925, #38924)
- Allow reordering of items in the Query Builder (#38862)
- "Contains" filter types on dashboards should allow users to pick values in the same way as an "is" filter (#38778)
- Required parameters: follow-ups (#38603)
- Fix liquibase rollbacks causing flaky tests on MySQL (#37884)
- Migrate `dataset: true` to enum value (#37367)
- RFC 70 - Automate sorting imports (#33883)
- Add ability to replace the lighthouse image with a custom image (#25276)
- Connecting dashboard filters to cards can be difficult (#20048)
- Clojure log macros should throw a compile-time exception if you use `tru` inside them (#15886)
- Do not translate error log messages, or add unique error codes for each error (#10764)
- Query response time (#9408)
- Make new native queries default to using the last-selected database (#8780)

### Bug fixes

- **After upgrading to Metabase 50, all non-admin users are seeing the error message: ERROR: syntax error at or near ")"  (#44043)**
- **Switching from a `stack - 100%` chart to a line chart causes the line chart to break (#43538)**
- **Cannot interact with the scrollbar in the suggestions list (#41165)**
- Clicking two times over the metabase logo will return that something's wrong (#43800)
- Logs filled with 'uploads-enabled' has been removed; use 'uploads_enabled' on the database instead (#43756)
- "Show value for this series" setting does nothing when "Show values for data points" is disabled (#43737)
- Table background changes when adding it to a dashboard (#43665)
- RowCharts continuously shrink on hover (row charts have become shy) (#43631)
- `Stack values to show` setting does not work with ordinal x-axis scale (#43454)
- Redundant `#edit` in the URL after creating a dashboard (#43192)
- Connecting a filter to a model will render "unknown field" (#43155)
- Filters connected to categorical fields don't work anymore if question is based on a model (#43154)
- New Search button does not shrink on mobile (#43083)
- Admin Email does not Display on Question Timeout Page (#42929)
- Sidebar items vary in height (#42877)
- Metabase doesn't automatically center-align labels in horizontal axis when removing columns (#42695)
- Metrics (v1) revisions API is broken (#42633)
- [dc.js migration] static charts crash on stats (#42282)
- Window function does not generate a correct inner query (#42234)
- Views are logged for cards in a dashboard even if the user didn't view the tab (#41892)
- Cannot tab through fields in Save Question modal (#41683)
- [dc.js migration] waterfall chart with unaggregated time-series data is broken (#41551)
- [dc.js migration] very small values on bar charts can appear invisible (#41291)
- [dc.js migration] data labels are less readable when overlap with goal and trend lines (#41280)
- Hovering on legend to see a specific series always shows first series as well (#41526)
- Performance hit after upgrade to 1.49.x (#41468)
- `add-alias-info` gets confused when using multiple nominal field literal refs for same column in source query (#41325)
- Create collection modal starts with an error (#41241)
- Visual regression: too many items are getting a separator (#41136)
- Dashboards are broken (#41071)
- `lib.convert/-&gt;legacy-mbql` incorrectly generates `:aggregation-options` clauses in `:expressions` if they contain certain options (#41053)
- `mbql.u/add-order-by-clause` ignores clauses if an order by already exists for that field even if temporal unit is different (#40995)
- `unique-name-generator` generates incorrect names, which can cause broken queries (#40994)
- `add-alias-info` breakouts with multiple order bys on the same field (#40993)
- Use window function versions of cumulative aggregations for BigQuery (#40992)
- Fix window function cumulative aggregations for SQL Server (#40990)
- Model descriptions overflow when they contain a long URL (#40725)
- Visualization differs after converting question with aggregation and breakout to SQL (#40711)
- Not possible to save static text as a custom expression (#39438)
- Audit collection permission not the same as audit permission in settings (#39197)
- Multi-question cards filter data incorrectly in email / Slack dashboard subscriptions (#39083)
- Stacked bar chart showing wrong percentage when total value is negative (#39012)
- [MLv2] fromLegacyQuery drops invalid expressions (#38954)
- Custom column disappears after creating with case(isempty([Some Column]), "true", "false") (#38944)
- Broken list of columns in table settings if the setting value is out of sync with the query (#38908)
- Metabase is sending alerts half an hour after it is actually scheduled to send alerts (#38800)
- Enum type columns don't show up for update actions in MySQL (#37638)
- A dashcard with multiple scalars shows two legends (#37287)
- Cannot rename a data series when the label is too long - label appears on top of the input value (#36421)
- Chart tooltip not showing all series in breakout (#34901)
- query_metadata does not load in parallel (#33786)
- Hover on a breakout series fades other lines but not the numbers (#32412)
- Charts such as Line or Bar are not able to interpret the difference between an empty string and NULL (#31238)
- Dashboard "still waiting" text ambiguous (#31135)
- Relative links inside tables get encoded characters and fail (#30894)
- Y-axis ticks cut off on the static line/area/bar chart in certain cases (#30609)
- dates on x-axis get cramped together (#30325)
- Large sets of collections in the `Move` modal takes a long time to load or doesn't work (#30117)
- Summarizing with category field type (Data Model column) breaks Visualization Style/Colour options (#28523)
- Log scale doesn't show y-axis values when data points are close to each other (#28186)
- Objects that are unarchived without parent collection being unarchived are orphaned (#26168)
- Changing X-axis breaks, when an invalid "X-axis scale" is defined can cause blank visualization or error (#25156)
- Wrong number of distinct values in a native model (#23103)
- When moving a collection, invalid choices should just be disabled (#21786)
- Adding an "on" date filter without a specific time to a custom date column returns no results (#17807)
- Should be able to run a card with another card as its source query with just permissions for the former (#15131)
- The results of divide or multiply two CumulativeSum are incorrect (#15118)
- Long Running Pulses will block other pulses from running (#14613)
- Cumulative Sum/Count fails when there's a custom column after the calculation (#13634)
- Manual Y axis min/max don't take the "Multiply by" factor into account (#12214)
- Clicking RawData-toggle on pivoted table makes the question dirty and shows Save-button (#11994)
- Scatter plot Y-Axis Minimum won't set correctly (#11968)
- Unexpected behavior when setting manual Y-axis range on scatterplots with bubble size variables (#11889)
- Cumulative aggregations with multiple breakouts should reset count/sum when values of one specific breakout columns change (#2862)

&lt;/details&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/metabase/metabase/releases/tag/v0.50.1" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/metabase/metabase/releases/tag/v0.50.2</id>
    <title>New release for Metabase: Metabase v0.50.2</title>
    <updated>2024-06-13T04:52:58-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>metabase/metabase</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Upgrading&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can download a .jar of the release, or get the latest on Docker. Make sure to back up your Metabase
database before you upgrade! Need help? Check out our &lt;a href="https://metabase.com/docs/latest/operations-guide/upgrading-metabase.html"&gt;upgrading instructions&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Docker image: &lt;a href="https://hub.docker.com/r/metabase/metabase/tags"&gt;&lt;code&gt;metabase/metabase:v0.50.2&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
Download the JAR here: https://downloads.metabase.com/v0.50.2/metabase.jar&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Notes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SHA-256 checksum for the v0.50.2 JAR:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;31d8dada385e75c8a53fa86ccb2948cca9e4ad528af1dc1cd55012ef294b177a&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;details&gt;
&lt;summary&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Changelog&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;/summary&gt;

### Enhancements

**Better cache controls** (#41430, #41429, #41427, #41426, #41478)
    - Add cache config form to question sidebar (#42729)
    - Tweak appearance of cache page and form (#42856, #42958)
    - Move model caching UI to Admin &gt; Performance (#43019)
    - Only show "Adaptive" and "Don't cache" options on OSS page (#43122, #43121)
    - Config should be editable if entity is accessible (#43522)
    - Fix width of save button in cache sidebar (tiny PR) (#43755)
    - Update copy on cache invalidation configuration forms (#42815)
    - Remove cache-related field from database creation form (#42808)
    - Remove cache timestamp from Question info sidebar (#42788)
    - Reduce query runs before cache hit from 3 to 2 (#35630)
    - Invalid cache-keys used for query caching (#37702)
    - Implement advanced cache strategies (#38434)
    - Basic cache admin UI (#39234)
    - Implement webhook handlers to reset/refresh query cache (#40548)
    - Add "Invalidate cache now" button (#40972)
    - Add cache configuration form to dashboard sidebar (#42192)
    - Use DelayedLoadingAndErrorWrapper component in Admin &gt; Performance (#41103)
    - Rename and re-order TTL strategy (#41108)
    - In Admin &gt; Performance, display minimum query duration in seconds (#40970)
    - Add Schedule strategy to Admin &gt; Performance (#41424, #41230)
    - In Admin &gt; Performance Data caching settings, the Save button is inaccessible when pushed offscreen by a long list of databases (#43813)

**Split data access and query builder access and merge Query Builder and SQL permissions (#26918)**
    - Newly added databases should be created with "No self-service" permissions - default permissions risks in strict data isolation contexts (#6735)
    - Not possible to view Native question unless given ad-hoc native query permissions if another group has Block (#21695)
    - Block permissions behave strangely after losing advanced permissions feature flag or switching to OSS (#20813)
    - Native query editor offers data source a user does not have native write permissions for (#39053)
    - Configuring sandboxed permissions in schemaless databases removes tables from the list (#41490)
    - Refactor `cy.updatePermissionsGraph`, `cy.updatePermissionsSchemas` &amp; `cy.updateCollectionGraph` to TypeScript (#39675, #39614)
    - No Access to Our Analytics will break the "Add to Dashboard" in multiple ways (#38856)
    - Grant Collection-only access that respects data sandboxing (#21703)
    - Block access on a database prevents executing actions and uploading CSVs, even with unrestricted access (#36298)    

**Chart appearance in subscriptions the same as in Metabase (#41764)**
    - Trend lines are not generated in subscriptions (#29836)
    - "Abbreviate days and months" setting is not respected in subscriptions (#36850)
    - Metabase subscription email not correct graphs (#27963)
    - Stacked area charts with 100% stacking show up in alerts/subscriptions as regular stacking (#30551)
    - Pulse card render error when sending dashboard via email. (#33705)
    - Subscription report not similar on mail (#33798)
    - Dashboard subscription Y-axis don't match the custom range (#30807)
    - Static viz multi-series shows two Y-axis (#20559)
    - Line Style formatting doesn't stick on e-mail/slack subscription (#30142)
    - Y-axis is unnecessarily split in static visualizations (#29281)
    - Y-axis in static visualizations can get too cramped when X-axis is rotated 90 degrees (#28822)
    - Static viz and App disagree in bar charts (#23743)
    - Area graph stacked in dashboard subscription email but unstacked in question (#25896)
    - Subscription charts rendering in Outlook does not look correct (#6874)
    - Different chart rendered in pulse from question (#5493)
    - Stacked bar graph is rendered as unstacked bar graph in email and Slack subscription (#30315)
    - Pulse card render error when sending dashboard via email. (#33705)
    - Subscription report not similar on mail (#33798)
    - Stacked bar graph is rendered as unstacked bar graph in email and Slack subscription (#30315)
    - Pulse card render error when sending dashboard via e-mail. (#33705)
    - Charts that Render via GUI Fail to Render in Subscriptions (#39178)
    - Subscription report not similar on mail (#33798)
    - Incorrect Y-axis unit in subscription email for line chart (#27942)
    - Static visualization for simple stacked lines produces different result in Slack (#26769)
    - Scatter plot renders as a Table in Email/Slack subscription (#33586)
    - ‘Error occurred while displaying this card’ in email subscriptions (#36626)
    - Surface statistics about Pulse send status (#12084)

**Visualization improvements and fixes** (#33626)
    - Stacked bar - show data values for each bar within a stack (#13096)
    - Allow non-zero Y-axis auto range (#7196)
    - Smart number projected values (#9170)
    - Stacked combo charts (stacked bars with lines) (#12008)
    - Line settings for changing thickness and/or pattern (#9255)
    - Show percentage change in tooltips for funnel charts (#27236)
    - Row Chart x-axis formatting applies column metric scaling twice (#43779)

**Pivot tables look pivoted in export**
    - CSV downloads for pivot tables are missing header row when multiple measures exist (#43325)

**Browse Models (**#36368)
    - Remove Metabase analytics models from Browse models (#43778, #43251)
    - Use breadcrumbs to display collection paths in Browse models (#41960)
    - Ellipsify descriptions properly in Browse models (#42456)
    - Move createMockModelResult to browse folder (#42690)
    - Combine breadcrumbs into one link (#42951)
    - Remove dead Browse models sorting code (#42823)
    - Show Browse models link in nav only when there are models (#43286)
    - Filter toggle should be absent if there are no verified models (#43262)
    - Don't show browse models in sidebar when no models exist (#43253)
    - Add brand-colored dot to filter icon when the filter is active (#43350)
    - Add recents to Browse models table (#42138)
    - Linkify rows in Browse models table (#42111)
    - Use new icon for verified models (#42689)
    - Fix column widths in Browse models (#42601)
    - Tweak the Model explanation banner (#42413)
    - Add table of models to the Browse models page and make sortable (#41614, #41954, #41591, #41603, #43014, #42113, #42493)
    - Remove the tabs from Browse (#41955)
    - Restore Models in Browse data (#40633)
    - Add palette actions for Browse models and Browse databases (#41592)

**Command palette** (#39259, #43475)

**Suggest custom expressions (#41187)**
    - Add hover card column metadata on custom expressions (custom columns, aggregations) (#38869)

**Time-over-time comparisons - Cumulative and Offset Window functions (#40313,** #42751**)**
    - `Offset()` doesn't work after saving a question (#42323)
    - Do not suggest `Offset` in filters (#42753)
    - Waterfall charts with non-aggregated data improperly calculate y-offsets (#25597)
    - Bug fix - Cannot sort by aggregation that uses `Offset()` (#42554)
    - `diagnose-expression` throws when `Offset` is nested (#42377)Support `Offset()` in custom columns (#42318)
    - Disable offset() in custom columns (#43224)

**Data, Collection, and Menu picker improvements  (#40717, #41175,** #36411, #38315, #36376, #40207, #39869, #37833**)**
    - Data picker search shows tables in "Our Analytics" instead of in db/schema (#42978)
    - Empty collections shown in Data Picker (#42957)
    - Entity Picker Recents Tab (#39528)
    - Update Query Builder source picker dropdown to align more with other popovers (#38670)
    - Refactor types in CollectionPicker (#40377)
    - Add a type to collections returned by search (#42535)
    - Populate collection search results with effective parent (#43331)
    - Put bulk actions above popovers in collections (#42512)

**Smoother migration to Metabase Cloud  (#39654)**
    - Update copy and flow for Cloud Migration (#43116)
    - Cloud Migration RC1 issues (#43056)
    - Migrate to cloud copy (#42706)

**Allow changing data source in join (#40890)**
    - Make search surface columns when I’m working on joined tables (#41085)

**Make it easy to combine columns and extract from column headings (#39977, #38964)**
    - Support column addition / reordering (#39868)
    - Add `combine_via_column_header` analytics event (#41350)
    - Text column combination modal in the Query Builder (#41178)
    - "Combine columns" drill thru (#39980)
    - Allow duplicate combine column columns from column headers (#42314)
    - Fix broken test in column extraction drill (#42202)
    - Add plus icon to chill mode headers with extract column popover shortcut (#42151)
    - Add test for Extract action to column headings, URL and email columns (#39291, #42096)
    - Fix combine extract column drill icons (#42297)
    - Add combine column shortcut to the shortcut menu in the column header (#42172)
    - Regexextract option is not available anymore in GUI custom column (#43180)
    - Wrong columns shown in Extract/Combine expression when aggregation is present (#43222)
    - Add analytics events for extract via column header (#42093)
    - Add analytics events for combine shortcut in notebook editor (#41766)

**Remove Trash collection from 50 release**
    - Remove Trash from release v50 (#43159)
    - Make Trash Usable (#42339)
    - Questions within an archived collection shouldn't appear in the Archive list (#4013)
    - Allow deleting archived collections (#2783)
    - Make it clear that an archived collection is archived when navigating to its direct URL (#29229)
    - Archiving and unarchiving a collection leaves dashboards in the collection empty (#38646)
    - Make the delete button appear as default on the archive (#33180)
    - Unarchive question/dashboard/etc in one click from the "We're a little lost..." page (#10987)
    - Add filtering options to Archive page (#21341)
    - Add timestamp to archive items (#9555)

**Druid JDBC driver (#39938,** #43147)
**Let white-labeling customers customize illustrations (#39246)**
**Add license activation in the initial setup (#38867)**
    - Allow license tokens that start with `airgap_` (#42733)
**Remove global plain CSS styles (#39324, #40106, #40103, #40007, #40133, #38811, #41294)**
**Replace CSV data (#38788)**
    - CSV appends: integer columns should be convertable to float (#37069)
    - Auto-detect CSV separator on uploads (#34325)
    - Convert column to float when appending floats to an integer column (#39493)
    - CSV upload fails on rows with float type among mostly integer values (#38958)
    - Naive CSV Replacement (#40365)
    - Publish Snowplow events when appending to uploads (#39867)
**Embedding SDK**
    - Follow up work on SDK changelog automation (#43583)
    - Add types generation for embedding SDK package (#40975)
    - Integration commit (#40198)
    - CORS (#40394)
    - SDK plugins system proof of concept (#41560)
    - Fix SDK style overridden by CSS reset (#41891)
    - Fix table header styles calculation (#41449)
    - CI for Embedding SDK (#40629)

**Surface column info in places where it’d be most useful (#38394)**
    - Column info fixes (#39746)
    - Design update for column info (#42589)
    - Add hover card on visualization settings sidebar (#38918)
    - Add hover card column metadata on join column picker (#38863)
    - Add hover card column metadata on Notebook filters (#38845)
    - Add hover card column metadata on Summarize sidebar (#38812)
    - Add hover card on table picker (#39305)
    - Add info hover card on data reference in SQL query builder (#39114)
    - Add hover card on column picker (#38698)
    - Add hover card when picking a column to use for simple sandbox filtering (#39240)
    - Make info hover icons less intrusive (#40863)
    - Allow description columns to be dimensions of charts (#42539)

**Docs changes**
    - Note on locked filters (#43886)
    - Update env vars (#43885, #43612, #43150)
    - Update upload setting metadata (#43855)
    - Update list of releases (#43754)
    - Format SQL (#43753)
    - OpenAPI docs (#40162)
    - API change (#42975)
    - Druid JDBC and JSON unfolding (#43267)
    - Column heading options (#43409)
    - License step (#43534)
    - Models and caching (#43681)
    - Caching updates (#42857)
    - Automatically merge the doc PR (#43746)    

- **Let admins delete previous CSV uploads and their underlying table (#36369,** #41118**)**
- **Seed new instances with an example dashboard (#40066, #43190)**
- **Show generated SQL in a side bar automatically (#40254)**
- **Beef up Recents** 🥩 (#41957)
- **Preserve Dashboard Filter States (#39809)**
- **Selecting multiple values for all text filters (#41956)**
- **Capture more metadata: table count, field usage, last viewed/used_at (#38229,** #43603)
- **Enable drill-thru for single-row aggregates (#40174)**
- **Initial homepage experience for embedding admins (#40005)**
- **Appearance settings page polish (#38699)**
- **Change the default access of new added databases and groups (#36428)**

**Other stuff**
- [Flaky test] metabase.pulse.pulse-integration-test/skip-if-empty-test (#43912)
- Mark flaky tests for v50 Release Branch (#43839)
- 🤖 backported "[MBQL lib] Move the `field_ref` matching hack from #43848" (#43903)
- Fix unit test (#43895)
- Use the metric icon for metrics (#43893)
- Add line symbol on hover (#43887)
- [Flaky Test]: should correctly insert function suggestion with the opening parenthesis (#43872)
- Remove classnames (#43869)
- reset series displays when changing card display (#43868)
- Micro-edit: spaces not white spaces (#43860)
- Upgrade `@testing-library/cypress` to `v10.0.2` (#43842)
- Record Task History exception correctly during sync (#43821)
- Task history sorted by started at (#43809)
- Fix typo (#43808)
- Actually validate `view_log.context` matches `::view-log/context` on insert (#43801)
- Use RTK Query to obtain task/job information (#43798)
- Timeline events are on top of bars and data labels (#43738)
- [serdes] do not output exceptions used only for api tests (#43723)
- Instance Analytics content appears in add series modal without EE token (#42645)
- [Flaky Test]: sidebar should be resizable (#43696)
- Column metadata gets lost when connecting a filter to a model (#43799)
- Use "contains" and "between" as default filter operators for non-PK/FK/Category string and numeric columns (#40424)
- Add case for boolean columns in example (#41889)
- Enable customization of columns in ItemsTable (#41777)
- Expose `attached-dwh` token feature flag to frontend (#43657)
- Use a more obvious test error message (#43642)
- Run smaller smoke test suite for pre-release check (#43633)
- `/api/dataset/query_metadata` endpoint (#43629, #43628)
- Performance fix for getUrlWithParameters when there are no parameters (#43626)
- Loki CI improvements (#43607)
- E2E flake `e2e/test/scenarios/embedding/interactive-embedding.cy.spec.js` (#43587)
- Research handling changelog files in different branches. (#43582)
- Update dead jetty docs links (#43573)
- Amend stack values labels control copy (#43553)
- Using scaling on a question with multiple Y-axis columns breaks tool-tips and Y-axis label formatting (#43536)
- Temporarily remove the SameSite=None suggestion box (#43524)
- Batch fetch card__id table metadata (#43509)
- Demonstrate nesting dynamic redefines (#43496)
- Refactor public/embed reducers and related code (#43495)
- Measure auto compactness on correct values (#43477)
- Make compact formatting consistent across all series (#43472)
- Handle MySQL quotes when resolving analyzed fields (#43447)
- Don't throw an exception when a non-existent setting is in the config file (#43425)
- Move `isEditable` from query display info to a card property computed on the BE (#43386)
- Single metadata endpoint for cards (#43334)
- Multiple Measures Requires Additional Header Row in Pivot Exports (#43322)
- Rename `PublicDashboard` to `PublicOrEmbeddedDashboard` and isPublic to isPublicOrEmbed (#43289)
- Don't allow executing archived pivot-table cards in a public dashboard (#43206)
- 🤖 backported "Migrate uploads settings to the db-level behind the scenes, so the uploads DB can be set by the config file" (#43198)
- Update macaw for qualified rename support (#43195)
- Fix missing React key prop (#43179)
- Enable running tagged tests defined in TS (#43172)
- Make plus button less prominent (#43118)
- Provide Macaw with driver-based formatting options (#43096)
- Use table2 icon for questions (#43095)
- Update the design for custom expression shortcuts (#43064)
- Fix not being able to upload to a table if the uploads database has switched (#43026)
- Measure search performance (#43017)
- Drivers: Update the driver changelog with new features (#43004)
- Disable creating new items from the recents screen (#42976)
- Add UTM params to link (#42968)
- Fixes for InteractiveQuestion theming (#42932)
- Static embedding: Update link in "Powered by Metabase footer" (#42889)
- Restore default styles for subtle button (#42854)
- Optimize creating preview queries on the FE (#42831)
- Fix flaky BucketPickerPopover test (#42811)
- Update Metabase Analytics content for v50 (#42799)
- Make Metabot Cool Again (#42797)
- Remove Google Analytics driver and related special case stuff (#42792)
- [MBQL lib] Add `canPreview` and use it from the notebook (#42791)
- Don't explicitly set the dimensions of the verified model icon (#42702)
- Recents API Improvements (#42660)
- Embedding app origin setting should allow multiple origins for the `Access-Control-Allow-Origin` header (#42631)
- New modal after adding a database (#42592)
- Implement F&amp;R for native queries with references to other cards (#42582, #42580)
- Fix drill FK test flake by removing unneeded wait for /api/dataset (#42501)
- Fix pie chart display when switching from notebook editor (#42430)
- Remove dead API keys code (#42418)
- Port CollapseSection to ts (#42333)
- Remove snippets from search types (#42315)
- Backfill QueryField on Metabase startup (#42279)
- New Recents API Format (#42239)
- Use a Popover and user settings for filters (#41959)
- Move ItemsTable components to a higher-level folder (#41952)
- Port code relating to moderation to ts #41756 (#41903)
- Add Reset button for InteractiveQuestion (#41860)
- [dc.js migration] missing combined card in subscription (#41787)
- Add `collection.effective_ancestors` to model search results (#41746)
- Add console.trace() when capturing console error (#41657)
- Port six collection-related components to TypeScript (#41632)
- Fix Dispatch type (#41631)
- Store fields used in MBQL cards in QueryField (#41623)
- Bump dompurify in yarn.lock (#41583)
- Fix broken test in FilterPicker (#41523)
- Replace body with params for RTK Query GET requests (#41511)
- Bump mysql2 from 3.6.3 to 3.9.4 (#41398)
- Migrate dashboards to RTK (#41311)
- Localize text in AlertModals (#41254)
- Support parsing native queries with a {{#card-id}} ref in them (#41242)
- Add "Most used functions" to suggestion dropdown (#41237)
- Update suggestions to use Mantine components (#41198)
- Suggest the original question name for derived question in a "save question" modal (#41196)
- Add Danish Language Support (#41120, #43314)
- [ParseSQL] Catch mutation commands (#41115)
- [ParseSQL] Support `*` (#40247)
- Add interactive question component with drilldown (#41106)
- Add logging when something fails at Query Builder level (#41090)
- Do not print stacktrace when client closes connection too early (#40834)
- Migrate dashboards and alerts to RTK (#40791, #40789)
- Fix model card overflow bug (#40736)
- Fix some warnings in JS console (#40727)
- Hide Error Diagnostic modal + triggers in all embedding contexts (#40677)
- Deprecate entity hooks (#40666)
- Record field usage during query execution (#40494)
- Start of 50 Cycle Routine Clojure Dependency Bump (#40354)
- [E2E] Refactor question commands to function helpers (#40236)
- Improved pivot QP: use MLv2 and avoid recursive preprocessing (performance improvement) (#40141)
- Support parsing native queries with variables or a field filter in them (#39954, #39953)
- Provide a list of outdated native queries (#39950)
- Remove info icon on table (#39853)
- [MLv2] Introduce `swap-clauses` to reorder aggregations, etc. (#39850)
- [MLv2 × QP] Migrate pre-processing middleware `metabase.query-processor.middleware.upgrade-field-literals` (#39837)
- [E2E] Overload the existing E2E visitQuestion helper to make it work with the alias (#39683)
- Refactor `cy.archiveQuestion`, `cy.createQuestion` &amp; `cy.createNativeQuestion` to TypeScript ()
- Use arrow functions in e2e &amp; unit tests definitions (#39512)
- Ring-JSON already supports converting stuff to keywords (#39416)
- Use LLMs for autocompletion of Question, Dashboard Titles and Descriptions (#39112)
- Easy List Virtualization (#39074)
- Parameter field mapping (#39042)
- Migrate dataset flag - move changes to master (#39041)
- Fix availableDrillThrus typing (#38957)
- Align paths in Prettier &amp; ESLint scripts (#38951)
- Include e2e directory in prettier scripts (#38948)
- Detect tables, fields, and columns used in which query (#38926, #38925, #38924)
- Allow reordering of items in the Query Builder (#38862)
- "Contains" filter types on dashboards should allow users to pick values in the same way as an "is" filter (#38778)
- Required parameters: follow-ups (#38603)
- Fix liquibase rollbacks causing flaky tests on MySQL (#37884)
- Migrate `dataset: true` to enum value (#37367)
- RFC 70 - Automate sorting imports (#33883)
- Add ability to replace the lighthouse image with a custom image (#25276)
- Connecting dashboard filters to cards can be difficult (#20048)
- Clojure log macros should throw a compile-time exception if you use `tru` inside them (#15886)
- Do not translate error log messages, or add unique error codes for each error (#10764)
- Query response time (#9408)
- Make new native queries default to using the last-selected database (#8780)

### Bug fixes

- **Model persistence tab in Performance should be available on OSS (#44058)**
- **Error migrating to the 50.0 with the database connection encrypted (#44012)**
- **"Manage database" perms incorrectly show up on the schema-level permissions page (#37998)**
- Clicking two times over the metabase logo will return that something's wrong (#43800)
- Logs filled with 'uploads-enabled' has been removed; use 'uploads_enabled' on the database instead (#43756)
- "Show value for this series" setting does nothing when "Show values for data points" is disabled (#43737)
- Table background changes when adding it to a dashboard (#43665)
- RowCharts continuously shrink on hover (row charts have become shy) (#43631)
- `Stack values to show` setting does not work with ordinal x-axis scale (#43454)
- Redundant `#edit` in the URL after creating a dashboard (#43192)
- Connecting a filter to a model will render "unknown field" (#43155)
- Filters connected to categorical fields don't work anymore if question is based on a model (#43154)
- New Search button does not shrink on mobile (#43083)
- Admin Email does not Display on Question Timeout Page (#42929)
- Sidebar items vary in height (#42877)
- Metabase doesn't automatically center-align labels in horizontal axis when removing columns (#42695)
- Metrics (v1) revisions API is broken (#42633)
- [dc.js migration] static charts crash on stats (#42282)
- Window function does not generate a correct inner query (#42234)
- Views are logged for cards in a dashboard even if the user didn't view the tab (#41892)
- Cannot tab through fields in Save Question modal (#41683)
- [dc.js migration] waterfall chart with unaggregated time-series data is broken (#41551)
- [dc.js migration] very small values on bar charts can appear invisible (#41291)
- [dc.js migration] data labels are less readable when overlap with goal and trend lines (#41280)
- Hovering on legend to see a specific series always shows first series as well (#41526)
- Performance hit after upgrade to 1.49.x (#41468)
- `add-alias-info` gets confused when using multiple nominal field literal refs for same column in source query (#41325)
- Create collection modal starts with an error (#41241)
- Visual regression: too many items are getting a separator (#41136)
- Dashboards are broken (#41071)
- `lib.convert/-&gt;legacy-mbql` incorrectly generates `:aggregation-options` clauses in `:expressions` if they contain certain options (#41053)
- `mbql.u/add-order-by-clause` ignores clauses if an order by already exists for that field even if temporal unit is different (#40995)
- `unique-name-generator` generates incorrect names, which can cause broken queries (#40994)
- `add-alias-info` breakouts with multiple order bys on the same field (#40993)
- Use window function versions of cumulative aggregations for BigQuery (#40992)
- Fix window function cumulative aggregations for SQL Server (#40990)
- Model descriptions overflow when they contain a long URL (#40725)
- Visualization differs after converting question with aggregation and breakout to SQL (#40711)
- Not possible to save static text as a custom expression (#39438)
- Audit collection permission not the same as audit permission in settings (#39197)
- Multi-question cards filter data incorrectly in email / Slack dashboard subscriptions (#39083)
- Stacked bar chart showing wrong percentage when total value is negative (#39012)
- [MLv2] fromLegacyQuery drops invalid expressions (#38954)
- Custom column disappears after creating with case(isempty([Some Column]), "true", "false") (#38944)
- Broken list of columns in table settings if the setting value is out of sync with the query (#38908)
- Metabase is sending alerts half an hour after it is actually scheduled to send alerts (#38800)
- Enum type columns don't show up for update actions in MySQL (#37638)
- A dashcard with multiple scalars shows two legends (#37287)
- Cannot rename a data series when the label is too long - label appears on top of the input value (#36421)
- Chart tooltip not showing all series in breakout (#34901)
- query_metadata does not load in parallel (#33786)
- Hover on a breakout series fades other lines but not the numbers (#32412)
- Charts such as Line or Bar are not able to interpret the difference between an empty string and NULL (#31238)
- Dashboard "still waiting" text ambiguous (#31135)
- Relative links inside tables get encoded characters and fail (#30894)
- Y-axis ticks cut off on the static line/area/bar chart in certain cases (#30609)
- dates on x-axis get cramped together (#30325)
- Large sets of collections in the `Move` modal takes a long time to load or doesn't work (#30117)
- Summarizing with category field type (Data Model column) breaks Visualization Style/Colour options (#28523)
- Log scale doesn't show y-axis values when data points are close to each other (#28186)
- Objects that are unarchived without parent collection being unarchived are orphaned (#26168)
- Changing X-axis breaks, when an invalid "X-axis scale" is defined can cause blank visualization or error (#25156)
- Wrong number of distinct values in a native model (#23103)
- When moving a collection, invalid choices should just be disabled (#21786)
- Adding an "on" date filter without a specific time to a custom date column returns no results (#17807)
- Should be able to run a card with another card as its source query with just permissions for the former (#15131)
- The results of divide or multiply two CumulativeSum are incorrect (#15118)
- Long Running Pulses will block other pulses from running (#14613)
- Cumulative Sum/Count fails when there's a custom column after the calculation (#13634)
- Manual Y axis min/max don't take the "Multiply by" factor into account (#12214)
- Clicking RawData-toggle on pivoted table makes the question dirty and shows Save-button (#11994)
- Scatter plot Y-Axis Minimum won't set correctly (#11968)
- Unexpected behavior when setting manual Y-axis range on scatterplots with bubble size variables (#11889)
- Cumulative aggregations with multiple breakouts should reset count/sum when values of one specific breakout columns change (#2862)

&lt;/details&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/metabase/metabase/releases/tag/v0.50.2" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/metabase/metabase/releases/tag/v0.49.16</id>
    <title>New release for Metabase: Metabase v0.49.16</title>
    <updated>2024-06-13T07:44:42-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>metabase/metabase</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Upgrading&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can download a .jar of the release, or get the latest on Docker. Make sure to back up your Metabase
database before you upgrade! Need help? Check out our &lt;a href="https://metabase.com/docs/latest/operations-guide/upgrading-metabase.html"&gt;upgrading instructions&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Docker image: &lt;a href="https://hub.docker.com/r/metabase/metabase/tags"&gt;&lt;code&gt;metabase/metabase:v0.49.16&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
Download the JAR here: https://downloads.metabase.com/v0.49.16/metabase.jar&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Notes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SHA-256 checksum for the v0.49.16 JAR:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;5e7c25efbcb7ea6e4a75d438c52f25d6c5efb3e5b3677d8e0f65a32c836fff70&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;details&gt;
&lt;summary&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Changelog&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;/summary&gt;

**Bug fixes**

- Add connection string parsing to Snowflake (#43923)
- Filters show raw values on public version of dashboard  (#44047)

&lt;/details&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/metabase/metabase/releases/tag/v0.49.16" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/metabase/metabase/releases/tag/v0.50.3</id>
    <title>New release for Metabase: Metabase v0.50.3</title>
    <updated>2024-06-13T05:44:11-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>metabase/metabase</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Upgrading&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can download a .jar of the release, or get the latest on Docker. Make sure to back up your Metabase
database before you upgrade! Need help? Check out our &lt;a href="https://metabase.com/docs/latest/operations-guide/upgrading-metabase.html"&gt;upgrading instructions&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Docker image: &lt;a href="https://hub.docker.com/r/metabase/metabase/tags"&gt;&lt;code&gt;metabase/metabase:v0.50.3&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
Download the JAR here: https://downloads.metabase.com/v0.50.3/metabase.jar&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Notes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SHA-256 checksum for the v0.50.3 JAR:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;def3903f275276e339f2ed99bb37fd2f85652b62f8f3be50cb0e708f1eeaffbc&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;details&gt;
&lt;summary&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Changelog&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;/summary&gt;

**Bug fixes**

- Users with No Access to the Our Analytics collection are not able to use the Query Editor for Saved Questions or Models (#44071)
- Comma in quoted string during CSV upload: CSV error (unexpected character: ,) (#44060)

&lt;/details&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/metabase/metabase/releases/tag/v0.50.3" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
