<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://selfh.st/apps</id>
  <title>Mox Releases</title>
  <updated>2025-05-23T00:36:23.386064-04:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>selfh.st</name>
    <email>contact@selfh.st</email>
  </author>
  <link href="https://selfh.st/apps" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>Self-hosted software releases generated by selfh.st</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/mjl-/mox/releases/tag/v0.0.11</id>
    <title>New release for Mox: v0.0.11</title>
    <updated>2024-04-30T15:38:14-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>mjl-/mox</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h1&gt;New features&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improve queue management (40ade995a5e5)&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add option to put messages in the queue "on hold", preventing delivery
  attempts until taken off hold again.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add "hold rules", to automatically mark some/all submitted messages as "on
  hold", e.g. from a specific account or to a specific domain.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add operation to "fail" a message, causing a DSN to be delivered to the
  sender. previously we could only drop a message from the queue.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Update admin page &amp;amp; add new cli tools for these operations, with new
  filtering rules for selecting the messages to operate on. In the admin
  interface, add filtering and checkboxes to select a set of messages to operate
  on.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add a webapi and webhooks for a simple HTTP/JSON-based API, helps with
  sending transactional email. (for issue #31 by cuu508, 09fcc492234e)&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Webapi allows submitting messages without having to compose the message
  yourself, and without having to know SMTP.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Webhooks makes it easy to process delivery failure/success updates, without
  needing IMAP and process DSNs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;History about outgoing/sent messages can be kept for a configurable interval,
  per account. Also for the new webhook queue.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Messages can be delivered with a "unique SMTP MAIL FROM" address, using a
  unique id after the localpart catchall separator, e.g.
  &lt;code&gt;you+&amp;lt;unique&amp;gt;@example.org&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Automatic suppression list management, protecting server reputation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Extra metadata can be attached through the webapi, or through
  X-Mox-Extra-&lt;key&gt;: &lt;value&gt; headers during SMTP submission.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Most settings are per-account, configurable through config file and 
  account web interface. The webapi must be enabled in mox.conf through field
  WebAPIHTTP(s).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gopherwatch.org was created to validate this functionality, and it can now
  operate either with SMTP/IMAP or webapi/webhooks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add aliases/lists: when sending to an alias, the message gets delivered to all
  members. (for issue #57 by hmfaysal, issue #99 by naturalethic, feedback by
  damir &amp;amp; marin, 960a51242d51).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IMAP quota extension (RFC 9208), so mail clients can show disk usage (issue
  #115 by pmarini, 4dea2de34374)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Webmail: when moving a single message out of/to the inbox, ask if user wants
  to create/remove a rule to automatically do that server-side for future
  deliveries, either based on list-id header if present, or message-from address.
  (6c0439cf7b9e)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Webmail: add server-side stored settings, initially for signature, top/bottom
  reply and showing the security indicator bars below address input fields.
  (for issue #102 by nixigaj, 70adf353ee07)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Webmail: for replies/forwards, add button "send and archive thread" next to
  the "send" button, and give it a control+shift+Enter shortcut. (for issue #135
  by mattfbacon, 5229d01601ad)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Webmail: store composed message as draft until send, ask about unsaved changes
  when closing compose window. (9529ae0bd4f7)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Webmail: remember server-side per from-address whether we should show the
  text/html/html-with-external-resources version of a message. (0f735a17100b)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Improvements&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add account config option to skip first-time sender delay for incoming
  messages over SMTP. (8b2c97808d88)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In quickstart, check if outgoing SMTP connection on port 25 can be made. New
  cloud machines tend to have the port blocked, early warning is helpful.
  (reported by arnt, 0262f4621e13)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In quickstart, use "postmaster@" for the contact address with the ACME account
  for Let's Encrypt if the initial address has a non-ASCII localpart, to prevent
  account registration from failing. (reported by arnt, f4b6e14cb9f7)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add a "direct" transport, that allows influencing behaviour of the normal
  delivery mechanism of dialing MX records: The IP address family can be limited
  to IPv4 or IPv6 (either may not have proper reverse DNS set up). (for issue
  #149, PR #153 by lmeunier, be570d1c7d3d)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Also give delivery another try with 5xx response when it happens during MAIL
  FROM/RCPT TO, not only EHLO as before. (related to #149, PR #152 by lmeunier,
  feb8e6c37947)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make error messages around syntax errors in config files related to
  spurious spaces more helpful/understandable. (reported by arnt, 6516a27689cb)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In SMTP server, reevaluate if SMTPUTF8 extension is needed for delivery, to
  prevent potential delivery problems to servers that don't implement SMTPUTF8.
  (issue #145, by lmeunier, 9c5d2341629f)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When importing maildir, use file mtime as received timestamp if no timestamp
  is available in filename. (based on message from abdul h, 6d38a1e9a4bb)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If webauth login cookie is missing, and forwarding was configured, hint that
  reverse proxy may be stripping path. (for issue #151 by naturalethic,
  afc47c8108f8)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Webmail: When adding submitted message to Sent mailbox, keep any Bcc address
  in Bcc header.  (c9451d4d065e)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make more of the dynamic config options (in domains.conf) configurable through
  the web interfaces, instead of requiring editing the config file. (baf4df55a6cd,
  a69887bfabe3, e702f45d32d3)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Webmail: Allow resizing of compose window, and remember width/height for
  viewport dimension. (e8bbaa451b13)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Webmail: Show all images (inline and attachment) below the text part (for the
  text view, not for html view). (3a58b2a1f49f)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Webmail: Add export functionality, similar to existing option in account web
  interface, but not also possible per mailbox or hierarchy. (bf5cfca6b99f)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Webmail: ctrl+Backspace on empty address input field removes the field (b54e903f015a)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Localserve: delivery from queue now goes through the smtp server instead of
  directly from queue to local accounts. To go through the full regular delivery
  paths. (1cf747764266)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Many small improvements.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Bug fixes&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Always properly escape values in Authentication-Results header added to
  incoming messages. Some generated values could have characters that weren't
  escaped. (2c9cb5b847a7)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix logging in on account and webmail interface for account names (not email
  addresses) with non-ASCII characters. (reported by arnt, 666f84edead6)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Update to latest bstore with a fix for ordering of certain database results.
  Only a single query in mox would have triggered the issue, with no expected
  impact. (d34dd8aae6ca)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For incoming TLS connections (HTTPS, but also SMTP and IMAP) for unrecognized
  domain names (for which we don't have a TLS certificate), don't respond with an
  "internal error" TLS alert, but with an "unrecognized name" alert. More helpful
  to user figuring out what's going on. (reported by arnt, 89a9a8bc9796).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Update instructions&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before upgrading, do a dry-run first.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make a temporary backup with the old mox version:
    &lt;code&gt;mox-v0.0.10 backup data/tmp/testupgrade&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Verify that all is well with the old version:
    &lt;code&gt;mox-v0.0.10 verifydata data/tmp/testupgrade&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Verify the state with the new version:
    &lt;code&gt;mox-v0.0.11 verifydata data/tmp/testupgrade&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With a successful dry-run, the upgrade should go smoothly.  Make a new backup
with &lt;code&gt;mox-v0.0.10 backup data/tmp/backup&lt;/code&gt; (the previous backup was modified by
the dry-run, so couldn't be used to restore!), replace the binary and restart.
For further details, see
https://www.xmox.nl/faq/#hdr-how-do-i-upgrade-my-mox-installation&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you run into any problems, please create a bug report.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Thanks&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks for contributions and/or feedback from: pmarini, tabatinga0xffff,
lmeunier, alex, arnt, abdul h, cuu508, naturalethic, nixigaj, mattfbacon,
jsfan3, hmfaysal, damir &amp;amp; marin from sartura, RobSlgm, daftaupe, vipas84,
TragicLifeHu, manaus0xff, jdlawrie, Bloomers7577, kbrgmn (and all those I
missed).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feedback, feature requests, bug reports, contributions (start small!) are all
welcome. An easy way to help mox is to use it and spread the word!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Development on mox is funded through the NLnet NGI0 Entrust Fund,
https://nlnet.nl/entrust/, with financial support from the European
Commission's Next Generation Internet programme.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/mjl-/mox/releases/tag/v0.0.11" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/mjl-/mox/releases/tag/v0.0.12</id>
    <title>New release for Mox: v0.0.12</title>
    <updated>2024-10-06T08:11:46-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>mjl-/mox</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h1&gt;Improvements&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;webmail: Change many inline styles to using css classes, and add dark mode.
  (#163 by mattfbacon, a16c08681b71)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;webmail: In compose window, merge close &amp;amp; cancel button, and align buttons on
  the right. (4d28a02621f2)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;mox backup: Add hint about systemd ReadWritePaths if hardlinking fails on
  linux due to cross-device link. (#170 by rdelaage, 44a6927379cd)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;mox backup: Clarify behaviour with destination directory, and exit code.
  (#172 by RobSlgm, 1fc8f165f75e)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When removing account, remove its data directory instead of leaving it
  around. (#162 by RobSlgm &amp;amp; x8x, 30ac690c8f64)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Give more helpful pointers for dns-related setup, such as troubleshooting dns
  resolving, and multi-line dkim dns records. (#158, #164, vipas84, RobSlgm,
  83004bb18e3c)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improve http request handling for internal services (web interfaces) and
  multiple domains. The handler for /admin/ is now only enabled on the listener
  (machine) host name by default, no longer all hosted domains. The internal
  handlers (for admin, account, webmail, webapi), can now also be explicitly
  configured in the webserver section, for additional/custom endpoints to serve
  those services on. (#160 by TragicLifeHu, 614576e409a6)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;During DNS self-check, if the SRV records with just a dot (for a non-existent
  service), is missing, show as warning, not as error. (#184 by morki,
  e350af7eed68)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;During DNS self-check, warn when DANE is not configured (through static host
  keys), instead of showing "OK". (#185 by morki, 73373a19c134)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Systemd service file now syslogs as facility "mail". (by kiekerjan,
  151bd1a9c044)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add favicon to web interfaces. Admins can use the webserver config to serve a
  different file. (#186 by morki, c629ae26afee)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Attempts at improving interoperability with SMTP clients and the "login" SASL
  authentication mechanism. (#51 by hmfaysal, #223 by gdunstone &amp;amp; wneessen,
  aead73883601, 7ecc3f68ce92)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Recognize more charsets than utf-8/iso-8859-1/us-ascii when parsing message
  headers with addresses. (#204 by morki, 5678b0332486)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;webapi: Implement adding "alternative files" to messages sent with the Send
  method. (#188 by morki, 6c488ead0b9e)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;webmail: Add setting to show html version of a message by default, instead of
  text version. (#196 by GildedHonour, b77f44ab5819)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When login sessions to admin/account/webmail interfaces expiry or are no
  longer valid, explain the reason in the message above the login form. (#202
  by ally9335, a977082b89db)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;webapi: Add "RcptTo" to webapi MessageGet result. (mattanja on matrix,
  b0c4b090102c)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;webadmin: At managing aliases, mention an alias member won't receive a
  message if the member address is in the message From header. (#220 by
  wneessen, bbc419c6ab91)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In ACME port config option, explain why using a HTTPS reverse proxy will not
  work for ACME tls-alpn-01 verification. (#218 by mgkirs, 7d3f3071561b)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add more details to X-Mox-Reason message header added during delivery, for
  understanding why a message is accepted/rejected. (#179 by Fell, #157 by
  mattfbacon, 32b549b260a1)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Many small improvements.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Bug fixes&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;webadmin: Propagate error when quota size cannot be parsed, improve parsing
  and hint in error message. (#115 by pmarini-nc, 72be3e8423f6)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;webadmin: Don't show js runtime typecheck errors for invalid values in DMARC
  and TLS reports. (#161 by RobSlgm, a2c9cfc55be6)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;webmail: In list of From address to use in compose window, don't add the
  catchall address. (1a0a396713ab)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;webmail: Only show "edit" button on drafts, and similar for "e" shortcut.
  (8254e9ce66d2)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;webadmin: Show correct host TLSRPT record in dns selfcheck, and make all
  suggested dns records absolute. (#182 by mdavids, 9bab3124f6fa)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Show the same SPF record for a domain in the dnsrecords and dnscheck
  output/pages. (#176 by rdelaage &amp;amp; RobSlgm, 7e54280a9d9d)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix parsing message headers with addresses that need double quotes. (#199 by
  gene-hightower, 016fde8d7832)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reject attempts at STARTTLS for SMTP &amp;amp; IMAP when no TLS config is present.
  Instead of dereferencing a nil pointer, which is caught by the go runtime,
  with fallback error handling gracefully closing the SMTP connection.
  (a7bdc41cd407)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For certain errors during SCRAM authentication, handle errors more gracefully
  instead of aborting the connection. (#222 by wneessen, c7315cb72d65)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For messages retired from the delivery queue, set "success" field properly,
  and include the SMTP code/enhanced code on success too (not only on failure).
  (fdc0560ac4e7)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;webmail: Fix loading a "view" (messages in a mailbox) when the "initial"
  message cannot be parsed. (#219 by wneessen, fb65ec0676ab)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;smtpclient: Handle server closing connection after writing its response to
  RCPT TO in pipelined mode. (#198 by soheilpro, 17346d6def1d)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;imapserver: Prevent unbounded memory allocations when handling a command
  (solves same problem as in CVE-2024-34055). (aef99a72d8f8)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For incoming SMTP deliveries with STARTTLS, use certificate of hostname if
  SNI hostname is unknown. Instead of failing the connection because no
  certificates are available. Fixes interoperability with SMTP clients that do
  opportunistic SMTP without sending a hostname. (#206 by RobSlgm, 62bd2f442731)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Update instructions&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before upgrading, do a dry-run first.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make a temporary backup with the old mox version:
        &lt;code&gt;mox-v0.0.11 backup data/tmp/testupgrade&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Verify that all is well with the old version:
        &lt;code&gt;mox-v0.0.11 verifydata data/tmp/testupgrade&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Verify the state with the new version:
        &lt;code&gt;mox-v0.0.12 verifydata data/tmp/testupgrade&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With a successful dry-run, the upgrade should go smoothly.  Make a new backup
with &lt;code&gt;mox-v0.0.11 backup data/tmp/backup&lt;/code&gt; (the previous backup was modified by
the dry-run, so couldn't be used to restore!), replace the binary and restart.
For further details, see
https://www.xmox.nl/faq/#hdr-how-do-i-upgrade-my-mox-installation&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you run into any problems, please create a bug report.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After upgrading, you may want to run "mox reparse" to parse the message headers
of all messages in all accounts. Message headers for addresses with character
sets other than us-ascii/utf-8/iso-8859-1 will be fixed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Thanks&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks for all contributions, bug reports, feedback and discussions. It improves
mox, keep it coming!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Development on mox is funded through the NLnet NGI0 Entrust Fund,
https://nlnet.nl/entrust/, with financial support from the European
Commission's Next Generation Internet programme.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Downloading &amp;amp; compiling&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See https://www.xmox.nl/install/#hdr-download.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/mjl-/mox/releases/tag/v0.0.12" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/mjl-/mox/releases/tag/v0.0.13</id>
    <title>New release for Mox: v0.0.13</title>
    <updated>2024-11-06T18:11:08-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>mjl-/mox</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;This release fixes TLS interoperability with incoming deliveries from Microsoft
servers by disabling TLS session tickets. If you have MTA-STS and/or DANE
enabled, TLS is required for successful delivery, and updating to v0.0.13 is
required to receive messages from Microsoft again. TLS session tickets may be
enabled again in a future release, possibly per port/service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Improvements&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In the IMAP server, for the "bodystructure" response item to a "FETCH"
  command, add the content-type parameters for multiparts so IMAP clients will
  get the MIME boundary without having to parse the message themselves. (issue
  #217, 8fa197b19dfe)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add an HTTP handler for the acme http-01 validiation mechanism to all plain
  http (non-tls) webservers (ports), not only to the one listening on port 80.
  (#issue 218, 0fbf24160c65)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Properly link to matrix room so users can find it. (issue #226, 76f7b9ebf64c)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Bug fixes&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Disable session tickets for tls to workaround deliverability issues with
  incoming email from Microsoft over smtp with starttls. Without this fix,
  email from Microsoft is no long coming in. (issue #237, 22c8911bf3f7)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In the SMTP server, when logging about problems with recipients, actually
  show which recipients were present in the session. (issue #232,
  598c5ea6ac9f).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Webmail: During "send and archive", don't fail with error message when
  message that is being responded to is already in archive folder. (issue #233,
  879477a01f72)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Webmail: if we don't have loaded account settings yet, abort loading the
  popup after showing an error that the settings aren't available yet. (issue
  #218, 04305722a783)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Update instructions&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before upgrading, do a dry-run first.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make a temporary backup with the old mox version:
        &lt;code&gt;mox-v0.0.12 backup data/tmp/testupgrade&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Verify that all is well with the old version:
        &lt;code&gt;mox-v0.0.12 verifydata data/tmp/testupgrade&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Verify the state with the new version:
        &lt;code&gt;mox-v0.0.13 verifydata data/tmp/testupgrade&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With a successful dry-run, the upgrade should go smoothly.  Make a new backup
with &lt;code&gt;mox-v0.0.12 backup data/tmp/backup&lt;/code&gt; (the previous backup was modified by
the dry-run, so couldn't be used to restore!), replace the binary and restart.
For further details, see
https://www.xmox.nl/faq/#hdr-how-do-i-upgrade-my-mox-installation&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you run into any problems, please create a bug report.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Thanks&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks for all the contributions/bug reports/feedback/discussions, much
appreciated!  Special thanks to mdavids, danieleggert, startup-001-steve,
snabb, mattfbacon, mgkirs, exander77.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Development on mox is funded through the NLnet NGI0 Entrust Fund,
https://nlnet.nl/entrust/, with financial support from the European
Commission's Next Generation Internet programme.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Downloading &amp;amp; compiling&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See https://www.xmox.nl/install/#hdr-download.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/mjl-/mox/releases/tag/v0.0.13" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/mjl-/mox/releases/tag/v0.0.14</id>
    <title>New release for Mox: v0.0.14</title>
    <updated>2025-01-20T07:17:54-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>mjl-/mox</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h1&gt;New features&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Implement TLS client certificate authentication using their public keys (not
  other certificate properties, so no name/expiration/constraint validation).
  Accounts can add multiple TLS public keys, e.g. one for each mail client. For
  use with SMTP/IMAP and the "external" SASL authentication mechanism. IMAP
  "preauth" is enabled with TLS certificate authentication, but can be disabled
  per key. (8804d6b60ec0)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Improvements&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;quickstart: Write all output to a file "quickstart.log" for later reference
  (2255ebcf1186)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;smtpserver: Add an option for the smtp delivery listener to enable/disable tls
  session tickets. (issue #237, e59f894a94c2)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;smtpserver: Add prometheus metric and alerting rule for failing starttls
  handshakes for incoming deliveries. (related to issue #237, afb182cb14de)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;webmail: Split pasted address into multiple address, by commas. (PR #252,
  501f594a0af5)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clarify that "aliases" are more small-scale lists, not additional addresses
  for an account. And make "public posting" the default for new aliases. (issue
  #244, 0e338b0530c3, cbe418ec5934)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;smtpserver: When doing slow writes due to spammy incoming delivery, try a bit
  harder to prevent a timeout for the other side (if it is mox/itself!)
  (5a14a5b067ac)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;quickstart: For -existing-webserver, also add tls key/cert placeholder for
  mail.$domain. (5320ec1c5bc8)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do not try to get a tls cert for autoconfig.&lt;domain&gt; at startup if there is no
  listener with autoconfig enabled. Reduces needless logging in setups that don't
  use autoconfig. (35af7e30a6ad)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"mox retrain" command: Make the "account" parameter optional, retraining all
  accounts when absent. (94fb48c2dc02)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;webmail: Move config options for showing keyboard shortcuts and for showing
  additional headers from localstorage to the settings popup, storing their values
  on the server. (3f727cf38094)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;webmail: Don't bind to shortcuts ctrl-l, ctrl-u and ctrl-I since they are
  commonly used in browsers. (4d3c4115f823)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;webapi: Add Content-Disposition and Filename to the payload of incoming
  webhooks (issue #258, 42793834f8b6)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add ability to include custom CSS &amp;amp; JS in web interfaces (webmail, webaccount,
  webadmin), and use css variables in webmail for easier customization.
  (96d86ad6f1e6, related to issue #114)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;webmail: When marking message as unread, also clear its (non)junk flags
  (1f604c6a3db4)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;webaccount: Update text about opening apple mobileconfig profile files, it has
  gotten harder to use in iOS18. (636bb91df6d8)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;admin: Better handling of disabled MTA-STS during self-check. (7f5e1087d42d)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;admin: In self-check for SPF records against our IPs, don't try checking the
  unspecified addresses (0.0.0.0 and ::), and warn if there are no explicitly
  configured IPs. (726c0931f77d)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;autoconfig: More RFC compliant SRV service not available DNS records (issue
  #240, 355488028db4)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Bug fixes&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix verifying DANE-TA connections for outgoing email deliveries where the
  DANE-TA record is not for the first certificate in the chain after the leaf
  certifiate. (f7666d1582fe)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;junk filter: Fix adjusting word counts after train/untrain. (17baf9a8830c)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Log when mox root process cannot forward signals to unprivileged child and
  give the mox.service permissions to send such signals. (32d4e9a14c25)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;webadmin: When loading page with webserver routes, internal services would
  always be shown with "admin" as internal services, and saving the handler would
  overwrite the correct setting. (issue #264, 965a2b426fae)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When opening an account by email address, such as during login attempts, and
  the address is an alias, fail with proper error "no such credentials" instead of
  with error "no such account" and printing a stack trace. (for issue #238,
  3d4cd0043094)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;webmail: Fix using the compose window/popup after saving a draft message
  failed. (issue #256, ee48cf0dfd46)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;webmail: Fix css to not show text on button (actually html "a" element for
  links) for downloaded (visited) attachments in blue. (f7193bd4c321)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Update procedure&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After updating, run "mox retrain" to retrain the bayesian junk filter for all
accounts. Retraining an account with many messages can require quite some
working memory. Due to a bug (now fixed), reclassifying messages as (non)-junk
updated the scores of words incorrectly, sometimes resulting in very high
(non)-junk reputation of some words. The junk filter should perform better
after retraining.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are using the mox.service systemd unit file on Linux, you should add
"CAP_KILL" to CapabilityBoundingSet (and reload &amp;amp; restart the service) so
graceful shut downs are faster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before upgrading, do a dry-run first.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make a temporary backup with the old mox version:
        &lt;code&gt;mox-v0.0.13 backup data/tmp/testupgrade&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Verify that all is well with the old version:
        &lt;code&gt;mox-v0.0.13 verifydata data/tmp/testupgrade&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Verify the state with the new version:
        &lt;code&gt;mox-v0.0.14 verifydata data/tmp/testupgrade&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With a successful dry-run, the upgrade should go smoothly.  Make a new backup
with &lt;code&gt;mox-v0.0.13 backup data/tmp/backup&lt;/code&gt; (the previous backup was modified by
the dry-run, so couldn't be used to restore!), replace the binary and restart.
For further details, see
https://www.xmox.nl/faq/#hdr-how-do-i-upgrade-my-mox-installation&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you run into any problems, please create a bug report.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Thanks&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks for all the contributions/bug reports/feedback/discussions, much
appreciated!  Special thanks to: exander77, bwbroersma, Robby-, wneessen,
kiekerjan, robbo5000, morki, laura-lilly, ally9335, spectral369, mattfbacon,
mwyvr, s0ph0s-dog, soheilpro and many more!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Downloading &amp;amp; compiling&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See https://www.xmox.nl/install/#hdr-download.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/mjl-/mox/releases/tag/v0.0.14" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/mjl-/mox/releases/tag/v0.0.15</id>
    <title>New release for Mox: v0.0.15</title>
    <updated>2025-04-18T15:47:02-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>mjl-/mox</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h1&gt;New features&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Implement IMAP NOTIFY extension from RFC 5465. Where IDLE is for monitoring a
  single mailbox, NOTIFY allows monitoring many/all mailboxes in an account at
  once. (8bab38eac4c5)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Implement IMAP UIDONLY extension, RFC 9586, greatly reducing data
  accounting and memory use for IMAP connections (once clients support it).
  (507ca73b96ac)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Implement IMAP MULTISEARCH extension, searching multiple mailboxes with a single
  command. (479bf2912489)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Implement IMAP PREVIEW extension (RFC 8970), and store previews in
  the message database. Automatically generated and stored on first request for
  existing messages, or during delivery for new messages. (aa631c604c19,
  6ab31c15b798, 3ac38aacca27)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Implement IMAP REPLACE extension, RFC 8508, used for replacing drafts
  as they are typed. (92a87acfcbb5)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Implement MULTIAPPEND extension, RFC 3502, for appending multiple messages in
  a single command, useful for importing messages into a mailbox.  (78e0c0255f8d)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Implement IMAP METADATA extension, RFC 5464 (f30c44eddb20,
  28091364514e, #290)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Implement RFC 9590, returning metadata in the IMAP extended list
  command (0ed820e3b084)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Implement IMAP "INPROGRESS" response code (RFC 9585) for keepalive
  and progress reportng during long search. (cc5e3165eaf6)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Announce support for IMAP NAMESPACE extension in imap
  capabilities line. (95d2002e7762)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Implement IMAP WITHIN extension, RFC 5032, for additional search command
  criteria. (5e4d80d48e1d)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Implement IMAP CREATE-SPECIAL-USE extension for the mailbox
  create command, part of RFC 6154. (dcaa99a85c00)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Implement IMAP SAVEDATE extension, RFC 8514. (7288e038e67f)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Keep track of login attempts, both successful and failures. Now shown in
  account and admin interfaces. (1277d78cb1a0)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add config domain option for multiple localpart catch all separators, e.g.
  both "+" and "-", for addresses you+anything@example.com and
  you-anything@example.com. (#301, 9a8bb1134b1b)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add account config option to prevent the account for setting their own custom
  password, only allowing mox to generate a new password, and enable by default
  for new accounts. Should prevent password reuse and users picking weak
  passwords, but does not prevent password phishing. (#286, 3e53abc4dbed)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add config options to disable a domain and to disable logins for an account.
  (#175, 2d3d726f0580)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add account config option to reject incoming deliveries with an error during
  the smtp transaction. Useful for rejecting deliveries to specific addresses when
  a catchall is configured. (#156, 3e2695323c1e)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;webmail: Add buttons to download a message as eml, and export 1 or more
  messages as mbox/maildir in zip/tgz/tar, like for entire mailboxes.
  (a5d74eb7185c)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;webmail: Add button to create a mailbox below another one, for convenience.
  (ef77f58e086b)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;webmail: Add button to mark a mailbox and its children as read.
  (ad26fd265d58)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Improvements&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Write base64 message parts with 76 data bytes on a line instead of 78, as
  required by RFC 2045 (MIME). The 78 byte lines work as well, except that
  SpamAssassin gives them a higher spam score.
  (69d269996168)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Change "mox backup $destdir" from storing only data files to $destdir to
  storing them under $destdir/data and now also copying config files, to
  $destdir/config. (#150, 76e96ee673f8)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;quickstart: Check if domain was registered recently using RDAP, and warn
  about potential deliverability issues. (2f0997682beb)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hide version number from smtp banner and imap ID command response (when
  unauthenticated), and web interfaces. (68729fa5a312, 3a3a11560e17, #322)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When adding a new domain, only set up RSA DKIM keys, not ed25519. The ed25519
  key is causing admin confusion due to many other mail servers not recognizing
  the keys and sending DMARC reports containing unhelpful DKIM verification
  errors. (#299, 2fc75b5b7b7b)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;webmail: Reconnect automatically in more cases, changing the "stop
  reconnection automatically" period from 10 minutes to 5 seconds. (5dcf67476166)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;webmail: For "cid"/content-id's used in html, look for them in all other
  parts, not just when there is a multipart/related in the message. Fixes
  displaying messages sent by the gmail app, which sends messages with a MIME form
  of multipart/mixed containing text/html and image/jpeg. We were only resolving
  "cid"s in multipart/related, now we resolve them anywhere in the message. (#327,
  462568d878e7)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add support for negotiating IMAP and SMTP on the HTTPS port 443 using TLS
  ALPN "imap" and "smtp". Intended for future use with chatmail servers. (#255,
  3c77e076e228)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;imapserver: Return all the optional extensible fields for "fetch" attribute
  "bodystructure", notably for content-disposition. Makes the gmail apps show
  image attachments properly, instead of rendering the image bytes as (garbled)
  text. This requires reparsing all messages, which is done automatically, in the
  background, on first account open after the upgrade (2defbce0bc05, 31c22618f5de,
  07533252b33b, #327, #217)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;webmail: When composing, no longer remove the last remaining To address with
  the ctrl+backspace shortcut. Too easy to trigger accidentally, almost never done
  intentionally. (70aedddc9096)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improve expunged message/UID tracking in IMAP sessions, track synchronization
  history for mailboxes/annotations. We now delay removing message files from disk
  until the last reference in any session goes away (e.g. after sending an IMAP
  EXPUNGE/VANISHED response to all connected IMAP clients with the mailbox open).
  (577944310cb6)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When removing an account, wait until the last account reference has gone away
  before removing the account files. We store intent to remove in the database,
  until we get to it, possibly at next startup in case of sudden shutdown.
  (ac4b006ecd91)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;imapserver: Don't keep account write-locked during IMAP FETCH command, for
  responsiveness during large mailbox syncs. (#128, b822533df31d)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add prometheus metrics for errors when getting certificates through ACME
  (typically from let's encrypt), and add alerting rule. (e5e15a3965c2)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;webmail: When forwarding a message, include the
  subject,date,from,reply-to,to,cc headers in the message (1c4bf8909c45)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Also unicode-normalize usernames (email addresses) when logging into the
  imapserver and webapps. (c7354cc22b22)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When delivering over smtp, do not require the other server to announce the
  8bitmime extension for 8-bit data unless in pedantic mode. (#287, 46c1693ee935)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do not use results from junk filter if we have less than 50 positive
  classifications to base the decision on. Useful for new accounts, we don't want
  to start rejecting incoming messages when there's too little information to
  decide. (#64, 6aa2139a54c9)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Admin check: Do not raise error when forward-confirmed reverse dns does not
  match hostname. Probably relatively common with setups involving NAT. (#239,
  acc1c133b022)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add config option to an account destination to reject messages that don't
  pass a dmarc-like aligned spf/aligned dkim check. (6da5f8f586ac)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;cli: Add subcommand "mox admin imapserve $preauthaddress", for admins to open
  a preauthenticated imap connection for an account, even if it is disabled for
  logins (useful for migrations). (#175, 49e2eba52bb0)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;webmail: In message view, under More, add button to open currently displayed
  part (either text or html) as raw text (but decoded if in
  base64/quoted-printable/etc). (008de1cafb34)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;cli: Add subcommand "mox config account list", printing all accounts and
  whether they are disabled. (1b2b152cb5d3)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For the web interfaces, ensure the effective configured http paths end in a
  slash to prevent 404's and/or errors accessing the web interfaces, preventing
  admin confusion. (#325, 3e128d744e7f)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Bug fixes&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;smtp: Add data reader fuzzer + fix OOB read. (f10bb2c1ae22)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;webmail: When completing a recipient address, quote the "name" if necessary
  for proper interpretation. (#305, 1c58d382803c)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;After queueing a message in the web api's, prevent context cancelation (e.g.
  aborted http connections) from completing the operation in full. (b37faa06bdd2)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;smtpserver: In localserve mode, don't reject messages "From" domain
  "localhost" if localhost doesn't resolve to an IP through DNS. (d0b241499fc3)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;webserver: Don't raise a 500 server error for static file requests with
  overlong names. (aa2b24d861fd)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;webmail: Fix parsing search filter "start:&lt;date&gt;" and "end:&lt;date&gt;".
  (091faa8048e0)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;webmail: Fix dark mode, broken since v0.0.14. (#278, d08e0d3882dd)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;webmail: Fix nil pointer dereference when searching for attachment types, eg
  "a:spreadsheet" (#272, 0203dfa9d981)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;imapserver: Return proper response for FETCH of "BODY[1.MIME]" where 1 is a
  message (39c21f80cd31)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;imapserver: Properly accept literal8 for APPEND, since we claim to implement
  the BINARY extension (88a68e91439d)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In domain/dns self-check, for unused services, check in SRV records that port
  is 0 like how we told users to configure it and fix checking for errors during
  srv lookups, and show the value we got but didn't expect; show config snippet
  for HostTLSRPT if it isn't configured; don't warn about reverse dns resolving to
  multiple names. (9dff879164b3, 3d0dc3a79db8, 6f678125a56d, 1d6f45e59229)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Update procedure&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before upgrading, do a dry-run first.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make a temporary backup with the old mox version:
        &lt;code&gt;mox-v0.0.14 backup data/tmp/testupgrade&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Verify that all is well with the old version:
        &lt;code&gt;mox-v0.0.14 verifydata data/tmp/testupgrade&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Verify the state with the new version:
        &lt;code&gt;mox-v0.0.15 verifydata data/tmp/testupgrade&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With a successful dry-run, the upgrade should go smoothly.  Make a new backup
again with &lt;code&gt;mox-v0.0.14 backup data/tmp/backup&lt;/code&gt; (the previous backup was
modified by the dry-run, so couldn't be used to restore!), replace the binary
and restart.  For further details, see
https://www.xmox.nl/faq/#hdr-how-do-i-upgrade-my-mox-installation&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you run into any problems, please create a bug report.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Manual update actions&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additional manual actions to consider:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You may want to modify your backup scripts: "mox backup" now writes a data/
  and config/ directory to the backup destination directory. Previously it only
  wrote data files, directly to the backup destination directory. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You may want to disable signing with ed25519 DKIM keys to reduce noise in
  DMARC reports from other mail servers that often don't understand ed25519 keys.
  Make sure you do keep signing with an RSA key.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You may want to add the new prometheus alerting rule for
  "mox_autotls_cert_request_errors_total", alerting on errors when
  fetching/refreshing certificates with ACME. See prometheus.rules in the mox
  repository.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Thanks&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to everyone on irc/matrix/slack and the issue tracker for providing
feedback, and asking &amp;amp; answering questions. Much appreciated!  In particular:
ulrichwisser, eric l, kjetilho, Myp3a, mattfbacon, janc13, dstotijn, Eygem,
martin, rawtaz, ilijamt, skyguy, mattanja, BlankEclair, gdunstone, unguamorray,
DanielG, RobSlgm, ally9335, x8x, exander77, s0ph0s-dog, odama626, wneessen,
omartijn, sam-willsey, QuadrupleA, hrstoyanov, mtgxx, martinjanda, shleeable,
haraldrudell, and more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have open bug reports/issues mentioned in this release, please verify
the issue is resolved and either close the issue or write a comment. Thanks!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Special thanks to NLnet foundation for sponsoring development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Downloading &amp;amp; compiling&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See https://www.xmox.nl/install/#hdr-download.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/mjl-/mox/releases/tag/v0.0.15" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
