<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://selfh.st/apps</id>
  <title>MyBibliotheca Releases</title>
  <updated>2025-06-27T23:36:40.611417-04:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>selfh.st</name>
    <email>contact@selfh.st</email>
  </author>
  <link href="https://selfh.st/apps" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>Self-hosted software releases generated by selfh.st</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/pickles4evaaaa/mybibliotheca/releases/tag/v1.0.0</id>
    <title>New release for MyBibliotheca: v1.0.0</title>
    <updated>2025-06-11T09:47:33-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>pickles4evaaaa/mybibliotheca</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;Initial release&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Full Changelog&lt;/strong&gt;: https://github.com/pickles4evaaaa/bibliotheca/commits/v1.0.0&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/pickles4evaaaa/mybibliotheca/releases/tag/v1.0.0" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/pickles4evaaaa/mybibliotheca/releases/tag/v1.0.1</id>
    <title>New release for MyBibliotheca: Docker! </title>
    <updated>2025-06-11T17:14:39-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>pickles4evaaaa/mybibliotheca</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;Many changes in this release, and I am still getting around to keeping things tidy. For now, please keep an eye on the commit notes for the most accurate changes. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of the work today was spent on the following two items:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;1 Support for Docker (arm64 and amd64 support was just added.)&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The container now uses a named volume due to issues with trying to map host folders. The volume stores the books.db database and can easily be inspected and copied with a few CLI commands. For those wanting to look under the hood at the database, using those docker CLI tools will be helpful. You can even run SQLite3 commands within a container. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note&lt;/strong&gt;: This build officially uses Gunicorn to serve the Flask application. Gunicorn (Green Unicorn) is a production-grade WSGI HTTP server that is designed for performance, security, and reliability in real-world deployments. Unlike Flask’s built-in development server (flask run), which is intended for debugging and local testing, Gunicorn can handle multiple requests concurrently, works well with process managers like systemd or supervisord, and is compatible with reverse proxies such as Nginx.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By using Gunicorn, this build ensures:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Better concurrency via worker processes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved stability under load or concurrent users&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Proper error handling and graceful restarts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Compatibility with production best practices&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note: #3 At the moment, there is ZERO workaround for this. Users will need to either obtain SSL certificates/host their instance behind a Cloudflare tunnel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note: #4 Documentation is a WIP and will continue to be so...&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/pickles4evaaaa/mybibliotheca/releases/tag/v1.0.1" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/pickles4evaaaa/mybibliotheca/releases/tag/v1.0.2</id>
    <title>New release for MyBibliotheca: </title>
    <updated>2025-06-12T12:56:46-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>pickles4evaaaa/mybibliotheca</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;📦 Release Notes
✅ Minor Changes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved Docker workflow: Cleaner build process, persistent volumes, and environment-based configuration.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reading streaks now stored in database: Ensures streak data persists and is synced properly across sessions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added version numbers to footer of web app to keep things organized.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New Docker image has been pushed and is live&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/pickles4evaaaa/mybibliotheca/releases/tag/v1.0.2" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/pickles4evaaaa/mybibliotheca/releases/tag/v1.1.1</id>
    <title>New release for MyBibliotheca: V1.1.1 MyBibliotheca</title>
    <updated>2025-06-16T13:55:27-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>pickles4evaaaa/mybibliotheca</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update&lt;/strong&gt;:
&lt;em&gt;A name change and social icon footer was added to this realease, but only to the Docker tage (1.1.1)
Use image '&lt;strong&gt;pickles4evaaaa/mybibliotheca:1.1.1&lt;/strong&gt;' to apply these changes.
The source code will remain without the name or footer social icon changes.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wow! We have been making a lot of changes. First of all, thank you to those who have contributed code as well as awesome ideas and feedback. This whole thing is new to me and I feel like we have hit the ground running!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Version 1.1.0 is the biggest release yet, and there are a ton of changes. I promise I will get better at logging them more effectively. For now, keep an eye on the commits. Below are some of the major changes that have been made! &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Missing database columns are auto-added for new changes in this update. It is highly advised that you BACK UP YOUR DATABASE. We have added a handy little button in the footer of the project to download 'books.db'&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Book metadata has been added insofar as users can now list their library by language, publisher, title, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bulk import of CSVs has been added! Check out test_files/test_bulk_import_upcs.csv for how the CSV file should be formatted. Goodreads bulk import has stayed put and can continue to be used. Users have reported that, depending on their library size, the server may crash. Until we have a true fix, I recommend dividing up the Goodreads file or just using the bulk importer which uses a simpler method to import large datasets. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There have been many minor improvements and bug fixes. Please check out the commit history to get specifics, as well as check out the issue history to see what has been closed. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Going forward, releases will now have tags on Docker hub :) Closes #18 &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Help Wanted&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am asking for help with getting official documentation #4  going for Bibliotheca. Please reach out to me if you are interested in tackling this. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Again, thanks to all who have submitted pull requests, comments, feedback, and bug reports. This project has been so much fun, and I look forward to seeing where it goes from here!! &lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/pickles4evaaaa/mybibliotheca/releases/tag/v1.1.1" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
