<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://selfh.st/apps</id>
  <title>Mylar3 Releases</title>
  <updated>2025-03-10T06:32:06.096925-04:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>selfh.st</name>
    <email>contact@selfh.st</email>
  </author>
  <link href="https://selfh.st/apps" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>Self-hosted software releases generated by selfh.st</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/mylar3/mylar3/releases/tag/v0.7.7</id>
    <title>New release for Mylar3: Friendship is real, yo, and it kicked your butt!</title>
    <updated>2023-12-27T02:52:41-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>mylar3/mylar3</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Improvements&lt;/strong&gt;
IMP: Prefer HD-Upscale/HD-Digital added as an option under the DDL banner in the config page.
IMP: Permissions redid to make sure that owner / group values entered are present prior to attempting to enforce. If not available will default to the user running mylar or the group user belong to depending on what is not present.
IMP: Manage DDL page -&amp;gt; will now show the full filename of the pack instead of series #issuenumber (ie. Superhero # 1)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fixes&lt;/strong&gt;
FIX: (#1461) MAC OS metadata files would be scanned in mistakingly during series page loads / rechecks
FIX: (#1444) Annuals not included during group metatagging operation
FIX: (#1446) Occasional db conflict during issue updates in previous PR
FIX: Fixed some table overlapping on the Manage DDL page resulting in overflows
FIX: Increased last issue table on main page as was cutting off/overlapping on large issue numbers
FIX: When updating series info with new issue data, if a series was paused it would un-pause and mark issues as wanted if the options were enabled (mark all as wanted, mark upcoming as wanted)
FIX: Provider order would not be honored if DDL was an available option due to the way the search thru number padding was. Will now search all possible queries in a provider before moving onto the next provider regardless of the issue number
FIX: Searching would take the cover date as the actual search date, not the store date which caused problems around the end of the year
FIX: New issues set to Skipped even when series is not paused
FIX: CDH would fail to post-process items immediately if additional items were in the sabnzbd queue
FIX: When searching for issues published in late 2023, wouldn't match to 2024 filenames due to invalid date comparison
FIX: Mark all issues as wanted config option would mark every issue of a series as Wanted after each recheck/refresh that was not in a Downloaded status, regardless of previous state (ie. manually marking an issue as Skipped)&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/mylar3/mylar3/releases/tag/v0.7.7" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/mylar3/mylar3/releases/tag/v0.7.8</id>
    <title>New release for Mylar3: These streets are deader than Gwen Stacy.</title>
    <updated>2024-01-15T22:07:08-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>mylar3/mylar3</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;FIX:(#1463) Truncated image retrieval check - if failure, will retrieve alternate image quality
FIX:(#1469) incorrect logger reference causing traceback on SAB snatches that are completed quickly
FIX:(#1471) pillow check so it's case-insensitive (went from Pillow to pillow)
FIX: Move gzip header to fix tempermental ddl (@scooterpsu)
FIX: requirements -&amp;gt; bump versions for &lt;strong&gt;cheroot&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;&amp;gt;8.2.1&lt;/em&gt;) and &lt;strong&gt;pillow&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;&amp;gt;10.1 due to python3.12 not working on less than this verison&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/mylar3/mylar3/releases/tag/v0.7.8" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/mylar3/mylar3/releases/tag/v0.8.0</id>
    <title>New release for Mylar3: There is science to conduct… in the laboratory of violence</title>
    <updated>2024-03-14T03:50:04-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>mylar3/mylar3</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Improvements&lt;/strong&gt;
IMP: (DDL) Allow additonal downloading from mega, mediafire and pixeldrain links when using DDL GC.
IMP: (DDL -- config.ini) ddl_priority_order can be customized to set the priority order in which the DDL links will be attempted
IMP: (DDL) Will cycle thru ddl_priority_order in sequence attempting each link as it gets to it, until link is able to be downloaded or link exhaustion occurs
IMP: Don't post-process or scan extensions if provided in ignore_search_words
IMP: listAnnualSeries api endpoint added
IMP: (DDL) Additional add-on server entry for DDL
IMP: (DDL) Improved Pack parsing / detection
IMP: Dupechecker will now prioritize (F#)/(f#) in filenames as 'Fixed' over normally named files or lower numbered (f#)
IMP: Pack issue # tracking will track issues that belong to a particular pack so individually queueing issues within pack before it's completed, will not redownload issues belonging to the pack.
IMP: Added Link column to DDL Manage page (display which type of link was/is being used)
IMP: (DDL --&amp;gt; Manage) Adjusted column widths &amp;amp; spacing to correct some double-lines occurring
IMP: (DDL --&amp;gt; Manage) Show pack issue range for packs as opposed to showing the individual item that was being searched for
IMP: Notification of packs being downloaded will now show which DDL link was used to download as well as complete name of pack
IMP: Update current default user_agent string to a more current string
IMP: CT will now use user_agent string defined by Mylar as opposed to a random generic one on each request (if not updated, will force-update it accordingly)
IMP: Removed individual provider entries for nzbsu and dognzb from GUI, now treated as newznabs. If enabled, will be converted to newznab entry provided doesn't already exist as a newznab.
IMP: If CV indicates series year does not exist (ie. 2099) instead of using 2099, will use year of first issue or if not invalid, current year
IMP: When refreshing/adding a series that has a directory created with the incorrect year (2099), rename existing directory using correct year
IMP: Allow for future removal of outdated config.ini options with BAD_DEFINITIONS code
IMP: CV Api Key entry field on configuration page proper placeholder of None so will auto-remove value prior to typing in field
IMP: Add option to remove SABnzbd completed downloads from SABnzbd history
IMP: ASCII art logo added to startup sequence (cause why not, right?)
IMP: Test python module requirements prior to actually starting the program - failure will result in application exit with appropriate log messages
IMP: Basic configuration check started - comic location failure on existence/creation/permissions will throw a popup error until resolved
IMP: Filter input box on Watchlist page &amp;amp; searchresults page will accept exlusion filters preceded by (:-&lt;term&gt;)
IMP: (#1473) Weeklypull will honor ignore_publishers when displaying the weekly pullist
IMP: Wildcards (&lt;em&gt;) are acceptable in the ignore_publishers value in the config.ini (ie. panini&lt;/em&gt;)
IMP: scheduled searches will have status checked prior to actually searching (cannot be in a Downloaded or Snatched status) unless it was initiated manually (ie. magnifying glass search)
IMP: Added Remove option to DDL table options so items that are stuck in a Start/Incomplete status can be removed
IMP: Detect and handle CV reusing existing ComicIDs via GUI Dialog (Keep / Delete) (see #1506)
IMP: Status color-coded legend to the bottom of the main watchlist/index page
IMP: format_booktype now set to True by default (allows use of $Type in folder format)
IMP: Post-Processing option is now enabled by default
IMP: default usenet_retention set to 3500 days.
IMP: default enforce_permissions set to False
IMP: default metatagging option cmtag_start_year_as_volume set to True
IMP: requirements.txt (added): pycryptodome, tenacity&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fixes&lt;/strong&gt;
FIX: Annuals were written to incorrect table sometimes resulting in status/filename being locked in db and unable to remove
FIX: Annuals that had the year present in the annual name and no issue number would not be recognized during series scans
FIX: (carepackage) when creating carepackage, if requirements were set to == would cause error if it was higher/lower versioning
FIX: Volume of series on cv &amp;gt; 10 would not be recognized as such when adding/refreshing series
FIX: Parsing of files that had part /volume would fail when part was part of the series title
FIX: One-shots with no issue number (but year is present) in filename will now be properly accounted for in series rechecks if booktype is set correctly
FIX: Removed some incorrect logger.warn references so that will log regardless of language
FIX: Error when removing directory that doesn't physically exist where it was recorded as being (delete series option)
FIX: (searchresults --&amp;gt; Edit) would not update comic location path when booktype was changed via dropdown
FIX: (searchresults --&amp;gt; Edit) GN was incorrectly labelled as GC within the booktype dropdown
FIX: Incorrect status colours for annuals when integration is enabled (Archived, Ignored)
FIX: Improper parsing of sabnzbd version in with newer versions would cause errors when checking / sending to sabnzbd
FIX: Remove depreciated imghdr module in lieu of using pillow (api.py)
FIX: Replace depreciated SafeConfigParser call from configparser when generating carepackage
FIX: Depreciation of pkg_resources - use packaging now (addition to requirements)
FIX: Ensure index page will load if provider_order is in error for some reason
FIX: Index page would display Unknown variations for published date when invalid instead of N/A
FIX: Ensure post-processing would be allowed for CV series that have been removed from CV but retained as is within Mylar
FIX: Mass publishers variable would sometimes be in an incorrect type (str) as opposed to type (list) which would cause the mass publishers job to not run
FIX: Selecting All checkbox on seriesdetail page will now select only relevant table (issues / annuals) as opposed to both
FIX: Discord notifications would always throw a could not send notification log message, but notif would be sent ok
FIX: When parsing results of DDL, if pack was detected and an invalid issue number was parsed, would traceback
FIX: DDL --&amp;gt; mediafire would try to get filesize of file that could possibly not exist due to failure resulting in traceback error
FIX: DDL --&amp;gt; traceback when count of links discovered would be more than indicated, not using any links discovered prior to the invalid count check
FIX: DDL --&amp;gt; traceback due to invalid variable reference (comicinfo[[0]['pack'])
FIX: DDL --&amp;gt; prefer upscaled option would incorrectly assume SD-Digital instead of just a normal/undefined labelling of said issue
FIX: Removal of () in folder structure
FIX: Link to CV for items within collected editions
FIX: Searchresults filter would filter everything if used
FIX: Casing when invoking updater.dbUpdate (@cwar)
FIX: (#1510) Adding by comicid would result in error in GUI, but series would still add successfully.
FIX: (#1508) Typo in logger when viewing a Paused series that contained annuals
FIX: (#1507) .Black and .White numbering exceptions added
FIX: When popup appeared, would open all hidden/minimized options in config page if tab was open
FIX: Infinity numbering vs Infinity in series name fix
FIX: Would fail to set selection when previous failures resulted in main link being used
FIX: Remove some additional information from cleaned ini due to previous config additions
FIX:(#1502) sabnzbd version detection problem on startup re: versioning format
FIX: Numeric sort for issue number column on Watchlist and Wanted pages instead of alpha-based
FIX: Booktype will default to Print instead of None
FIX: Error when searching for items being returned no issue numbers
FIX: Ensure Minimum &amp;amp; Maximum filesize restrictions contain only numerics
FIX: Feedparser would blow up (traceback error) when parsing non-digital dates in some cases
FIX: StoryArcs -&amp;gt; Search For Missing button would traceback when initiating the search
FIX: series.json creation as per schema (update to v1.0.2), FIX: proper reload of issues table on regeneration of json
FIX: Subset DDL site(s) to better handle failures/failed marking
FIX: Folder monitor would die on lock, FIX: spamming pack exclusions
FIX: html_cache in cache_dir for GC html files so won't redownload html file until item is successfully downloaded.
FIX: html_cache location added to cleanup_cache section
FIX: Better handling of corrupt images being retrieved from CV (will retry alternate image size if available)
FIX: dbupdater would error when attempting to merge previous_failed_id info into a non-existent dictionary
FIX: Wanted page may not display if IssueNumber field is blank or some other field is empty. Will attempt to default to ComicName.
FIX: DDL ReQueue / Restart would throw a red popup warning due to invalid reference (One-Shot) on Manage DDL page
FIX: DDL  -&amp;gt; If it was the first link used, would cause a traceback when clearing the queue of the id
FIX: DDL --&amp;gt; If it was a retry/requeue, would error on attempting to preload a variable that's not really needed (one-shot) / site name
FIX: DDL --&amp;gt; When initiating a ReQueue/Restart, the resume option will only be attempted if it a main server GC link
FIX: StoryArcs:
--&amp;gt; Search for Missing would fail during post-processing due to invalid variable reference in db table
--&amp;gt; Search for Missing would use invalid issueid when attempting to post-process when downloading resulting in traceback
--&amp;gt; Search for Missing will now mark issues belonging to watchlisted series as Wanted if not already in that status
--&amp;gt; Search for Missing option now indicates what it does on mouseover&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/mylar3/mylar3/releases/tag/v0.8.0" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/mylar3/mylar3/releases/tag/v0.8.1</id>
    <title>New release for Mylar3: I bring you a gospel of oblivion.</title>
    <updated>2025-01-13T02:17:42-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>mylar3/mylar3</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;FIX: pullist updated to accommodate 2025 changes to the weekly format...
FIX: html_cache would not be found when using ddl after saving settings without a restart
FIX: (#1523)(#1530) Horizontal alignment of footer on index page
FIX: ddl_location would not be honored
FIX: optional cbr/cbz cache removal added&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-- note--
this update is required if the pull-list is to be used properly due to the year rollover...2025!&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/mylar3/mylar3/releases/tag/v0.8.1" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/mylar3/mylar3/releases/tag/v0.8.1.1</id>
    <title>New release for Mylar3: No. Not plan B. Plan 2. Plan B implies we only have 26</title>
    <updated>2025-01-13T16:32:19-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>mylar3/mylar3</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;The initial load of the pull-list when starting would have wrong date ranges listed&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a hot-fix / monkey-patch / party favor because people are gonna notice eventually....&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/mylar3/mylar3/releases/tag/v0.8.1.1" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
