<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://selfh.st/apps</id>
  <title>Obsidian LiveSync Releases</title>
  <updated>2024-12-16T08:32:51.961343-05:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>selfh.st</name>
    <email>contact@selfh.st</email>
  </author>
  <link href="https://selfh.st/apps" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>Self-hosted software releases generated by selfh.st</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/vrtmrz/obsidian-livesync/releases/tag/0.24.2</id>
    <title>New release for Obsidian LiveSync: 0.24.2</title>
    <updated>2024-11-21T06:44:01-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>vrtmrz/obsidian-livesync</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h2&gt;0.24.2&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apologies for the lack of replies! I will try to reply to you all little by little.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Rewritten&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hidden File Sync is now respects the file changes on the storage. Not simply comparing modified times.&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This makes hidden file sync more robust and reliable.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Fixed&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Scan hidden files before replication&lt;/code&gt; is now configurable again.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some unexpected errors are now handled more gracefully.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Meaningless event passing during boot sequence is now prevented.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Error handling for non-existing files has been fixed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hidden files will not be batched to avoid the potential error.&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This behaviour had been causing the error in the previous versions in specific situations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The log which checking automatic conflict resolution is now in verbose level.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Replication log (skipping non-targetting files) shows the correct information.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The dialogue that asking enabling optional feature during &lt;code&gt;Rebuild Everything&lt;/code&gt; now prevents to show the &lt;code&gt;overwrite&lt;/code&gt; option.&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The rebuilding device is the first, meaningless.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Files with different modified time but identical content are no longer processed repeatedly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some unexpected errors which caused after terminating plug-in are now avoided.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Improved&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;JSON files are now more transferred efficiently.&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Now the JSON files are transferred in more fine chunks, which makes the transfer more efficient.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/vrtmrz/obsidian-livesync/releases/tag/0.24.2" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/vrtmrz/obsidian-livesync/releases/tag/0.24.3</id>
    <title>New release for Obsidian LiveSync: 0.24.3</title>
    <updated>2024-12-08T19:49:02-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>vrtmrz/obsidian-livesync</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h2&gt;0.24.3&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Improved&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Many messages have been improved for better understanding as thanks to the fine works of @Volkor3-16 ! Thank you so much!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Documentations also have been updated to reflect the changes in the messages.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Now the style of In-Editor Status has been solid for some Android devices.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/vrtmrz/obsidian-livesync/releases/tag/0.24.3" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/vrtmrz/obsidian-livesync/releases/tag/0.24.4</id>
    <title>New release for Obsidian LiveSync: 0.24.4</title>
    <updated>2024-12-12T06:19:18-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>vrtmrz/obsidian-livesync</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h2&gt;0.24.4&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Updating around the &lt;code&gt;processor&lt;/code&gt;, but some other things (i.e., noisy messages and more) still have been left (even though not fatal than processor). 
Thank you for reporting the issue! I will handle it later!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Fixed&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed so many inefficient and buggy modules inherited from the past.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Improved&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tasks are now executed in an efficient asynchronous library.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;On-demand chunk fetching is now more efficient and keeps the interval between requests.&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This will reduce the load on the server and the network.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;And, safe for the Cloudant.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/vrtmrz/obsidian-livesync/releases/tag/0.24.4" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/vrtmrz/obsidian-livesync/releases/tag/0.24.5</id>
    <title>New release for Obsidian LiveSync: 0.24.5</title>
    <updated>2024-12-13T06:16:59-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>vrtmrz/obsidian-livesync</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h2&gt;0.24.5&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As with 0.24.4, this release focuses on weeding out bugs identified during testing. While there are still areas for improvement, this release lays a solid foundation for addressing them more effectively in the future. (However, sorry for keeping the issues open and lacking replies).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Status line updates have been significantly optimised and are now approximately 7x faster, with consistent CPU usage. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Complement: I noticed that the log pane is kept empty now… This will be fixed soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Fixed&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed incorrect behaviour when comparing objects with undefined as a property value.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Improved&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The status line and the log summary are now displayed more smoothly and efficiently.&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This improvement has also been applied to the logs displayed in the log pane.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/vrtmrz/obsidian-livesync/releases/tag/0.24.5" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/vrtmrz/obsidian-livesync/releases/tag/0.24.6</id>
    <title>New release for Obsidian LiveSync: 0.24.6</title>
    <updated>2024-12-13T12:41:44-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>vrtmrz/obsidian-livesync</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h2&gt;0.24.6&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sorry for the recent hasty releases! I am still wondering why I have not noticed... However, it has been clear that issue reporting will not be possible without fixing this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Fixed (Quick Fix)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed the issue of logs not being displayed on the log pane if the pane had not been shown on startup.&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This release is only for it. However, fixing this had been necessary to report any other issues.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/vrtmrz/obsidian-livesync/releases/tag/0.24.6" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
