<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://selfh.st/apps</id>
  <title>Obsidian LiveSync Releases</title>
  <updated>2024-08-02T00:32:52.835734-04:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>selfh.st</name>
    <email>contact@selfh.st</email>
  </author>
  <link href="https://selfh.st/apps" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>Self-hosted software releases generated by selfh.st</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/vrtmrz/obsidian-livesync/releases/tag/0.23.15</id>
    <title>New release for Obsidian LiveSync: 0.23.15</title>
    <updated>2024-07-01T02:37:41-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>vrtmrz/obsidian-livesync</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h2&gt;0.23.15&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Maintenance Release&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The so-called 'inventions on wheels' associated with our constraints that have been created so far have been separated from this project and the library project as a new library. And with that, tests have been written for them for more robust future modifications.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I am also going to refine the platform-dependent libraries (as Phase 2). Then, common things on LiveSync-families will be separated as an isomorphic library (Phase 3). &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I know that this is not an easy way. But we have to get ready for robust synchronisation. Recently, I have had a family sickness being absent for a while, and I feel responsible for a lot of recent problems. And, that I have been writing code that is hard to understand for all of us so. I hope to make it better the things.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note: Due to being frequently away from the keyboard, I created a Fediverse account for such things that were not related to a specific project or for my mere status updates. I still have so much things that relied onto the DeepL and Grammalry, so I may reply in quite broken English. However, now the twitter cannot be reliable, this might be a hotline. (And, I have trying to post in English). Feel free to touch me! &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The account is this: &lt;a href="https://mozilla.social/@vrtmrz"&gt;@vrtmrz@mozilla.social&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(However, I might choose another instance). &lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/vrtmrz/obsidian-livesync/releases/tag/0.23.15" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/vrtmrz/obsidian-livesync/releases/tag/0.23.16</id>
    <title>New release for Obsidian LiveSync: 0.23.16</title>
    <updated>2024-07-10T00:29:21-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>vrtmrz/obsidian-livesync</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h2&gt;0.23.16:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Maintenance Update:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Library refining (Phase 1 - step 2). There are no significant changes on the user side.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Including the following fixes of potentially problems:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the problem which the path had been obfuscating twice has been resolved.&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Note: potential problems of the library; which has not happened in Self-hosted LiveSync for some reasons. However, it could have occurred in LiveSync-Hub.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/vrtmrz/obsidian-livesync/releases/tag/0.23.16" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/vrtmrz/obsidian-livesync/releases/tag/0.23.17</id>
    <title>New release for Obsidian LiveSync: 0.23.17</title>
    <updated>2024-07-12T05:19:54-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>vrtmrz/obsidian-livesync</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h2&gt;0.23.17:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note: Updated the dependencies, please let me know if you have got troubled especially on the traditional devices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Improved:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Overall performance has been improved by using PouchDB 9.0.0.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Configuration mismatch detection is refined. We can resolve mismatches more smoothly and naturally.
More detail is on &lt;a href="https://github.com/vrtmrz/obsidian-livesync/blob/main/docs/troubleshooting.md#how-to-resolve-tweaks-mismatched-of-changed"&gt;&lt;code&gt;troubleshooting.md&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; on the repository.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Fixed:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Customisation Sync will be disabled when a corrupted configuration is detected.
  Therefore, the Device Name can be changed even in the event of a configuration mismatch.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;New feature:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We can get a notification about the storage usage of the remote database.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Default: We will be asked.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If the remote storage usage approaches the configured value, we will be asked whether we want to Rebuild or increase the limit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/vrtmrz/obsidian-livesync/releases/tag/0.23.17" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/vrtmrz/obsidian-livesync/releases/tag/0.23.18</id>
    <title>New release for Obsidian LiveSync: 0.23.18</title>
    <updated>2024-07-25T08:44:31-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>vrtmrz/obsidian-livesync</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h2&gt;0.23.18:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A lot of things have been going on and it has been late. Thank you for your patience. However! Customisation Sync has reached Beta 3.
The screen no longer collapses and it also works very quickly when per-file-saved customisation sync is enabled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you probably already know, I often post my daily progress on &lt;a href="https://mozilla.social/@vrtmrz"&gt;Fediverse&lt;/a&gt;. Many days I only have my smartphone and tablet with me during my free time. Of course, I will reply to issues soon! I always appreciate your posts!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;New feature:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Per-file-saved customization sync has been shipped.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We can synchronise plug-ins etc., more smoothly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Default: disabled. We need a small migration when enabling this. And all devices should be updated to v0.23.18. Once we enabled this, we lost compatibility with old versions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Customisation sync has got beta3.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We can set &lt;code&gt;Flag&lt;/code&gt; to each item to select the newest, automatically.&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This configuration is per device.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Improved:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Start-up speed has been improved.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Fixed:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;On the customisation sync dialogue, buttons are kept within the screen.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No more unnecessary entries on &lt;code&gt;data.json&lt;/code&gt; for customisation sync.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Selections are no longer lost while updating customisation items.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Tidied on source codes:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Many typos have been fixed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some unnecessary type casting removed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/vrtmrz/obsidian-livesync/releases/tag/0.23.18" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/vrtmrz/obsidian-livesync/releases/tag/0.23.20</id>
    <title>New release for Obsidian LiveSync: 0.23.20</title>
    <updated>2024-07-30T21:34:29-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>vrtmrz/obsidian-livesync</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h2&gt;0.23.20:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Fixed:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Customisation Sync now checks the difference while storing or applying the configuration.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No longer storing the same configuration multiple times.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Time difference in the dialogue has been fixed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Remote Storage Limit Notification dialogue has been fixed, now the chosen value is saved.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Improved:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Enlarging button on the enlarging threshold dialogue now displays the new value.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/vrtmrz/obsidian-livesync/releases/tag/0.23.20" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
