<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://selfh.st/apps</id>
  <title>Obsidian LiveSync Releases</title>
  <updated>2024-11-02T05:32:31.655707-04:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>selfh.st</name>
    <email>contact@selfh.st</email>
  </author>
  <link href="https://selfh.st/apps" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>Self-hosted software releases generated by selfh.st</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/vrtmrz/obsidian-livesync/releases/tag/0.23.20</id>
    <title>New release for Obsidian LiveSync: 0.23.20</title>
    <updated>2024-07-30T21:34:29-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>vrtmrz/obsidian-livesync</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h2&gt;0.23.20:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Fixed:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Customisation Sync now checks the difference while storing or applying the configuration.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No longer storing the same configuration multiple times.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Time difference in the dialogue has been fixed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Remote Storage Limit Notification dialogue has been fixed, now the chosen value is saved.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Improved:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Enlarging button on the enlarging threshold dialogue now displays the new value.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/vrtmrz/obsidian-livesync/releases/tag/0.23.20" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/vrtmrz/obsidian-livesync/releases/tag/0.23.21</id>
    <title>New release for Obsidian LiveSync: 0.23.21</title>
    <updated>2024-09-06T13:10:16-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>vrtmrz/obsidian-livesync</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h2&gt;0.23.21&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the past two months, I have had the privilege of caring for our merciful mother for her departure. I would like to once again express my heartfelt gratitude to all of you. Thank you very much.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This time, I am releasing updates and fixes that have accumulated. I encourage you to install it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These changes have been gradually implemented in my Vault part by part, day by day. So I do not anticipate any major issues. However, if you encounter anything, please do not hesitate to let me know. And, I apologise for any delays in my responses. I will definitely respond.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am available on &lt;a href="https://njump.compile-error.net/npub1a79dtp6wzpp9kj4fynzyc40rqwm7h3gaf4m9yzluu5krzu0vpllqkstec2"&gt;Nostr&lt;/a&gt; and Fediverse(https://mozilla.social/@vrtmrz), so feel free to reach out. Please note that my English may be far from perfect, but I would love to try to do my best.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note: if you are troubled with using IBM Cloudant, please set 1(MB) to Maximum size of chunk send in one request, or disable Send chunks in bulk. Sorry for lacking handling. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;New Features:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Case-insensitive file handling&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Files can now be handled case-insensitively.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This behaviour can be modified in the settings under &lt;code&gt;Handle files as Case-Sensitive&lt;/code&gt; (Default: Prompt, Enabled for previous behaviour).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved chunk revision fixing&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Revisions for chunks can now be fixed for faster chunk creation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This can be adjusted in the settings under &lt;code&gt;Compute revisions for chunks&lt;/code&gt; (Default: Prompt, Enabled for previous behaviour).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bulk chunk transfer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chunks can now be transferred in bulk during uploads.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This feature is enabled by default through &lt;code&gt;Send chunks in bulk&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Creation of missing chunks without&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Missing chunks can be created without storing notes, enhancing efficiency for first synchronisation or after prolonged periods without synchronisation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Improvements:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;File status scanning on the startup&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Quite significant performance improvements.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No more missing scans of some files.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Status in editor enhancements&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Significant performance improvements in the status display within the editor.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Notifications for files that will not be synchronised will now be properly communicated.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Encryption and Decryption&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;These processes are now performed in background threads to ensure fast and stable transfers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Verify and repair all files&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Got faster through parallel checking.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Migration on update&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Migration messages and wizards have become more helpful.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Behavioural changes:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chunk size adjustments&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Large chunks will no longer be created for older, stable files, addressing storage consumption issues.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Flag file automation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Confirmation will be shown and we can cancel it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Fixed:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Database File Scanning&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All files in the database will now be enumerated correctly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Miscellaneous&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dependency updated.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Now, tree shaking is left to terser, from esbuild.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/vrtmrz/obsidian-livesync/releases/tag/0.23.21" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/vrtmrz/obsidian-livesync/releases/tag/0.23.22</id>
    <title>New release for Obsidian LiveSync: 0.23.22</title>
    <updated>2024-09-08T05:00:44-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>vrtmrz/obsidian-livesync</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h2&gt;0.23.22:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Fixed:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Case-insensitive file handling&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Full-lower-case files are no longer created during database checking.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bulk chunk transfer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The default value will automatically adjust to an acceptable size when using IBM Cloudant.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/vrtmrz/obsidian-livesync/releases/tag/0.23.22" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/vrtmrz/obsidian-livesync/releases/tag/0.23.23</id>
    <title>New release for Obsidian LiveSync: 0.23.23</title>
    <updated>2024-09-24T09:16:09-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>vrtmrz/obsidian-livesync</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h2&gt;0.23.23:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Refined:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Setting dialogue very slightly refined.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The hodgepodge inside the &lt;code&gt;Hatch&lt;/code&gt; pane has been sorted into more explicit categorised panes.&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Now we have new panes for:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Selector&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Advanced&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Power users&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Patches (Edge case)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Applying the settings will now be more informative.&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The header bar will be shown for applying the settings which needs a database rebuild.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Applying methods are now more clearly navigated.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Definitely, drastic change&lt;/strong&gt;. I hope this will be more user-friendly. However, if you notice any issues, please let me know. I hope that nothing missed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;New features:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Word-segmented chunk building on users language&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chunks can now be built with word-segmented data, enhancing efficiency for markdown files which contains the multiple sentences in a single line.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This feature is enabled through &lt;code&gt;Use Segmented-splitter&lt;/code&gt;. &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(Default: Disabled, Please be relived, I have learnt).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Fixed:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sending chunks on &lt;code&gt;Send chunk in bulk&lt;/code&gt; are now buffered to avoid the out-of-memory error.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Send chunk in bulk&lt;/code&gt; is back to default disabled. (Sorry, not applied to the migrated users; I did not think we should deepen the wound any further "automatically").&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Merging conflicts of JSON files are now works fine even if it contains &lt;code&gt;null&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Development:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Implemented the logic for automatically generating the stub of document for the setting dialogue.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mangling variable names are now disabled.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/vrtmrz/obsidian-livesync/releases/tag/0.23.23" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/vrtmrz/obsidian-livesync/releases/tag/0.24.0</id>
    <title>New release for Obsidian LiveSync: 0.24.0</title>
    <updated>2024-10-27T22:20:54-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>vrtmrz/obsidian-livesync</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h2&gt;0.24.0&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know that we have been waiting for a long time. It is finally released!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the past three years since the inception of the plugin, various features have been implemented to address diverse user needs. This is truly honourable, and I am grateful for your years of support. However, this process has led to an increasingly disorganised codebase, with features becoming entangled. Consequently, this has led to a situation where bugs can go unnoticed and resolving one issue may inadvertently introduce another.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 0.24.0, I reorganised the previously jumbled main codebase into clearly defined modules. Although I had assumed that the total size of the code would not increase, I discovered that it has in fact increased. While the complexity is still considerable, the refactoring has improved the clarity of the code's structure. Additionally, while testing the release candidates, we still found many bugs to fix, which helped to make this plug-in robust and stable. Therefore, we are now ready to use the updated plug-in, and in addition to that, proceed to the next step.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is also the first step towards a fully-fledged-fancy LiveSync, not just a plug-in from Obsidian. Of course, it will still be a plug-in primarily and foremost, but this development marks a significant step towards the self-hosting concept.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, I would like to once again express my respect and gratitude to all of you. My gratitude extends to all of the dev testers! Your contributions have certainly made the plug-in robust and stable!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you, and I hope your troubles will be resolved!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;0.24.0&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Improved&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The welcome message is now more simple to encourage the use of the Setup-URI.&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The secondary message is also simpler to guide users to Minimal Setup.&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;But Setup-URI will be recommended again, due to its importance.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;These dialogues contain a link to the documentation which can be clicked.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The minimal setup is more minimal now. And, the setup is more user-friendly.&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Now the Configuration of the remote database is checked more robustly, but we can ignore the warning and proceed with the setup.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Before we are asked about each feature, we are asked if we want to use optional features in the first place.&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This is to prevent the user from being overwhelmed by the features.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;And made it clear that it is not recommended for new users.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Many messages have been improved for better understanding.&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ridiculous messages have been (carefully) refined.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dialogues are more informative and friendly.&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A lot of messages have been mostly rewritten, leveraging Markdown.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Especially auto-closing dialogues are now explicitly labelled: &lt;code&gt;To stop the countdown, tap anywhere on the dialogue&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Now if the is plugin configured to ignore some events, we will get a chance to fix it, in addition to the warning.&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;And why that has happened is also explained in the dialogue.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A note relating to device names has been added to Customisation Sync on the setting dialogue.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We can verify and resolve also the hidden files now.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Fixed&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We can resolve the conflict of the JSON file correctly now.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Verifying files between the local database and storage is now working correctly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;While restarting the plug-in, the shown dialogues will be automatically closed to avoid unexpected behaviour.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Replicated documents that the local device has configured to ignore are now correctly ignored.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The chunks of the document on the local device during the first transfer will be created correctly.&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;And why we should create them is now explained in the dialogue.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If optional features have been enabled in the wizard, &lt;code&gt;Enable advanced features&lt;/code&gt; will be toggled correctly.
The hidden file sync is now working correctly.&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Now the deletion of hidden files is correctly synchronised.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Customisation Sync is now working correctly together with hidden file sync.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No longer database suffix is stored in the setting sharing markdown.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A fair number of bugs have been fixed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Changed&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some default settings have been changed for an easier new user experience.&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Preventing the meaningless migration of the settings.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Tiding&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The codebase has been reorganised into clearly defined modules.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Commented-out codes have been gradually removed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/vrtmrz/obsidian-livesync/releases/tag/0.24.0" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
