<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://selfh.st/apps</id>
  <title>Obsidian LiveSync Releases</title>
  <updated>2025-06-23T10:33:26.528500-04:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>selfh.st</name>
    <email>contact@selfh.st</email>
  </author>
  <link href="https://selfh.st/apps" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>Self-hosted software releases generated by selfh.st</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/vrtmrz/obsidian-livesync/releases/tag/0.24.25</id>
    <title>New release for Obsidian LiveSync: 0.24.25</title>
    <updated>2025-04-22T06:33:28-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>vrtmrz/obsidian-livesync</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h2&gt;0.24.25&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Improved&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Peer-to-peer synchronisation has been got more robust.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Fixed&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No longer broken falsy values in settings during set-up by the QR code generation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Refactored&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some &lt;code&gt;window&lt;/code&gt; references now have pointed to &lt;code&gt;globalThis&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some sloppy-import has been fixed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A server side implementation &lt;code&gt;Synchromesh&lt;/code&gt; has been suffixed with &lt;code&gt;deno&lt;/code&gt; instead of &lt;code&gt;server&lt;/code&gt; now.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/vrtmrz/obsidian-livesync/releases/tag/0.24.25" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/vrtmrz/obsidian-livesync/releases/tag/0.24.26</id>
    <title>New release for Obsidian LiveSync: 0.24.26</title>
    <updated>2025-05-14T09:00:37-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>vrtmrz/obsidian-livesync</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h2&gt;0.24.26&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The long excuse is that CORS can now be ignored.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This update introduces an option to circumvent Cross-Origin Resource Sharing (CORS) constraints for CouchDB requests, by leveraging Obsidian's native request API. The implementation of such a feature had previously been deferred due to significant security considerations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CORS is a vital security mechanism, enabling servers like CouchDB -- which functions as a sophisticated REST API -- to control access from different origins, thereby ensuring secure communication across trust boundaries. I had long hesitated to offer a CORS circumvention method, as it deviates from security best practices; My preference was for users to configure CORS correctly on the server-side.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, this policy has shifted due to specific reports of intractable CORS-related configuration issues, particularly within enterprise proxy
environments where proxy servers can unpredictably alter or block communications. Given that a primary objective of the "Self-hosted LiveSync" plugin is to facilitate secure Obsidian usage within stringent corporate settings, addressing these 'unavoidable' user-reported problems became essential. Mostly raison d'être of this plugin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consequently, the option "Use Request API to avoid &lt;code&gt;inevitable&lt;/code&gt; CORS problem" has been implemented. Users are strongly advised to enable this &lt;em&gt;only&lt;/em&gt; when operating within a trusted environment. We can enable this option in the &lt;code&gt;Patch&lt;/code&gt; pane.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, just to whisper, this is tremendously fast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Replies to Issues will be a little delayed, but I will make sure to do so!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;New Features&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Automatic display-language changing according to the Obsidian language setting. (#630)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We will be asked on the migration or first startup.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note: Please revert to the default language if you report any issues.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Not all messages are translated yet. We welcome your contribution!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Now we can limit files to be synchronised even in the hidden files. (#631)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"Use Request API to avoid &lt;code&gt;inevitable&lt;/code&gt; CORS problem" has been implemented. (#632) (#508) etc...&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Less secure, please use it only if you are sure that you are in the trusted environment and be able to ignore the CORS. No &lt;code&gt;Web viewer&lt;/code&gt; or similar tools are recommended. (To avoid the origin forged attack). If you are able to configure the server setting, always that is recommended.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Show status icon instead of file warnings banner&lt;/code&gt; has been implemented. (#634)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If enabled, the ⛔ icon will be shown inside the status instead of the file warnings banner. No details will be shown.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Improved&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All regular expressions can be inverted by prefixing &lt;code&gt;!!&lt;/code&gt; now.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Fixed&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No longer unexpected files will be gathered during hidden file sync. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No longer broken &lt;code&gt;\n&lt;/code&gt; and new-line characters during the bucket synchronisation. (#639)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We can purge the remote bucket again if we using MinIO instead of AWS S3 or Cloudflare R2.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Purging the remote bucket is now more reliable.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;100 files are purged at a time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some wrong messages have been fixed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Behaviour changed&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Entering into the deeper directories to gather the hidden files is now limited by &lt;code&gt;/&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;\/&lt;/code&gt; prefixed ignore filters. (It means that directories are scanned deeper than before).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;However, inside the these directories, the files are still limited by the ignore filters.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Etcetera&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some code has been tidied up.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Trying less warning-suppressing and be more safer-coding.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dependent libraries have been updated to the latest version.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some build processes have been separated to &lt;code&gt;pre&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;post&lt;/code&gt; processes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/vrtmrz/obsidian-livesync/releases/tag/0.24.26" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/vrtmrz/obsidian-livesync/releases/tag/0.24.27</id>
    <title>New release for Obsidian LiveSync: 0.24.27</title>
    <updated>2025-06-09T21:58:45-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>vrtmrz/obsidian-livesync</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h2&gt;0.24.27&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It has been a happy sort of busy time recently, but a lot of things have been happening at the same time.
I have been posting about the details on social media, so if you wonder what I am doing, please feel free to talk to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Improved&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We can use prefix for path for the Bucket synchronisation.&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For example, if you set the &lt;code&gt;vaultName/&lt;/code&gt; as a prefix for the bucket in the root directory, all data will be transferred to the bucket under the &lt;code&gt;vaultName/&lt;/code&gt; directory.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The "Use Request API to avoid &lt;code&gt;inevitable&lt;/code&gt; CORS problem" option is now promoted to the normal setting, not a niche patch.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Fixed&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Now switching replicators applied immediately, without the need to restart Obsidian.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Tidied up&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some dependencies have been updated to the latest version.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/vrtmrz/obsidian-livesync/releases/tag/0.24.27" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/vrtmrz/obsidian-livesync/releases/tag/0.24.28</id>
    <title>New release for Obsidian LiveSync: 0.24.28</title>
    <updated>2025-06-15T05:52:19-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>vrtmrz/obsidian-livesync</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h2&gt;0.24.28&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Fixed&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Batch Update is no longer available in LiveSync mode to avoid unexpected behaviour. (#653)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Now compatible with Cloudflare R2 again for bucket synchronisation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;@edo-bari-ikutsu, thank you for &lt;a href="https://github.com/vrtmrz/livesync-commonlib/pull/12"&gt;your contribution&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Prevention of broken behaviour due to database connection failures added (#649).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(It is not a sure fixing, but it should help).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/vrtmrz/obsidian-livesync/releases/tag/0.24.28" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/vrtmrz/obsidian-livesync/releases/tag/0.24.29</id>
    <title>New release for Obsidian LiveSync: 0.24.29</title>
    <updated>2025-06-20T07:47:39-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>vrtmrz/obsidian-livesync</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h2&gt;0.24.29&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Fixed&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Synchronisation with buckets now works correctly, regardless of whether a prefix is set or the bucket has been (re-) initialised (#664).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An information message is now displayed again, during any automatic synchronisation is enabled (#662).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Tidied up&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Importing paths have been tidied up.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/vrtmrz/obsidian-livesync/releases/tag/0.24.29" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
