<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://selfh.st/apps</id>
  <title>Obsidian LiveSync Releases</title>
  <updated>2025-02-04T21:32:55.312844-05:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>selfh.st</name>
    <email>contact@selfh.st</email>
  </author>
  <link href="https://selfh.st/apps" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>Self-hosted software releases generated by selfh.st</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/vrtmrz/obsidian-livesync/releases/tag/0.24.5</id>
    <title>New release for Obsidian LiveSync: 0.24.5</title>
    <updated>2024-12-13T06:16:59-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>vrtmrz/obsidian-livesync</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h2&gt;0.24.5&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As with 0.24.4, this release focuses on weeding out bugs identified during testing. While there are still areas for improvement, this release lays a solid foundation for addressing them more effectively in the future. (However, sorry for keeping the issues open and lacking replies).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Status line updates have been significantly optimised and are now approximately 7x faster, with consistent CPU usage. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Complement: I noticed that the log pane is kept empty now… This will be fixed soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Fixed&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed incorrect behaviour when comparing objects with undefined as a property value.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Improved&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The status line and the log summary are now displayed more smoothly and efficiently.&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This improvement has also been applied to the logs displayed in the log pane.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/vrtmrz/obsidian-livesync/releases/tag/0.24.5" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/vrtmrz/obsidian-livesync/releases/tag/0.24.6</id>
    <title>New release for Obsidian LiveSync: 0.24.6</title>
    <updated>2024-12-13T12:41:44-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>vrtmrz/obsidian-livesync</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h2&gt;0.24.6&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sorry for the recent hasty releases! I am still wondering why I have not noticed... However, it has been clear that issue reporting will not be possible without fixing this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Fixed (Quick Fix)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed the issue of logs not being displayed on the log pane if the pane had not been shown on startup.&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This release is only for it. However, fixing this had been necessary to report any other issues.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/vrtmrz/obsidian-livesync/releases/tag/0.24.6" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/vrtmrz/obsidian-livesync/releases/tag/0.24.7</id>
    <title>New release for Obsidian LiveSync: 0.24.7</title>
    <updated>2025-01-07T06:37:27-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>vrtmrz/obsidian-livesync</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h2&gt;0.24.7&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Fixed (Security)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Assigning IDs to chunks has been corrected for more safety.
    -   Before version 0.24.6, there were possibilities in End-to-End encryption where a brute-force attack could be carried out against an E2EE passphrase via a chunk ID if a zero-byte file was present. Now the chunk ID should be assigned more safely, and not all of passphrases are used for generating the chunk ID.
    -   This is a security fix, and it is recommended to update and rebuild database to this version as soon as possible.
    -   Note: It keeps the compatibility with the previous versions, but the chunk ID will be changed for the new files and modified files. Hence, deduplication will not work for the files which are modified after the update. It is recommended to rebuild the database to avoid the potential issues, and reduce the database size.
    -   Note2: This fix is only for with E2EE. Plain synchronisation is not affected by this issue.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Fixed&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Now the conflict resolving dialogue is automatically closed after the conflict has been resolved (and transferred from other devices; or written by some other resolution).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Resolving conflicts by timestamp is now working correctly.
    -   It also fixes customisation sync.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Improved&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Notifications can be suppressed for the hidden files update now.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No longer uses the old-xxhash and sha1 for generating the chunk ID. Chunk ID is now generated with the new algorithm (Pure JavaScript hash implementation; which is using Murmur3Hash and FNV-1a now used).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/vrtmrz/obsidian-livesync/releases/tag/0.24.7" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/vrtmrz/obsidian-livesync/releases/tag/0.24.8</id>
    <title>New release for Obsidian LiveSync: 0.24.8</title>
    <updated>2025-01-22T07:08:25-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>vrtmrz/obsidian-livesync</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h2&gt;0.24.8&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am so sorry I could not respond at all. Really.
I just left insomnia, and am able to sleep now (quite good trend), but still on deadline. Time is a difficult thing to use.
Anyway, I will get back to you as soon as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Fixed&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some parallel-processing tasks are now performed more safely.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some error messages has been fixed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Improved&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Synchronisation is now more efficient and faster.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Saving chunks is a bit more robust.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;New Feature&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We can remove orphaned chunks again, now!&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Without rebuilding the database!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Note: Please synchronise devices completely before removing orphaned chunks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Note2: Deleted files are using chunks, if you want to remove them, please commit the deletion first. (&lt;code&gt;Commit File Deletion&lt;/code&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Note3: If you lost some chunks, do not worry. They will be resurrected if not so much time has passed. Try &lt;code&gt;Resurrect deleted chunks&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Note4: This feature is still beta. Please report any issues you encounter.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Note5: Please disable &lt;code&gt;On demand chunk fetching&lt;/code&gt;, and enable &lt;code&gt;Compute revisions for each chunk&lt;/code&gt; before using this feature.&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;These settings is going to be default in the future.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/vrtmrz/obsidian-livesync/releases/tag/0.24.8" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/vrtmrz/obsidian-livesync/releases/tag/0.24.10</id>
    <title>New release for Obsidian LiveSync: 0.24.10</title>
    <updated>2025-02-04T20:56:21-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>vrtmrz/obsidian-livesync</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h2&gt;0.24.10&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a minor release. However, the upcoming will be a great one. 
P2P synchronisation is being implemented now. I am always late, but this time you can expect a bit more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Fixed&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed the issue where the filename is shown as &lt;code&gt;undefined&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed the issue where files transferred at short intervals were not reflected.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Improved&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add more translations: &lt;code&gt;ja-JP&lt;/code&gt; (Japanese) by @kohki-shikata (Thank you so much)!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Internal&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some files have been prettified.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/vrtmrz/obsidian-livesync/releases/tag/0.24.10" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
