<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://selfh.st/apps</id>
  <title>Obsidian LiveSync Releases</title>
  <updated>2024-05-22T17:33:06.133858-04:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>selfh.st</name>
    <email>contact@selfh.st</email>
  </author>
  <link href="https://selfh.st/apps" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>Self-hosted software releases generated by selfh.st</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/vrtmrz/obsidian-livesync/releases/tag/0.23.4</id>
    <title>New release for Obsidian LiveSync: 0.23.4</title>
    <updated>2024-05-05T10:51:23-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>vrtmrz/obsidian-livesync</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h2&gt;0.23.4&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sorry for the wait, the issue of not being able to close the dialogue in iOS is probably next.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Fixed:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No longer experimental configuration is shown on the Minimal Setup.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;New feature:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We can now use &lt;code&gt;Incubate Chunks in Document&lt;/code&gt; to reduce non-well-formed chunks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Default: disabled / Preferred: enabled in all devices.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When we enabled this toggle, newly created chunks are temporarily kept within the document, and graduated to become independent chunks once stabilised.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;a href="https://github.com/vrtmrz/obsidian-livesync/blob/3925052f9290b3579e45a4b716b3679c833d8ca0/docs/design_docs_of_keep_newborn_chunks.md"&gt;design document&lt;/a&gt; has been also available. (Some update is upcoming).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/vrtmrz/obsidian-livesync/releases/tag/0.23.4" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/vrtmrz/obsidian-livesync/releases/tag/0.23.5</id>
    <title>New release for Obsidian LiveSync: 0.23.5</title>
    <updated>2024-05-07T08:03:03-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>vrtmrz/obsidian-livesync</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h2&gt;0.23.5:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;New feature:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Now we can check configuration mismatching between clients before synchronisation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Default: enabled / Preferred: enabled / We can disable this by the &lt;code&gt;Do not check configuration mismatch before replication&lt;/code&gt; toggle in the &lt;code&gt;Hatch&lt;/code&gt; pane.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It detects configuration mismatches and prevents synchronisation failures and wasted storage.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Now we can perform remote database compaction from the &lt;code&gt;Maintenance&lt;/code&gt; pane.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Fixed:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We can detect the bucket could not be reachable.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Note:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Known inexplicable behaviour: Recently, (Maybe while enabling &lt;code&gt;Incubate chunks in Document&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;Fetch chunks on demand&lt;/code&gt; or some more toggles), our customisation sync data is sometimes corrupted. It will be addressed by the next release.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/vrtmrz/obsidian-livesync/releases/tag/0.23.5" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/vrtmrz/obsidian-livesync/releases/tag/0.23.6</id>
    <title>New release for Obsidian LiveSync: 0.23.6</title>
    <updated>2024-05-08T11:07:30-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>vrtmrz/obsidian-livesync</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h2&gt;0.23.6:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A bit urgent release for the canaries as like me! I will address more things and read and reply issues and discussion tomorrow (Now at midnight in here). Thank you for your understandin, cooperation, and contribution!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Fixed:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Now the remote chunks could be decrypted even if we are using &lt;code&gt;Incubate chunks in Document&lt;/code&gt;. (One of the notes of 0.23.6 has been fixed).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chunk retrieving with &lt;code&gt;Incubate chunks in document&lt;/code&gt; got more efficient.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No longer task processor misses the completed tasks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Replication is no longer started automatically during changes in window visibility (e.g., task switching on the desktop) when off-focused.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This causes a database open error.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/vrtmrz/obsidian-livesync/releases/tag/0.23.6" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/vrtmrz/obsidian-livesync/releases/tag/0.23.7</id>
    <title>New release for Obsidian LiveSync: 0.23.7</title>
    <updated>2024-05-10T06:43:21-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>vrtmrz/obsidian-livesync</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h2&gt;0.23.7&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Fixed:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No longer missing tasks which have queued as the same key (e.g., for the same operation to the same file).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The hourglass and other indicators that remain on display mean the missed tasks. It was more serious than I thought. I appreciate your patience, cooperation, and contributions! &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This occurs, for example, with hidden files that have been changed multiple times in a very short period of time, such as &lt;code&gt;appearance.json&lt;/code&gt;. Thanks for the report!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This may fixes some more issues. I will reply in a few days!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some trivial issues have been fixed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;New feature:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reloading Obsidian can be scheduled until that file and database operations are stable.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/vrtmrz/obsidian-livesync/releases/tag/0.23.7" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/vrtmrz/obsidian-livesync/releases/tag/0.23.8</id>
    <title>New release for Obsidian LiveSync: 0.23.8</title>
    <updated>2024-05-22T09:09:56-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>vrtmrz/obsidian-livesync</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h2&gt;0.23.8&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I might write this every time, but I have now returned from the depths of the papers and claims. (Yes, I submitted them successfully, finally this time). I would love to express deep gratitude to you for your patience to you all! 
I am getting back into the swing of things, so I will gradually write replies. (Indeed, some functions have been done before that...)
In this release, the setting dialogue has been almost completely rewritten. Please let me know of any problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;New feature:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Now we are ready for i18n. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Patch or PR of &lt;code&gt;rosetta.ts&lt;/code&gt; are welcome!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The setting dialogue has been refined. Very controllable, clearly displayed disabled items, and ready to i18n.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Fixed:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Many memory leaks have been rescued.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chunk caches now work well.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Many trivial but potential bugs are fixed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No longer error messages will be shown on retrieving checkpoint or server information.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Now we can check and correct tweak mismatch during the setup&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Improved:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Customisation synchronisation has got more smoother.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Tidied&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Practically unused functions have been removed or are being prepared for removal.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Many of the type-errors and lint errors have been corrected.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Unused files have been removed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Note:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;From this version, some test files have been included. However, they are not enabled and released in the release build.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To try them, please run Self-hosted LiveSync in the dev build.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/vrtmrz/obsidian-livesync/releases/tag/0.23.8" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
