<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://selfh.st/apps</id>
  <title>OctoPrint Releases</title>
  <updated>2024-10-13T09:31:59.454133-04:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>selfh.st</name>
    <email>contact@selfh.st</email>
  </author>
  <link href="https://selfh.st/apps" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>Self-hosted software releases generated by selfh.st</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/OctoPrint/OctoPrint/releases/tag/1.9.2</id>
    <title>New release for OctoPrint: 1.9.2</title>
    <updated>2023-07-18T07:11:50-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>OctoPrint/OctoPrint</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h2&gt;✋ Heads-ups&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The heads-ups from 1.9.0 still apply&lt;/strong&gt;, please read this release's &lt;a href="https://github.com/OctoPrint/OctoPrint/releases/tag/1.9.0"&gt;release notes&lt;/a&gt; as well for a full picture of what you should be aware of and what changed!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;⛈ Issues while updating?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On every new OctoPrint release we see some people run into the same issues with outdated or broken environments all over again. If you encounter a problem during update, please check &lt;a href="https://community.octoprint.org/t/my-octoprint-update-fails/37880"&gt;this collection of the most common issues&lt;/a&gt; encountered over the past couple of release cycles first, and test if the included fixes solve your problem. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;♻ Changes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;🐛 Bug fixes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/OctoPrint/OctoPrint/issues/4779"&gt;#4779&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;a href="https://github.com/OctoPrint/OctoPrint/pull/4780"&gt;PR#4780&lt;/a&gt;: Work around &lt;code&gt;argon2&lt;/code&gt; password hashing algorithm not working reliably on Rock64/aarch64 - no error is produced, but the hash verification just fails.  Fall back to &lt;code&gt;pbkdf2_sha256&lt;/code&gt; if this happens. Backported from 1.10.0.dev.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/OctoPrint/OctoPrint/issues/4806"&gt;#4806&lt;/a&gt;: Fix the &lt;code&gt;httpheader&lt;/code&gt; software update check type. Backported from 1.10.0.dev.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/OctoPrint/OctoPrint/issues/4854"&gt;#4854&lt;/a&gt;: Upgrade PyYaml dependency to 6.0.1+. This works around an issue existing in PyYaml versions 5.4.0 to 6.0.0 with its dependency Cython in version 3.0, which was released on July 17th 2023. Said issue renders OctoPrint uninstallable due to PyYaml's install failing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;🎉 Special thanks to all the contributors!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Special thanks to everyone who contributed to this bugfix release, especially to &lt;a href="https://github.com/cperrin88"&gt;@cperrin88&lt;/a&gt; for their PR!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;🔗 More information&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/OctoPrint/OctoPrint/compare/1.9.1...1.9.2"&gt;Commits&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As this is a bugfix release, there were no release candidates&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/OctoPrint/OctoPrint/releases/tag/1.9.2" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/OctoPrint/OctoPrint/releases/tag/1.9.3</id>
    <title>New release for OctoPrint: 1.9.3</title>
    <updated>2023-10-09T11:06:46-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>OctoPrint/OctoPrint</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p align="center"&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://octoprint.org/support-octoprint/" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;img width="100%" src="https://gist.githubusercontent.com/foosel/8da9b09112c17ac8831735b7c18ac9e7/raw/938338fc55891ee9e28dee943823477d3e7bb14f/banner.svg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;✋ Heads-ups&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The heads-ups from 1.9.0 still apply&lt;/strong&gt;, please read this release's &lt;a href="https://github.com/OctoPrint/OctoPrint/releases/tag/1.9.0"&gt;release notes&lt;/a&gt; as well for a full picture of what you should be aware of and what changed!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;⛈ Issues while updating?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On every new OctoPrint release we see some people run into the same issues with outdated or broken environments all over again. If you encounter a problem during update, please check &lt;a href="https://community.octoprint.org/t/my-octoprint-update-fails/37880"&gt;this collection of the most common issues&lt;/a&gt; encountered over the past couple of release cycles first, and test if the included fixes solve your problem. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;♻ Changes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;🔒 Security fixes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Severity Medium (6.4): It was possible for a malicious admin to configure a specially crafted &lt;a href="https://docs.octoprint.org/en/master/features/gcode_scripts.html"&gt;GCODE script&lt;/a&gt; through the Settings that would allow code execution during rendering of that script. An attacker could have used this to extract data managed by OctoPrint, or manipulate data managed by OctoPrint, as well as execute arbitrary commands with the rights of the OctoPrint process on the server system. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please note that GCODE files uploaded to be printed were not affected! This vulnerability exclusively affected GCODE Scripts to be executed on connection to the printer, print pause, resume etc, as described &lt;a href="https://docs.octoprint.org/en/master/features/gcode_scripts.html"&gt;in the documentation&lt;/a&gt;, to be found under Settings &amp;gt; GCODE Scripts and configurable only by users with the &lt;code&gt;ADMIN&lt;/code&gt; permission.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See also the &lt;a href="https://github.com/OctoPrint/OctoPrint/security/advisories/GHSA-fwfg-vprh-97ph"&gt;GitHub Security Advisory&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://nvd.nist.gov/vuln/detail/CVE-2023-41047"&gt;CVE-2023-41047&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;🐛 Bug fixes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/OctoPrint/OctoPrint/issues/4849"&gt;#4849&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;a href="https://github.com/OctoPrint/OctoPrint/pull/4860"&gt;PR#4860&lt;/a&gt;: Fix for not being able to extrude/retract from the control panel in the UI after editing the extrusion speed in the printer profile.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/OctoPrint/OctoPrint/issues/4893"&gt;#4893&lt;/a&gt;: Pin pydantic dependency to 1.10.12. This works around an issue existing in some environments with pydantic version 1.10.13, which was released on September 26 2023. Said issue causes OctoPrint to no longer be able to start. See also &lt;a href="https://github.com/pydantic/pydantic/issues/7689"&gt;pydantic/pydantic#7689&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;🎉 Special thanks to all the contributors!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Special thanks to everyone who contributed to this bugfix release, especially to &lt;a href="https://github.com/srLinux"&gt;@srLinux&lt;/a&gt; for their PR!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also a big thank you to tianxin Wu (Bearcat), Vulnerability Researcher at Numen Cyber Labs, Singapore, for responsibly disclosing the security vulnerability that was fixed in this release.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;🔗 More information&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/OctoPrint/OctoPrint/compare/1.9.2...1.9.3"&gt;Commits&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As this is a bugfix release, there were no release candidates&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/OctoPrint/OctoPrint/releases/tag/1.9.3" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/OctoPrint/OctoPrint/releases/tag/1.10.0</id>
    <title>New release for OctoPrint: 1.10.0</title>
    <updated>2024-04-24T07:04:21-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>OctoPrint/OctoPrint</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p align="center"&gt;&lt;a href="https://octoprint.org/support-octoprint/" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;img src="https://gist.githubusercontent.com/foosel/a66c9642e294cd61e79b760143c0200a/raw/72fce2cc4f6f2aef3864abdd99ece7b2f377ff56/funding-banner.svg" alt="Click here if you want to help with OctoPrint's funding!"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;✋ Heads-ups&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;🔒 You will now be expected to re-enter your password on critical operations&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This version of OctoPrint requires you to reauthenticate with your password every five minutes on various critical operations you might do on your installation, e.g. adding, changing and deleting users, adding, changing and deleting groups, installing plugins, revealing the deprecated global API key, generating, revoking, revealing and granting application keys, accessing the recovery page and downloading or restoring backups. This change matches best practices with regards to security of web applications and was done in order to protect you from various potential attack vectors. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you do not want this reauthentication requirement, you can find information on how to disable it in the &lt;a href="https://docs.octoprint.org/en/master/configuration/config_yaml.html#access-control"&gt;configuration docs&lt;/a&gt;. Be aware though that by doing so you'll negatively impact your installation's security!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;☝️ Slow update if your Pi is still running pip &amp;lt;= 20.3 (e.g. as shipped on early OctoPi 0.18 preview versions)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the release candidate phase we found that if your OctoPrint installation still is using a &lt;code&gt;pip&lt;/code&gt; version below 20.3, updating to this version will take slightly longer than usual due to having to compile a third party dependency that got updated (&lt;code&gt;zeroconf&lt;/code&gt;), as these ancient &lt;code&gt;pip&lt;/code&gt; versions are not fetching the precompiled version from piwheels in this scenario. If you are affected, plan ahead accordingly and allow some time for the update or alternatively update pip (you can do that via the Software Update plugin's settings). Most of you however should not be affected by this at all. If you are not running a prerelease version of OctoPi 0.18.0 (the stable release of 0.18.0 is fine!), you are likely not affected by this. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;⛈ Issues while updating?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On every new OctoPrint release we see some people run into the same issues with outdated or broken environments all over again. If you encounter a problem during update, please check &lt;a href="https://community.octoprint.org/t/my-octoprint-update-fails/37880"&gt;this collection of the most common issues&lt;/a&gt; encountered over the past couple of release cycles first, and test if the included fixes solve your problem. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;♻ Changes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;🔒 Security fixes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Severity Moderate (4.2): It was possible for admins to perform password changes for their own account or others via the Settings dialog without having to re-enter their password. A malicious administrator or an attacker having taken over an administrator's session could have used this to effectively lock out users from their accounts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This has now been fixed by introducing a reauthentication requirement on changing passwords in the Settings. Unless the user has authenticated with their password (and other credentials possibly in the future) in the past 5min of their login session, a reauthentication dialog to re-enter the credentials will be shown, and only after that has done properly will the request work. This reauthentication dialog has also been added to other critical operations (adding, changing and deleting users, adding, changing and deleting groups, installing plugins, revealing the deprecated global API key, generating, revoking, revealing and granting application keys, accessing the recovery page). The reauthentication timeout of 5min is configurable via &lt;code&gt;config.yaml&lt;/code&gt;, see the documentation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See also the &lt;a href="https://github.com/OctoPrint/OctoPrint/security/advisories/GHSA-5626-pw9c-hmjr"&gt;GitHub Security Advisory&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://nvd.nist.gov/vuln/detail/CVE-2024-23637"&gt;CVE-2024-23637&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Severity Moderate (4.0): It was possible for a malicious admin to configure or to talk a victim with admin rights into configuring a webcam snapshot URL which when tested through the "Test" button included in the web interface would execute JavaScript code in the victim's browser when attempting to render the snapshot image. An attacker who successfully talked a victim with admin rights into performing a snapshot test with such a crafted URL could use this to retrieve or modify sensitive configuration settings, interrupt prints or otherwise interact with the OctoPrint instance in a malicious way.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This has now been fixed by properly sanitizing the data received from the snapshot URL.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See also the &lt;a href="https://github.com/OctoPrint/OctoPrint/security/advisories/GHSA-x7mf-wrh9-r76c"&gt;GitHub Security Advisory&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://nvd.nist.gov/vuln/detail/CVE-2024-28237"&gt;CVE-2024-28237&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;✨ Features &amp;amp; improvements&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Core&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/OctoPrint/OctoPrint/issues/4586"&gt;#4586&lt;/a&gt;: Added the capability report of the firmware as returned from &lt;code&gt;M115&lt;/code&gt; to &lt;code&gt;octoprint.log&lt;/code&gt; and also the systeminfo bundle in shape of a new &lt;code&gt;m115.txt&lt;/code&gt; file that gets generated if the bundle gets created while there's an active printer connection.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/OctoPrint/OctoPrint/issues/4617"&gt;#4617&lt;/a&gt;: Added a manual refresh button to the webcam view that allows to reload the underlying webcam stream (if webcam plugin supports that by having implemented &lt;code&gt;onWebcamRefresh&lt;/code&gt; in its viewmodel, otherwise the button will be a no-op). Only gets made visible when hovering over the webcam.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/OctoPrint/OctoPrint/issues/4681"&gt;#4681&lt;/a&gt;: Added information on old and new file to the "file already exists dialog". See also &lt;a href="https://github.com/OctoPrint/OctoPrint/pull/4721"&gt;PR#4721&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/OctoPrint/OctoPrint/issues/4685"&gt;#4685&lt;/a&gt;: Implemented &lt;a href="https://github.com/OctoPrint/OctoPrint/blob/maintenance/src/octoprint/_version.py"&gt;a custom versioning tool&lt;/a&gt; to replace the so far used customized version of &lt;code&gt;versioneer&lt;/code&gt; that has gotten quite long in the tooth. It should behave the same, but with way less code to keep maintained.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/OctoPrint/OctoPrint/issues/4714"&gt;#4714&lt;/a&gt;: Added a new dialog that gets displayed when the printer reports an unrecoverable error, containing the error message, what happened due to that error (print cancellation, disconnect), if available a link to an FAQ entry, the last lines of communication and a big reminder that printer errors are &lt;em&gt;printer&lt;/em&gt; errors and not OctoPrint's fault. The dialog will be automatically opened on connected clients, however it can also be accessed later by clicking on the new error icon added to the printer state panel.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/OctoPrint/OctoPrint/issues/4747"&gt;#4747&lt;/a&gt;: Made temperature graph time axis always show the configured cutoff interval. That should prevent any jumping of events.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/OctoPrint/OctoPrint/issues/4760"&gt;#4760&lt;/a&gt;: Made OctoPrint compatible to Python 3.12.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/OctoPrint/OctoPrint/issues/4764"&gt;#4764&lt;/a&gt;: Refactored the Tornado/WSGI interface based on the current Tornado code to make it async. That fixed the issue with connection reuse and as a very welcome side effect also very much increased the performance of the internal web server in general. Long running Flask endpoints now should no longer be able to fully block Tornado, and requests can get parallelized by the frontend, leading to a large reduction of time needed to fully load the UI.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/OctoPrint/OctoPrint/issues/4838"&gt;#4838&lt;/a&gt;: Improved performance of the internal settings data structure, reducing the initial settings fetch right after a server start from 2s+ to 400-700ms.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/OctoPrint/OctoPrint/issues/4843"&gt;#4843&lt;/a&gt;: Made the upload drop zone an optional feature that can be disabled in the settings. See also &lt;a href="https://github.com/OctoPrint/OctoPrint/pull/4853"&gt;PR#4853&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/OctoPrint/OctoPrint/issues/4866"&gt;#4866&lt;/a&gt;: Added axis labels to model size info. See also &lt;a href="https://github.com/OctoPrint/OctoPrint/pull/4898"&gt;PR#4898&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/OctoPrint/OctoPrint/issues/4880"&gt;#4880&lt;/a&gt;: Removed &lt;code&gt;scripts&lt;/code&gt; folder from repo.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/OctoPrint/OctoPrint/issues/4881"&gt;#4881&lt;/a&gt;: Display an error popup in case of startup issues due to inaccessible application directories.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/OctoPrint/OctoPrint/issues/4892"&gt;#4892&lt;/a&gt;: Keep tool change controls enabled while printing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/OctoPrint/OctoPrint/issues/4921"&gt;#4921&lt;/a&gt;: Added graph markers for the &lt;code&gt;Connected&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;Disconnected&lt;/code&gt; events to the temperature graph.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/OctoPrint/OctoPrint/pull/4743"&gt;PR#4743&lt;/a&gt;: Migrate from &lt;code&gt;netifaces&lt;/code&gt; to the pretty much drop-in replacement &lt;code&gt;netifaces2&lt;/code&gt;, since the former has been abandoned.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/OctoPrint/OctoPrint/pull/4752"&gt;PR#4752&lt;/a&gt;: Send initial history message when the web socket subscription is changed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/OctoPrint/OctoPrint/pull/4752"&gt;PR#4820&lt;/a&gt;: Added file and print head position to paused and cancel event &amp;amp; log entries.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/OctoPrint/OctoPrint/pull/4833"&gt;PR#4833&lt;/a&gt;: Improved first run wizard safety hints. They are now visually more alerting and the wizard now also requires the user to acknowledge having read and understood each warning by checking a checkbox.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/OctoPrint/OctoPrint/pull/4874"&gt;PR#4874&lt;/a&gt;: Added new &lt;code&gt;Thermal Malfunction&lt;/code&gt; error to recognized as a kill inducing error on Marlin.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/OctoPrint/OctoPrint/pull/4899"&gt;PR#4899&lt;/a&gt;: Removed the upper version pin for the &lt;code&gt;argon2-cffi&lt;/code&gt; dependency.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/OctoPrint/OctoPrint/pull/4918"&gt;PR#4918&lt;/a&gt;: Made target temperature lines in the temperature graph dashed. Improves accessibility for color blind users.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/OctoPrint/OctoPrint/pull/4928"&gt;PR#4928&lt;/a&gt;: Further improve screen reader accessibility.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use a file &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;basefolder&amp;gt;/.incomplete_startup&lt;/code&gt; to flag an incomplete startup instead of a &lt;code&gt;config.yaml&lt;/code&gt; entry. Makes it easier to reconfigure the server in CI situations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved the UX of the systeminfo CLI. &lt;code&gt;octoprint systeminfo&lt;/code&gt; will now generate a bundle in the current directory even without an explicitly added &lt;code&gt;.&lt;/code&gt; parameter. &lt;code&gt;octoprint systeminfo --short&lt;/code&gt; has been added to generated an abridged version directly on the command line. This should clear up issues we saw in the past where people forgot the &lt;code&gt;.&lt;/code&gt; and then just pasted the abridged text only version when in fact a bundle was needed and requested.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added &lt;code&gt;progress&lt;/code&gt; to &lt;code&gt;PrintFailed&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;PrintCancelled&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;PrintPaused&lt;/code&gt; events.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added &lt;code&gt;operation&lt;/code&gt; to &lt;code&gt;FileRemoved&lt;/code&gt; event. Allows distinguishing between a removal due to an actual &lt;code&gt;remove&lt;/code&gt; or a &lt;code&gt;move&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added a funding banner to the About dialog and a funding link to the footer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Achievement Plugin (✨ New!)&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Added a new bundled Achievements plugin! OctoPrint will now internally record some instance stats and monitor some events and based on that give out various achievements. This version contains 36 achievements, 22 of which are hidden and for you to be discovered. Additionally, the instance stats are also being recorded per year to make it possible in the future to give you some yearly stats overview of your OctoPrint and printing use. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unlocked achievements are also tracked via the &lt;a href="https://tracking.octoprint.org"&gt;Anonymous Usage Tracking&lt;/a&gt;. Of course, this can be disabled, and if you have not opted into tracking in the first place, nothing will be tracked, as always. Achievement stats are available on &lt;a href="https://data.octoprint.org"&gt;data.octoprint.org&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The goal of these achievements is not to gamify OctoPrint, but rather to give you something fun while also making it more visible how this project is funded and how you can help. If you are not interested in achievements, just disable the bundled Achievements plugin via the plugin manager.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Action Command Notification Plugin&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/OctoPrint/OctoPrint/issues/4326"&gt;#4326&lt;/a&gt;: Added ability to ignore incoming printer notifications based on a filter regex. This is to combat notification spam by firmwares which abuse the feature. Please talk to your firmware provider about not abusing the notification action command for things triggered by the user, e.g. mirroring &lt;code&gt;M117&lt;/code&gt; commands! See also &lt;a href="https://github.com/OctoPrint/OctoPrint/pull/4886"&gt;PR#4886&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Application Keys Plugin&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/OctoPrint/OctoPrint/issues/4894"&gt;#4894&lt;/a&gt;: Added application key details incl. QR Code to user settings. See also &lt;a href="https://github.com/OctoPrint/OctoPrint/pull/4895"&gt;PR#4895&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Classic Webcam Plugin&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/OctoPrint/OctoPrint/issues/4837"&gt;#4837&lt;/a&gt;: Apply the selected camera aspect ratio to its &lt;code&gt;video&lt;/code&gt; tag.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Discovery Plugin&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Updated the &lt;code&gt;zeroconf&lt;/code&gt; dependency.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Event Manager Plugin&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/OctoPrint/OctoPrint/issues/4869"&gt;#4869&lt;/a&gt;: Added UI support for events with multiple triggers. See also &lt;a href="https://github.com/OctoPrint/OctoPrint/pull/4851"&gt;PR#4851&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Plugin Manager Plugin&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Removed an unused variable.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Software Update Plugin&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/OctoPrint/OctoPrint/issues/4819"&gt;#4819&lt;/a&gt;: OctoPrint will now be clearly marked as not updateable when running on Windows.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Virtual Printer Plugin&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/OctoPrint/OctoPrint/pull/4799"&gt;PR#4799&lt;/a&gt;: Added support for generating an area report as part of the response to &lt;code&gt;M115&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Made the simulated errors configurable via the settings. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Documentation&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/OctoPrint/OctoPrint/issues/4787"&gt;#4787&lt;/a&gt;: Added a note to the documentation of the &lt;code&gt;SettingsPlugin&lt;/code&gt; mixin that updating settings will trigger a reload screen.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/OctoPrint/OctoPrint/issues/4852"&gt;#4852&lt;/a&gt;: Updated the plugin tutorial to reflect current CLI outputs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/OctoPrint/OctoPrint/pull/4823"&gt;PR#4823&lt;/a&gt;: Slight improvement on the pause GCODE script.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Testing &amp;amp; CI&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/OctoPrint/OctoPrint/issues/4908"&gt;#4908&lt;/a&gt;: Automatically publish release build artifacts on GitHub Releases as well as PyPI. Also automatically publish source tarball.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Updated the &lt;code&gt;node-qunit-puppeteer&lt;/code&gt; version to combat some JS unit test flakyness.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Run the E2E tests against the lowest and highest supported Python version, to make sure things work on both edge cases.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Updated &lt;code&gt;playwright&lt;/code&gt; used for the E2E tests.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Improvements done during the release candidate phase&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Core&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/OctoPrint/OctoPrint/issues/4957"&gt;#4957&lt;/a&gt;: Bump &lt;code&gt;websocket-client&lt;/code&gt; dependency to version 1.6.1, after verifying that it should still work with Python 3.7 in this version, to enable third party plugins to use bug fixes included in that version.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/OctoPrint/OctoPrint/pull/4964"&gt;PR#4964&lt;/a&gt;: Harden the filename sanitization in the &lt;code&gt;download_file&lt;/code&gt; function against possible path traversal issue in future use cases.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use &lt;code&gt;aria-label&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;role&lt;/code&gt; instead of &lt;code&gt;sr-only&lt;/code&gt; headings, resolving issues with the UI Customizer Plugin or other heavy CSS manipulation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use a reload popup instead of a blocking overlay modal on UI plugin and/or settings change. That should reduce the annoyance of the reload overlay popping up due to settings updates in the background. It should also help with the reload prompts sometimes observed during the newly introduced reauthentication workflow.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improve JS error reporting in Firefox.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Backup Plugin&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Require credential recheck for download &amp;amp; restore.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Testing &amp;amp; CI&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/OctoPrint/OctoPrint/issues/4908"&gt;#4908&lt;/a&gt;: Also automatically publish a source tarball upon release.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix a potential race condition that might have caused some build errors recently.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;🐛 Bug fixes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Core&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/OctoPrint/OctoPrint/issues/4719"&gt;#4719&lt;/a&gt;: Normalize paths in file manager methods and called hooks and events.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/OctoPrint/OctoPrint/issues/4753"&gt;#4753&lt;/a&gt;: Fixed an error when attempting to set a custom logging level under certain circumstances.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/OctoPrint/OctoPrint/issues/4756"&gt;#4756&lt;/a&gt;: Fixed including variables in GCODE scripts from more than one plugin. See also &lt;a href="https://github.com/OctoPrint/OctoPrint/pull/4757"&gt;PR#4757&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/OctoPrint/OctoPrint/issues/4769"&gt;#4769&lt;/a&gt;: Fixed a translation error in the included german language files. See also &lt;a href="https://github.com/OctoPrint/OctoPrint/pull/4897"&gt;PR#4897&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/OctoPrint/OctoPrint/pull/4794"&gt;PR#4794&lt;/a&gt;: Protect against issues when a double slash is contained in the timelapse base folder, leading to not being able to delete timelapses.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/OctoPrint/OctoPrint/issues/4800"&gt;#4800&lt;/a&gt;: Fixed folder sorting by date of last print.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/OctoPrint/OctoPrint/issues/4808"&gt;#4808&lt;/a&gt;: Fixed wrong initial field set in printer state (&lt;code&gt;printTimeOrigin&lt;/code&gt; instead of the correct &lt;code&gt;printTimeLeftOrigin&lt;/code&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/OctoPrint/OctoPrint/issues/4812"&gt;#4812&lt;/a&gt;: Fixed &lt;code&gt;octoprint systeminfo .&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/OctoPrint/OctoPrint/pull/4830"&gt;PR#4830&lt;/a&gt;: Fixed translateability of the filament usage information in the state panel.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/OctoPrint/OctoPrint/issues/4835"&gt;#4835&lt;/a&gt;: Fixed &lt;code&gt;octoprint get&lt;/code&gt; not properly returning sub trees for plugin settings hierarchies, due to a missing initialization.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/OctoPrint/OctoPrint/issues/4841"&gt;#4841&lt;/a&gt;: Fixed a broken knockout binding in the GCODE Viewer's size warning dialog, leading to the file name missing. See also &lt;a href="https://github.com/OctoPrint/OctoPrint/pull/4842"&gt;PR#4842&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/OctoPrint/OctoPrint/issues/4843"&gt;#4843&lt;/a&gt;: Don't trigger the drop zone for uploading files when not dragging files. Fixes issues when accidentally dragging selected text and similar.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/OctoPrint/OctoPrint/issues/4867"&gt;#4867&lt;/a&gt;: Fixed a warning about using the old webcam settings access path.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/OctoPrint/OctoPrint/issues/4903"&gt;#4903&lt;/a&gt;: Hardened temperature offset code against empty temperature commands and added logging for such cases.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/OctoPrint/OctoPrint/issues/4922"&gt;#4922&lt;/a&gt;: Fixed sorting of folder list in "move or rename file" dialog.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/OctoPrint/OctoPrint/issues/4929"&gt;#4929&lt;/a&gt;: Fixed a regression in the webcam styles that caused issues with the (abandoned) third party plugin TouchUI. See also &lt;a href="https://github.com/OctoPrint/OctoPrint/pull/4930"&gt;PR#4930&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Keep updating the temperature graph with empty entries even while disconnected, to ensure events shown there properly reflect their point in time from "now".&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enabled CORS on asset plugins.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed some warnings in the vendored &lt;code&gt;awesome-slugify&lt;/code&gt; dependency.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Classic Webcam Plugin&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/OctoPrint/OctoPrint/issues/4885"&gt;#4885&lt;/a&gt;: Fixed snapshot timeout &amp;amp; SSL validation settings.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Discovery Plugin&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/OctoPrint/OctoPrint/issues/4814"&gt;#4814&lt;/a&gt;: Join multicast group for SSDP discovery on all available addresses. Fixes issues with discovery on VLAN enabled hosts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Plugin Manager Plugin&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Properly handle unset plugin versions in plugin notifications from the repository, e.g. when attempting to load notifications for a bundled plugin (which normally shouldn't happen, but turned out to happen during development thanks to an identifier clash).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Software Update Plugin&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed &lt;code&gt;httpheader&lt;/code&gt; check type. It was not storing its current value properly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Virtual Printer Plugin&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/OctoPrint/OctoPrint/issues/4907"&gt;#4907&lt;/a&gt;: Fixed a race condition related to &lt;code&gt;G4&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;wait&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Documentation&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/OctoPrint/OctoPrint/issues/4906"&gt;#4906&lt;/a&gt;: Adjusted documentation to reflect correct name for &lt;code&gt;logsViewModel&lt;/code&gt; dependency.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/OctoPrint/OctoPrint/pull/4815"&gt;PR#4815&lt;/a&gt;: Updated documentation of &lt;code&gt;PrinterInterface.set_temperature&lt;/code&gt; to reflect the current implementation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/OctoPrint/OctoPrint/pull/4868"&gt;PR#4868&lt;/a&gt;: Removed some repeating words.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clarify how to reconfigure log formatters. OctoPrint now either uses &lt;code&gt;simple&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;colored&lt;/code&gt; formatters for the console log output, this still needed to get properly documented.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Fixes done during the release candidate phase&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Core&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/OctoPrint/OctoPrint/issues/4939"&gt;#4939&lt;/a&gt; (regression): Fix drag'n'drop initialization.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/OctoPrint/OctoPrint/issues/4940"&gt;#4940&lt;/a&gt; (regression): Make &lt;code&gt;octoprint._version&lt;/code&gt; backward compatible enough again to work around use on OctoPi images and third party plugins out there.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/OctoPrint/OctoPrint/issues/4941"&gt;#4941&lt;/a&gt; (regression): Fix some syntax under Python 3.7 &amp;amp; 3.8.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/OctoPrint/OctoPrint/issues/4942"&gt;#4942&lt;/a&gt; (regression): Fix handling of setting an empty dict on the configuration. Also added a unit test for this.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/OctoPrint/OctoPrint/issues/4943"&gt;#4943&lt;/a&gt; (regression): Fix fetching of file details for the existence check, preventing the "file already exists" dialog from making the correct checks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/OctoPrint/OctoPrint/issues/4966"&gt;#4966&lt;/a&gt; (regression): Fix handling of the reauthentication workflow for external users created &amp;amp; logged in from a configured header. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/OctoPrint/OctoPrint/issues/4969"&gt;#4969&lt;/a&gt; (regression): Fix the final page of the firstrun wizard interfering with the completion of arbitrary wizards from plugins, when not even shown.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/OctoPrint/OctoPrint/issues/4980"&gt;#4980&lt;/a&gt;: Fix missing temperature history for anything but the first extruder. This was actually not a regression, but the bug only could be seen now after extending the timeline of the temperature graph to the full available history.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/OctoPrint/OctoPrint/issues/4983"&gt;#4983&lt;/a&gt; (regression): Fix prefix caching for custom defaults. Manifested in no longer being able to select release channels in the Software Update plugin.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/OctoPrint/OctoPrint/issues/4983"&gt;#4987&lt;/a&gt; (regression): Fix creation of the static version file during installation of sdist under Windows.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Removed a left-over from the Access Control settings panel.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Properly reflect that users logged in from a configured header can't log out through the logout button but rather must log out by closing the browser.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Achievements Plugin&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/OctoPrint/OctoPrint/issues/4984"&gt;#4984&lt;/a&gt;: Make the "Mass Production" achievement detect modifications of the file.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix the "Heavy Chonker" achievement.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix the default groups for the achievement permission.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Action Command Notification Plugin&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/OctoPrint/OctoPrint/issues/4967"&gt;#4967&lt;/a&gt; (regression): Fix the filter logic so that an empty filter regex won't lead to &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; notifications to be filtered out.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GCODE Viewer&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/OctoPrint/OctoPrint/issues/4978"&gt;#4978&lt;/a&gt;: Fix reloading of the same file. First thought to be a regression, turned out to not be one but was a low hanging fruit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;🎉 Special thanks to all the contributors!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Special thanks to everyone who contributed to this RC, especially to @0r31, @bigfoxtail, @CMR-DEV, @cociweb, @cperrin88, @credomane, @crysxd, @danielkucera, @dawidpieper, @eumiro, @evanwurden, @hynek, @jatin-47, @jneilliii , @kaenguruhs, @mad73923, @max246, @MichaIng, @mintsoft, @neod123 and @thinkyhead for their PRs!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And an extra shoutout to our 13 first time contributors: @bigfoxtail, @CMD-DEV, @cociweb, @cperrin88, @credomane, @danielkucera, @evanwurden, @hynek, @jatin-47, @kaenguruhs, @mad73923, @mintsoft and @neod123! 🎉&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also a big thank you to @tkruppert and @jacopotediosi for responsibly disclosing the security vulnerabilities fixed in this release. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;☝️ Known issues&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following issues were discovered in earlier versions, but too late to still be fixed in this version, and are going to get a fix in an upcoming bugfix release.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/OctoPrint/OctoPrint/issues/4952"&gt;#4952&lt;/a&gt;: Upload of multiple files is impossible if SD support is disabled. Keep SD support enabled for now if you want to upload more than one file at once via the web UI.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/OctoPrint/OctoPrint/issues/4975"&gt;#4975&lt;/a&gt;: Reserved identifiers in the temperature reports from the printer lead to a warning getting logged each time instead of just once, which can increase the log file with broken firmware implementations. Avoid firmware reporting reserved identifiers, e.g. reporting a chamber temperature while also marking a chamber as not available as observed on current Prusa XL firmware builds.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/OctoPrint/OctoPrint/issues/4993"&gt;#4993&lt;/a&gt;: A bug in the GCODE analyser implementation can cause the server to get blocked if a lot of files need to get analysed at once during startup or due to a bulk upload. For now it is strongly suggested to limit the amount of freshly added files to a max of 10 at once and/or be aware of the server being very busy for a few minutes after larger numbers of added files.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;🔗 More information&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/OctoPrint/OctoPrint/compare/1.9.3...1.10.0"&gt;Commits&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Release candidates:&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/OctoPrint/OctoPrint/releases/tag/1.10.0rc1"&gt;1.10.0rc1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/OctoPrint/OctoPrint/releases/tag/1.10.0rc2"&gt;1.10.0rc2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/OctoPrint/OctoPrint/releases/tag/1.10.0rc3"&gt;1.10.0rc3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/OctoPrint/OctoPrint/releases/tag/1.10.0rc4"&gt;1.10.0rc4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/OctoPrint/OctoPrint/releases/tag/1.10.0" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/OctoPrint/OctoPrint/releases/tag/1.10.1</id>
    <title>New release for OctoPrint: 1.10.1</title>
    <updated>2024-05-14T05:52:38-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>OctoPrint/OctoPrint</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p align="center"&gt;&lt;a href="https://octoprint.org/support-octoprint/" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;img src="https://gist.githubusercontent.com/foosel/a66c9642e294cd61e79b760143c0200a/raw/72fce2cc4f6f2aef3864abdd99ece7b2f377ff56/funding-banner.svg" alt="Click here if you want to help with OctoPrint's funding!"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;✋ Heads-ups&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The heads-ups from 1.10.0 still apply&lt;/strong&gt;, please read this release's &lt;a href="https://github.com/OctoPrint/OctoPrint/releases/tag/1.10.0"&gt;release notes&lt;/a&gt; as well for a full picture of what you should be aware of and what changed!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These heads-ups were added:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;🔒 If you use autologin and have additional reverse proxies in front of OctoPrint, make sure they are configured correctly&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have autologin enabled (which means OctoPrint will log you in automatically if you are accessing it from a local address), it is of utmost importance to properly configure any reverse proxies in front of OctoPrint so that the client IP can be determined correctly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are accessing OctoPrint through haproxy as shipped on OctoPi, or behind a reverse proxy configured following one of the  &lt;a href="https://faq.octoprint.org/reverse-proxy"&gt;reverse proxy example configurations&lt;/a&gt;, there should be no issue. However, &lt;strong&gt;if you yourself have added any additional reverse proxies&lt;/strong&gt; in front of OctoPrint, make sure those are configured correctly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please read more about this &lt;a href="https://faq.octoprint.org/reverse-proxy"&gt;in the FAQ&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;⛈ Issues while updating?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On every new OctoPrint release we see some people run into the same issues with outdated or broken environments all over again. If you encounter a problem during update, please check &lt;a href="https://community.octoprint.org/t/my-octoprint-update-fails/37880"&gt;this collection of the most common issues&lt;/a&gt; encountered over the past couple of release cycles first, and test if the included fixes solve your problem. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;♻ Changes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;🔒 Security fixes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Severity High (7.1): It was possible for an unauthenticated attacker to completely bypass the authentication if the &lt;code&gt;autologinLocal&lt;/code&gt; option was enabled within the Access Control configuration, even if they came from networks that were not configured as &lt;code&gt;localNetworks&lt;/code&gt;, by spoofing their IP via the &lt;code&gt;X-Forwarded-For&lt;/code&gt; header.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please note that this does not affect you unless you've enabled the &lt;code&gt;autologinLocal&lt;/code&gt; feature (it ships as disabled by default and requires adjusting the &lt;code&gt;config.yaml&lt;/code&gt; file to enable, or the installation of a third party plugin that does this for you). It likely also doesn't affect you if you have enabled said feature but have OctoPrint only accessible on a trusted network. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have &lt;code&gt;autologinLocal&lt;/code&gt; enabled and your OctoPrint instance is reachable from a hostile network like the internet, e.g. through a port forward, this &lt;em&gt;does&lt;/em&gt; affect you and you need to update ASAP. Until you are able to update, it is strongly recommended to disable the autologin feature and/or make your instance inaccessible from potentially hostile networks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See also the &lt;a href="https://github.com/OctoPrint/OctoPrint/security/advisories/GHSA-2vjq-hg5w-5gm7"&gt;GitHub Security Advisory&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://nvd.nist.gov/vuln/detail/CVE-2024-32977"&gt;CVE-2024-32977&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;✨ Features &amp;amp; improvements&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Core&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/OctoPrint/OctoPrint/issues/4975"&gt;#4975&lt;/a&gt;: Reserved temperature identifiers not confirmed as supported but still sent by the printer's firmware will now only cause a warning log entry in &lt;code&gt;octoprint.log&lt;/code&gt; on their first occurrence during a connection, not every time a temperature report is received. This is to combat log spam in case of firmware bugs and misconfiguration.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/OctoPrint/OctoPrint/issues/5003"&gt;#5003&lt;/a&gt;: Make the ticks on the temperature graph's timeline automatically scale with the cutoff to keep the graph readable even with several hours of history.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Revert back to the &lt;code&gt;netifaces&lt;/code&gt; dependency. While &lt;code&gt;netifaces2&lt;/code&gt; as used in 1.10.0 works well, it is sadly causing some build issues in the field. In the interest of giving as many people as possible access to any bug and especially security fixes, we are thus reverting to the (unmaintained) netifaces for now and keeping an eye on the wheel availability and compatibility of &lt;code&gt;netifaces2&lt;/code&gt; for a future rollout.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Achievements Plugin&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/OctoPrint/OctoPrint/issues/5007"&gt;#5007&lt;/a&gt;: Clarify the requirement to properly configure the timezone and allow to reset all or only the time based achievements.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clarify that the Achievements Plugin is a &lt;strong&gt;plugin&lt;/strong&gt; that can be disabled, if one doesn't want to have achievements.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;🐛 Bug fixes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Core&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/OctoPrint/OctoPrint/issues/4952"&gt;#4952&lt;/a&gt;: Uploading multiple files through the web interface will now also work if printer side SD support has been disabled (see also &lt;a href="https://github.com/OctoPrint/OctoPrint/issues/4953"&gt;PR#4953&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/OctoPrint/OctoPrint/issues/4993"&gt;#4993&lt;/a&gt;: Fix resource consumption and server performance issues caused by a busy loop in the GCODE analysis.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/OctoPrint/OctoPrint/issues/4996"&gt;PR#4996&lt;/a&gt;: Fix screenreader role on tabs to enable keyboard navigation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/OctoPrint/OctoPrint/issues/5004"&gt;#5004&lt;/a&gt;: Fix drag'n'drop file uploading in Safari.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/OctoPrint/OctoPrint/issues/5005"&gt;#5005&lt;/a&gt;: Fix netmask &amp;amp; external address detection.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Achievements Plugin&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix the quote of the "One small step for (a) man" achievement to match NASA's official transcript.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use configured timezone for internal stats as well.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Application Keys Plugin&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/OctoPrint/OctoPrint/issues/5001"&gt;#5001&lt;/a&gt;: Fix regular user's (non-admins) not being able to revoke application keys.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;🎉 Special thanks to all the contributors!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Special thanks to everyone who contributed to this bugfix release, especially to @cp2004 and @dawidpieper for their PRs!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also a big thank you to @jacopotediosi for responsibly disclosing the security vulnerability fixed in this release. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;🔗 More information&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/OctoPrint/OctoPrint/compare/1.10.0...1.10.1"&gt;Commits&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Release candidates:&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As this is a bugfix release, there were no release candidates&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/OctoPrint/OctoPrint/releases/tag/1.10.1" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/OctoPrint/OctoPrint/releases/tag/1.10.2</id>
    <title>New release for OctoPrint: 1.10.2</title>
    <updated>2024-06-18T04:10:19-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>OctoPrint/OctoPrint</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p align="center"&gt;&lt;a href="https://octoprint.org/support-octoprint/" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;img src="https://gist.githubusercontent.com/foosel/a66c9642e294cd61e79b760143c0200a/raw/72fce2cc4f6f2aef3864abdd99ece7b2f377ff56/funding-banner.svg" alt="Click here if you want to help with OctoPrint's funding!"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;✋ Heads-ups&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The heads-ups from 1.10.0 still apply&lt;/strong&gt;, please read this release's &lt;a href="https://github.com/OctoPrint/OctoPrint/releases/tag/1.10.0"&gt;release notes&lt;/a&gt; as well for a full picture of what you should be aware of and what changed!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The same holds true for the &lt;strong&gt;heads-ups from 1.10.1&lt;/strong&gt; which you can find &lt;a href="https://github.com/OctoPrint/OctoPrint/releases/tag/1.10.1"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;⛈ Issues while updating?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On every new OctoPrint release we see some people run into the same issues with outdated or broken environments all over again. If you encounter a problem during update, please check &lt;a href="https://community.octoprint.org/t/my-octoprint-update-fails/37880"&gt;this collection of the most common issues&lt;/a&gt; encountered over the past couple of release cycles first, and test if the included fixes solve your problem. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;♻ Changes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;🐛 Bug fixes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Core&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/OctoPrint/OctoPrint/issues/5002"&gt;#5002&lt;/a&gt;: Fix a translation string in the german translation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/OctoPrint/OctoPrint/issues/5019"&gt;#5019&lt;/a&gt;: Fix/workaround for a third party dependency change, breaking the &lt;code&gt;octoprint dev plugin:new&lt;/code&gt; command.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/OctoPrint/OctoPrint/issues/5021"&gt;#5021&lt;/a&gt;: Fix behaviour of "Hide successful prints" filter in the file list. Folders will be shown as long as they have at least one file in them that has not been printed successfully yet, and they will also be shown if they contain the currently selected file, regardless of the amount of successful prints.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix an import to be compatible to Jinja2&amp;gt;=3.1.3.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pin pydantic to 1.10.16 to work around an issue with Python 3.12.4.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Achievements Plugin&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/OctoPrint/OctoPrint/issues/5017"&gt;#5017&lt;/a&gt;: Fix a string in the german translation that caused the Achievements overview to not correctly render if german language was selected.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/OctoPrint/OctoPrint/issues/5027"&gt;#5027&lt;/a&gt;: Fix description of the Adventurer achievement&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix event processing if the backup or plugin manager plugins are disabled.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;🎉 Special thanks to all the contributors!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Special thanks to everyone who contributed to this bugfix release!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;🔗 More information&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/OctoPrint/OctoPrint/compare/1.10.1...1.10.2"&gt;Commits&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Release candidates:&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As this is a bugfix release, there were no release candidates&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/OctoPrint/OctoPrint/releases/tag/1.10.2" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
