<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://selfh.st/apps</id>
  <title>OpenProject Releases</title>
  <updated>2025-07-08T22:36:06.216821-04:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>selfh.st</name>
    <email>contact@selfh.st</email>
  </author>
  <link href="https://selfh.st/apps" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>Self-hosted software releases generated by selfh.st</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/opf/openproject/releases/tag/v15.5.1</id>
    <title>New release for OpenProject: OpenProject 15.5.1</title>
    <updated>2025-05-05T02:03:25-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>opf/openproject</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;Release date: 2025-05-05&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We released OpenProject &lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/versions/2195"&gt;OpenProject 15.5.1&lt;/a&gt;.
The release contains several bug fixes and we recommend updating to the newest version.
In these Release Notes, we will give an overview of important feature changes.
At the end, you will find a complete list of all changes and bug fixes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Bug fixes and changes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;!-- Warning: Anything within the below lines will be automatically removed by the release script --&gt;
&lt;!-- BEGIN AUTOMATED SECTION --&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bugfix: PDF Export: Strikethrough formatting in tables is not applied [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/62231"&gt;#62231&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bugfix: Non-working days can be choosen via date field [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/62525"&gt;#62525&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bugfix: &amp;#39;Related to&amp;#39; relations is added when user adds any other type of relations [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/62587"&gt;#62587&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bugfix: Cannot start /usr/bin/openproject run web after Upgrade to 15.3.2 [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/62764"&gt;#62764&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bugfix: ActiveRecord::RecordNotFound in WorkPackages::DatePickerController#show [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/62834"&gt;#62834&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bugfix: ActiveRecord::RecordNotUnique on RecurringMeetingsController#update [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/63381"&gt;#63381&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bugfix: SystemStackError on api/v3/projects with larger pageSize (e.g. 1000) [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/63498"&gt;#63498&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bugfix: Error 500 on deleting Categories [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/63502"&gt;#63502&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bugfix: All /assets/frontend requests return 404 not found [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/63503"&gt;#63503&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bugfix: 500 when sending empty workflow [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/63514"&gt;#63514&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bugfix: ActiveRecord::RecordNotFound on WorkPackageRelationsController#destroy [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/63521"&gt;#63521&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bugfix: Git authentication fails after upgrading to OP 15.5.0 [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/63534"&gt;#63534&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bugfix: Error 500 when changing duration days of successor to zero  [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/63598"&gt;#63598&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bugfix: PDF timesheet: Error for TimeEntry with hours set to nil [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/63600"&gt;#63600&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bugfix: OpenProject 15.5.0: Error 500 when clicking diff in a repository [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/63604"&gt;#63604&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bugfix: Ordering by version/assignee/responsible and sorting by custom field of type version/user at the same time fails [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/63671"&gt;#63671&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bugfix: IFC conversion failing in helm installation [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/63762"&gt;#63762&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;!-- END AUTOMATED SECTION --&gt;
&lt;!-- Warning: Anything above this line will be automatically removed by the release script --&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Contributions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A big thanks to our Community members for reporting bugs and helping us identify and provide fixes.
This release, special thanks for reporting and finding bugs go to Sven Kunze, Dan Goodliffe, Robin Reichenbach, Nicolas Salguero.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/opf/openproject/releases/tag/v15.5.1" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/opf/openproject/releases/tag/v16.0.0</id>
    <title>New release for OpenProject: OpenProject 16.0.0</title>
    <updated>2025-05-21T08:10:34-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>opf/openproject</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;Release date: 2025-05-21&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We released &lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/versions/1412"&gt;OpenProject 16.0.0&lt;/a&gt;. This major release contains many features and bug fixes and we recommend updating to the newest version. In these Release Notes, we will give an overview of important updates, important feature changes and important technical updates. At the end, you will find a complete list of all changes and bug fixes for 16.0.0.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Important updates&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Enterprise plans (Basic, Professional, Premium, and Corporate) have been updated. Each plan now includes a specific set of Enterprise add-ons. Support levels and pricing remain unchanged with version 16.0.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Current Enterprise customers retain their existing plans with access to all Enterprise add-ons available at that time. No features are removed. From this version onward, new Enterprise add-ons may be included only in higher-tier plans. For example, the new &lt;a href="#internal-comments-in-work-packages-enterprise-add-on"&gt;Internal comments feature&lt;/a&gt; is part of the Professional plan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Customers on lower Enterprise plans who want to try out new add-ons from higher plans can do so by &lt;a href="https://www.openproject.org/contact/"&gt;requesting a new Enterprise trial token (on-premises)&lt;/a&gt; or by &lt;a href="https://start.openproject.com/"&gt;starting a new Cloud trial instance&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More details are available in our updated &lt;a href="https://www.openproject.org/pricing"&gt;Pricing page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Important feature changes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Meeting backlogs&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meeting organization becomes even easier with OpenProject 16.0: Meeting backlogs allow users to collect, manage, and prepare agenda items more flexibly — both for one-time meetings and for recurring meeting series.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In one-time meetings, the new &lt;a href="https://www.openproject.org/docs/release-notes/16-0-0/../../user-guide/meetings/one-time-meetings/#agenda-backlogs"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Agenda backlog&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; stores topics that are not yet assigned to the current meeting but may be added later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="A one-time meeting in OpenProject with an Agenda backlog and info to 'Drag items here or create a new one'." src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/opf/openproject/release/16.0/docs/release-notes/16-0-0/openproject-16-0-meeting-backlogs-one-time-highlighted.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In recurring meetings, the shared &lt;a href="https://www.openproject.org/docs/release-notes/16-0-0/../../user-guide/meetings/recurring-meetings/#meeting-backlogs-for-recurring-meetings"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Series backlog&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; helps track open points across all meeting occurrences and move items between them as priorities change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="A recurring meeting in OpenProject with a Series backlog and and options to Edit, add notes, Move to current meeting or Remove from agenda." src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/opf/openproject/release/16.0/docs/release-notes/16-0-0/openproject-16-0-meeting-backlogs-recurring-options.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Agenda items can easily be moved from the backlog to a meeting — or back to the backlog if an agenda item needs to be postponed. Work packages can also be added directly to the backlog. Even meetings without current agenda items can maintain a backlog of important topics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meeting backlogs support better preparation, more flexibility, and a clearer structure for meeting management in OpenProject.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;End of classic meetings&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With version 16.0, the 'classic’ option will no longer be offered when creating a new meeting in OpenProject. With the release of meeting outcomes and now also meeting backlogs, classic meetings are considered outdated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No data will get lost with the update, apart from the Meeting history of your classic meetings. If you used classic meetings in the past, see &lt;a href="https://www.openproject.org/blog/end-classic-meetings-may-2025/"&gt;this blog article&lt;/a&gt; to learn more about the change and the reasons behind it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Internal comments in work packages (Enterprise add-on)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Users of the Enterprise Professional version are now able to communicate internally in the work package Activity tab. To use this feature, a project admin has to enable internal comments. By default, these are only visible to the project admin role, but administrators can grant a new set of permissions to any number of roles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All users with these permissions then see an "Internal comment" checkbox when adding a new comment. If they check this box, the comment will only be visible to other people with these permissions. The different background color indicates that a comment is internal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="OpenProject work package with open Activity tab, a comment from a user and a not yet submitted comment with confidential content where the checkmark for Internal comment is activated." src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/opf/openproject/release/16.0/docs/release-notes/16-0-0/openproject-16-0-internal-comment.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[!TIP]
To check who is able to see your internal comment, type '@' and you will see a list of all users that have the permission to see internal comments. If a user is not in that list, you will not be able to @mention them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[!NOTE]
Starting with 16.0, &lt;strong&gt;files uploaded in the Activity tab will not be included in the Files tab&lt;/strong&gt;. Even though internal comments are the technical trigger for this change, it applies to both regular and internal comments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Find out more about &lt;a href="https://www.openproject.org/docs/release-notes/16-0-0/../../user-guide/activity/#internal-comments-enterprise-add-on"&gt;internal comments in this user guide&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.openproject.org/blog/internal-comments/"&gt;this blog article&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Automatically generated work package subjects (Enterprise add-on)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OpenProject now supports automatically generated subjects for work packages. This new Enterprise add-on, available in the Professional plan, allows administrators to define subject patterns for each work package type. When enabled, the subject field is &lt;strong&gt;filled automatically and becomes non-editable during work package creation and updates&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Two screenshots: One showing the administration for a work package type 'Candidate interview' with the subject pattern /Candidate with /Assignee on /Start date. One showing a work package of the type Candidate interview with an automatically generated work package subject following that pattern - &amp;quot;Lydia Schiffer with Cyril Dupont on 2025-05-26&amp;quot;" src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/opf/openproject/release/16.0/docs/release-notes/16-0-0/openproject-16-0-automatically-generated-work-package-subjects-candidate-interview-explained.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is especially useful for structured processes such as vacation requests, IT tickets, or maintenance reports, where consistent naming is required. Subject patterns can include static text as well as dynamic placeholders like project name, work package type, or custom field values.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Get an &lt;a href="https://www.openproject.org/docs/release-notes/16-0-0/../../user-guide/work-packages/automatic-subjects/"&gt;introduction in the user guide&lt;/a&gt;, learn more about &lt;a href="https://www.openproject.org/docs/release-notes/16-0-0/../../system-admin-guide/manage-work-packages/work-package-types/automatic-subjects/"&gt;configuring automatically generated work package subjects in OpenProject system administration guide&lt;/a&gt;, or consult this &lt;a href="https://www.openproject.org/blog/automatically-generated-work-package-subjects/"&gt;blog article&lt;/a&gt; for more use case examples. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Separate time tracking module with calendar view&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OpenProject 16.0 offers a separate time tracking module with a calendar view. It is accessible from the global view and listed in the left side bar navigation called &lt;a href="https://www.openproject.org/docs/release-notes/16-0-0/../../user-guide/my-time-tracking/"&gt;My time tracking&lt;/a&gt;. There, users can view and edit their logged time with start and end times. The user can switch between daily, weekly, work week and monthly views and also log new time entries directly by clicking in the calendar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each day shows the sum of the tracked time, and in the weekly and monthly views, the total tracked time is displayed in the lower right corner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="OpenProject's My time tracking module in calendar view, showing a work week with different time entries." src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/opf/openproject/release/16.0/docs/release-notes/16-0-0/openproject-16-0-my-time-tracking-work-week-final.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please note that this module has to be activated by an administrator first. Navigate to &lt;em&gt;Administration → Time and costs → Defaults&lt;/em&gt; and check the box next to 'Allow exact time tracking' to enable tracking start and finish dates. If 'Allow exact time tracking' is enabled, the calendar becomes the default view for the My time tracking module. If 'Require exact times' is checked, users must provide both start and end times when logging time. Otherwise, the list view remains the default. In the calendar view, all entries are then displayed at the top of the respective day column.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learn more about My time tracking module in &lt;a href="https://www.openproject.org/docs/release-notes/16-0-0/../../user-guide/my-time-tracking/"&gt;this user guide&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.openproject.org/blog/time-tracking-module/"&gt;this blog article&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Time entries with legally required mandatory fields: start time and finish time&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Time reports now include explicit start and end times, addressing common legal requirements. Before 16.0, time reports showed only the total duration of logged time. Now, they also include start and end times for greater accuracy. This applies to all features where time tracking is possible, e.g. the new time tracking module, PDF timesheets, or the My spent time widget.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Overview of time logged per day per user in PDF timesheet&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Exported PDF timesheets now include an overview of logged time per day and user. It is displayed in a table view at the beginning of the report. If the list contains more than five users, the view is split into several tables.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Example PDF timesheet showing different times logged by five different people in a table view" src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/opf/openproject/release/16.0/docs/release-notes/16-0-0/openproject-16-0-timesheet-hours-user-day.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Release to Community: Graphs on project overview page&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From time to time an Enterprise add-on is released for the free Community version. We are happy to announce that with OpenProject 16.0, the &lt;strong&gt;graphs on the project overview page are now available in all editions&lt;/strong&gt;. This means that Community users can now display graphs directly on the project overview page to visualize important project information and communicate project status to the team and management.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The work package graph widgets display information about the work packages within a project and can be shown in different views, such as bar graphs or pie charts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.openproject.org/docs/release-notes/16-0-0/../../user-guide/project-overview/#work-package-graph-widgets"&gt;Learn more about this feature in our user guide&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Different graphs displayed on a project overview page in OpenProject: Work package status in a pie chart, work packages progress in a graph with percentages, closed + open work packages sorted by type and number of assignees." src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/opf/openproject/release/16.0/docs/release-notes/16-0-0/openproject-project-reports.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Parent relation displayed in work package relations tab&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As requested by our users, you can now add a parent work package relation by choosing it directly from the dropdown menu in the Relations tab. This is also still possible by clicking on &lt;strong&gt;Set parent&lt;/strong&gt; on the top left corner of a work package. Both will make the related work package a parent of the current (child) work package.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Dropdown in work package Relations tab, showing highlighted Parent relation." src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/opf/openproject/release/16.0/docs/release-notes/16-0-0/openproject-16-0-parent-relation.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Save work package export configuration&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When &lt;a href="https://www.openproject.org/docs/release-notes/16-0-0/../../user-guide/work-packages/exporting/"&gt;exporting a (public or private) work package table&lt;/a&gt;, users can now save their configuration settings, e.g. a specific order and display of columns or long text fields. This saves time and allows users to share the export settings with their team (e.g. for a defects and approval report). Please note that this setting is not individual and will &lt;strong&gt;change the default configuration for this specific format and type for everyone&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="OpenProject work package table export modal with a highlighted checkbox to save settings." src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/opf/openproject/release/16.0/docs/release-notes/16-0-0/openproject-16-0-save-export-settings-highlighted.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Storage Health status: Multiple visible checks and download option&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Health check for file storages has been extended in OpenProject 16.0. Administrators can now view &lt;strong&gt;multiple visible results&lt;/strong&gt;, grouped into base configuration, authentication, and automatically-managed folders. Each group displays a short summary indicating whether all checks passed, warnings occurred, or failures were detected. If issues are found, a link to detailed documentation is provided.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The summary of the most recent health check remains visible in the sidebar. In addition, a new option allows administrators to open a &lt;strong&gt;full detailed report&lt;/strong&gt; to review all individual checks directly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To make troubleshooting even easier, administrators can now also &lt;strong&gt;download&lt;/strong&gt; the complete health check report as a text file, for example to include in a support request.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Option to select favorite project tab as default in project quick search&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When selecting the &lt;strong&gt;Favorites&lt;/strong&gt; tab in the Projects dropdown, OpenProject now remembers this preference and shows it by default the next time the dropdown is opened. It is a personal setting that remains active until the user switches back to &lt;strong&gt;All&lt;/strong&gt;. This small usability improvement saves time for users who frequently work with favorite projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Important technical changes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Seamless integration of user sessions of Nextcloud and OpenProject using OIDC &amp;amp; JWTs (Enterprise add-on)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OpenProject 16.0 introduces a major improvement for customers of the Enterprise Corporate plan that are using Nextcloud alongside OpenProject. Through a new configuration based on OpenID Connect (OIDC) and JSON Web Tokens (JWTs), OpenProject and Nextcloud can now integrate user sessions seamlessly without showing separate consent screens in each application.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead of mutually acting as OAuth servers and clients, both OpenProject and Nextcloud can now authenticate against a common Identity Provider (IDP). This allows OpenProject to reuse the user session to call Nextcloud APIs directly — improving the user experience and reducing complexity in daily workflows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please see &lt;a href="https://www.openproject.org/docs/release-notes/16-0-0/../../system-admin-guide/integrations/nextcloud/oidc-sso/"&gt;our system admin guide&lt;/a&gt; to learn how to set up this integration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the first version of OpenProject to support this new integration method with Nextcloud. Since this feature was not yet
exposed to large installations, we still consider it experimental. Please share your feedback regarding this new feature with us and stay tuned
for further enhancements around it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Breaking: API requests with JWT issued by OpenID Connect provider require scope&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href="https://www.openproject.org/docs/release-notes/16-0-0/../../release-notes/14/14-0-0/"&gt;OpenProject 14.4.0&lt;/a&gt; we introduced the possibility to access the OpenProject API through a JSON Web Token created by an OpenID Connect
provider. Back then we only intended them to be used in the context of our APIv3. However, as OpenProject evolves further, we want to
be able to use them in additional contexts. Starting with OpenProject 16.0.0, we will therefore require all tokens to carry a scope called
&lt;code&gt;api_v3&lt;/code&gt; for API requests to our APIv3. This is consistent with other tokens issued by OpenProject itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Bug fixes and changes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;!-- Warning: Anything within the below lines will be automatically removed by the release script --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;component [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/62577"&gt;#62577&lt;/a&gt;]
- Feature: Migrate classic meeting functionality into dynamic meetings [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/62621"&gt;#62621&lt;/a&gt;]
- Feature: Introduce enterprise banner for enforced start &amp;amp; end time tracking [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/62624"&gt;#62624&lt;/a&gt;]
- Feature: Create a CollapsibleSectionComponent  [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/62754"&gt;#62754&lt;/a&gt;]
- Feature: Storage sidebar button in projects should behave correctly in all scenarios [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/62758"&gt;#62758&lt;/a&gt;]
- Feature: Show warning if a user tries to uncheck the &amp;#39;Internal comment&amp;#39; checkbox when there&amp;#39;s already text in the comment box [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/62785"&gt;#62785&lt;/a&gt;]
- Feature: Additional protections for internal comments in places where comments are accessed [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/62988"&gt;#62988&lt;/a&gt;]
- Feature: Check the accessibility on CollapsibleSectionComponent &amp;amp; CollapsibleHeaderComponent [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/63275"&gt;#63275&lt;/a&gt;]
- Feature: Time tracking list view [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/63336"&gt;#63336&lt;/a&gt;]
- Feature: Communicate dangers of automatic self registration [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/63379"&gt;#63379&lt;/a&gt;]
- Feature: Download Storage Health status report [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/63467"&gt;#63467&lt;/a&gt;]
- Feature: Create Project Status Component [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/63482"&gt;#63482&lt;/a&gt;]
- Feature: Add error codes to health check results [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/63518"&gt;#63518&lt;/a&gt;]
- Feature: Implement medium banner component [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/63525"&gt;#63525&lt;/a&gt;]
- Feature: PDF Timesheet: Restore previous overview table and add headlines [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/63526"&gt;#63526&lt;/a&gt;]
- Feature: Make the SaaS Trial Plan Premium [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/63532"&gt;#63532&lt;/a&gt;]
- Feature: Add meeting backlogs [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/63543"&gt;#63543&lt;/a&gt;]
- Feature: Primerize Administration &amp;gt; Authentication settings [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/63567"&gt;#63567&lt;/a&gt;]
- Feature: Release Enterprise add-on &amp;quot;Graphs on project overview page&amp;quot; to the Community version [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/63619"&gt;#63619&lt;/a&gt;]
- Feature: Work week available in the view selector of time tracking calendar and list [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/63621"&gt;#63621&lt;/a&gt;]
- Feature: Remove internal comments feature flag [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/63635"&gt;#63635&lt;/a&gt;]
- Feature: Remove work package comment ID URL feature flag [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/63646"&gt;#63646&lt;/a&gt;]
- Feature: Show attribute name instead of N/A if attribute is just empty [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/63660"&gt;#63660&lt;/a&gt;]
- Feature: Implement new homescreen enterprise banner style [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/63727"&gt;#63727&lt;/a&gt;]
- Feature: Use Chargebee custom field (Domain) for generation of new version 5 Enterprise token [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/63845"&gt;#63845&lt;/a&gt;]
- Feature: Combine legacy_enterprise custom field with plan name [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/63905"&gt;#63905&lt;/a&gt;]
- Bugfix: Search shows browser autofil [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/57836"&gt;#57836&lt;/a&gt;]
- Bugfix: User is able to edit someone else&amp;#39;s comment [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/58511"&gt;#58511&lt;/a&gt;]
- Bugfix: Boards search for WorkPackages is too small [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/58702"&gt;#58702&lt;/a&gt;]
- Bugfix: Quick wins for top bar search [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/58704"&gt;#58704&lt;/a&gt;]
- Bugfix: String &amp;quot;All&amp;quot; within search cannot be translated [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/59247"&gt;#59247&lt;/a&gt;]
- Bugfix: Inconsistently used red color for notification bell and ongoing time tracking [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/59379"&gt;#59379&lt;/a&gt;]
- Bugfix: Error 500 when bulk editing work packages [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/60580"&gt;#60580&lt;/a&gt;]
- Bugfix: Primer Dialog close button ARIA label is not localised [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/61631"&gt;#61631&lt;/a&gt;]
- Bugfix: Token Refresh and Exchange does not work when Client ID contains special characters [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/61694"&gt;#61694&lt;/a&gt;]
- Bugfix: Empty audience translation is missing [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/61855"&gt;#61855&lt;/a&gt;]
- Bugfix: SSO users storage connection does not work on project storage members page  [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/61880"&gt;#61880&lt;/a&gt;]
- Bugfix: Autocompleter dropdown in pattern input is missing default entry [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/61935"&gt;#61935&lt;/a&gt;]
- Bugfix: Can&amp;#39;t associate storage to project via storage admin view [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/61936"&gt;#61936&lt;/a&gt;]
- Bugfix: Input with angle brackets disappears on save but is saved [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/62040"&gt;#62040&lt;/a&gt;]
- Bugfix: Linking to project storage via SSO fails when user can&amp;#39;t authenticate [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/62166"&gt;#62166&lt;/a&gt;]
- Bugfix: Updating a work package with generated subject fails, if project is missing custom field [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/62217"&gt;#62217&lt;/a&gt;]
- Bugfix: Storage shows as healthy even if audience is misconfigured [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/62237"&gt;#62237&lt;/a&gt;]
- Bugfix: PDF export does not export all embedded screenshots [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/62293"&gt;#62293&lt;/a&gt;]
- Bugfix: Cannot inline create a WP with auto generated subject when no other attribute is a required field [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/62318"&gt;#62318&lt;/a&gt;]
- Bugfix: Project attribute list entries not displayed when applied as filter in project list [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/62386"&gt;#62386&lt;/a&gt;]
- Bugfix: Add missing attributes in subject patterns [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/62429"&gt;#62429&lt;/a&gt;]
- Bugfix: Wrong meeting date displayed in side panel [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/62441"&gt;#62441&lt;/a&gt;]
- Bugfix: OpenProject enterprise key domain check is case-sensitive [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/62520"&gt;#62520&lt;/a&gt;]
- Bugfix: Work package info line opens in a new tab [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/62545"&gt;#62545&lt;/a&gt;]
- Bugfix: Marking a notification as read automatically selects the first notification [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/62604"&gt;#62604&lt;/a&gt;]
- Bugfix: Long code block breaks meeting outcome [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/62689"&gt;#62689&lt;/a&gt;]
- Bugfix: Sum queries (∑) do not display children that are not in the current project in view [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/62847"&gt;#62847&lt;/a&gt;]
- Bugfix: Exposing restricted comments when polling [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/62978"&gt;#62978&lt;/a&gt;]
- Bugfix: Insufficient spacing between meeting agenda notes and outcome [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/63108"&gt;#63108&lt;/a&gt;]
- Bugfix: The auto time-tracking timer button keeps changing width when the timer is running [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/63345"&gt;#63345&lt;/a&gt;]
- Bugfix: Gantt module work package list still uses old term &amp;quot;follower&amp;quot; [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/63351"&gt;#63351&lt;/a&gt;]
- Bugfix: Inconsistent bottom-margin on agenda items [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/63353"&gt;#63353&lt;/a&gt;]
- Bugfix: User with a particular set of permissions sees error when updating WP dates [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/63434"&gt;#63434&lt;/a&gt;]
- Bugfix: Missing attributes of generated work package subjects are displayed wrongly [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/63441"&gt;#63441&lt;/a&gt;]
- Bugfix: Missing space when putting multiple CollapsibleSections below each other [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/63442"&gt;#63442&lt;/a&gt;]
- Bugfix: Collapsed preview not working [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/63443"&gt;#63443&lt;/a&gt;]
- Bugfix: Sort projects in Favorite Projects widget on My page alphabetically  [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/63444"&gt;#63444&lt;/a&gt;]
- Bugfix: Moving single date work packages in the Calendar adds the second date without user intent [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/63475"&gt;#63475&lt;/a&gt;]
- Bugfix: Missing parent attributes in subject patterns [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/63483"&gt;#63483&lt;/a&gt;]
- Bugfix: Users without the manage meeting minutes permission still see the &amp;quot;Add outcome&amp;quot; option [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/63535"&gt;#63535&lt;/a&gt;]
- Bugfix: My Time tracking calendar view, does not look properly in dark mode [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/63548"&gt;#63548&lt;/a&gt;]
- Bugfix: Bad translations of &amp;quot;All checks passed&amp;quot; for Arabic and Latvian languages [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/63568"&gt;#63568&lt;/a&gt;]
- Bugfix: Work package meetings tab has discrepency when work packages are added to a template [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/63571"&gt;#63571&lt;/a&gt;]
- Bugfix: My sessions page takes forever to load [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/63587"&gt;#63587&lt;/a&gt;]
- Bugfix: SAML Setup with metadata URL does not fill IdP Cert [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/63610"&gt;#63610&lt;/a&gt;]
- Bugfix: SAML auth: Obsolete fingerprint is used despite presence of IdP certficate [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/63612"&gt;#63612&lt;/a&gt;]
- Bugfix: Boolean custom fields in subject patterns are not supported [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/63641"&gt;#63641&lt;/a&gt;]
- Bugfix: &amp;#39;Add work package to meeting&amp;#39; dialog has incorrect meeting field label [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/63692"&gt;#63692&lt;/a&gt;]
- Bugfix: xls export of time fields work in wrong format (should be 10 h instead of 1 d 2h) [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/63739"&gt;#63739&lt;/a&gt;]
- Bugfix: Focus is not set on Agenda item title when adding to Backlog/meeting sections [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/63784"&gt;#63784&lt;/a&gt;]
- Bugfix: Error 500 when bulk delete related work packages [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/63831"&gt;#63831&lt;/a&gt;]
- Bugfix: Antivirus settings should be hidden on SaaS [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/64034"&gt;#64034&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- END AUTOMATED SECTION --&gt;
&lt;!-- Warning: Anything above this line will be automatically removed by the release script --&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Contributions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A very special thank you goes to City of Cologne, Deutsche Bahn and ZenDiS for sponsoring released or upcoming features. Your support, alongside the efforts of our amazing Community, helps drive these innovations. Also a big thanks to our Community members for reporting bugs and helping us identify and provide fixes. Special thanks for reporting and finding bugs go to alex e, Klaas vT, Daniel Elkeles, Marcel Carvalho, Regina Schikora, Çağlar Yeşilyurt, and Александр Татаринцев.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last but not least, we are very grateful for our very engaged translation contributors on Crowdin, who translated quite a few OpenProject strings! This release we would like to particularly thank the following users:
- &lt;a href="https://crowdin.com/profile/postbse"&gt;Сергей Баранов&lt;/a&gt;, for a great number of translations into Russian.
- &lt;a href="https://crowdin.com/profile/gzyyy"&gt;Gzyyy&lt;/a&gt;, for a great number of translations into Chinese simplified.
- &lt;a href="https://crowdin.com/profile/rlmpereira"&gt;rlmpereira&lt;/a&gt;, for a great number of translations into Portuguese.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Would you like to help out with translations yourself? Then take a look at our &lt;a href="https://www.openproject.org/docs/release-notes/16-0-0/../../contributions-guide/translate-openproject/"&gt;translation guide&lt;/a&gt; and find out exactly how you can contribute. It is very much appreciated!&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/opf/openproject/releases/tag/v16.0.0" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/opf/openproject/releases/tag/v16.0.1</id>
    <title>New release for OpenProject: OpenProject 16.0.1</title>
    <updated>2025-06-05T04:15:25-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>opf/openproject</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;Release date: 2025-06-05&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We released OpenProject &lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/versions/2200"&gt;OpenProject 16.0.1&lt;/a&gt;.
The release contains several bug fixes and we recommend updating to the newest version.
In these Release Notes, we will give an overview of important feature changes.
At the end, you will find a complete list of all changes and bug fixes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Bug fixes and changes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;!-- Warning: Anything within the below lines will be automatically removed by the release script --&gt;
&lt;!-- BEGIN AUTOMATED SECTION --&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Feature: Add internal:boolean property to activity comments (read) API [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/62130"&gt;#62130&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bugfix: Some dates and scheduling mode are lost when creating project from template [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/62426"&gt;#62426&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bugfix: Edge case when creating a section for an empty non-blankslate meeting [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/63422"&gt;#63422&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bugfix: Error when dragging a work package to its children in work packages list [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/63499"&gt;#63499&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bugfix: Creation of sub-items in hierarchy custom field not possible (error 500) [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/63855"&gt;#63855&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bugfix: Missing/wrong error handling for periodic activity tab updates [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/64073"&gt;#64073&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bugfix: Polling meeting updates can cause Browser&amp;#39;s Basic auth pop-up [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/64088"&gt;#64088&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bugfix: Polling work package activity updates can cause Browser&amp;#39;s Basic auth pop-up [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/64091"&gt;#64091&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bugfix: NoMethodError on PATCH::API::V3::WorkPackages::WorkPackagesAPI#/work_packages/:id/  [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/64133"&gt;#64133&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bugfix: Database migration 20240405131352_create_meeting_sections fails on Update [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/64298"&gt;#64298&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bugfix: Internal comments can be added without a valid token in some cases [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/64324"&gt;#64324&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;!-- END AUTOMATED SECTION --&gt;
&lt;!-- Warning: Anything above this line will be automatically removed by the release script --&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/opf/openproject/releases/tag/v16.0.1" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/opf/openproject/releases/tag/v16.1.0</id>
    <title>New release for OpenProject: OpenProject 16.1.0</title>
    <updated>2025-06-18T03:42:31-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>opf/openproject</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;Release date: 2025-06-18&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We released &lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/versions/2194"&gt;OpenProject 16.1.0&lt;/a&gt;. The release contains several bug fixes and we recommend updating to the newest version. In these Release Notes, we will give an overview of important feature changes and important technical changes. At the end, you will find a complete list of all changes and bug fixes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Important feature changes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Structure the project life cycle with phases and phase gates&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OpenProject 16.1 introduces a powerful new way to reflect your project’s structure over time: using project phases like &lt;strong&gt;Initiating, Planning, Executing, and Closing&lt;/strong&gt;, with optional phase gates at the start or end of each phase.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Project administrators can now &lt;strong&gt;activate relevant phases and phase gates per project&lt;/strong&gt;. Portfolio managers can then assign start and finish dates to each phase, with automatic scheduling of all following phases and phase gates based on working days. This helps reduce manual effort and keeps your project timelines consistent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Work packages can be assigned to a specific phase, making it easier to understand their context, filter by phase, and group work in the table view. And in the project list, you can use columns and new filters to track which projects are currently in which phase or gate – ideal for portfolio level planning and reporting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You’ll find the full life cycle directly in the project overview page, where you can enter dates, view the current phase, and access the new scheduling tools at a glance:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Project overview page with the project life cycle displayed in the right column" src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/opf/openproject/release/16.1/docs/release-notes/16-1-0/openproject-16-1-project-life-cycle-project-overview-highlighted.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[!NOTE]
With the Enterprise add-on available in the Premium plan or higher, you can configure existing project phases and phase gates and even create new ones. This is done in the global settings. The project-level features are available in all editions, with pre-defined phases based on the &lt;a href="https://www.openproject.org/pm2/"&gt;open source PM² framework&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.openproject.org/docs/release-notes/16-1-0/../../system-admin-guide/projects/project-life-cycle/"&gt;Read more about working with a project life cycle in OpenProject&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Export meetings in PDF format&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the most upvoted Community requests is now available: You can now &lt;strong&gt;export meetings as PDF documents&lt;/strong&gt; in OpenProject.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meeting organizers and participants can generate a printable PDF that includes the agenda, outcomes, participants, and more. This makes it ideal for sharing with colleagues, archiving meeting records, or informing stakeholders who could not attend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The export is available via the More (⋯) menu for both one-time meetings and individual occurrences of recurring meetings. You can &lt;strong&gt;customize the PDF&lt;/strong&gt; before download by choosing wheather to include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the list of participants,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the list of attachments,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the backlog,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the agenda outcomes,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a customized footer text (e.g. project name), which appears on each page.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The PDF is generated in A4 format and includes a clearly structured layout. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.openproject.org/docs/release-notes/16-1-0/../../user-guide/meetings/one-time-meetings/#export-a-meeting"&gt;Learn more about exporting meetings in PDF format in our documentation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Overlay of Export PDF options for OpenProject meetings" src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/opf/openproject/release/16.1/docs/release-notes/16-1-0/openproject-16-1-export-meeting-to-pdf.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Set smart default options for reminders&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We released work package reminders with OpenProject 15.2 in January 2025. With this update, it’s easier than ever to use them to stay organized and keep your notification center clean.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To make setting reminders even quicker, OpenProject now offers pre-filled options when clicking the reminder icon on a work package. Instead of entering details manually, you can now choose one of the following defaults:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tomorrow&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In 3 days&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In a week&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In a month&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;At a particular date/time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Selecting one of the quick options will open the reminder dialog with a pre-filled date and time – typically at 9:00 local time on the selected future day. You can still adjust the date, time, and add a note before saving the reminder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.openproject.org/docs/release-notes/16-1-0/../../user-guide/work-packages/edit-work-package/#work-package-reminders"&gt;Learn more about work package reminders in our documentation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Dropdown menu on a work package when clicking on the reminder icon, with options to quickly choose a date to be reminded" src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/opf/openproject/release/16.1/docs/release-notes/16-1-0/openproject-16-1-reminder-options.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Use negative lag for work package dates&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can now define &lt;strong&gt;negative lag&lt;/strong&gt; when setting up relations between work packages. This allows you to specify that a work package should start a few days before its &lt;strong&gt;predecessor&lt;/strong&gt; finishes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When adding or editing a successor or predecessor relation, the Lag field now accepts negative values. The updated help text reads: “The minimum number of working days in between the two work packages. It can also be negative.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This makes it easier to represent overlapping tasks and more flexible schedules in your project plan. For example, you may want the review of a document to begin two days before the final draft is complete. You will then have to enter a lag of -3 days for the (review) Successor work package.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Overlay of editing a successor (after) with a lag of -3 days" src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/opf/openproject/release/16.1/docs/release-notes/16-1-0/openproject-16-1-negative-lag.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please note that negative lags can be counterintuitive:
- A lag of 0 schedules the successor one day after the predecessor’s finish date.
- A lag of -1 schedules it on the same day.
- A lag of -2 schedules it one day before, and so on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[!NOTE]
&lt;strong&gt;Only working days&lt;/strong&gt; are taken into account. For example: If work package A finishes on a Tuesday and Saturday/Sunday are non-working days, then a lag of -3 will schedule its successor (work package B) to start on the previous Friday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.openproject.org/docs/release-notes/16-1-0/../../user-guide/work-packages/work-package-relations-hierarchies/#work-package-relations"&gt;Learn more about work package relations in our documentation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Display hierarchy trees for hierarchy custom fields (Enterprise add-on)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hierarchy custom fields are now easier to explore and use. When viewing such a custom field, a &lt;strong&gt;hierarchical tree is displayed next to the details section&lt;/strong&gt;, showing the entire structure at a glance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This tree helps you understand the position of the current item in the overall hierarchy and makes it easier to add or navigate related items. The currently selected item is highlighted, and all its parent nodes are automatically expanded, while unrelated branches remain collapsed by default.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clicking on any entry in the tree opens that item in the same view, making it easy to move through even complex hierarchies without losing context.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.openproject.org/docs/release-notes/16-1-0/../../system-admin-guide/custom-fields/"&gt;Learn more about custom fields in our system admin guide&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Example of a hierarchy custom field with the new visualization, the hierarchical tree" src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/opf/openproject/release/16.1/docs/release-notes/16-1-0/openproject-hierarchy-custom-field-tree.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Benefit from improved accessibility for the date picker with ARIA live regions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OpenProject 16.1 includes an important accessibility enhancement for users working with screen readers: Dynamic updates are now announced automatically using ARIA live regions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This applies to &lt;strong&gt;changes in the date picker&lt;/strong&gt; such as scheduling mode, working days only selector, start and finish dates, and duration. When one of these values is updated, the screen reader will announce a full summary like: “Date picker updated. Scheduling mode: Manual, Working days only, Start date: June 10, Finish date: June 12, Duration: 3 days”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This ensures that no important context is lost and improves the experience for all users relying on assistive technologies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To learn what more is planned regarding accessibility in OpenProject, see &lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/projects/openproject/work_packages?query_id=2906"&gt;these open work packages on our Community instance&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Important technical changes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Added API for emoji reactions, reminders, and internal comments&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OpenProject 16.1 extends its API to support three features that were previously only available via the web interface. This update enables integrations with other clients to access:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Emoji reactions on work package comments&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reminders for work packages&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Internal comments with restricted visibility&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Developers can now read and manage emoji reactions, create and update reminders, and write internal comments via API V3.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Bug fixes and changes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;!-- Warning: Anything within the below lines will be automatically removed by the release script --&gt;
&lt;!-- BEGIN AUTOMATED SECTION --&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Feature: Extend API V3 to cover Emoji reactions on work package comments (read, toggle) and extend documentation [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/57265"&gt;#57265&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Feature: Allow users to enter negative lag [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/58011"&gt;#58011&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Feature: Fixed set of project phases and gates editable on project overview page [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/58159"&gt;#58159&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Feature: Project phase columns on project list [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/58160"&gt;#58160&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Feature: Global phase administration [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/58161"&gt;#58161&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Feature: Phases as work package attribute [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/58162"&gt;#58162&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Feature: Project specific phase administration [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/58163"&gt;#58163&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Feature: Journalize changes to phases and gates [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/59178"&gt;#59178&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Feature: Option to copy phase on copying a project [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/59179"&gt;#59179&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Feature: Automatic scheduling for phases and phase gates [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/59180"&gt;#59180&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Feature: Filters for phases and phase gates in project list [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/59183"&gt;#59183&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Feature: Order by phases and phase gates on project list [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/59184"&gt;#59184&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Feature: Extend Reminders API V3 to include create, update &amp;amp; delete operations [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/59473"&gt;#59473&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Feature: Optimize life cycle modal UX [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/60330"&gt;#60330&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Feature: Document and implement proper mobile behaviour for Sub Header component (OP Primer) [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/60332"&gt;#60332&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Feature: Reminders: Offer quick-set options like &amp;#39;tomorrow&amp;#39; or &amp;#39;next week&amp;#39; with smart defaults [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/60357"&gt;#60357&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Feature: PDF export of meetings [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/60730"&gt;#60730&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Feature: Date picker to edit phases and phase gates of a project life cycle [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/61610"&gt;#61610&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Feature: Turn gates into property of phase (rename life cycle elements to &amp;quot;Phase&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;Phase gates&amp;quot;) [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/61952"&gt;#61952&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Feature: Add hovercard to gates [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/62608"&gt;#62608&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Feature: TreeView Primer View Component [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/62667"&gt;#62667&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Feature: Implementing ARIA live regions to communicate contextual changes [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/62708"&gt;#62708&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Feature: Show a TreeView on the page of hierachy customFields [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/62993"&gt;#62993&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Feature: Show attribute help texts in Primerized Project Settings &amp;gt; Information form [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/63737"&gt;#63737&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Feature: Primerize attribute help texts [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/63738"&gt;#63738&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Feature: Re-order and re-structure the &amp;#39;More&amp;#39; action menu for sections and agenda items [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/64074"&gt;#64074&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Feature: Configure scopes to be used during Token Exchange [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/64121"&gt;#64121&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Feature: [TreeView] Allow nodes to be anchors or buttons [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/64132"&gt;#64132&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Feature: Add work package internal comments (write) API [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/64166"&gt;#64166&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Feature: [TreeView] Bubble the expanded state from children to parents [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/64215"&gt;#64215&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Feature: Meeting PDF export: show if users are invited or attended [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/64565"&gt;#64565&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Feature: Differentiate between meeting agenda and meeting minutes in pdf export [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/64793"&gt;#64793&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Feature: Meeting PDF export: Refinement [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/64828"&gt;#64828&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bugfix: Project search is under the Search icon in New Recurring Meeting modal [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/59945"&gt;#59945&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bugfix: User can&amp;#39;t save lifecycle modal if project is invalid [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/60666"&gt;#60666&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bugfix: Activity Tab renders the same turbo frame multiple times inside of itself [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/61544"&gt;#61544&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bugfix: The &amp;#39;overdue&amp;#39; date colour does not adapt well to dark mode (fixed hex/odd colour variable) [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/62199"&gt;#62199&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bugfix: Seeder fails during upgrade with ArgumentError: Nothing registered with reference :default_role_project_admin (ArgumentError) [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/62582"&gt;#62582&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bugfix: (Regression) Error on Save (in various places) [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/62627"&gt;#62627&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bugfix: Reminders: saving without entering a date or time throws an error but also unnecessarily clears the other field [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/63461"&gt;#63461&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bugfix: ArgumentError in seeder [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/63826"&gt;#63826&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bugfix: ActiveRecord::RecordNotUnique in POST::API::V3::TimeEntries::TimeEntriesAPI#/time_entries [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/63839"&gt;#63839&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bugfix: Projects tab displayed for custom fields of type user, group, spent time and version [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/63900"&gt;#63900&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bugfix: Back arrow cannot be reached via keyboard [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/64222"&gt;#64222&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bugfix: Project overview page renders an h2 inside an h3 [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/64226"&gt;#64226&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bugfix: [Accessibility] Editable toolbar header is not recognized as headline by screenreaders [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/64227"&gt;#64227&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bugfix: Home screen widgets have the wrong headline tag [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/64228"&gt;#64228&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bugfix: Focus issues with WP primary button [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/64236"&gt;#64236&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bugfix: Access tokens of disabled OAuth applications are accepted by API [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/64258"&gt;#64258&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bugfix: Disabling an incomplete phase leads to inconsistencies [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/64292"&gt;#64292&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bugfix: Input fields suggest previously entered text [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/64312"&gt;#64312&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bugfix: The time in the pdf export is different from the time in the file name [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/64337"&gt;#64337&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bugfix: No updated path to 16.0.0 package source in manual  [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/64362"&gt;#64362&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bugfix: Checkbox label not clickable in 2FA settings [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/64367"&gt;#64367&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bugfix: Work packages &amp;quot;default&amp;quot; priority is lost when deleted. [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/64369"&gt;#64369&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bugfix: Attribute help text page is missing a page title [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/64417"&gt;#64417&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bugfix: The second phase&amp;#39;s start date selection is not enabled [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/64496"&gt;#64496&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bugfix: OpenProject 16.0.1: Error 500 when clicking on a revision link in a repository [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/64508"&gt;#64508&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bugfix: NoMethodError during Meetings::ExportJob [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/64510"&gt;#64510&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bugfix: The following phase&amp;#39;s finish date is inconsistent with the start date [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/64532"&gt;#64532&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bugfix: My time tracking has two dividers in the PageHeader [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/64573"&gt;#64573&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bugfix: Cannot switch back from Manual to Automatic scheduling on milestone successor [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/64603"&gt;#64603&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bugfix: Clearing the start date of a following phase is not possible [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/64628"&gt;#64628&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bugfix: Seeding error when seeding a second time with a different language [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/64711"&gt;#64711&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bugfix: Nothing registered with reference :default_color_green_light [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/64811"&gt;#64811&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bugfix: Attachments delete confirmation dialog opens behind attribute help text dialog [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/64831"&gt;#64831&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bugfix: Incorrect rescheduling after non working days are changed [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/64836"&gt;#64836&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bugfix: Error banners persist on page reload on Project Settings &amp;gt; Information form [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/64839"&gt;#64839&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bugfix: Attribute help text links for widgets on Projects Overview page lack padding [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/64846"&gt;#64846&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bugfix: Update working days settings warning messages to include phases [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/64855"&gt;#64855&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Feature: Add API for recent Communicator features (Emoji, Reminders, Internal Comments) [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/62507"&gt;#62507&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;!-- END AUTOMATED SECTION --&gt;
&lt;!-- Warning: Anything above this line will be automatically removed by the release script --&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Contributions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A very special thank you goes to City of Cologne, Deutsche Bahn and ZenDiS for sponsoring released or upcoming features. Your support, alongside the efforts of our amazing Community, helps drive these innovations. Also a big thanks to our Community members for reporting bugs and helping us identify and provide fixes. Special thanks for reporting and finding bugs go to Cameron Dutro and Maxim Béliveau.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last but not least, we are very grateful for our very engaged translation contributors on Crowdin, who translated quite a few OpenProject strings! This release we would like to particularly thank the following users:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://crowdin.com/profile/bigseung"&gt;BigSeung&lt;/a&gt;, for a great number of translations into Korean.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://crowdin.com/profile/rmiyata"&gt;rmiyata&lt;/a&gt;, for a great number of translations into Japanese.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://crowdin.com/profile/williamfromtw"&gt;William&lt;/a&gt;, for a great number of translations into Chinese Traditional.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Would you like to help out with translations yourself? Then take a look at our &lt;a href="https://www.openproject.org/docs/release-notes/16-1-0/../../contributions-guide/translate-openproject/"&gt;translation guide&lt;/a&gt; and find out exactly how you can contribute. It is very much appreciated!&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/opf/openproject/releases/tag/v16.1.0" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/opf/openproject/releases/tag/v16.1.1</id>
    <title>New release for OpenProject: OpenProject 16.1.1</title>
    <updated>2025-06-26T06:02:04-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>opf/openproject</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;Release date: 2025-06-26&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We released OpenProject &lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/versions/2206"&gt;OpenProject 16.1.1&lt;/a&gt;.
The release contains several bug fixes and we recommend updating to the newest version.
In these Release Notes, we will give an overview of important feature changes.
At the end, you will find a complete list of all changes and bug fixes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Bug fixes and changes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;!-- Warning: Anything within the below lines will be automatically removed by the release script --&gt;
&lt;!-- BEGIN AUTOMATED SECTION --&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bugfix: ActiveRecord::Deadlocked on Attachments::FinishDirectUploadJob#perform leading to lost uploads [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/63380"&gt;#63380&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bugfix: Unclear error message on bulk edit of parent and children wps [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/64203"&gt;#64203&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bugfix: Wrong wording for project phases in system administration [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/64794"&gt;#64794&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bugfix: Edited reminder is not working (not reminding at the selected time and date) [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/64971"&gt;#64971&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bugfix: Error 500 when making a predecessor with children a child of its successor [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/64973"&gt;#64973&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bugfix: Rendering and Server Error when managing a Custom Action with a multi-select user custom field. [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/64981"&gt;#64981&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bugfix: ActiveRecord::RecordNotUnique (app/services/journals/create_service.rb:99 in block in Journals::CreateService#create_journal) [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/65009"&gt;#65009&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bugfix: SystemStackError in WorkPackage::SchedulingRules#schedule_automatically? [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/65062"&gt;#65062&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bugfix: OIDC does not forward to end_session_endpoint as configured [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/65076"&gt;#65076&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bugfix: Inline comment attachments are not linked to the comment when submit is via API [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/65077"&gt;#65077&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bugfix: create_meeting_minutes was never renamed to manage_outcomes [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/65081"&gt;#65081&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;!-- END AUTOMATED SECTION --&gt;
&lt;!-- Warning: Anything above this line will be automatically removed by the release script --&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/opf/openproject/releases/tag/v16.1.1" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
