<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://selfh.st/apps</id>
  <title>OpenProject Releases</title>
  <updated>2025-08-07T22:36:44.615439-04:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>selfh.st</name>
    <email>contact@selfh.st</email>
  </author>
  <link href="https://selfh.st/apps" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>Self-hosted software releases generated by selfh.st</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/opf/openproject/releases/tag/v16.1.0</id>
    <title>New release for OpenProject: OpenProject 16.1.0</title>
    <updated>2025-06-18T03:42:31-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>opf/openproject</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;Release date: 2025-06-18&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We released &lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/versions/2194"&gt;OpenProject 16.1.0&lt;/a&gt;. The release contains several bug fixes and we recommend updating to the newest version. In these Release Notes, we will give an overview of important feature changes and important technical changes. At the end, you will find a complete list of all changes and bug fixes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Important feature changes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Structure the project life cycle with phases and phase gates&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OpenProject 16.1 introduces a powerful new way to reflect your project’s structure over time: using project phases like &lt;strong&gt;Initiating, Planning, Executing, and Closing&lt;/strong&gt;, with optional phase gates at the start or end of each phase.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Project administrators can now &lt;strong&gt;activate relevant phases and phase gates per project&lt;/strong&gt;. Portfolio managers can then assign start and finish dates to each phase, with automatic scheduling of all following phases and phase gates based on working days. This helps reduce manual effort and keeps your project timelines consistent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Work packages can be assigned to a specific phase, making it easier to understand their context, filter by phase, and group work in the table view. And in the project list, you can use columns and new filters to track which projects are currently in which phase or gate – ideal for portfolio level planning and reporting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You’ll find the full life cycle directly in the project overview page, where you can enter dates, view the current phase, and access the new scheduling tools at a glance:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Project overview page with the project life cycle displayed in the right column" src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/opf/openproject/release/16.1/docs/release-notes/16-1-0/openproject-16-1-project-life-cycle-project-overview-highlighted.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[!NOTE]
With the Enterprise add-on available in the Premium plan or higher, you can configure existing project phases and phase gates and even create new ones. This is done in the global settings. The project-level features are available in all editions, with pre-defined phases based on the &lt;a href="https://www.openproject.org/pm2/"&gt;open source PM² framework&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.openproject.org/docs/release-notes/16-1-0/../../system-admin-guide/projects/project-life-cycle/"&gt;Read more about working with a project life cycle in OpenProject&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Export meetings in PDF format&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the most upvoted Community requests is now available: You can now &lt;strong&gt;export meetings as PDF documents&lt;/strong&gt; in OpenProject.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meeting organizers and participants can generate a printable PDF that includes the agenda, outcomes, participants, and more. This makes it ideal for sharing with colleagues, archiving meeting records, or informing stakeholders who could not attend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The export is available via the More (⋯) menu for both one-time meetings and individual occurrences of recurring meetings. You can &lt;strong&gt;customize the PDF&lt;/strong&gt; before download by choosing wheather to include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the list of participants,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the list of attachments,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the backlog,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the agenda outcomes,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a customized footer text (e.g. project name), which appears on each page.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The PDF is generated in A4 format and includes a clearly structured layout. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.openproject.org/docs/release-notes/16-1-0/../../user-guide/meetings/one-time-meetings/#export-a-meeting"&gt;Learn more about exporting meetings in PDF format in our documentation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Overlay of Export PDF options for OpenProject meetings" src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/opf/openproject/release/16.1/docs/release-notes/16-1-0/openproject-16-1-export-meeting-to-pdf.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Set smart default options for reminders&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We released work package reminders with OpenProject 15.2 in January 2025. With this update, it’s easier than ever to use them to stay organized and keep your notification center clean.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To make setting reminders even quicker, OpenProject now offers pre-filled options when clicking the reminder icon on a work package. Instead of entering details manually, you can now choose one of the following defaults:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tomorrow&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In 3 days&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In a week&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In a month&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;At a particular date/time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Selecting one of the quick options will open the reminder dialog with a pre-filled date and time – typically at 9:00 local time on the selected future day. You can still adjust the date, time, and add a note before saving the reminder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.openproject.org/docs/release-notes/16-1-0/../../user-guide/work-packages/edit-work-package/#work-package-reminders"&gt;Learn more about work package reminders in our documentation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Dropdown menu on a work package when clicking on the reminder icon, with options to quickly choose a date to be reminded" src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/opf/openproject/release/16.1/docs/release-notes/16-1-0/openproject-16-1-reminder-options.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Use negative lag for work package dates&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can now define &lt;strong&gt;negative lag&lt;/strong&gt; when setting up relations between work packages. This allows you to specify that a work package should start a few days before its &lt;strong&gt;predecessor&lt;/strong&gt; finishes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When adding or editing a successor or predecessor relation, the Lag field now accepts negative values. The updated help text reads: “The minimum number of working days in between the two work packages. It can also be negative.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This makes it easier to represent overlapping tasks and more flexible schedules in your project plan. For example, you may want the review of a document to begin two days before the final draft is complete. You will then have to enter a lag of -3 days for the (review) Successor work package.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Overlay of editing a successor (after) with a lag of -3 days" src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/opf/openproject/release/16.1/docs/release-notes/16-1-0/openproject-16-1-negative-lag.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please note that negative lags can be counterintuitive:
- A lag of 0 schedules the successor one day after the predecessor’s finish date.
- A lag of -1 schedules it on the same day.
- A lag of -2 schedules it one day before, and so on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[!NOTE]
&lt;strong&gt;Only working days&lt;/strong&gt; are taken into account. For example: If work package A finishes on a Tuesday and Saturday/Sunday are non-working days, then a lag of -3 will schedule its successor (work package B) to start on the previous Friday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.openproject.org/docs/release-notes/16-1-0/../../user-guide/work-packages/work-package-relations-hierarchies/#work-package-relations"&gt;Learn more about work package relations in our documentation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Display hierarchy trees for hierarchy custom fields (Enterprise add-on)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hierarchy custom fields are now easier to explore and use. When viewing such a custom field, a &lt;strong&gt;hierarchical tree is displayed next to the details section&lt;/strong&gt;, showing the entire structure at a glance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This tree helps you understand the position of the current item in the overall hierarchy and makes it easier to add or navigate related items. The currently selected item is highlighted, and all its parent nodes are automatically expanded, while unrelated branches remain collapsed by default.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clicking on any entry in the tree opens that item in the same view, making it easy to move through even complex hierarchies without losing context.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.openproject.org/docs/release-notes/16-1-0/../../system-admin-guide/custom-fields/"&gt;Learn more about custom fields in our system admin guide&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Example of a hierarchy custom field with the new visualization, the hierarchical tree" src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/opf/openproject/release/16.1/docs/release-notes/16-1-0/openproject-hierarchy-custom-field-tree.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Benefit from improved accessibility for the date picker with ARIA live regions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OpenProject 16.1 includes an important accessibility enhancement for users working with screen readers: Dynamic updates are now announced automatically using ARIA live regions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This applies to &lt;strong&gt;changes in the date picker&lt;/strong&gt; such as scheduling mode, working days only selector, start and finish dates, and duration. When one of these values is updated, the screen reader will announce a full summary like: “Date picker updated. Scheduling mode: Manual, Working days only, Start date: June 10, Finish date: June 12, Duration: 3 days”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This ensures that no important context is lost and improves the experience for all users relying on assistive technologies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To learn what more is planned regarding accessibility in OpenProject, see &lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/projects/openproject/work_packages?query_id=2906"&gt;these open work packages on our Community instance&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Important technical changes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Added API for emoji reactions, reminders, and internal comments&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OpenProject 16.1 extends its API to support three features that were previously only available via the web interface. This update enables integrations with other clients to access:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Emoji reactions on work package comments&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reminders for work packages&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Internal comments with restricted visibility&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Developers can now read and manage emoji reactions, create and update reminders, and write internal comments via API V3.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Bug fixes and changes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;!-- Warning: Anything within the below lines will be automatically removed by the release script --&gt;
&lt;!-- BEGIN AUTOMATED SECTION --&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Feature: Extend API V3 to cover Emoji reactions on work package comments (read, toggle) and extend documentation [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/57265"&gt;#57265&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Feature: Allow users to enter negative lag [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/58011"&gt;#58011&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Feature: Fixed set of project phases and gates editable on project overview page [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/58159"&gt;#58159&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Feature: Project phase columns on project list [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/58160"&gt;#58160&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Feature: Global phase administration [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/58161"&gt;#58161&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Feature: Phases as work package attribute [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/58162"&gt;#58162&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Feature: Project specific phase administration [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/58163"&gt;#58163&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Feature: Journalize changes to phases and gates [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/59178"&gt;#59178&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Feature: Option to copy phase on copying a project [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/59179"&gt;#59179&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Feature: Automatic scheduling for phases and phase gates [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/59180"&gt;#59180&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Feature: Filters for phases and phase gates in project list [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/59183"&gt;#59183&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Feature: Order by phases and phase gates on project list [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/59184"&gt;#59184&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Feature: Extend Reminders API V3 to include create, update &amp;amp; delete operations [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/59473"&gt;#59473&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Feature: Optimize life cycle modal UX [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/60330"&gt;#60330&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Feature: Document and implement proper mobile behaviour for Sub Header component (OP Primer) [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/60332"&gt;#60332&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Feature: Reminders: Offer quick-set options like &amp;#39;tomorrow&amp;#39; or &amp;#39;next week&amp;#39; with smart defaults [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/60357"&gt;#60357&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Feature: PDF export of meetings [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/60730"&gt;#60730&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Feature: Date picker to edit phases and phase gates of a project life cycle [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/61610"&gt;#61610&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Feature: Turn gates into property of phase (rename life cycle elements to &amp;quot;Phase&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;Phase gates&amp;quot;) [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/61952"&gt;#61952&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Feature: Add hovercard to gates [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/62608"&gt;#62608&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Feature: TreeView Primer View Component [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/62667"&gt;#62667&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Feature: Implementing ARIA live regions to communicate contextual changes [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/62708"&gt;#62708&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Feature: Show a TreeView on the page of hierachy customFields [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/62993"&gt;#62993&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Feature: Show attribute help texts in Primerized Project Settings &amp;gt; Information form [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/63737"&gt;#63737&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Feature: Primerize attribute help texts [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/63738"&gt;#63738&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Feature: Re-order and re-structure the &amp;#39;More&amp;#39; action menu for sections and agenda items [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/64074"&gt;#64074&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Feature: Configure scopes to be used during Token Exchange [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/64121"&gt;#64121&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Feature: [TreeView] Allow nodes to be anchors or buttons [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/64132"&gt;#64132&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Feature: Add work package internal comments (write) API [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/64166"&gt;#64166&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Feature: [TreeView] Bubble the expanded state from children to parents [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/64215"&gt;#64215&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Feature: Meeting PDF export: show if users are invited or attended [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/64565"&gt;#64565&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Feature: Differentiate between meeting agenda and meeting minutes in pdf export [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/64793"&gt;#64793&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Feature: Meeting PDF export: Refinement [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/64828"&gt;#64828&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bugfix: Project search is under the Search icon in New Recurring Meeting modal [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/59945"&gt;#59945&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bugfix: User can&amp;#39;t save lifecycle modal if project is invalid [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/60666"&gt;#60666&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bugfix: Activity Tab renders the same turbo frame multiple times inside of itself [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/61544"&gt;#61544&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bugfix: The &amp;#39;overdue&amp;#39; date colour does not adapt well to dark mode (fixed hex/odd colour variable) [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/62199"&gt;#62199&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bugfix: Seeder fails during upgrade with ArgumentError: Nothing registered with reference :default_role_project_admin (ArgumentError) [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/62582"&gt;#62582&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bugfix: (Regression) Error on Save (in various places) [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/62627"&gt;#62627&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bugfix: Reminders: saving without entering a date or time throws an error but also unnecessarily clears the other field [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/63461"&gt;#63461&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bugfix: ArgumentError in seeder [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/63826"&gt;#63826&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bugfix: ActiveRecord::RecordNotUnique in POST::API::V3::TimeEntries::TimeEntriesAPI#/time_entries [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/63839"&gt;#63839&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bugfix: Projects tab displayed for custom fields of type user, group, spent time and version [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/63900"&gt;#63900&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bugfix: Back arrow cannot be reached via keyboard [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/64222"&gt;#64222&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bugfix: Project overview page renders an h2 inside an h3 [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/64226"&gt;#64226&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bugfix: [Accessibility] Editable toolbar header is not recognized as headline by screenreaders [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/64227"&gt;#64227&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bugfix: Home screen widgets have the wrong headline tag [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/64228"&gt;#64228&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bugfix: Focus issues with WP primary button [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/64236"&gt;#64236&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bugfix: Access tokens of disabled OAuth applications are accepted by API [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/64258"&gt;#64258&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bugfix: Disabling an incomplete phase leads to inconsistencies [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/64292"&gt;#64292&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bugfix: Input fields suggest previously entered text [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/64312"&gt;#64312&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bugfix: The time in the pdf export is different from the time in the file name [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/64337"&gt;#64337&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bugfix: No updated path to 16.0.0 package source in manual  [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/64362"&gt;#64362&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bugfix: Checkbox label not clickable in 2FA settings [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/64367"&gt;#64367&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bugfix: Work packages &amp;quot;default&amp;quot; priority is lost when deleted. [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/64369"&gt;#64369&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bugfix: Attribute help text page is missing a page title [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/64417"&gt;#64417&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bugfix: The second phase&amp;#39;s start date selection is not enabled [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/64496"&gt;#64496&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bugfix: OpenProject 16.0.1: Error 500 when clicking on a revision link in a repository [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/64508"&gt;#64508&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bugfix: NoMethodError during Meetings::ExportJob [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/64510"&gt;#64510&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bugfix: The following phase&amp;#39;s finish date is inconsistent with the start date [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/64532"&gt;#64532&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bugfix: My time tracking has two dividers in the PageHeader [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/64573"&gt;#64573&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bugfix: Cannot switch back from Manual to Automatic scheduling on milestone successor [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/64603"&gt;#64603&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bugfix: Clearing the start date of a following phase is not possible [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/64628"&gt;#64628&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bugfix: Seeding error when seeding a second time with a different language [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/64711"&gt;#64711&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bugfix: Nothing registered with reference :default_color_green_light [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/64811"&gt;#64811&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bugfix: Attachments delete confirmation dialog opens behind attribute help text dialog [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/64831"&gt;#64831&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bugfix: Incorrect rescheduling after non working days are changed [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/64836"&gt;#64836&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bugfix: Error banners persist on page reload on Project Settings &amp;gt; Information form [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/64839"&gt;#64839&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bugfix: Attribute help text links for widgets on Projects Overview page lack padding [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/64846"&gt;#64846&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bugfix: Update working days settings warning messages to include phases [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/64855"&gt;#64855&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Feature: Add API for recent Communicator features (Emoji, Reminders, Internal Comments) [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/62507"&gt;#62507&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;!-- END AUTOMATED SECTION --&gt;
&lt;!-- Warning: Anything above this line will be automatically removed by the release script --&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Contributions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A very special thank you goes to City of Cologne, Deutsche Bahn and ZenDiS for sponsoring released or upcoming features. Your support, alongside the efforts of our amazing Community, helps drive these innovations. Also a big thanks to our Community members for reporting bugs and helping us identify and provide fixes. Special thanks for reporting and finding bugs go to Cameron Dutro and Maxim Béliveau.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last but not least, we are very grateful for our very engaged translation contributors on Crowdin, who translated quite a few OpenProject strings! This release we would like to particularly thank the following users:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://crowdin.com/profile/bigseung"&gt;BigSeung&lt;/a&gt;, for a great number of translations into Korean.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://crowdin.com/profile/rmiyata"&gt;rmiyata&lt;/a&gt;, for a great number of translations into Japanese.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://crowdin.com/profile/williamfromtw"&gt;William&lt;/a&gt;, for a great number of translations into Chinese Traditional.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Would you like to help out with translations yourself? Then take a look at our &lt;a href="https://www.openproject.org/docs/release-notes/16-1-0/../../contributions-guide/translate-openproject/"&gt;translation guide&lt;/a&gt; and find out exactly how you can contribute. It is very much appreciated!&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/opf/openproject/releases/tag/v16.1.0" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/opf/openproject/releases/tag/v16.1.1</id>
    <title>New release for OpenProject: OpenProject 16.1.1</title>
    <updated>2025-06-26T06:02:04-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>opf/openproject</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;Release date: 2025-06-26&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We released OpenProject &lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/versions/2206"&gt;OpenProject 16.1.1&lt;/a&gt;.
The release contains several bug fixes and we recommend updating to the newest version.
In these Release Notes, we will give an overview of important feature changes.
At the end, you will find a complete list of all changes and bug fixes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Bug fixes and changes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;!-- Warning: Anything within the below lines will be automatically removed by the release script --&gt;
&lt;!-- BEGIN AUTOMATED SECTION --&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bugfix: ActiveRecord::Deadlocked on Attachments::FinishDirectUploadJob#perform leading to lost uploads [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/63380"&gt;#63380&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bugfix: Unclear error message on bulk edit of parent and children wps [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/64203"&gt;#64203&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bugfix: Wrong wording for project phases in system administration [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/64794"&gt;#64794&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bugfix: Edited reminder is not working (not reminding at the selected time and date) [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/64971"&gt;#64971&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bugfix: Error 500 when making a predecessor with children a child of its successor [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/64973"&gt;#64973&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bugfix: Rendering and Server Error when managing a Custom Action with a multi-select user custom field. [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/64981"&gt;#64981&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bugfix: ActiveRecord::RecordNotUnique (app/services/journals/create_service.rb:99 in block in Journals::CreateService#create_journal) [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/65009"&gt;#65009&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bugfix: SystemStackError in WorkPackage::SchedulingRules#schedule_automatically? [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/65062"&gt;#65062&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bugfix: OIDC does not forward to end_session_endpoint as configured [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/65076"&gt;#65076&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bugfix: Inline comment attachments are not linked to the comment when submit is via API [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/65077"&gt;#65077&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bugfix: create_meeting_minutes was never renamed to manage_outcomes [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/65081"&gt;#65081&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;!-- END AUTOMATED SECTION --&gt;
&lt;!-- Warning: Anything above this line will be automatically removed by the release script --&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/opf/openproject/releases/tag/v16.1.1" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/opf/openproject/releases/tag/v16.2.0</id>
    <title>New release for OpenProject: OpenProject 16.2.0</title>
    <updated>2025-07-16T04:32:26-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>opf/openproject</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;Release date: 2025-07-16&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We released &lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/versions/2196"&gt;OpenProject 16.2.0&lt;/a&gt;. The release contains several bug fixes and we recommend updating to the newest version. In these Release Notes, we will give an overview of important feature changes and important technical changes. At the end, you will find a complete list of all changes and bug fixes. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Important feature changes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take a look at our release video showing the most important features introduced in OpenProject 16.2.0:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://openproject-docs.s3.eu-central-1.amazonaws.com/videos/OpenProject_16_2_release.mp4"&gt;Release video of OpenProject 16.2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;New header and sidebar with improved navigation and design&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OpenProject 16.2 introduces a redesigned header and sidebar that make navigating your projects noticeably easier. The sidebar toggle (hamburger icon) has moved inside the sidebar itself, the default sidebar color in light mode is now lighter and more modern, and the search and create buttons have been repositioned in the top bar for a more intuitive workflow. Together, these changes create a cleaner, more focused interface that helps you find what you need faster and align with the user interface used in &lt;a href="https://www.openproject.org/opendesk/"&gt;openDesk&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="OpenProject Home page with the new header and sidebar navigation and design" src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/opf/openproject/release/16.2/docs/release-notes/16-2-0/openproject-16-2-design-updates.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please note that if you have customized the sidebar colors, your individual settings will remain unchanged.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Primer design system added to project create and project copy forms&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The forms for &lt;a href="https://www.openproject.org/docs/release-notes/16-2-0/../../getting-started/projects/#create-a-new-project"&gt;creating and copying projects&lt;/a&gt; now use the &lt;a href="https://www.openproject.org/blog/primer-design-system/"&gt;Primer design system&lt;/a&gt;, providing a cleaner and more consistent interface. This improves accessibility and ensures the process remains just as familiar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you &lt;strong&gt;copy&lt;/strong&gt; a project or create a project &lt;strong&gt;based on a template&lt;/strong&gt;, you will immediately be able to choose which modules and parts you want to copy and which to skip. Also, the option to activate sending email notifications during the project copy is much more visible. Before 16.2, you had to click on Copy Options to unfold.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="OpenProject screenshot: Create new project, with options to choose what to copy from a template" src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/opf/openproject/release/16.2/docs/release-notes/16-2-0/openproject-16-2-create-project.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Non-Latin languages and emojis supported in PDF exports for work packages&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PDF work package exports in OpenProject now support &lt;strong&gt;non-Latin characters and emojis&lt;/strong&gt;. This means that project information written in scripts such as Chinese, Arabic, Cyrillic, or accented characters — as well as any emojis you use in work packages, meetings, or descriptions — will display correctly in exported PDF files. This ensures that documents generated from OpenProject reflect your content accurately, no matter which language or symbols you use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.openproject.org/docs/release-notes/16-2-0/../../user-guide/work-packages/exporting/"&gt;Read more about work package PDF exports with OpenProject&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="PDF export extract from an OpenProject work package that contains emojis, symbols and non-Latin characters" src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/opf/openproject/release/16.2/docs/release-notes/16-2-0/openproject-16-2-pdf-export.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please note that the screenshot only displays some of the now supported characters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Second level navigation for Relations create menu&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The + Relation menu has been reorganized with a new two-level structure, making it clearer and easier to navigate. The most common relations like &lt;strong&gt;Related to&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Predecessor&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Successor&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;(New) Child&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;Parent&lt;/strong&gt; are now shown directly, while less frequently used options such as Duplicates, Blocks, or Requires are grouped under Other relations. This helps you see the primary choices at a glance and keep your work package relations more structured.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="OpenProject work package Relations tab when clicking on +Relation, showing some relations unfolded under 'Other relations'" src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/opf/openproject/release/16.2/docs/release-notes/16-2-0/openproject-user-guide-relations-second-level-navigation.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.openproject.org/docs/release-notes/16-2-0/../../user-guide/work-packages/work-package-relations-hierarchies/"&gt;Read more about relations in OpenProject&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Select formats for custom fields and project attributes earlier in creation process&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When creating a new custom field, you can now select the format — such as text, list, or date — right at the beginning, on the index page of custom fields and project attributes. The same applies to project attributes. This streamlines the creation process and avoids unnecessary steps, since each type opens directly in the appropriate form. This improvement is especially helpful for administrators who frequently set up new custom fields or project attributes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read more about how to manage &lt;a href="https://www.openproject.org/docs/release-notes/16-2-0/../../system-admin-guide/custom-fields/"&gt;custom fields&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.openproject.org/docs/release-notes/16-2-0/../../user-guide/projects/project-settings/project-attributes/"&gt;project attributes&lt;/a&gt; in OpenProject.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="OpenProject administration to add a new custom field: Dropdown lets you choose the type during the first step" src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/opf/openproject/release/16.2/docs/release-notes/16-2-0/openproject-16-2-custom-field-type.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;My time tracking: Collapse future days for week and work week views&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the &lt;strong&gt;My time tracking&lt;/strong&gt; module, the week and work week views now automatically collapse future and past days while keeping today expanded. This helps you focus on logging time for the current and past days without being distracted by empty future slots. If you view a past week, all days are expanded as before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[!TIP]
Don't know the My time tracking module yet? We released it with &lt;a href="https://www.openproject.org/docs/release-notes/16-2-0/../../release-notes/16-0-0/"&gt;OpenProject 16.0.0&lt;/a&gt;. This module shows individual time entries in a calendar or list view, and is very helpful if you use start and end times for your time tracking. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="OpenProject's My time tracking module in list view, only Today expanded" src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/opf/openproject/release/16.2/docs/release-notes/16-2-0/user-guide-my-time-tracking-module-list-view.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.openproject.org/docs/release-notes/16-2-0/../../user-guide/time-and-costs/my-time-tracking/"&gt;Learn more about the My time tracking module in our documentation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Option to disable keyboard shortcuts for better accessibility&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OpenProject 16.2 makes the application more accessible by allowing users to &lt;strong&gt;disable keyboard shortcuts&lt;/strong&gt;. This is especially helpful for people using assistive technologies, where keyboard shortcuts might interfere with screen readers or other tools. The option can be found under &lt;em&gt;Account settings → Interface&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="OpenProject account settings on interface options, with highlighted option to disable keyboard shortcuts" src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/opf/openproject/release/16.2/docs/release-notes/16-2-0/openproject-user-guide-account-settings-interface.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Work package reminders presented in relative humanized time format&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you set a reminder for a work package, OpenProject now confirms this with a &lt;strong&gt;relative, human-friendly time&lt;/strong&gt;. Instead of just showing a fixed date and time, the success message will say, for example, &lt;em&gt;“Reminder set successfully. You will receive a notification for this work package tomorrow.”&lt;/em&gt; This small improvement makes it easier to quickly understand when your reminder will appear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="User information that appears when setting a reminder: Reminder set successfully. You will receive a notification for this work package tomorrow." src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/opf/openproject/release/16.2/docs/release-notes/16-2-0/openproject-16-2-reminder.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.openproject.org/docs/release-notes/16-2-0/../../user-guide/work-packages/edit-work-package/#work-package-reminders"&gt;Learn more about work package reminders in OpenProject&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Important technical changes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;SCIM server functionality added to OpenProject via SCIM API (Enterprise add-on)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OpenProject 16.2 adds a &lt;strong&gt;SCIM server API&lt;/strong&gt;, available as an Enterprise add-on in the Corporate plan. This allows Identity Providers (IdPs) such as Keycloak to keep user data in OpenProject synchronized automatically. Administrators can manage SCIM clients directly in OpenProject, configure authentication methods, and revoke tokens when needed. This makes it much easier to maintain consistent user records across your systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="OpenProject administration with option to add a new SCIM client" src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/opf/openproject/release/16.2/docs/release-notes/16-2-0/openproject-16-2-scim-api.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.openproject.org/docs/release-notes/16-2-0/../../system-admin-guide/authentication/"&gt;Learn more about authentication methods with OpenProject&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;API support for internal comments&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The API has been extended to fully support &lt;strong&gt;internal comments on work packages&lt;/strong&gt;. You can now check via the Capabilities API whether a user can create, view, or edit internal comments. This helps external apps and integrations, such as mobile clients, support internal team discussions securely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Commenting on work packages fires a webhook&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When a comment is added to a work package, it now triggers a webhook. This enables external systems to react in real time to comments in OpenProject, for example by updating dashboards or notifying integrated tools. &lt;a href="https://www.openproject.org/docs/release-notes/16-2-0/../../system-admin-guide/api-and-webhooks/#webhooks"&gt;See our system admin guide to learn more about webhooks for OpenProject&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Bug fixes and changes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;!-- Warning: Anything within the below lines will be automatically removed by the release script --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(ng) implementations [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/65824"&gt;#65824&lt;/a&gt;]
- Bugfix: Managing group membership does not work in Keycloak plugin setup. [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/65855"&gt;#65855&lt;/a&gt;]
- Bugfix: IFC conversion failing in helm installation (regression from 16.0) [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/65872"&gt;#65872&lt;/a&gt;]
- Feature: PDF Export: Support non-latin languages and emojis [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/52082"&gt;#52082&lt;/a&gt;]
- Feature: Add SCIM server API  [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/62107"&gt;#62107&lt;/a&gt;]
- Feature: Accept client credentials token issued by OIDC IDP [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/62301"&gt;#62301&lt;/a&gt;]
- Feature: Allow multiple enterprise tokens to be present [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/62493"&gt;#62493&lt;/a&gt;]
- Feature: Allow managing SCIM clients [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/62516"&gt;#62516&lt;/a&gt;]
- Feature: Add authentication to SCIM server API [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/62592"&gt;#62592&lt;/a&gt;]
- Feature: Multi-level Action Menu Primer View Component [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/62976"&gt;#62976&lt;/a&gt;]
- Feature: Primerize Project create form [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/63593"&gt;#63593&lt;/a&gt;]
- Feature: Primerise project copy form [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/63594"&gt;#63594&lt;/a&gt;]
- Feature: PDF Export: Minor design changes in contract template [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/63609"&gt;#63609&lt;/a&gt;]
- Feature: Move hamburger sidebar toggle from main navigation to sidebar [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/63811"&gt;#63811&lt;/a&gt;]
- Feature: Updated enterprise banner for automatic subject configuration [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/63873"&gt;#63873&lt;/a&gt;]
- Feature: Preserve user external accounts data [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/63912"&gt;#63912&lt;/a&gt;]
- Feature: Add notification / banner to Enterprise features during trial to communicate which plan they are included in [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/64005"&gt;#64005&lt;/a&gt;]
- Feature: Commenting on work packages fires a webhook [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/64129"&gt;#64129&lt;/a&gt;]
- Feature: Allow partial updates on work package type [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/64220"&gt;#64220&lt;/a&gt;]
- Feature: Introduce account setting to disable keyboard shortcuts (for accessibility) [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/64234"&gt;#64234&lt;/a&gt;]
- Feature: Use second level navigation for Relations create menu [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/64377"&gt;#64377&lt;/a&gt;]
- Feature: Moving spike for replacing CKEditor 5 with BlockNoteJS into dev branch and behind a feature flag [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/64507"&gt;#64507&lt;/a&gt;]
- Feature: My time tracking: Collapse future days for week and work week views [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/64549"&gt;#64549&lt;/a&gt;]
- Feature: Add internal comments to capabilities API [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/64694"&gt;#64694&lt;/a&gt;]
- Feature: Reminders: Upon setting a work package reminder, present the reminder time in relative humanized format [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/64695"&gt;#64695&lt;/a&gt;]
- Feature: Select custom field format at the index page of custom fields &amp;amp; project attributes [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/64800"&gt;#64800&lt;/a&gt;]
- Feature: Make OpenProject the organizer of the meeting [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/64849"&gt;#64849&lt;/a&gt;]
- Feature: Reorganise Primerized project copy, create forms; Improve copy options display [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/65026"&gt;#65026&lt;/a&gt;]
- Feature: Change default color of sidebar in light mode [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/65091"&gt;#65091&lt;/a&gt;]
- Feature: Change position of search and create button in top bar [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/65324"&gt;#65324&lt;/a&gt;]
- Feature: Limit access to SCIM clients UI to enterprise customers [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/65339"&gt;#65339&lt;/a&gt;]
- Feature: Add SCIM server functionality to OpenProject via SCIM API [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/55941"&gt;#55941&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- END AUTOMATED SECTION --&gt;
&lt;!-- Warning: Anything above this line will be automatically removed by the release script --&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Contributions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A very special thank you goes to City of Cologne, Deutsche Bahn and ZenDiS for sponsoring released or upcoming features. Your support, alongside the efforts of our amazing Community, helps drive these innovations. Also a big thanks to our Community members for reporting bugs and helping us identify and provide fixes. Special thanks for reporting and finding bugs go to Michael Lathion, Jason Culligan, Sven Kunze, and Gábor Alexovics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last but not least, we are very grateful for our very engaged translation contributors on Crowdin, who translated quite a few OpenProject strings! This release we would like to particularly thank the following users:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://crowdin.com/profile/williamfromtw"&gt;William&lt;/a&gt;, for a great number of translations into Chinese Traditional.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://crowdin.com/profile/rmiyata"&gt;rmiyata&lt;/a&gt;, for a great number of translations into Japanese.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://crowdin.com/profile/rubenpedrolopez"&gt;rubenpedrolopez&lt;/a&gt;, for a great number of translations into Spanish.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Would you like to help out with translations yourself? Then take a look at our &lt;a href="https://www.openproject.org/docs/release-notes/16-2-0/../../contributions-guide/translate-openproject/"&gt;translation guide&lt;/a&gt; and find out exactly how you can contribute. It is very much appreciated!&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/opf/openproject/releases/tag/v16.2.0" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/opf/openproject/releases/tag/v16.2.1</id>
    <title>New release for OpenProject: OpenProject 16.2.1</title>
    <updated>2025-08-04T10:12:33-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>opf/openproject</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;Release date: 2025-08-04&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We released OpenProject &lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/versions/2212"&gt;OpenProject 16.2.1&lt;/a&gt;.
The release contains several bug fixes and we recommend updating to the newest version.
In these Release Notes, we will give an overview of important feature changes.
At the end, you will find a complete list of all changes and bug fixes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Bug fixes and changes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;!-- Warning: Anything within the below lines will be automatically removed by the release script --&gt;
&lt;!-- BEGIN AUTOMATED SECTION --&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bugfix: Checked checkboxes in Primer components have wrong border color when choosing an accent color [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/65361"&gt;#65361&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bugfix: Auth providers registered via the AuthPlugin API (register_auth_providers) broken with 16.2 provider link changes [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/65892"&gt;#65892&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bugfix: ActionView::Template::Error in HomescreenController#index [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/65925"&gt;#65925&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bugfix: Impossible to change the left-side menu colour [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/65926"&gt;#65926&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bugfix: OIDC attribute mapping not working for email, first name, last name [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/66242"&gt;#66242&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;!-- END AUTOMATED SECTION --&gt;
&lt;!-- Warning: Anything above this line will be automatically removed by the release script --&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/opf/openproject/releases/tag/v16.2.1" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/opf/openproject/releases/tag/v16.2.2</id>
    <title>New release for OpenProject: OpenProject 16.2.2</title>
    <updated>2025-08-07T07:13:26-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>opf/openproject</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;Release date: 2025-08-07&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We released OpenProject &lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/versions/2217"&gt;OpenProject 16.2.2&lt;/a&gt;.
The release contains several bug fixes and we recommend updating to the newest version.
In these Release Notes, we will give an overview of important feature changes.
At the end, you will find a complete list of all changes and bug fixes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Bug fixes and changes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;!-- Warning: Anything within the below lines will be automatically removed by the release script --&gt;
&lt;!-- BEGIN AUTOMATED SECTION --&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bugfix: Keycloak OIDC login doesn&amp;#39;t work since update to 16.2.1 [&lt;a href="https://community.openproject.org/wp/66432"&gt;#66432&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;!-- END AUTOMATED SECTION --&gt;
&lt;!-- Warning: Anything above this line will be automatically removed by the release script --&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Contributions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A big thanks to our Community members for reporting bugs and helping us identify and provide fixes.
This release, special thanks for reporting and finding bugs go to Stefan Weiberg.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/opf/openproject/releases/tag/v16.2.2" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
