<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://selfh.st/apps</id>
  <title>Outline Releases</title>
  <updated>2024-08-07T07:31:07.633895-04:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>selfh.st</name>
    <email>contact@selfh.st</email>
  </author>
  <link href="https://selfh.st/apps" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>Self-hosted software releases generated by selfh.st</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/outline/outline/releases/tag/v0.77.0</id>
    <title>New release for Outline: v0.77.0</title>
    <updated>2024-06-13T15:43:00-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>outline/outline</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[!WARNING]&lt;br /&gt;
This release regressed support for ARM processors due to an AWS SDK dependency upgrade, skip straight to v0.77.1 or greater for those on ARM architecture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What's Changed&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This release changes how documents are rendered, allowing the introduction of new editor functionality and attributes. Highlighted for this release are some big improvements to tables:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="https://github.com/outline/outline/assets/380914/6109e4a5-fc5a-4a25-ae33-eebbe9adc0db" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Column resizing:&lt;/strong&gt; You can now resize columns by dragging the border between them&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Full-width tables:&lt;/strong&gt; Tables now expand to the full width of the editor&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;More content:&lt;/strong&gt; Table cells now support embeds, code blocks, and all other content types&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Toggleable headers:&lt;/strong&gt; You can now toggle a header row and column&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Improved overflow:&lt;/strong&gt; Tables now scroll horizontally when they're too wide for the editor&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Improved row and column controls&lt;/strong&gt;: We've made it one click to add rows and columns&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Other improvements&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added more highlighter color choices in https://github.com/outline/outline/pull/7012&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New collection permissions UI in https://github.com/outline/outline/pull/6917&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Big rendering performance improvements for documents with many images&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add &lt;code&gt;Manage&lt;/code&gt; permission to documents allows other users to manage sharing in https://github.com/outline/outline/pull/7003&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added an embedded Yandex Maps component by @shashinma in https://github.com/outline/outline/pull/6881&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added a permission selector in document/collection invite flow in https://github.com/outline/outline/pull/6948&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added support for embedded youtube clips by @Pranav2612000 in https://github.com/outline/outline/pull/6942&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Matomo integration in https://github.com/outline/outline/pull/7009&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;/&lt;/code&gt; block insert shortcut now works anywhere on a line or table in https://github.com/outline/outline/pull/7026&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added the ability to remove a previously uploaded team logo or profile picture&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added a menu option to create template directly in collection&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Fixes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Various fixes to improve the fluidity of app loading&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Image placeholders are now correctly sized when uploading retina images&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Images and PDF's are now served with inline content disposition in https://github.com/outline/outline/pull/6924&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added support for Figma's new link formats and Figjam boards by @RenderCoder in https://github.com/outline/outline/pull/6946&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;files.get&lt;/code&gt; now supports range header, fixes video loading in Safari in https://github.com/outline/outline/pull/6950&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed an issue where zoomed images could get stuck in https://github.com/outline/outline/pull/6980&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Share button was removed on templates&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed race condition that could result in document emoji not saving&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Removed trust of &lt;code&gt;state.host&lt;/code&gt; in auth error redirect&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Collapsed sidebar now works better in Arc/Edge redesign&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;New Contributors&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;@shashinma made their first contribution in https://github.com/outline/outline/pull/6881&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;@lng2020 made their first contribution in https://github.com/outline/outline/pull/6731&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;@RenderCoder made their first contribution in https://github.com/outline/outline/pull/6946&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;@Frzk made their first contribution in https://github.com/outline/outline/pull/6971&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;@bkrausz made their first contribution in https://github.com/outline/outline/pull/7022&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Full Changelog&lt;/strong&gt;: https://github.com/outline/outline/compare/v0.76.0...v0.77.0&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/outline/outline/releases/tag/v0.77.0" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/outline/outline/releases/tag/v0.77.1</id>
    <title>New release for Outline: v0.77.1</title>
    <updated>2024-06-14T20:44:04-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>outline/outline</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h3&gt;Fixes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Restores ARM architecture compatibility&lt;/strong&gt; (Docker image switched from Alpine -&amp;gt; Debian slim)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed an issue that could cause the app to become unresponsive when zooming out of an image&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Restored the &lt;code&gt;text&lt;/code&gt; field in outgoing document webhooks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Page scroll now resets correctly on mobile when navigating between documents&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tables with a single remaining column now automatically fill available width&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/outline/outline/releases/tag/v0.77.1" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/outline/outline/releases/tag/v0.77.2</id>
    <title>New release for Outline: v0.77.2</title>
    <updated>2024-06-17T22:08:15-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>outline/outline</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h3&gt;Fixes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Restores ability to use IAM roles for S3 storage integration&lt;/strong&gt; (Regressed with SDK upgrade in 0.77.0)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed table attributes in template lost on application&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed PDF's and images now correctly return &lt;code&gt;inline&lt;/code&gt; content disposition on shared docs using local storage strategy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed vertical alignment of document contents&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Escape&lt;/code&gt; correctly closes command menu again when viewing a document or collection&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/outline/outline/releases/tag/v0.77.2" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/outline/outline/releases/tag/v0.77.3</id>
    <title>New release for Outline: v0.77.3</title>
    <updated>2024-07-14T12:19:53-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>outline/outline</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h3&gt;Fixes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Unable to scroll comment sidebar until multiple comments are posted&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Error parsing attachment IDs when node data contains invalid src&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix for type confusion with node attrs (&lt;a href="https://github.com/outline/outline/security/advisories/GHSA-888c-mvg8-v6wh"&gt;CVE-2024-40626&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/outline/outline/releases/tag/v0.77.3" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/outline/outline/releases/tag/v0.78.0</id>
    <title>New release for Outline: v0.78.0</title>
    <updated>2024-07-19T08:39:59-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>outline/outline</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h2&gt;What's Changed&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Comment resolving&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width="737" alt="image" src="https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/31f12e81-61a5-4331-b7a8-6902cbb9dc9e"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's now possible to resolve comment threads on documents from the comment menu. You can always view and restore a document's resolved comments by clicking the checkmark icon at the top right of the sidebar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Icon and emojis&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width="737" alt="image" src="https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/f1956172-09ec-4b72-85f1-b569234eea38"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to @hmacr who put in a ton of work to rebuild our picker interface, you can now select emoji and icons for both document and collection in one unified UI – this finally enables using emoji for collections and icons on documents. We also added even more new icons to choose from in this release.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Discord Authentication&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Discord was added as a fully supported authentication provider plugin. In addition to the regular security controls for email domain you can also configure to restrict logins to a specific Discord server and roles. See more in the &lt;a href="https://docs.getoutline.com/s/hosting/doc/discord-g4JdWFFub6"&gt;documentation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Other improvements&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When creating a document inside a collection it is now published by default (#7243)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A display preference was added to move the table of contents to the right side of documents (#6943)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Users with "Can edit" permission for a document now have the ability to create child documents. This brings the permission inline with the Edit permission on collections (#7257)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Frequently used code block languages are now shown first in the list (#7222)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;AZURE_TENANT_ID&lt;/code&gt; added to allow custom azure tenant (#7028)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Table of contents is now enabled by default on publicly shared docs with headings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Images that cannot load now show an improved broken state in the editor (#7200)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Support for TLDraw viewer links added (#7205)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Users will no longer be prompted to install the PWA on publicly shared docs (#7198)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Collection icon can now be directly updated in the same manner as collection (#7120)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sharing dialog now has keyboard navigation (#7102)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;API keys now display when they were last used (#7082)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;API keys can now have an expiry set (#7064)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Full Swedish 🇸🇪  and Norwegian 🇳🇴 translations were added&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Fixes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Groups added to a collection are no longer always added with &lt;code&gt;read-only&lt;/code&gt; permission&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Admins were unable to see documents shared from another users private collection (#7264)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Collection actions available in command menu after navigating away from a collection (#7241)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"Edit" button and other functionality disappears after unpublishing a document (#7258)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Table insert controls no longer visible in read only mode (#7249)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Document icons are now shown in link search results in the editor&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Image and file upload now works correctly on mobile devices (#7161)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed an issue where the "Archived by" text would temporarily reference the wrong user (#7223)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed an issue with groups not appearing in collection share options&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed an issue where the table of contents last heading would never be highlighted (#7204)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Contrast of search highlighting increased in dark mode&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Text will no longer become selected when resizing sidebars&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CJK document content no longer overflows in search results (#7183)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Whitespace only comments are no longer allowed (#7168)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Duplicating a document no longer loses advanced formatting&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Iframely is now correctly disabled with no API_KEY in env&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reduced false positives for "smart" replacement of fractions in editor (#7141)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed an issue where it was not possible to choose 'No access' as bulk import permission&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Scrollwheel can no longer cause zoomed images to get stuck (#7083)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;New Contributors&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;@sebasptsch made their first contribution in https://github.com/outline/outline/pull/7005&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;@mkrfowler made their first contribution in https://github.com/outline/outline/pull/7061&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;@MnkyArts made their first contribution in https://github.com/outline/outline/pull/7184&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;@airbenich made their first contribution in https://github.com/outline/outline/pull/7028&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;@feingold-ant made their first contribution in https://github.com/outline/outline/pull/7243&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;@guoard made their first contribution in https://github.com/outline/outline/pull/7246&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;@alexislefebvre made their first contribution in https://github.com/outline/outline/pull/7273&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Full Changelog&lt;/strong&gt;: https://github.com/outline/outline/compare/v0.77.3...v0.78.0&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/outline/outline/releases/tag/v0.78.0" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
