<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://selfh.st/apps</id>
  <title>Passbolt Releases</title>
  <updated>2024-06-11T08:32:59.426429-04:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>selfh.st</name>
    <email>contact@selfh.st</email>
  </author>
  <link href="https://selfh.st/apps" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>Self-hosted software releases generated by selfh.st</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/passbolt/passbolt_api/releases/tag/v4.6.0</id>
    <title>New release for Passbolt: Purple Haze</title>
    <updated>2024-03-14T07:30:45-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>passbolt/passbolt_api</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;Release song: https://youtu.be/Ub0NtPOj7es?si=3IL4HKS4-g17uPal&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Passbolt Community Edition 4.6.0 release "Purple Haze", brings enhancements that focus primarily on the administrative aspect and overall system health.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This update introduces the Health Check feature within the Admin workspace, designed to offer administrators a comprehensive tool for system assessment and upkeep.
In addition, this version addresses a range of minor bugs and delivers the awaited PHP 8.3 support.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This version furthermore lays the foundations for successive performance gains by refining data verification processes and reducing memory usage, particularly when browsing. Expect more significant improvements with the next releases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;[4.6.0] - 2024-03-14&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Added&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-24485 As an administrator I can view the API healthcheck in the administration section&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-29396 As an administrator I can hide the share folder capability with a RBAC&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-25463 As an administrator I can disable the healthcheck index endpoint with a flag&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-29397 As an administrator I can disable the healthcheck administration panel with a flag&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Improved&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-29009 As an administrator completing my setup I should not receive a notification that I completed my setup&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-26152 The API should identify openpgpjs v5.10 revoked key as revoked&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-29437 As an administrator I can log internal errors with the complete trace in Json format&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Security&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-30155 Update phpseclib/phpseclib to fix composer security vulnerability&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Fixed&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-30019 As a user I should not get a 500 when editing a user with payload containing integers as fields&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-29964 As an administrator disabling a user I should not get a 500 if the disabled date is not valid&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-29970 As a group manager I should receive an accurate summary in my notifications on group permission changes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-29054 As an administrator I should not get an error when running the cleanup command and the users table does not exist&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-28719 As an administrator sending emails the timezone displayed in the emails should be in the correct time zone&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-30266 As an administrator sending emails with the email digest the message ID should be defined&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-30182 Build the styleguide on version 4.6.1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Maintenance&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-28247 Update cakephp/cakephp to version 4.5&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/passbolt/passbolt_api/releases/tag/v4.6.0" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/passbolt/passbolt_api/releases/tag/v4.6.1</id>
    <title>New release for Passbolt: Reptillia</title>
    <updated>2024-03-27T07:04:04-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>passbolt/passbolt_api</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;Release song: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=b8-tXG8KrWs&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Passbolt is pleased to announce the immediate availability of version 4.6.1. This is a maintenance update that contains an important fix for the API, addressing the issue reported by the community since version 4.6.0.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most notably this update fixes a problem when an administrator is not able to re-enable a suspended user.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We would like to express our sincere thanks to the community members who brought issues to our attention and helped the team to make passbolt better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;[4.6.1] - 2024-03-27&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Fixed&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-32354 As an admin, I can re-enable a suspended user (GITHUB #512)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/passbolt/passbolt_api/releases/tag/v4.6.1" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/passbolt/passbolt_api/releases/tag/v4.6.2</id>
    <title>New release for Passbolt: One Nation Under A Groove</title>
    <updated>2024-04-11T11:49:11-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>passbolt/passbolt_api</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;Release song: https://youtu.be/3WOZwwRH6XU?si=jvTiezg7eEEpEh-S&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Passbolt is pleased to announce the immediate availability of version v4.6.2. This version is a targeted security release of both the API and the browser extension focusing on fixing security issues reported by security researchers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We would like to express our appreciation to the community for their assistance in making Passbolt more secure. Further details about the issues will be shared in a separate communication.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;[4.6.2] - 2024-04-11&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Security&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-32932 Fix error template title&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/passbolt/passbolt_api/releases/tag/v4.6.2" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/passbolt/passbolt_api/releases/tag/v4.7.0</id>
    <title>New release for Passbolt: Bulls On Parade</title>
    <updated>2024-04-30T07:42:43-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>passbolt/passbolt_api</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;Release song: https://youtu.be/3L4YrGaR8E4&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Passbolt Community Edition v4.7 is a maintenance release that resolves multiple issues identified by the community. Furthermore, this release supports the commitment to improving customization options and integration features, making it easier for organizations to tailor the system to their specific needs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A key enhancement in this release is the ability to use custom SSL certificates for SMTP server connections. This long-awaited feature is particularly beneficial for organizations operating in air-gapped environments or those using their own root CAs, enabling passbolt to more securely integrate with internal tools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;[4.7.0] - 2024-04-30&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Added&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-30330 Add HTTP HEAD method support to /healthcheck/status.json to support more uptime monitoring tools (GITHUB #507)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-26156 As an administrator I can configure SMTP to use TLS with a self-signed cert on my mail server (GITHUB #498)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Security&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-30255 As an authenticated user I cannot access to the healthcheck endpoint when debug is on&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Fixed&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-30379 As an authenticating user I should not get a 500 if the gpg_auth is not an array&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-32889 As an administrator I should not get an exception when running core healthcheck and the host cannot be resolved&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-32928 As user I should see the accurate URL in the email footer when passbolt runs on multiple instances&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-32566 As a user setting up my account I should not get an unexpected 500&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-32903 Fix deprecation error on password expiry settings validation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Maintenance&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-29983 Refactor health check code domain for better maintenance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-30394 Moves code in ActionLogsModelListener into a dedicated service&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-32881 Disable by default all plugins in integration tests&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-32978 Use dependency proxy to reduce docker pull limit&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-22605 Refactor ShareSearchControllerTest, SecretViewControllerTest and GroupsDeleteControllerTest with fixture factories&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-32594 Add tests for SecretCreateService&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/passbolt/passbolt_api/releases/tag/v4.7.0" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/passbolt/passbolt_api/releases/tag/v4.8.0</id>
    <title>New release for Passbolt: Angel</title>
    <updated>2024-05-21T07:19:34-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>passbolt/passbolt_api</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;Release song: https://youtu.be/hbe3CQamF8k&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Passbolt v4.8.0 is a maintenance release focusing on the migration of the browser extension to the latest MV3
architecture and adding tools for administrators to help them manage their instance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This release marks the introduction of the first version of the MV3 extension for Chrome. The transition to MV3 has been
in progress since last year, with changes rolled out progressively until now. The base code between MV2 and MV3 is
nearly identical, and both extensions will continue to be maintained in parallel. A detailed blog post explaining our
migration process will be coming soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A new feature allowing administrators to purge audit logs from the command line was added. This will help reclaim database
space for logs that are no longer relevant, improving the performance of long-running instances while keeping necessary
logs for forensic and audit activities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A new command has also been added to help administrators debug issues with their SMTP server. Email functionality is
crucial for Passbolt, and diagnosing connection problems is not always straightforward. This new command aims to simplify
the process when connecting to a new SMTP server as well as understand errors that could occur on existing integration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As passbolt moves towards supporting more content types this year, significant work has been done to enhance performance
across the entire stack, from the database to the API and the browser extension. This release includes some of these
improvements, with more enhancements on the way in the next coming release v4.9.0.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We hope these updates enhance your experience with Passbolt. Your feedback is always valuable to us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;[4.8.0] - 2024-05-21&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Added&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-33071 As an administrator I can purge the action logs table with a dedicated command&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-33231 As an administrator I want to know if a custom certificate is in use for SMTP&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-32579 As an administrator I can view email_queue records via passbolt command&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Improved&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-32888 As an admin I should not get a time-out on health checks on air-gapped network&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-32983 Access email settings only when emails are sent&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Fixed&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-33451 Fix 500 error on authentication when nonce is not a string&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-33073 As a user logging in, invalid login operation should not be logged as success in the audit logs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-33234 The application should not throw an error if the JWT public key is not parsable&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Maintenance&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-30314 Bump passbolt/passbolt-test-data to v4.8&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/passbolt/passbolt_api/releases/tag/v4.8.0" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
