<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://selfh.st/apps</id>
  <title>Passbolt Releases</title>
  <updated>2025-07-22T10:33:16.434259-04:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>selfh.st</name>
    <email>contact@selfh.st</email>
  </author>
  <link href="https://selfh.st/apps" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>Self-hosted software releases generated by selfh.st</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/passbolt/passbolt_api/releases/tag/v5.1.1</id>
    <title>New release for Passbolt: One Love</title>
    <updated>2025-05-22T06:27:38-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>passbolt/passbolt_api</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;Release song: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Nbav4oWMqEY&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a maintenance release to fix reported issues from Pro customers where directory synchronization was returning various type errors. It also includes a security fix to only include user’s IP &amp;amp; browser agent information if enabled via configuration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you for the valuable feedback and patience!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;[5.1.1] - 2025-05-22&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Fixed&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-42701 Fix the contain of missing metadata key on view user endpoint&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Security&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-42687 Security alert emails should display user IP and user agent only if configured&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/passbolt/passbolt_api/releases/tag/v5.1.1" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/passbolt/passbolt_api/releases/tag/v5.2.0</id>
    <title>New release for Passbolt: Something's Got a Hold on Me</title>
    <updated>2025-06-11T05:57:08-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>passbolt/passbolt_api</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;Release song: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ZA2JknKrCbM&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Passbolt 5.2 introduces the first features built on encrypted metadata, enhancing resource management and customisation.
This update lays the groundwork for future improvements and delivers practical everyday benefits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Resources using encrypted metadata now support multiple URIs. For example, addresses like app.example.com and admin.example.com
can be linked to the same credential, helping the browser extension recognise credentials across multiple domains.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Icons and colours can now be set for resources with encrypted metadata, using a method compatible with KeePass for easy
import and export. This visual distinction helps users quickly navigate large workspaces.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A new density setting is available to adjust grid spacing, providing a clearer, more comfortable view.
Users can easily toggle this in the workspace column settings as needed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Passbolt interface now supports Ukrainian and Slovenian languages, enabling native speakers to use the tool comfortably without relying on English.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additionally, resource owners now receive notifications on the day their passwords expire, supporting teams in managing rotation policies effectively.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This update includes several bug fixes and maintenance improvements based on community feedback.
Thanks to everyone who contributed by reporting issues and suggesting improvements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;[5.2.0] - 2025-06-11&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Added&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-42861 As a user I can use passbolt in Slovenian language&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-42986 As a user I can use passbolt in Ukrainian language&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-42878 Add User GPG key policies (ECC by default) support behind a feature flag&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-41966 As a resource owner I should receive a notification on the day that my resources expire&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Improved&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-42706 Alias POST /metadata/keys/privates.json endpoint to POST /metadata/keys/private.json&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Fixed&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-42800 The check metadata key presence in the healthcheck should not fail if no metadata key is required&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-42701 Fixes the contain of missing metadata key on view user endpoint&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Security&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-42687 Security alert emails should display user IP and user agent only if configured&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-42379 PBL-13-004 - Fixes HTML injections in email notifications&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Maintenance&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-42935 Upgrade API babel dev dependency&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-42893 Upgrade API lock-link-api dev dependency&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-42923 refactor code to remove warning in selenium execution context&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/passbolt/passbolt_api/releases/tag/v5.2.0" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/passbolt/passbolt_api/releases/tag/v5.3.0</id>
    <title>New release for Passbolt: Riders on the Storm</title>
    <updated>2025-07-09T04:40:33-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>passbolt/passbolt_api</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;Release song: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ubWL8VAPoYw&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Passbolt 5.3 adds custom fields, one of the five most‑requested features from the community.
Built on top of encrypted‑metadata introduced earlier this year, custom fields let users attach
additional key‑value pairs to a resource or as a standalone one.
Typical use‑cases include centralising CI/CD job variables and storing environment‑specific
configuration values that need more structure than a general note.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As part of our continuous performance work, this release concentrates on folder browsing.
Loading folders and their resources is now faster and reduces the load on API and client,
improving day-to-day usability for organizations having thousands of credentials under management.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Several bugs reported by the community have also been fixed. As always, thank you to everyone who
took the time to file issues, test patches and suggest improvements.
For a complete list of changes, consult the changelog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;[5.3.0] - 2025-07-09&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Added&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-43066 As a developer I can setup my development environment using ddev&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-43188 Adds Custom Fields Standalone resource type migration&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-43383 Improves the performance of most paginated endpoints&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-43659 Improve error handling when metadata key could not be saved due to unexpected reason&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Fixed&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-43382 As an administrator I should not get a connection error when running the healthcheck when the database is empty&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-43007 Fixes emails not sent after v5 upgrade if SMTP credentials are stored in environment variables (GITHUB #545)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-43122 As an administrator retrieving users metadata key, I should not trigger a validation type issue on the missing metadata_keys_id in certain conditions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-43137 Fixes a potential settings conflict in user key policy where key of type rsa should not have a preferred curve&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-42784 As an administrator I should not get a health check error when all email notifications are enabled&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-43259 Fixes a record not found error on table &lt;code&gt;organization_settings&lt;/code&gt; in healthcheck after v5 upgrade (GITHUB #548)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-42072 As a user sharing permissions, I should not get a 500 response if the payload is wrongly formatted&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-42071 Fixes 500 errors on malformed UTF-8 character-based URLs when using the JsonTraceFormatter class&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-43659 Improves the error catching on creation of organization metadata key&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Maintenance&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-42177 Upgrades CakePHP version to 5.2.5&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-43010 Replaces the use of static fixtures with fixture factories in multiple test cases&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-41724 Map &lt;em&gt;cake_core&lt;/em&gt; cache config with &lt;em&gt;cake_translations&lt;/em&gt; in the bootstrap.php file&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-42380 Adds the missing v5 resource types on data insertion in the passbolt-test-data vendor&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-43658 Use FQN to load all vendor plugin&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/passbolt/passbolt_api/releases/tag/v5.3.0" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/passbolt/passbolt_api/releases/tag/v5.3.1</id>
    <title>New release for Passbolt: Beautiful People</title>
    <updated>2025-07-09T09:44:04-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>passbolt/passbolt_api</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;Release song: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=h7V36waLN0M&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This hot-fix resolves a regression introduced in v5.3.0 that blocked the creation of standalone Custom Fields content types. A validation error in the API prevented these resources from being saved. With v5.3.1, the validation logic has been corrected, so users can now create and test Custom Fields content types as intended.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you to everyone in the community who spotted the issue so quickly and helped us verify the fix!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;[5.3.1] - 2025-07-09&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Fixed&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-43748 Users are unable to save a new standalone custom field resource&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/passbolt/passbolt_api/releases/tag/v5.3.1" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/passbolt/passbolt_api/releases/tag/v5.3.2</id>
    <title>New release for Passbolt: Somebody to love</title>
    <updated>2025-07-17T04:50:54-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>passbolt/passbolt_api</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;Release song: &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-GxmblM_jss"&gt;https//www.youtube.com/watch?v=-GxmblM_jss&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Passbolt v5.3.2 is a security release designed to strengthen the security posture of your organization. It introduces a
clipboard flushing feature and addresses issues related to encrypted metadata.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new clipboard flush timer lets you copy secrets just long enough to use them; clipboard data is automatically cleared
when the countdown (30s) expires, significantly reducing the risk of accidental exposure or leaks from forgotten clipboard content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This update also resolves several encrypted metadata issues, moving the feature closer to general availability.
Organizations can now enable encrypted metadata even if users have imported their own more complex keys
(e.g. keys that were set to expire at some point), streamlining adoption for advanced users. Admin changes are smoother
too: if the original metadata-enabling administrator leaves, newly invited users will still receive the metadata key automatically,
removing the need for manual distribution. Lastly, users who owned shared resources using the new encrypted metadata format can now
be deleted without issue, as ownership transfer is now handled correctly during the deletion process.
A big thank you to all testers who helped refine these features. If you’re new to any of them, we welcome your feedback on the community
forum or through your usual support channels!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;[5.3.2] - 2025-07-16&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Fixed&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-43910 As an administrator installing passbolt on postgres, the default postgres schema should be public&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-43956 Fix OpenPGP_PHP behavior discrepancy for keys with multiple self-signed key signatures with different expiry times&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-43746 A metadata key should be shareable with new users even if the administrator who created the key is soft-deleted&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-37106 As an administrator running healthCheck, I should see the right path to the logs if the directory permissions are not correct&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Maintenance&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-43966 Selenium specific endpoints should be enabled for local testing with ddev&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-43480 Writes stack traces in logs on metadata key validation 500 errors&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/passbolt/passbolt_api/releases/tag/v5.3.2" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
