<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://selfh.st/apps</id>
  <title>Passbolt Releases</title>
  <updated>2024-05-10T22:32:38.031436-04:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>selfh.st</name>
    <email>contact@selfh.st</email>
  </author>
  <link href="https://selfh.st/apps" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>Self-hosted software releases generated by selfh.st</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/passbolt/passbolt_api/releases/tag/v4.5.0</id>
    <title>New release for Passbolt: Summer is ending</title>
    <updated>2024-02-08T06:22:17-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>passbolt/passbolt_api</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;Release song: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=HR1KH4zElcY&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Passbolt v4.5.0 named "Summer is Ending" brings a host of new features and improvements, all designed to make your password management experience more secure, efficient, and user-friendly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the heart of this release is the introduction of the Password Expiry feature, a much-anticipated functionality that allows administrators to enable the automatic expiry policy, enhancing security by ensuring that potentially passwords are rotated when someone loses access to resources, for example by leaving a group or the organization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alongside, we're excited to introduce the Russian translation, making Passbolt more accessible to a wider audience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We've also expanded our SMTP settings to include Microsoft 365 and Outlook providers, responding to the community's feedback for more integration options. The section to help users install and configure the Windows desktop application feature is also now enabled by default.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Improvements in the performance of some important API endpoints and other security enhancements and bug fixes are also part of this release.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to everyone in our community for your ongoing support and contributions that made this release possible. Your feedback and involvement continue to shape Passbolt, enhancing our collective security and usability. Together, we're making password management better for everyone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;[4.5.0] - 2024-02-08&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Added&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-23913 As a user I can see my passwords marked as expired when users lose permissions on these&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-23913 As an administrator I can activate the password expiry feature&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-28923 As a user I want to be able to use passbolt in Russian&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-21484 As an administrator I can define Microsoft 365 and Outlook providers in SMTP settings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-19652 As an administrator I can cleanup groups with no members with the cleanup command&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-27707 As administrator, with RBAC I should be able to set “can see users workspace” to “Allow if group manager”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-28716 Desktop application flag is now enabled by default&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-26203 Desktop app define the account kit exportation help page&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Improved&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-27616 Improve resources serialization performance on GET resources.json&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Security&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-29148 Bump selenium API plugin version to v4.5&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-29005 Upgrades phpseclib/phpseclib to fix composer audit security vulnerability&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-22336 As an admin I should be able to enable/disable request group managers to add users to groups emails separately (LDAP/AD)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-28871 Mitigate supply chain attack on PR and lint lock files&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-28658 Mitigate supply chain attack on post npm install script&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Fixed&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-29200 Fixes the recover_user command (GITHUB #504)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-29164 Fix recent InstallCommand changes breaking selenium tests&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-29132 Fix composer lock file not up-to-date message when installing dependencies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-29160 Fix failing static analysis job in CI&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-29137 Fix failing in UsersEditDisableControllerTest file due to purifier&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-29113 Fix a typo in the email sent when admins lose their admin role&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-28130 Fix invalid cookie name should not trigger a 500&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-29007 Fix constantly failing test in RbacsUpdateControllerTest file&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-28991 Fix email queue entries not marked as sent&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Maintenance&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-28857 Require phpunit-speedtrap to track down slow tests&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-25516 Remove --dev from .gitlab test options, it has not effect and will break with composer v3&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-28844 Improves the methods testing email content&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-28845 Skip unauthenticated exception from logging&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-28653 Speed-up tests by mocking the client in healthcheck relevant tests&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/passbolt/passbolt_api/releases/tag/v4.5.0" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/passbolt/passbolt_api/releases/tag/v4.6.0</id>
    <title>New release for Passbolt: Purple Haze</title>
    <updated>2024-03-14T07:30:45-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>passbolt/passbolt_api</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;Release song: https://youtu.be/Ub0NtPOj7es?si=3IL4HKS4-g17uPal&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Passbolt Community Edition 4.6.0 release "Purple Haze", brings enhancements that focus primarily on the administrative aspect and overall system health.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This update introduces the Health Check feature within the Admin workspace, designed to offer administrators a comprehensive tool for system assessment and upkeep.
In addition, this version addresses a range of minor bugs and delivers the awaited PHP 8.3 support.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This version furthermore lays the foundations for successive performance gains by refining data verification processes and reducing memory usage, particularly when browsing. Expect more significant improvements with the next releases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;[4.6.0] - 2024-03-14&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Added&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-24485 As an administrator I can view the API healthcheck in the administration section&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-29396 As an administrator I can hide the share folder capability with a RBAC&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-25463 As an administrator I can disable the healthcheck index endpoint with a flag&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-29397 As an administrator I can disable the healthcheck administration panel with a flag&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Improved&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-29009 As an administrator completing my setup I should not receive a notification that I completed my setup&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-26152 The API should identify openpgpjs v5.10 revoked key as revoked&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-29437 As an administrator I can log internal errors with the complete trace in Json format&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Security&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-30155 Update phpseclib/phpseclib to fix composer security vulnerability&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Fixed&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-30019 As a user I should not get a 500 when editing a user with payload containing integers as fields&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-29964 As an administrator disabling a user I should not get a 500 if the disabled date is not valid&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-29970 As a group manager I should receive an accurate summary in my notifications on group permission changes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-29054 As an administrator I should not get an error when running the cleanup command and the users table does not exist&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-28719 As an administrator sending emails the timezone displayed in the emails should be in the correct time zone&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-30266 As an administrator sending emails with the email digest the message ID should be defined&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-30182 Build the styleguide on version 4.6.1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Maintenance&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-28247 Update cakephp/cakephp to version 4.5&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/passbolt/passbolt_api/releases/tag/v4.6.0" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/passbolt/passbolt_api/releases/tag/v4.6.1</id>
    <title>New release for Passbolt: Reptillia</title>
    <updated>2024-03-27T07:04:04-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>passbolt/passbolt_api</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;Release song: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=b8-tXG8KrWs&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Passbolt is pleased to announce the immediate availability of version 4.6.1. This is a maintenance update that contains an important fix for the API, addressing the issue reported by the community since version 4.6.0.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most notably this update fixes a problem when an administrator is not able to re-enable a suspended user.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We would like to express our sincere thanks to the community members who brought issues to our attention and helped the team to make passbolt better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;[4.6.1] - 2024-03-27&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Fixed&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-32354 As an admin, I can re-enable a suspended user (GITHUB #512)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/passbolt/passbolt_api/releases/tag/v4.6.1" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/passbolt/passbolt_api/releases/tag/v4.6.2</id>
    <title>New release for Passbolt: One Nation Under A Groove</title>
    <updated>2024-04-11T11:49:11-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>passbolt/passbolt_api</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;Release song: https://youtu.be/3WOZwwRH6XU?si=jvTiezg7eEEpEh-S&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Passbolt is pleased to announce the immediate availability of version v4.6.2. This version is a targeted security release of both the API and the browser extension focusing on fixing security issues reported by security researchers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We would like to express our appreciation to the community for their assistance in making Passbolt more secure. Further details about the issues will be shared in a separate communication.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;[4.6.2] - 2024-04-11&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Security&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-32932 Fix error template title&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/passbolt/passbolt_api/releases/tag/v4.6.2" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/passbolt/passbolt_api/releases/tag/v4.7.0</id>
    <title>New release for Passbolt: Bulls On Parade</title>
    <updated>2024-04-30T07:42:43-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>passbolt/passbolt_api</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;Release song: https://youtu.be/3L4YrGaR8E4&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Passbolt Community Edition v4.7 is a maintenance release that resolves multiple issues identified by the community. Furthermore, this release supports the commitment to improving customization options and integration features, making it easier for organizations to tailor the system to their specific needs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A key enhancement in this release is the ability to use custom SSL certificates for SMTP server connections. This long-awaited feature is particularly beneficial for organizations operating in air-gapped environments or those using their own root CAs, enabling passbolt to more securely integrate with internal tools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;[4.7.0] - 2024-04-30&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Added&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-30330 Add HTTP HEAD method support to /healthcheck/status.json to support more uptime monitoring tools (GITHUB #507)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-26156 As an administrator I can configure SMTP to use TLS with a self-signed cert on my mail server (GITHUB #498)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Security&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-30255 As an authenticated user I cannot access to the healthcheck endpoint when debug is on&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Fixed&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-30379 As an authenticating user I should not get a 500 if the gpg_auth is not an array&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-32889 As an administrator I should not get an exception when running core healthcheck and the host cannot be resolved&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-32928 As user I should see the accurate URL in the email footer when passbolt runs on multiple instances&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-32566 As a user setting up my account I should not get an unexpected 500&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-32903 Fix deprecation error on password expiry settings validation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Maintenance&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-29983 Refactor health check code domain for better maintenance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-30394 Moves code in ActionLogsModelListener into a dedicated service&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-32881 Disable by default all plugins in integration tests&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-32978 Use dependency proxy to reduce docker pull limit&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-22605 Refactor ShareSearchControllerTest, SecretViewControllerTest and GroupsDeleteControllerTest with fixture factories&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-32594 Add tests for SecretCreateService&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/passbolt/passbolt_api/releases/tag/v4.7.0" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
