<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://selfh.st/apps</id>
  <title>Passbolt Releases</title>
  <updated>2025-06-18T16:32:56.074922-04:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>selfh.st</name>
    <email>contact@selfh.st</email>
  </author>
  <link href="https://selfh.st/apps" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>Self-hosted software releases generated by selfh.st</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/passbolt/passbolt_api/releases/tag/v4.12.1</id>
    <title>New release for Passbolt: Basket Case</title>
    <updated>2025-03-17T10:33:56-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>passbolt/passbolt_api</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;Release song: https://youtu.be/NUTGr5t3MoY?si=1hitMfMv8PDn1Wf2&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a maintenance release. It fixes a reported issue when notifying group administrators that a user should be added to a group. The issue occurred when a group administrator had been suspended.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you to the community for the valuable feedback!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;[4.12.1] - 2025-03-17&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Fixed&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-39959 Fixes an issue when fetching the locale of suspended users when queried in a sub-query&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/passbolt/passbolt_api/releases/tag/v4.12.1" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/passbolt/passbolt_api/releases/tag/v5.0.0</id>
    <title>New release for Passbolt: Need To Feel Loved</title>
    <updated>2025-04-10T05:52:57-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>passbolt/passbolt_api</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;Release song: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=yf1f8zNvR1I&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Even the longest day has its end” goes the old Irish proverb, and here we are at long last announcing the Passbolt 5.x series.
This first release v5.0 ships with a complete redesign of the application’s interface, which had remained largely unchanged since
Passbolt’s early days and was limiting the addition of new capabilities.
The new version offers a more spacious layout that provides room for meaningful information and addresses long-standing ergonomic issues.
If you want to know more, check out what changed in this &lt;a href="https://community.passbolt.com/t/passbolt-5-ui-redesign/12717"&gt;Passbolt 5, UI Redesign&lt;/a&gt; community post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Passbolt v5.0 lays the groundwork for the v5.x series, which will expand the software’s capabilities to handle more sensitive data types that the community has requested,
such as key-value pairs, SSH keys, and certificates. The blog article about the passbolt v5.0 release is coming soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, with each major version come the inevitable breaking changes, which we strive to minimize as much as possible.
With this release, the minimum server requirement has changed to PHP 8.2 or greater, so be sure to check out our latest blog article on &lt;a href="https://www.passbolt.com/blog/preparing-for-passbolt-v5-php-8-2-requirement"&gt;how to upgrade to PHP 8.2&lt;/a&gt;.
Additionally this is a perfect moment to back up your server data and prepare for the unexpected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you to the community for all your feedback, testing, and support in making this milestone possible. We hope you’ll enjoy what Passbolt v5.0 has to offer and look forward to hearing from you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;[5.0.0] - 2025-04-10&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Added&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-39434 As an administrator I can log user actions on file in an SIEM compatible format&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-39627 Enforce PHP 8.2 as minimum passbolt API requirement&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-40155 Add Passbolt API support of PHP 8.4&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-40247 Add API status documentation link to the health check command&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Fixed&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-39706 When creating a user from CLI the metadata_private_keys should have their fields created_by and modified_by set&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-41356 As an administrator I can delete a resource type associated to deleted resources&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-41374 Fix unlimited session lifetime introduced in CakePHP 5&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-41379 Updates the minimum next version to 8.2 to remove false warning from installation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Maintenance&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-28246 Refactor the whole application to upgrade CakePHP to version 5&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-39434 Add code coverage to ActionLogsUsernameQueryStrategy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-39660 Mock MfaFormInterface to avoid tests failing occasionally&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-39630 Fix ResourcesIndexControllerPaginationTest recurrently failing test&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/passbolt/passbolt_api/releases/tag/v5.0.0" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/passbolt/passbolt_api/releases/tag/v5.1.0</id>
    <title>New release for Passbolt: Four to the Floor</title>
    <updated>2025-05-15T10:18:19-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>passbolt/passbolt_api</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;Release song: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=d9WHUTKMD8k&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 5.1 release adds support for encrypted resource metadata features as an opt-in feature.
Early adopters can turn it on, test real-world workflows and feed back improvements,
while more cautious teams, or teams with a lot of custom integrations, can wait until they are ready.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a major milestone for the product, further extending Passbolt’s security model to improve
confidentiality for the contextual information surrounding credentials.
This means that metadata such as names, login URLs, and similar fields are now also cryptographically protected.
As is customary for high-risk security features, this implementation has been audited by security researchers
from Cure53 with a public report publication coming soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To ensure a smooth and cautious rollout, the feature is released as an opt-in capability with v5.1 and is scheduled for stable
release in v5.2. If you want to know more about how to enable it and start testing, a blog article published shortly,
will provide a step-by-step guidance on how to activate the feature and a deeper dive into what’s changed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additionally, the password expiry feature is now enabled by default for new installations.
This capability is considered a security best practice, helping organizations enforce rotation policies and
mitigate risks associated with long-lived shared credentials. For existing instances, administrators can enable
this feature manually from the administration workspace.
To learn more, check out the blog article: &lt;a href="https://www.passbolt.com/blog/passbolts-new-automation-of-shared-passwords-expiry"&gt;Passbolt’s New Automation of Shared Passwords Expiry&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As usual, this release also includes a few bug fixes and performance improvements, like a faster folder tree that handles 5,000+ folders for the ones that are running a tight ship.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As always, thank you to our community for your feedback, contributions, and bug reports. A special thanks to the CakePHP maintainers for the fast post v5 upgrade support!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For full technical details of everything in this release, check out the changelog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;[5.1.0] - 2025-05-15&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Added&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-40712 Enable password expiry by default for new instances&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-41629 As a client I should know if the metadata plugin is set as in beta&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-41628 Enable the metadata plugin by default&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Fixed&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-41736 Adjust the datacheck command to support v5 resources&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-41769 Fix action_logs_purge command only purging 100 records&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-42108 Fix the APP_BASE variable ignored when generated URLs with CakePHP&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Security&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-42378 PBL-13-001 - Sanitize open redirect on MFA step in login&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Improved&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-41840 Return creator along metadata keys on GET /metadata/keys.json&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-42117 Populate metadata key ID for personal resources if null in payload&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Maintenance&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-40626 Update passbolt-test-data to improve PHP 8.4 compatibility&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-40365 Updates the test pipelines to cover PHP 8.4&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-40630 Bump bacon/bacon-qr-code to v3.0&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-40627 Bump league/flysystem package to v3.29&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-40625 Bump Spomky-Labs/otphp package to v11.3&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-40641 Replace vimeo/psalm to psalm/phar&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/passbolt/passbolt_api/releases/tag/v5.1.0" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/passbolt/passbolt_api/releases/tag/v5.1.1</id>
    <title>New release for Passbolt: One Love</title>
    <updated>2025-05-22T06:27:38-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>passbolt/passbolt_api</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;Release song: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Nbav4oWMqEY&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a maintenance release to fix reported issues from Pro customers where directory synchronization was returning various type errors. It also includes a security fix to only include user’s IP &amp;amp; browser agent information if enabled via configuration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you for the valuable feedback and patience!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;[5.1.1] - 2025-05-22&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Fixed&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-42701 Fix the contain of missing metadata key on view user endpoint&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Security&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-42687 Security alert emails should display user IP and user agent only if configured&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/passbolt/passbolt_api/releases/tag/v5.1.1" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/passbolt/passbolt_api/releases/tag/v5.2.0</id>
    <title>New release for Passbolt: Something's Got a Hold on Me</title>
    <updated>2025-06-11T05:57:08-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>passbolt/passbolt_api</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;Release song: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ZA2JknKrCbM&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Passbolt 5.2 introduces the first features built on encrypted metadata, enhancing resource management and customisation.
This update lays the groundwork for future improvements and delivers practical everyday benefits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Resources using encrypted metadata now support multiple URIs. For example, addresses like app.example.com and admin.example.com
can be linked to the same credential, helping the browser extension recognise credentials across multiple domains.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Icons and colours can now be set for resources with encrypted metadata, using a method compatible with KeePass for easy
import and export. This visual distinction helps users quickly navigate large workspaces.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A new density setting is available to adjust grid spacing, providing a clearer, more comfortable view.
Users can easily toggle this in the workspace column settings as needed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Passbolt interface now supports Ukrainian and Slovenian languages, enabling native speakers to use the tool comfortably without relying on English.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additionally, resource owners now receive notifications on the day their passwords expire, supporting teams in managing rotation policies effectively.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This update includes several bug fixes and maintenance improvements based on community feedback.
Thanks to everyone who contributed by reporting issues and suggesting improvements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;[5.2.0] - 2025-06-11&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Added&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-42861 As a user I can use passbolt in Slovenian language&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-42986 As a user I can use passbolt in Ukrainian language&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-42878 Add User GPG key policies (ECC by default) support behind a feature flag&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-41966 As a resource owner I should receive a notification on the day that my resources expire&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Improved&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-42706 Alias POST /metadata/keys/privates.json endpoint to POST /metadata/keys/private.json&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Fixed&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-42800 The check metadata key presence in the healthcheck should not fail if no metadata key is required&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-42701 Fixes the contain of missing metadata key on view user endpoint&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Security&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-42687 Security alert emails should display user IP and user agent only if configured&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-42379 PBL-13-004 - Fixes HTML injections in email notifications&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Maintenance&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-42935 Upgrade API babel dev dependency&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-42893 Upgrade API lock-link-api dev dependency&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PB-42923 refactor code to remove warning in selenium execution context&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/passbolt/passbolt_api/releases/tag/v5.2.0" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
