<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://selfh.st/apps</id>
  <title>Piglet Releases</title>
  <updated>2025-02-05T05:31:18.948933-05:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>selfh.st</name>
    <email>contact@selfh.st</email>
  </author>
  <link href="https://selfh.st/apps" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>Self-hosted software releases generated by selfh.st</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/k3nd0x/piglet/releases/tag/v1.1.0</id>
    <title>New release for Piglet: Piglet v1.1.0 </title>
    <updated>2023-07-17T09:00:51-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>k3nd0x/piglet</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Full Changelog&lt;/strong&gt;: https://github.com/k3nd0x/piglet/commits/v1.1.0&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/k3nd0x/piglet/releases/tag/v1.1.0" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/k3nd0x/piglet/releases/tag/v1.1.1</id>
    <title>New release for Piglet: </title>
    <updated>2023-07-19T16:56:57-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>k3nd0x/piglet</name>
    </author>
    <content/>
    <link href="https://github.com/k3nd0x/piglet/releases/tag/v1.1.1" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/k3nd0x/piglet/releases/tag/v1.3</id>
    <title>New release for Piglet: Piglet 1.3</title>
    <updated>2024-06-26T12:09:12-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>k3nd0x/piglet</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h1&gt;Piglet Release Notes - Version 1.3 🚀&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am excited to announce the release of Piglet version 1.3. This update brings several new features, enhancements, and fixes to improve your experience. Here are the details of what's included in this release:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;New Features and Enhancements&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;New Navbar and Dark Mode&lt;/strong&gt;: I've revamped the navigation bar and introduced a sleek new dark mode for a better user experience.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;New Symbols&lt;/strong&gt;: Added a few new symbols to enhance the visual appeal and usability.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cleaned Up JS/CSS Imports&lt;/strong&gt;: Optimized and cleaned up JavaScript and CSS imports for improved performance and maintainability.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Recurring Orders&lt;/strong&gt;: You can now schedule your orders on a daily, weekly, monthly, quarterly, or yearly basis, providing greater flexibility and automation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Enhanced Analyzing Feature&lt;/strong&gt;: The Analyze tab now includes average spending per category and a comparison of your spending between the current year and the previous year, offering deeper insights into your financial habits.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Random Image Generator&lt;/strong&gt;: Each new user will be greeted with a unique, randomly generated image, adding a personalized touch to the user experience - but you can still upload your own image if you want&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Fixes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fixes #1&lt;/strong&gt;: Resolved issue #1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fixes #2&lt;/strong&gt;: Addressed issue #2 &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fixed Celery Scheduler&lt;/strong&gt;: Fixed the issues with the Celery scheduler to ensure reliable task scheduling.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fixed empty fields&lt;/strong&gt;: Fixed the empty graphs if no data was added yet&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Database and Security Improvements&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Removed Old Code (User &amp;lt;-&amp;gt; Budget Mapping)&lt;/strong&gt;: Cleaned up old code related to user and budget mapping for a more streamlined codebase.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Made API and SQL Part for Recurring Orders (#14)&lt;/strong&gt;: Developed the API and SQL components to support recurring orders.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Updated Init SQL Schema to 1.3&lt;/strong&gt;: Updated the initial SQL schema to match the new version 1.3 standards.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Removed Old Bid Mapping Completely&lt;/strong&gt;: Removed all traces of the old bid mapping to maintain a clean and efficient system.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Piglet Running as 'piglet' User&lt;/strong&gt;: Piglet now operates under a user called 'piglet' for enhanced security and system integrity.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Database Update Schema Process&lt;/strong&gt;: Implemented a process to handle database schema updates smoothly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope you enjoy the new features and improvements in Piglet 1.3. Your feedback is invaluable to me, so please feel free to share your thoughts and suggestions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you for your continued support!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sincerely,&lt;br /&gt;
k3nd0x&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/k3nd0x/piglet/releases/tag/v1.3" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
