<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://selfh.st/apps</id>
  <title>PinePods Releases</title>
  <updated>2025-04-03T05:35:03.452640-04:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>selfh.st</name>
    <email>contact@selfh.st</email>
  </author>
  <link href="https://selfh.st/apps" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>Self-hosted software releases generated by selfh.st</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/madeofpendletonwool/PinePods/releases/tag/0.7.2</id>
    <title>New release for PinePods: Version 0.7.2 Released! RSS Feeds, Filtering/Sorting and bug squashing!</title>
    <updated>2024-12-22T13:42:56-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>madeofpendletonwool/PinePods</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;I'm excited to announce Pinepods 0.7.2, bringing significant improvements to podcast organization and accessibility! This update focuses on making your podcast listening experience more flexible and customizable, with new filtering options, RSS feed support, and numerous quality-of-life improvements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[x] Mobile Progress line (little line that appears above the line player to indicate your progress in the episode)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[x] Dynamically Adjusting chapters. Chapters now adapt and update as you play each one&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[x] Dynamic Play button. This means when you play an episode it will update to a pause button as you see it in a list of other episodes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[x] Fixed issue where Gpodder wasn't adding in podcasts right away after being connected.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[x] Fixed issues with admin user add component where you could adjust user settings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[x] Also adjusted error messages on user component so that it's more clear what went wrong&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[x] Added in RSS feed capability. There's a new setting to turn on RSS feeds in the user settings. This will allow you to get a feed of all your Pinepods podcasts that you can add into another podcast app.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[x] Individual Podcasts can also be subscribed to with feeds as well. Opening the individual Podcast page there's a new RSS icon you can click to get the feed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[x] Fixed issues where theme wasn't staying applied sometimes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[x] Added filtering throughout the app. You can now selectively filter whether podcasts is completed or in progress&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[x] Added quick search in numerous places. This allows you to quickly search for a podcast based on the name. Pages like History, Saved, Podcast have all gotten this&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[x] Added Sorting throughout the app. You can now sort podcasts in numerous ways, such as a-z, longest to shortest, newest to oldest, etc...&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[x] Fixed issue where images in descriptions could break the layout of episodes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[x] Adjusted categories to look nicer in the podcast page&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[x] Fixed issues with DB backup options&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[x] Implemented DB restore options&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[x] Fixed issue where the Queue on mobile wasn't adjusting episode placement&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/madeofpendletonwool/PinePods/releases/tag/0.7.2" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/madeofpendletonwool/PinePods/releases/tag/0.7.3</id>
    <title>New release for PinePods: Version 0.7.3 Released! YouTube Integration and Massive Improvements</title>
    <updated>2025-02-01T08:46:08-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>madeofpendletonwool/PinePods</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;Version 0.7.3 Released! YouTube Integration Unleashed!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm thrilled to announce Pinepods 0.7.3, a game-changing update that brings comprehensive YouTube integration to your podcast management experience! This release allows you to now manage YouTube content within Pinepods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[x] Full YouTube channel audio subscription support&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[x] Dynamic channel update mechanisms&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[x] Comprehensive YouTube content management&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[x] Seamless episode tracking and completion status alongside standard podcasts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[x] Nextcloud Sync Refinements&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[x] Fixed synchronization issues&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[x] Push episode completion status to Nextcloud/Gpodder&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[x] Enhanced Download Options&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[x] Episode downloads archived to the server can now be owned by your own user (see readme for instructions)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[x] Refined Episode Metadata&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[x] More descriptive downloaded episode titles&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[x] More robust podcast parsing capabilities on the frontend&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[x] Improved episode sorting (completed, in-progress options on the single-podcast page)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[x] Added completion icons on the single-podcast page&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[x] Better handling of episode page navigation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[x] Resolved refreshing inconsistencies across pages&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[x] Improved podcast index ID handling&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[x] Fixed up episode ordering accuracy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[x] Various other css and visual bug fixes in various spots &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you to the community for your continued support and feedback! If you notice any lingering issues when subscribing to YouTube channels, or anything else, please open an issue!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Happy podcasting! 🎧🚀&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/madeofpendletonwool/PinePods/releases/tag/0.7.3" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/madeofpendletonwool/PinePods/releases/tag/0.7.5</id>
    <title>New release for PinePods: Version 0.7.5: Quick Postgres Fix</title>
    <updated>2025-03-13T22:40:26-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>madeofpendletonwool/PinePods</name>
    </author>
    <content/>
    <link href="https://github.com/madeofpendletonwool/PinePods/releases/tag/0.7.5" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/madeofpendletonwool/PinePods/releases/tag/0.7.6</id>
    <title>New release for PinePods: Version 0.7.6: Revamped Notification System, Download Status, and Stability Improvements</title>
    <updated>2025-03-23T14:38:20-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>madeofpendletonwool/PinePods</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h1&gt;Version 0.7.6: Revamped Notification System, Download Status, and Stability Improvements&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm excited to announce PinePods 0.7.6, fully showing the power of the new notification system, things like episode downloads will now display percentages as they download in a brand new alert component that's been added. A worker system for background tasks that can be easily monitored on a per user basis so we can now get status of tasks as they execute was added back in version 0.7.4. Now we're starting to see what can be done with it. At this point I am confident Pinepods is the ultimate podcast archival tool. In the near future I will continue to migrate tasks over to this new system which will allow for even greater visibility into exactly what the server is doing. Think monitoring status of Nextcloud sync tasks etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition this update further improves some findings after the previous 0.7.4 update as it was a big one!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;📣 Brand New Alert System&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comprehensive Alert System&lt;/strong&gt; - This update introduces a brand new Alert System Component that can be opened to monitor status of background tasks. Downloads are the primary use-case at the moment&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Enhanced Notification Settings&lt;/strong&gt; - This update makes much needed adjustments to info messages and improves the look, and makes them less intrusive. They now show up on a timer as a small toast pop up. All tied into the new alert system.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;🎵 Playlist Enhancements&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Playlist Deletion&lt;/strong&gt; - Easily remove playlists you no longer need&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Improved Playlist Creation&lt;/strong&gt; - Fixed specific issues with playlist creation flow&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;🔄 NextCloud Integration&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NextCloud Removal Feature&lt;/strong&gt; - Added ability to delete NextCloud connections when no longer needed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;🔒 Authentication Refinements&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Finalized OIDC Error Handling&lt;/strong&gt; - More informative error messages and better recovery&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Smoother Authentication Flow&lt;/strong&gt; - Addressed edge cases in the authentication process&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Login Issues&lt;/strong&gt; - Took care of an issue where logging in a second time could sometimes cause an account not to be recognized&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;🎬 YouTube Support Improvements&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Enhanced YouTube Download Task&lt;/strong&gt; - Implemented better download handling for YouTube videos&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Improved Video Processing&lt;/strong&gt; - More reliable download and playback of YouTube content (and standard podcast content too for that matter)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;💻 Technical Improvements&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Migration Fixes&lt;/strong&gt; - Resolved DB upgrade issues when upgrading from version 0.7.3 to 0.7.5 or 0.7.4 to 0.7.5&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Package Updates&lt;/strong&gt; - Updated a few dependencies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Date Types with Downloads&lt;/strong&gt; - Fixed an issue where a date type with a / would break downloads&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;🖌️ UI Refinements&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Download Page Context Menu&lt;/strong&gt; - Fixed context menu functionality on the downloads page&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Adjusted Login Screen&lt;/strong&gt; - Improved placement and consistency of login screen components&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;General UI Polish&lt;/strong&gt; - Various small improvements throughout the interface&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you to all users and contributors for your continued support and feedback! Please feel free to reach out or create an issue if you have ideas for improving PinePods. Happy podcasting! 🎧🚀&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;🚧 Pending Tasks&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;OIDC Documentation is almost done. I needed to address this login issue with it before I could finish it up. Coming very soon.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/madeofpendletonwool/PinePods/releases/tag/0.7.6" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/madeofpendletonwool/PinePods/releases/tag/0.7.7</id>
    <title>New release for PinePods: Version 0.7.7: Quick Fix to a table casing on startup</title>
    <updated>2025-03-24T07:54:00-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>madeofpendletonwool/PinePods</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;This is a quick fix to take care of a table casing issue that could happen on startup when the table didn't already exist. &lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/madeofpendletonwool/PinePods/releases/tag/0.7.7" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
