<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://selfh.st/apps</id>
  <title>PinePods Releases</title>
  <updated>2025-06-17T00:34:52.832410-04:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>selfh.st</name>
    <email>contact@selfh.st</email>
  </author>
  <link href="https://selfh.st/apps" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>Self-hosted software releases generated by selfh.st</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/madeofpendletonwool/PinePods/releases/tag/0.7.3</id>
    <title>New release for PinePods: Version 0.7.3 Released! YouTube Integration and Massive Improvements</title>
    <updated>2025-02-01T08:46:08-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>madeofpendletonwool/PinePods</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;Version 0.7.3 Released! YouTube Integration Unleashed!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm thrilled to announce Pinepods 0.7.3, a game-changing update that brings comprehensive YouTube integration to your podcast management experience! This release allows you to now manage YouTube content within Pinepods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[x] Full YouTube channel audio subscription support&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[x] Dynamic channel update mechanisms&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[x] Comprehensive YouTube content management&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[x] Seamless episode tracking and completion status alongside standard podcasts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[x] Nextcloud Sync Refinements&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[x] Fixed synchronization issues&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[x] Push episode completion status to Nextcloud/Gpodder&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[x] Enhanced Download Options&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[x] Episode downloads archived to the server can now be owned by your own user (see readme for instructions)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[x] Refined Episode Metadata&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[x] More descriptive downloaded episode titles&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[x] More robust podcast parsing capabilities on the frontend&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[x] Improved episode sorting (completed, in-progress options on the single-podcast page)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[x] Added completion icons on the single-podcast page&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[x] Better handling of episode page navigation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[x] Resolved refreshing inconsistencies across pages&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[x] Improved podcast index ID handling&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[x] Fixed up episode ordering accuracy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[x] Various other css and visual bug fixes in various spots &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you to the community for your continued support and feedback! If you notice any lingering issues when subscribing to YouTube channels, or anything else, please open an issue!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Happy podcasting! 🎧🚀&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/madeofpendletonwool/PinePods/releases/tag/0.7.3" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/madeofpendletonwool/PinePods/releases/tag/0.7.5</id>
    <title>New release for PinePods: Version 0.7.5: Quick Postgres Fix</title>
    <updated>2025-03-13T22:40:26-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>madeofpendletonwool/PinePods</name>
    </author>
    <content/>
    <link href="https://github.com/madeofpendletonwool/PinePods/releases/tag/0.7.5" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/madeofpendletonwool/PinePods/releases/tag/0.7.6</id>
    <title>New release for PinePods: Version 0.7.6: Revamped Notification System, Download Status, and Stability Improvements</title>
    <updated>2025-03-23T14:38:20-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>madeofpendletonwool/PinePods</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h1&gt;Version 0.7.6: Revamped Notification System, Download Status, and Stability Improvements&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm excited to announce PinePods 0.7.6, fully showing the power of the new notification system, things like episode downloads will now display percentages as they download in a brand new alert component that's been added. A worker system for background tasks that can be easily monitored on a per user basis so we can now get status of tasks as they execute was added back in version 0.7.4. Now we're starting to see what can be done with it. At this point I am confident Pinepods is the ultimate podcast archival tool. In the near future I will continue to migrate tasks over to this new system which will allow for even greater visibility into exactly what the server is doing. Think monitoring status of Nextcloud sync tasks etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition this update further improves some findings after the previous 0.7.4 update as it was a big one!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;📣 Brand New Alert System&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comprehensive Alert System&lt;/strong&gt; - This update introduces a brand new Alert System Component that can be opened to monitor status of background tasks. Downloads are the primary use-case at the moment&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Enhanced Notification Settings&lt;/strong&gt; - This update makes much needed adjustments to info messages and improves the look, and makes them less intrusive. They now show up on a timer as a small toast pop up. All tied into the new alert system.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;🎵 Playlist Enhancements&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Playlist Deletion&lt;/strong&gt; - Easily remove playlists you no longer need&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Improved Playlist Creation&lt;/strong&gt; - Fixed specific issues with playlist creation flow&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;🔄 NextCloud Integration&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NextCloud Removal Feature&lt;/strong&gt; - Added ability to delete NextCloud connections when no longer needed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;🔒 Authentication Refinements&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Finalized OIDC Error Handling&lt;/strong&gt; - More informative error messages and better recovery&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Smoother Authentication Flow&lt;/strong&gt; - Addressed edge cases in the authentication process&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Login Issues&lt;/strong&gt; - Took care of an issue where logging in a second time could sometimes cause an account not to be recognized&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;🎬 YouTube Support Improvements&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Enhanced YouTube Download Task&lt;/strong&gt; - Implemented better download handling for YouTube videos&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Improved Video Processing&lt;/strong&gt; - More reliable download and playback of YouTube content (and standard podcast content too for that matter)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;💻 Technical Improvements&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Migration Fixes&lt;/strong&gt; - Resolved DB upgrade issues when upgrading from version 0.7.3 to 0.7.5 or 0.7.4 to 0.7.5&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Package Updates&lt;/strong&gt; - Updated a few dependencies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Date Types with Downloads&lt;/strong&gt; - Fixed an issue where a date type with a / would break downloads&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;🖌️ UI Refinements&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Download Page Context Menu&lt;/strong&gt; - Fixed context menu functionality on the downloads page&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Adjusted Login Screen&lt;/strong&gt; - Improved placement and consistency of login screen components&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;General UI Polish&lt;/strong&gt; - Various small improvements throughout the interface&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you to all users and contributors for your continued support and feedback! Please feel free to reach out or create an issue if you have ideas for improving PinePods. Happy podcasting! 🎧🚀&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;🚧 Pending Tasks&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;OIDC Documentation is almost done. I needed to address this login issue with it before I could finish it up. Coming very soon.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/madeofpendletonwool/PinePods/releases/tag/0.7.6" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/madeofpendletonwool/PinePods/releases/tag/0.7.7</id>
    <title>New release for PinePods: Version 0.7.7: Quick Fix to a table casing on startup</title>
    <updated>2025-03-24T07:54:00-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>madeofpendletonwool/PinePods</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;This is a quick fix to take care of a table casing issue that could happen on startup when the table didn't already exist. &lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/madeofpendletonwool/PinePods/releases/tag/0.7.7" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/madeofpendletonwool/PinePods/releases/tag/0.7.8</id>
    <title>New release for PinePods: Version 0.7.8: GPodder Sync Overhaul, Duration Detection, Description Timestamps</title>
    <updated>2025-05-14T08:56:54-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>madeofpendletonwool/PinePods</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h1&gt;Version 0.7.8: GPodder Sync Overhaul, Duration Detection, Description Timestamps&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm excited to announce &lt;strong&gt;PinePods 0.7.8&lt;/strong&gt;, a major update with core backend improvements, UI polish, and long-awaited quality-of-life features. Most notably, this release includes a full rebuild of the &lt;strong&gt;GPodder sync system&lt;/strong&gt;, a new backend setting to control &lt;strong&gt;YouTube episode retention&lt;/strong&gt;, and smarter episode duration handling for a smoother playback experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;🔄 GPodder Sync Reimagined&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Full GPodder Sync Rebuild&lt;/strong&gt; – The entire GPodder sync process has been rebuilt from scratch. You now get &lt;strong&gt;device management&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;manual sync options&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;session-based authentication&lt;/strong&gt; working cleanly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Built-in GPodder API Server&lt;/strong&gt; – No more separate GPodder server needed! PinePods can act as its own GPodder sync server. Just enable it from the podcast sync area in settings and connect apps (like AntennaPod) directly to PinePods. This server is built in Golang for speed and reliability. It can handle thousands of podcasts and will automatically use the Pinepods database you configure from the start. 
  Example: Use &lt;code&gt;https://my-pinepods-server.com&lt;/code&gt; and your PinePods credentials for user and password when connecting via external apps.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Documentation around gpodder and how the different options work can be found &lt;a href="https://www.pinepods.online/docs/tutorial-extras/gpodder-sync"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;🛠️ Backend &amp;amp; Core Features&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Description Timestamps&lt;/strong&gt; – Podcasts with timestamps in their descriptions will now appear as links. As long as that episode is playing you'll be able to jump between the times.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;YouTube Feed Retention Settings&lt;/strong&gt; – You can now control how many days of YouTube podcast episodes are retained. Defaults to 30. Accessible per channel in the YouTube settings panel.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Improved Image Caching&lt;/strong&gt; – Episode and podcast images now load faster and persist better when scrolling, with smarter caching logic.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Accurate MP3 Duration Detection&lt;/strong&gt; – Episode durations are now parsed &lt;strong&gt;before playback&lt;/strong&gt;, even if the feed doesn’t specify them—no more 0-minute placeholders.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Refresh Status Display&lt;/strong&gt; – Refreshing podcasts using the refresh button on home now shows a proper status in the &lt;strong&gt;Notification Center&lt;/strong&gt;, giving you better insight into background tasks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;YouTube Episode Count Fix&lt;/strong&gt; – Adding a new YouTube channel now correctly increments the podcast's episode count.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;🧹 Bug Fixes &amp;amp; Enhancements&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Episode Queue Removal Fixed&lt;/strong&gt; – Episodes can now reliably be removed from the queue without issues.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chapters Modal UX&lt;/strong&gt; – Tapping outside the chapters modal now properly dismisses it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Play Button Spacing Fix&lt;/strong&gt; – The play button on the shared episodes page now has proper spacing across devices.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Episode Count Bubbles&lt;/strong&gt; – The podcast grid now shows a small badge with the number of available episodes for each podcast.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Improved Podcast Deletion&lt;/strong&gt; – Deleting podcasts no longer shows a false error message. The operation now runs cleanly on all databases.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;📱 Android &amp;amp; UI Improvements&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mobile UI Scaling&lt;/strong&gt; – Layouts and touch targets have been adjusted for better usability on phones and smaller screens.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Visual Polish&lt;/strong&gt; – Numerous subtle interface tweaks and consistency fixes throughout the app.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;📄 Documentation &amp;amp; Community&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Helm Repo URL Fixed&lt;/strong&gt; – The Helm chart link in the README has been corrected for easier installation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Special thanks to &lt;a href="https://github.com/bbirney"&gt;@bbirney&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; – For their excellent work helping implement backend support for &lt;strong&gt;YouTube episode feed cutoff&lt;/strong&gt;, which is now a fully supported and configurable feature in PinePods.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As always, thank you for using PinePods! Your feedback and support are what drive this project forward. If you encounter any new issues or have feature suggestions, don’t hesitate to open an issue or drop a note.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enjoy the update and happy listening 🎧🚀&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/madeofpendletonwool/PinePods/releases/tag/0.7.8" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
