<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://selfh.st/apps</id>
  <title>PinePods Releases</title>
  <updated>2025-03-10T06:35:07.121213-04:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>selfh.st</name>
    <email>contact@selfh.st</email>
  </author>
  <link href="https://selfh.st/apps" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>Self-hosted software releases generated by selfh.st</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/madeofpendletonwool/PinePods/releases/tag/0.6.5</id>
    <title>New release for PinePods: Version 0.6.5 Released! Manual refresh, imrproved layouts, and various features!</title>
    <updated>2024-08-21T21:12:31-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>madeofpendletonwool/PinePods</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;This update tackles quite a few various features that have been asked for quite a bit. Podcast feeds with user and pass now work and can be easily added, the episode layout page can now handle podcast additions and removals much more gracefully, and you can now manually refresh podcasts! There's a button right on the home screen to quickly run a refresh. Plenty of additional fixes and cleanups have been completed in addition. Features are starting to slow somewhat as I start do everything I can to ensure a really polished experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[x] Fixed issue with Podcasts page not refreshing correctly&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[x] Added Add Custom Feed to Podcasts page&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[x] Allow for podcast feeds with user and pass&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[x] Add option to add podcast from feed on podcasts page&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[x] Ensure podcast loads onto podcast page when adding a new custom one in&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[x] Adjusted buttons on episode layout page so they dynamically adjust position to fit better&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[x] Option for user to manually update feeds&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[x] Update Feed directly after adding a Nextcloud/gpodder sync server instead of waiting for the next refresh&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[x] Fixed issue with episode refreshing where a panic could occur (This was due to the categories list)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[x] Ensured See More Button only shows when needed (Just made the descriptions clickable)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[x] Fixed issue with context for podcasts not dynamically updating on the episode layout page once the podcast was added to the db&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[x] Fixed issue with nextcloud sync on mysql dbs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[x] Fixed issue with db setup with mysql&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[x] Ensured deleting podcast when on the episode layout page it closes the deleted modal&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/madeofpendletonwool/PinePods/releases/tag/0.6.5" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/madeofpendletonwool/PinePods/releases/tag/0.7.0</id>
    <title>New release for PinePods: Version 0.7.0 Released! Mobile Apps, Desktop Clients, and PodPeopleDB Integration!</title>
    <updated>2024-12-08T17:34:01-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>madeofpendletonwool/PinePods</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;I'm thrilled to announce Pinepods 0.7.0, the biggest release yet! This update brings Pinepods to every major platform (except ios) with dedicated apps, introduces significant performance improvements, a new host subscription system and adds a host of new features that make podcast listening even better. To learn why ios is the exception &lt;a href="https://www.pinepods.online/blog/2024/12/08/ios-progress"&gt;click here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There's plenty to take in and discover with this new update. I highly recommend installing this new version and giving it a go! So much has been changed and updated. I additionally wrote up a blog post on the new PodPeopleDB integration feature. &lt;a href="https://www.pinepods.online/blog/2024/12/08/podpeople-db"&gt;Read that here!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[x] Android App&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[x] Flatpak Client&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[x] Snap Client&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[x] aur client&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[x] Added Valkey to make many processes faster&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[x] People Table with background jobs to update people found in podcasts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[x] Subscribe to people&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[x] Add loading spinner when adding podcast via people page&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[x] Four new themes added&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[x] People page dropdowns on podcasts and episodes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[x] Stop issues with timeouts on occation with mobile apps - Potentially fixed due to audio file caching. Testing needed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[x] Virtual Lines implemented for Home and Episode Layout. This will improve performance on those pages greatly&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[x] Dynamically adjusting buttons on episode page&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[x] PodcastPeople DB up and running and can be contributed to&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[x] Show currently updating podcast in refresh feed button at top of screen&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[x] Fixed up remaining issues with user podcast refresh&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[x] Podcast 3x layout&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[x] Finalize loading states so you don't see login page when you are already authenticated&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[x] Using valkey to ensure stateless opml imports&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[x] Android play/pause episode metadata&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[x] Draggable Queues on Mobile Devices&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[x] Make Chapters much nicer. Nice modern look to them&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[x] Add background task to remove shared episode references in db after 60 days&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[x] Dynamically adjusting Download, Queue, and Saved Episodes so that every page can add or remove from these lists&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[x] Fixed issue where some episodes weren't adding when refreshing due to redirects&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[x] Some pods not loading in from opml import - better opml validation. Say number importing. - OPML imports moved to backend to get pod values, also reporting function created to update status&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[x] Update queue slider to be centered&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[x] People don't clear out of hosts and people dropdowns if a podcast doesn't have people. So it shows the old podcast currently&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[x] div .title on audio player is now a link, not selectable text.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[x] Improved the playback and volume dropdowns so they don't interact with the rest of the page now&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[x] Added some box shadow to the episode image in the full screen player&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[x] When playing an episode &amp;lt;- and -&amp;gt; arrow keys skips forward and back for the playback now&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[x] Layout improved all over the place&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[x] Phosphor icons implemented as opposed to material&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[x] Settings page layout rebuilt&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[x] Better handle description html formatting&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/madeofpendletonwool/PinePods/releases/tag/0.7.0" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/madeofpendletonwool/PinePods/releases/tag/0.7.1</id>
    <title>New release for PinePods: Version 0.7.1 Minor fix for refreshing and People Subscriptions</title>
    <updated>2024-12-10T16:58:30-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>madeofpendletonwool/PinePods</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;This is a super quick follow up after the previous release where a couple issues were discovered&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;On postgres subscribing to a host didn't work&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Auto Refreshing Episodes was broken. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/madeofpendletonwool/PinePods/releases/tag/0.7.1" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/madeofpendletonwool/PinePods/releases/tag/0.7.2</id>
    <title>New release for PinePods: Version 0.7.2 Released! RSS Feeds, Filtering/Sorting and bug squashing!</title>
    <updated>2024-12-22T13:42:56-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>madeofpendletonwool/PinePods</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;I'm excited to announce Pinepods 0.7.2, bringing significant improvements to podcast organization and accessibility! This update focuses on making your podcast listening experience more flexible and customizable, with new filtering options, RSS feed support, and numerous quality-of-life improvements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[x] Mobile Progress line (little line that appears above the line player to indicate your progress in the episode)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[x] Dynamically Adjusting chapters. Chapters now adapt and update as you play each one&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[x] Dynamic Play button. This means when you play an episode it will update to a pause button as you see it in a list of other episodes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[x] Fixed issue where Gpodder wasn't adding in podcasts right away after being connected.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[x] Fixed issues with admin user add component where you could adjust user settings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[x] Also adjusted error messages on user component so that it's more clear what went wrong&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[x] Added in RSS feed capability. There's a new setting to turn on RSS feeds in the user settings. This will allow you to get a feed of all your Pinepods podcasts that you can add into another podcast app.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[x] Individual Podcasts can also be subscribed to with feeds as well. Opening the individual Podcast page there's a new RSS icon you can click to get the feed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[x] Fixed issues where theme wasn't staying applied sometimes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[x] Added filtering throughout the app. You can now selectively filter whether podcasts is completed or in progress&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[x] Added quick search in numerous places. This allows you to quickly search for a podcast based on the name. Pages like History, Saved, Podcast have all gotten this&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[x] Added Sorting throughout the app. You can now sort podcasts in numerous ways, such as a-z, longest to shortest, newest to oldest, etc...&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[x] Fixed issue where images in descriptions could break the layout of episodes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[x] Adjusted categories to look nicer in the podcast page&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[x] Fixed issues with DB backup options&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[x] Implemented DB restore options&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[x] Fixed issue where the Queue on mobile wasn't adjusting episode placement&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/madeofpendletonwool/PinePods/releases/tag/0.7.2" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/madeofpendletonwool/PinePods/releases/tag/0.7.3</id>
    <title>New release for PinePods: Version 0.7.3 Released! YouTube Integration and Massive Improvements</title>
    <updated>2025-02-01T08:46:08-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>madeofpendletonwool/PinePods</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;Version 0.7.3 Released! YouTube Integration Unleashed!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm thrilled to announce Pinepods 0.7.3, a game-changing update that brings comprehensive YouTube integration to your podcast management experience! This release allows you to now manage YouTube content within Pinepods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[x] Full YouTube channel audio subscription support&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[x] Dynamic channel update mechanisms&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[x] Comprehensive YouTube content management&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[x] Seamless episode tracking and completion status alongside standard podcasts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[x] Nextcloud Sync Refinements&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[x] Fixed synchronization issues&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[x] Push episode completion status to Nextcloud/Gpodder&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[x] Enhanced Download Options&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[x] Episode downloads archived to the server can now be owned by your own user (see readme for instructions)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[x] Refined Episode Metadata&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[x] More descriptive downloaded episode titles&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[x] More robust podcast parsing capabilities on the frontend&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[x] Improved episode sorting (completed, in-progress options on the single-podcast page)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[x] Added completion icons on the single-podcast page&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[x] Better handling of episode page navigation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[x] Resolved refreshing inconsistencies across pages&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[x] Improved podcast index ID handling&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[x] Fixed up episode ordering accuracy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[x] Various other css and visual bug fixes in various spots &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you to the community for your continued support and feedback! If you notice any lingering issues when subscribing to YouTube channels, or anything else, please open an issue!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Happy podcasting! 🎧🚀&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/madeofpendletonwool/PinePods/releases/tag/0.7.3" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
