<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://selfh.st/apps</id>
  <title>Plane Releases</title>
  <updated>2024-10-24T18:32:27.077012-04:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>selfh.st</name>
    <email>contact@selfh.st</email>
  </author>
  <link href="https://selfh.st/apps" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>Self-hosted software releases generated by selfh.st</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/makeplane/plane/releases/tag/v0.23.0</id>
    <title>New release for Plane: v0.23.0</title>
    <updated>2024-10-07T09:30:50-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>makeplane/plane</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;Here's everything that's new and better on Community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;❗❗ IMPORTANT: When upgrading to v0.23, make sure you are using the latest version of Docker Compose. If you are on a custom Docker setup, you'll need to install RabbitMQ and provide the necessary env variables in app-env.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;✨ New Features&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Lossless edits and version history in Pages&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Collaborate on Pages with your team without losing edits. Track changes in Pages with a version history going back 20 edits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Favorites&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Easily organize and access your favorite pages, projects, views, cycles, and modules under &lt;code&gt;Your Favourites&lt;/code&gt; on the sidebar on the left.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;👀 Improvements&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Guests can no longer create issues in projects or edit them. They can continue to create issues in Intake and see them through until they are closed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Viewers are now gone. Invite folks in as a Guest and toggle ↓ on to let them view all issues.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Three new external API endpoints are added. You can now add members to your workspace and projects, and attach files to issues with external IDs and sources.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Inbox&lt;/code&gt; is now &lt;code&gt;Intake&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;Notifications&lt;/code&gt; is now &lt;code&gt;Inbox&lt;/code&gt;. Simpler, we think.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pressing &lt;code&gt;/&lt;/code&gt; now brings the focus to a page.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The placeholder &lt;code&gt;Press / for commands&lt;/code&gt; in issue comments is now &lt;code&gt;Add comments&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Updated empty state image for project views.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Load more&lt;/code&gt; in layouts is now blue for better visibility.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Private pages can now be made public even when locked. The reverse is also true.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;My Work&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;My Projects&lt;/code&gt; are now &lt;code&gt;Your Work&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;Your Projects&lt;/code&gt;. It's all yours, after all.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Only admins and creators of issues, cycles, modules, views, and pages can delete them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The look and feel of your Profile is now better.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The drag experience in the page editor is now smoother.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clicking cycle stats now takes you to the cycle details page with relevant filters applied.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved UI for the empty state of workspace notifications.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Images can now be viewed in an expanded view by clicking on the expand icon on the image.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Removed &lt;code&gt;Workspace setting&lt;/code&gt;  form the sidebar now you can access it from the workspace dropdown.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;🐛 Bug fixes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Empty state for Views now has a button to add issues.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Archived sub-issues will now show under Archives by default.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Long project names are now truncated in the project dropdown in Analytics.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Left navbar auto-collapses on small screens.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tooltips no longer overlap in the icon select dropdown in Pages.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed text overflow in the project select dropdown in &lt;code&gt;Export Issue&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Leaving a project now redirects you to the home screen without refreshing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CMD + Z now works fine in issue descriptions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A warning now appears if you forget to add a title to an issue.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Switching projects resets filters applied on intake issues.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Restoring or deleting issues updates the issue count in the archived issues header.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Headings 4, 5, and 6 in markdown now work as they should.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed color inconsistencies in table headers for bold text.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Issue widgets for archived issues are no longer editable.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changes to issue details now instantly reflect on the issue cards in the calendar layout.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clicking &lt;code&gt;Mark as read&lt;/code&gt; now updates the inbox count properly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mentioning a user no longer causes the focus to disappear.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Removing an issue from a cycle now removes it from the board immediately.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Long display names (over 20 characters) now trigger an error message.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pressing Shift + Return in to-do lists correctly adds a new checkbox.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The image resizer outline now aligns correctly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All details are now visible at the bottom of &lt;code&gt;My work&lt;/code&gt; page.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changing layouts or adding display options no longer hides the &lt;code&gt;Update View&lt;/code&gt; button.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The progress bar now shows all state groups with their respective colors and state names on hover.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Workspace admins can now change the roles of other admins.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Exported issue file status updates automatically when processing is complete.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Toggling full-width mode in Pages is now faster in Safari.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Adding duplicate labels now shows a toast notification.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Adding an image to the &lt;code&gt;Create Issue&lt;/code&gt; modal no longer pulls images from a page.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cycle dates can no longer be changed for completed cycles.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Page links now work just fine.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Switching cycles or modules works even when one sidebar is already open.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Adding a parent to an issue from the peek-over view no longer reloads the screen.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Removed users’ avatars no longer appear on project cards.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Casing is now consistent throughout the platform.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Snoozed issues with past due dates no longer show the incorrect time remaining.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deleting a cycle, module, view, or page no longer shows a false "failed to delete" toast notification.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;code&gt;Help&lt;/code&gt; icon in the left navbar is better aligned.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Unauthorized users trying to delete issues now see the correct toast alert.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Password field no longer comes pre-filled during login.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Project members can no longer delete inbox issues.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Text overflow on hover is fixed for empty state comic buttons.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An error message now appears when you don't have permission to view a page.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed double placeholders for list items.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;After onboarding, users are now correctly redirected to the workspace.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Padding around the login screen is now consistent across all screen sizes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Module progress charts now switch between points and issues for archived modules.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;🏗️ Infra&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fixed &lt;a href="http://setup.sh"&gt;setup.sh&lt;/a&gt; for macOS support&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;setup.sh&lt;/code&gt; now runs smoothly on macOS, so you can install and set up Plane on your Mac without the previous issues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Self-hosted custom build&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can now create custom containerized versions of your self-hosted instance to suit your specific self-hosting setup.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/makeplane/plane/releases/tag/v0.23.0" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/makeplane/plane/releases/tag/v0.23.1</id>
    <title>New release for Plane: v0.23.1</title>
    <updated>2024-10-10T11:26:22-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>makeplane/plane</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h3&gt;⚙️ Improvements&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can now copy issue IDs by simply clicking on it once.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can now add more complex URLs to issue details.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;🪲 Bugs squashed&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Project admins can now change the project settings.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The drag handle in Pages scrolls smoothly now.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Guests can see images in full width across all editors.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No more flicker when making dropdown changes in the Table layout.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed aspect ratio issue with resizing images in editor&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;🔒 Security Patch&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Updated Django from 4.2.15 to 4.2.16&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/makeplane/plane/releases/tag/v0.23.1" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
