<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://selfh.st/apps</id>
  <title>PlanarAlly Releases</title>
  <updated>2025-08-04T08:38:05.245592-04:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>selfh.st</name>
    <email>contact@selfh.st</email>
  </author>
  <link href="https://selfh.st/apps" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>Self-hosted software releases generated by selfh.st</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/Kruptein/PlanarAlly/releases/tag/2025.1</id>
    <title>New release for PlanarAlly: Release 2025.1</title>
    <updated>2025-01-31T13:33:06-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Kruptein/PlanarAlly</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;For more details on what's new checkout https://www.planarally.io/blog/release-2025.1/&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;planarally-bin provides a prebuilt client, with a python server that you'll need to run yourself.
planarally-windows provides a compiled executable that can simply be run by double clicking the exe in the planarally-windows-2022.3 folder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check the documentation over at https://www.planarally.io for more info&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The changelog for this release:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Added&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Draw tool:&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added default colours for walls, windows, doors&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;These get automatically applied when the relevant vision/logic settings are enabled in the draw tool&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Can be disabled by unchecking the 'prefer default colours' checkbox in the draw tool vision settings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The specific colours used can be configured in the user options Appearance section and will update shapes retroactively&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Notes:&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Notes can now be popped out to a separate window&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;NoteManager:&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added a button to clear the current search&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In-Game Assets UI:&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Option to search through assets&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Option to add folder shortcuts per campaign&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;These allow quicker navigation to frequently used folders&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A "All assets" shortcut is always available&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[server] Assets:&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;limits:&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added limits to the total size of assets a user can upload and the size of a single asset&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;These limits can be configured in the server config&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;By default there are no limits, it's up to the server admin to configure them&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;These limits will only apply to new assets, existing assets are not affected&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Thumbnails:&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The server will now generate thumbnails for all assets&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Changed&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dashboard:&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed some border colours in the create new game menu&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MenuBar:&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add Notes button for players&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[tech] Select tool:&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Delayed syncing of selection state to the global state from mouse down to mouse move/up&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This fixes some of the entries in the Fixed section&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;AssetManager:&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed UI of renaming assets, allowing inline editing rather than opening a popup&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The images shown in the asset manager will now use the thumbnail of the asset if available&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This should reduce load times and improve general performance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This also applies to the preview when hovering over assets in the in-game assets sidebar&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Remove initiated from the context menu now removes the entire selection&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Context menu retains selection unless an item not in the current selection is clicked&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In-game assets:&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sidebar is removed and replaced with a new Assets dialog similar to notes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The new UI has almost full compatibility with the assets in the dashboard&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Notes:&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add filtering option 'All' to note manager to show both global and local notes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Note popouts for clients without edit access now show 'view source' instead of 'edit'&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dice tool:&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Last result is now displayed in the dice tool rather than a popup window&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Result breakdowns are shown in the last result display and history&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added a reroll button to quickly redo the previous roll&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added a reroll button to history entries&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add an option to roll 3D dice inside a dice box rather than over the playfield&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Input field now scrolls to the end after populating via the on screen buttons&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;@planarally/dice:&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(this is the standalone dice library that handles most of the dice logic and rendering)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Upgraded to v0.7&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dice will now stop sliding smoother&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clear state can be configured&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;D100 dice now properly work in 3D for the full range (1-100 / 0-99)&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Currently hardcoded to 1-100 in the client, but the library can be told otherwise&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I18n:&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added 95% i18n for zh (except diceTool)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[server] Assets:&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Assets are no longer stored in a flat folder structure, but instead use a subpath based structure&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An asset with hash &lt;code&gt;35eaef2e9a116aa152f7f161f1281411cb1e1375&lt;/code&gt; is now stored as &lt;code&gt;assets/35/ea/35eaef2e9a116aa152f7f161f1281411cb1e1375&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[tech] Systems: Move system-core from game/ to core/ so that it can also be used by e.g. assets&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Removed&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Labels:&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As mentioned in the last 2 releases these were going to be removed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I wasn't happy with the current implementation and they were causing more confusion than they were useful&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This also removes the Filter Tool&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;.paa asset handling&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This was no longer really maintained and the current frontend doesn't offer any support for it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Fixed&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Notes:&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It was possible to open a 'view-only' note on a tab you weren't supposed to see&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Note manager could be empty and unusable when changing locations or losing view access to an open note&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Search filter not resetting page to 1 potentially causing a blank page if on an other page&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Default edit access on notes was not correctly applied&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix searchbar overlapping over other modals&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Global notes no longer have a default access level&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Notes can no longer be locally edited by clients without edit access through the note popouts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Shape Properties:&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Input changes could not persist or save on the wrong shape if selection focus was changed while editing (see selection changes)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Modals&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dragging modals (e.g. notes) now also brings them to the foreground as if clicked&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Composites:&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Moving composites to a different location could sometimes lead to errors on the client even though the moves were succesful serverside&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Select Tool:&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Snapping an existing shape point to some other point could be overriden with a snap to the grid&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Game Listing:&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clicking on a session that shares a name with another session would foldout both&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/Kruptein/PlanarAlly/releases/tag/2025.1" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/Kruptein/PlanarAlly/releases/tag/2025.1.1</id>
    <title>New release for PlanarAlly: Release 2025.1.1</title>
    <updated>2025-02-08T06:21:19-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Kruptein/PlanarAlly</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;This is a fix to the docker &amp;amp; windows builds, no other changes were made.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See https://github.com/Kruptein/PlanarAlly/releases/tag/2025.1 for the main release notes.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/Kruptein/PlanarAlly/releases/tag/2025.1.1" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/Kruptein/PlanarAlly/releases/tag/v2025.2.0</id>
    <title>New release for PlanarAlly: </title>
    <updated>2025-06-14T10:24:20-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Kruptein/PlanarAlly</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;For more details on what's new checkout https://www.planarally.io/blog/release-2025.2/&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;planarally-bin provides a prebuilt client, with a python server that you'll need to run yourself.
planarally-windows provides a compiled executable that can simply be run by double clicking the exe in the planarally-windows-2022.3 folder. (~~note an issue with the windows build occurred, which I'll rectify with a separate v2025.2.1 release later~~ this has been resolved)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check the documentation over at https://www.planarally.io for more info&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The changelog for this release:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Server owners:&lt;/strong&gt; The server config has changed location and format. Ensure you check the release notes for the necessary info.
The old config files are not yet removed from git to prevent losing modifications you made to these files.
They will be removed in a future release though.
The server is now also managed using &lt;a href="https://docs.astral.sh/uv/"&gt;uv&lt;/a&gt;, if you manually manage the server using python/pip directly instead of using docker, you need to install this as well. See the server's readme for details.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Added&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New quick toggle to disable LoS rendering for the DM only&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Forgot password flow if Mail is configured on the server&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This only works if the user account actually has an email-address&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Success notification when changing email in the settings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mod improvements&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Can now register shape context menu entries&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Upload/Remove mods for a specific campaign&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Asset create folder/upload file/remove buttons to the in-game asset browser&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[server] Email configuration setup&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[server] Anonymous stat collection&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sends usage stats about number of campaigns and users to stats.planarally.io&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Identifiers are anonymized, no personal info is included&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Can be disabled&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Changed&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Access levels are no longer additive&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;e.g. edit access used to automatically include movement &amp;amp; vision access, this is no longer the case&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Selection draw box now appears on top of the fog&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Selection rotate UI now appears on top fo the fog&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Moved zoom bar and selection info behind main modals when overlapping&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the selection info can pop-over when hovered with the mouse&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[server] Server config setup has changed&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The server config is now by default stored in the &lt;code&gt;data&lt;/code&gt; directory and in toml format&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It's no longer tracked in git, as the default values are now coded in python itself&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An env variable can be used to change the location&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changes to the config are now checked and loaded by the server during runtime&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[tech] Server shutdown sequence has been modified&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[tech] Mod improvements&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;DataBlock API changes&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Made most functions sync&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Save method renamed to &lt;code&gt;sync&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;API added to handle reactivity inside the datablock&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Now listens to saved events from other clients to update local data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No longer runs the (de)serializer per key, but instead just on the entirety, alloweing root arrays&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added utility &lt;code&gt;useDataBlock&lt;/code&gt; hook to reduce a lot of boilerplate in mod components&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Serialize and Deserialize generic order are swapped&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Now expects a root level &lt;code&gt;events&lt;/code&gt; object with event functions instead of them being exported&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Remove registerTrackerSettings event&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Removed&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;code&gt;isToken&lt;/code&gt; property has been removed from all shapes&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This is now fully derived based on vision access of the shape&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Fixed&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Draw tool polygon was not updating vision until shape completion&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reduced some render overhead when token shapes that the player did not own were moved&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Shape context menu not closing when selecting an option&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Select tool build UI not appearing when mode toggling&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Datablocks for room and user categories had a bug in the server preventing creating them&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Asset context-menu remove not working&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Asset context-menu background colour being wrong in-game sometimes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Asset upload bar missing in the dashboard asset manager&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Asset picker out of game now uses the newer UI&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dropping assets you have shared-view permission for on the map was not working&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Movement only door toggle not immediately rerendering screen&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Select tool UI would sometimes stick around when there is no shape selected anymore&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/Kruptein/PlanarAlly/releases/tag/v2025.2.0" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/Kruptein/PlanarAlly/releases/tag/v2025.2.1</id>
    <title>New release for PlanarAlly: </title>
    <updated>2025-06-15T12:53:00-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Kruptein/PlanarAlly</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;This contains some small fixes/additions to the new mail setup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Added&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SSL email configuration&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Choose between START TLS / TLS / SSL / LMTP for smtp connection&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Fixed&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mail not working in envs where username env is missing (e.g. docker)&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This is a problem in the mail lib used, but circumvented in the Dockerfile&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mail error showing a 500 error in the client&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Email setup reset when the config changes to make sure new email values are used&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/Kruptein/PlanarAlly/releases/tag/v2025.2.1" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/Kruptein/PlanarAlly/releases/tag/v2025.2.2</id>
    <title>New release for PlanarAlly: </title>
    <updated>2025-06-19T13:18:06-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Kruptein/PlanarAlly</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;This is a small release that fixes three bugs reported on the latest release:
- Initiative effect rename losing focus after pressing 1 character
- Locked shapes not being selectable directly
- DM only auras where no longer rendered due to a bug in the new access logic&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/Kruptein/PlanarAlly/releases/tag/v2025.2.2" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
