<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://selfh.st/apps</id>
  <title>Plane Releases</title>
  <updated>2025-03-30T21:32:32.723403-04:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>selfh.st</name>
    <email>contact@selfh.st</email>
  </author>
  <link href="https://selfh.st/apps" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>Self-hosted software releases generated by selfh.st</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/makeplane/plane/releases/tag/v0.24.1</id>
    <title>New release for Plane: v0.24.1</title>
    <updated>2024-12-10T11:22:15-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>makeplane/plane</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;✨ New Features&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Real-Time Sync Enhancements on Pages&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When a member locks, unlocks, archives, or restores a page, it immediately happens for all users with access to that page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;⚙️ Improvements&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved UX by replacing User Notification Settings checkboxes with toggles&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pages access revamped for better security and flexibility, Guests can no longer create or edit pages.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Loader code refactor to improve page load performance.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reduced unused components to optimise application performance.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added sort order for issue activity.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Simplified navigation by removing Project Header Breadcrumb navigation from &lt;code&gt;project&lt;/code&gt; breadcrumb.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Preserved custom theme colors while checking todo list items in pages.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enhanced URL clarity for published Projects, Views, and Pages with meta data.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Optimized image aspect rations in pages across different screen resolutions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enhanced Hyper Mode performance with minor changes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added functionality to redirect users to the homepage when clicking the Plane logo on the invitations page.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;🐞 Bug Fixes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed an issue with estimates when enabled and not associated with any issue in the project is deleting the project&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Addressed an issue where removed cycles continued to appear in the issue detail page. The cycles list now dynamically updates to reflect changes accurately.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed a visibility issue with dropdown filters on Safari browsers to ensure consistent user experience across platforms.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed markdown rendering for images in pages.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Removed unused components to optimise application performance.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;UI fix for the shape of priority icons for improved visual clarity.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;Resolved intake issue permissions where users with member-level permissions couldn't edit their own issue immediately after creation without refreshing the page.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;🔑 Security&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Resolved Nivo Charts vulnerabilities.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Django and Express version upgraded for improved compatibility and security.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Updated UI package module resolution for better dependency management.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/makeplane/plane/releases/tag/v0.24.1" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/makeplane/plane/releases/tag/v0.25.0</id>
    <title>New release for Plane: v0.25.0</title>
    <updated>2025-02-24T10:20:56-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>makeplane/plane</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;The wait will be worth it. Bringing you the &lt;code&gt;v0.25.0&lt;/code&gt;. More features, more stability, more performance, and more secure. The notes might be brief, but this release is packed with over 400+ commits. Hit the &lt;a href="https://developers.plane.so/self-hosting/manage/upgrade-plane#community-edition"&gt;upgrade&lt;/a&gt; button as soon as you can!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;✨ New Features&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Introducing a brand new Home&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Home, now revamped from tons of your feedback, is now deliberately beautiful, extremely useful, and refactored for flexibility, whether you want to turn off everything or keep it all on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="60a5abd59d7d44068027ebea7fe90984-image" src="https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/95efe494-990e-4877-b5d5-78065d8694b4" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Widget controls&lt;/strong&gt; let you customize what you see and act on when you get Home.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Quicklinks&lt;/strong&gt; lets you paste links from anywhere should you want them handy as you go about your day.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Smart Recents&lt;/strong&gt; shows you a mixed bag of Plane entities so you can pick up from where you left.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can't wait to see how you use the new Home and what, if anything, doesn't work at all.&lt;a href="https://discord.com/invite/A92xrEGCge"&gt;Let us know&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;📘 Read more on &lt;a href="https://docs.plane.so/core-concepts/account/overview"&gt;Docs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;✍️ Issues are now Work Items&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the longest time, our top users and adopters were developers. &lt;code&gt;Issues&lt;/code&gt; made sense to them, and while they had a slightly negative meaning, other teams made do. Our audience split started changing after we launched Pro last year, though, and by the end of the year, we had overwhelming feedback, even from developers, to trade &lt;code&gt;Issues&lt;/code&gt; in for a more neutral term so more teams could get on Plane.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="ed0872a544ef481fa6bd97f8a11520dc-image" src="https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/7b6d14b9-04de-4f34-b7e0-f27d4ede44cc" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Introducing &lt;code&gt;Work Items&lt;/code&gt; as a worthy successor and a term that's wide in accommodating all teams anywhere&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Related changes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sub-issues&lt;/strong&gt; are now &lt;strong&gt;Sub-work items&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Issue Types&lt;/strong&gt; are now &lt;strong&gt;Work Item Types&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Work Items&lt;/strong&gt; goes beyond traditional issue tracking to more project management use cases in more teams than ever before.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It folds any term you like into a type, unlocked with &lt;strong&gt;Work Item Types&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It is the first of several planned steps to make Plane more collaborative, unifying, and flexible.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Customizable&lt;/strong&gt; left-nav pane&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Customize your left-nav pane with things you want at your fingertips and hide all else away for when you need them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="0308e9a579434aa9b9f75dcf5c6a862d-03" src="https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/4e219f31-8380-4e2d-94b0-cacb451dc630" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Short URLs for work items with Browse&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Who says you need to see sixteen-thousand characters in your work items’ URL when just eleven will do? Introducing &lt;code&gt;/browse/&lt;/code&gt; as the gateway to all your work items. Just add your work items’ ID to &lt;code&gt;instance-url/browse/**&lt;/code&gt; and voila!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Workspace invite links&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Invite someone to your workspace OR send them a link to join. Easy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="b14297dfe46d44ffacddf112e7e44a09-changelo-feb24-2" src="https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/8f75e867-495e-4fd4-a975-a080abdad422" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;🌍 Plane goes global with Language Support in beta&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use Plane in a language of your choice, starting with French, Spanish, and Japanese and several tens more planned in 2025. Available across all plans, making project collaboration truly global.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="43ef78debf434bf79af361af98796519-image" src="https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/1cdf0205-93aa-43e4-a2d7-fdd9ec7bd152" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We welcome contributions to language translations. Read the guidelines &lt;a href="https://github.com/makeplane/plane/blob/preview/CONTRIBUTING.md#contributing-to-language-support"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;🚀 Improvements&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;UI/UX Enhancements&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enhanced workspace experience with redesigned switcher and improved invitation system&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added floating toolbar functionality for pages&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enhanced date picker functionalities with improved user controls&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Updated empty states across the application for better user feedback&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved project navigation with enhanced breadcrumb redirection&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Project &amp;amp; Work item Management&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added functionality to add labels directly from dropdown&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enhanced project dropdown component with multiple selection capability&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added attachment support in intake work items&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added work item attachment external API endpoint&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enhanced member management with improved drop-downs and project member lists&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Performance&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Optimized project APIs for better performance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enhanced component modularity across the application: &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Command palette&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rich text editor with member mentions support&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Title/description loader&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Workspace invitation system&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Refactored pages' components for improved scalability&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Updated Home Quick links CRUD operations with validation and custom methods&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enhanced project cover image update functionality&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Resolved Cmd+k work items actions on work item detail pages.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Handled shift tab tab-index focus properly on work item create modal.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;🐛 Bug Fixes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Work item Management&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed mutation problem with work item properties while accepting intake work items&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Retained work item description when creating work item copies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added work item serializer to remove deleted labels and assignees&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed sub-work item collapsible visibility&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Restricted guest users from assignees and mentions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved handling of equal start and end dates in cycle creation and updates&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Disabled comment submit during image upload&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;UI/UX Fixes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enhanced image handling: &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved zooming for fullscreen images with proper magnification&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added trackpad pinch zoom support&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Implemented smooth movement of zoomed images&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved editor experience: &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Implemented smooth scrolling while dragging and dropping nodes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Removed drag handles from table cell content&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enhanced scroll thresholds and drag handling speed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed workspace-level toggle position, paddings, and tab navigation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Performance&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Avoided unnecessary API calls while creating work item drafts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Removed readonly collaborative document editor&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;🛠️ Deployments&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Docker Swarm support. Read more &lt;a href="https://github.com/makeplane/plane/pull/6406"&gt;[here](https://github.com/makeplane/plane/pull/6406)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;⬆️ System &amp;amp; Security&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Upgraded Django, Crypto and ESbuild versions to address vulnerability&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tiptap editor package version upgraded for better compatibility.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/makeplane/plane/releases/tag/v0.25.0" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/makeplane/plane/releases/tag/v0.25.1</id>
    <title>New release for Plane: v0.25.1</title>
    <updated>2025-03-05T08:52:46-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>makeplane/plane</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;Quick patch that improves workflow efficiency and fixes important bugs from &lt;code&gt;v0.25.0&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;🚀 Improvements&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enhanced the date range picker on the list of cycles and modules to save dates as they are selected&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Removed the &lt;code&gt;Apply changes&lt;/code&gt; button&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added validation for work item assignees to ensure work items remain assigned to members who join a workspace after being removed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved work item creation in Intake&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Updated Russian translations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added Italian translation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;🐞 Bug fixes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Implemented project ID validation for work item activity logging&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed an issue where attachment counts weren't updating when adding attachments to work items in peek view or detail view&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed an issue when transferring work items from completed cycles&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed screen flicker when module properties are updated on the Modules' List layout&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When navigating to Workspace Settings or any other screen from the Workspace Switcher, we now automatically close the Switcher.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/makeplane/plane/releases/tag/v0.25.1" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/makeplane/plane/releases/tag/v0.25.2</id>
    <title>New release for Plane: v0.25.2</title>
    <updated>2025-03-11T06:38:33-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>makeplane/plane</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h3&gt;🚀 Improvements&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added ability to disable comment submission while images are uploading.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sidebar projects list is now always expanded on load.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Updated several translations in all languages.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added Czech language support.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added a configuration option to enforce HTTPS when connecting to minio as object store.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;🐞 Bugfixes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed the issue with work item state changes removing assignees.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed overflowing issue in delete page modal with long page titles.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added additional padding to editor container for consistent UI across all resolutions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;🔒 Security&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Upgraded Django version to resolve vulnerabilities.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/makeplane/plane/releases/tag/v0.25.2" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/makeplane/plane/releases/tag/v0.25.3</id>
    <title>New release for Plane: v0.25.3</title>
    <updated>2025-03-21T08:03:38-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>makeplane/plane</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;🌍 Expanded language support&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We've added support for even more languages! You can now use Plane in: Slovenian, German, Ukrainian, Polish, Korean, and Traditional Chinese.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;⚡️ Improvements&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;Pin items on the sidebar for easier Workspace navigation.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Refined Celery cron configurations for better synchronization and more efficient background task processing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Command palette now delivers more relevant search results&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;🐛 Bug fixes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Resolved consistency issues in space app icons.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed incomplete activity rendering in notifications in the peek-over pane.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Favorites menu now opens by default for improved accessibility.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed issue preventing admins from deleting views created by other admins.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Corrected a security issue where guests could view all work items when HyperMode was enabled.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed live server dev port to 3100.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed Modules list sidebar positioning.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Corrected mutation issues in Favorites quick action.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/makeplane/plane/releases/tag/v0.25.3" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
