<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://selfh.st/apps</id>
  <title>Plane Releases</title>
  <updated>2025-07-12T14:33:11.158046-04:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>selfh.st</name>
    <email>contact@selfh.st</email>
  </author>
  <link href="https://selfh.st/apps" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>Self-hosted software releases generated by selfh.st</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/makeplane/plane/releases/tag/v0.25.3</id>
    <title>New release for Plane: v0.25.3</title>
    <updated>2025-03-21T08:03:38-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>makeplane/plane</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;🌍 Expanded language support&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We've added support for even more languages! You can now use Plane in: Slovenian, German, Ukrainian, Polish, Korean, and Traditional Chinese.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;⚡️ Improvements&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;Pin items on the sidebar for easier Workspace navigation.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Refined Celery cron configurations for better synchronization and more efficient background task processing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Command palette now delivers more relevant search results&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;🐛 Bug fixes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Resolved consistency issues in space app icons.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed incomplete activity rendering in notifications in the peek-over pane.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Favorites menu now opens by default for improved accessibility.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed issue preventing admins from deleting views created by other admins.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Corrected a security issue where guests could view all work items when HyperMode was enabled.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed live server dev port to 3100.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed Modules list sidebar positioning.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Corrected mutation issues in Favorites quick action.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/makeplane/plane/releases/tag/v0.25.3" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/makeplane/plane/releases/tag/v0.26.0</id>
    <title>New release for Plane: v0.26.0</title>
    <updated>2025-04-28T09:02:01-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>makeplane/plane</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;Our latest update brings significant improvements to the editor experience, adds five new languages, and includes numerous refinements to make your project management more intuitive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/npm/emoji-datasource-apple/img/apple/64/26a0-fe0f.png" alt="9888-65039" width="30px" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Important Configuration Change&lt;/strong&gt;\
Starting with version &lt;code&gt;v0.26.0&lt;/code&gt;, you must set either &lt;code&gt;APP_BASE_URL&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;WEB_URL&lt;/code&gt; in your &lt;code&gt;plane.env&lt;/code&gt; file for proper functionality. And update the Docker-compose and setup.sh to latest version.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;📝 Edit history&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now track who changed Work Item, Epic and Intake descriptions and when. Click the timestamp to see a complete history of edits, improving transparency in collaborative work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;🌍 &lt;strong&gt;New language support&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can now use Plane in: &lt;strong&gt;Romanian&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Indonesian&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Brazilian Portuguese&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Vietnamese&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;Turkish&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;⚡ Enhancements&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Moved Page icon picker inside the editor, plus improved width and layout for easier reading&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Project states now expand by default, and floating link tooltips work smoothly across all editors&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Users are now redirected to the workspace after accepting an invitation instead of Profile page.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Revamped headers for cycles, modules, pages, and views for visual consistency&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Updated billing and plans interface with a cleaner, more intuitive design&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create Account button is now hidden when signups are disabled in environment settings.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added translation support for Estimates&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added support for .sql file attachments.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added error toast message for .svg image upload failures.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;🔧 Bug fixes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed "Copy markdown to clipboard" functionality&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Corrected cycle dates to reflect the project's timezone&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed the issue where workspace role upgrades weren't properly carrying over to project level after a downgrade&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Eliminated duplicate work item sequences that were being generated&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed the count of subscribed issues in Your Work section to show the correct number&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stopped duplicate comments from appearing when you press Enter multiple times&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed the password change form for users who skipped password setup during onboarding&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Solved the issue where assignees weren't updating properly in Board layout when using sub-grouping&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed assets upload error in issue descriptions when switching project IDs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added error handling for link editing in the editor.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;🔒 Security&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Updated gunicorn to the latest version for improved performance and security&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Upgraded Next.js dependencies to address vulnerabilities&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Updated tsup version for better build optimization and security enhancements&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/makeplane/plane/releases/tag/v0.26.0" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/makeplane/plane/releases/tag/v0.26.1</id>
    <title>New release for Plane: v0.26.1</title>
    <updated>2025-06-06T08:32:24-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>makeplane/plane</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h2&gt;⚡ Enhancements&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Updated API service startup checks to use more reliable HTTP requests instead of log monitoring.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved backup and restore scripts for better containerized data handling.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Upgraded Next.js and Django versions for better performance, security, and stability.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/makeplane/plane/releases/tag/v0.26.1" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/makeplane/plane/releases/tag/v0.27.0</id>
    <title>New release for Plane: v0.27.0</title>
    <updated>2025-07-01T08:24:09-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>makeplane/plane</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h3&gt;July 1, 2025 · v0.27.0&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;📊 Analytics 2.0&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We've completely revamped our analytics experience from the ground up! Analytics 2.0 brings powerful data insights with a redesigned interface and enhanced capabilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://docs.plane.so/core-concepts/analytics"&gt;📖 Learn more&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/2d9af7a6-5fda-4bd5-87ca-7c89474b1b08" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;🧭 Revamped breadcrumbs&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We've completely redesigned the breadcrumb navigation system to be more than just a simple path indicator. Instead of static text showing your path, breadcrumbs now serve as navigation hubs. Whether you're deep in project pages or browsing through different sections, you can quickly pivot to related content or go back to any level in the hierarchy with rich context about what's available at each step.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/700368a3-e7f4-4fbe-9b8d-6cd1600687e8" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;⚙️ Settings page revamp&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We've completely redesigned the Settings experience to make configuration management more intuitive and efficient. The new unified interface brings together Account, Workspace, and Project settings in one cohesive location.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/2eb557b8-2e28-49e6-9ffd-8cdbf2dc58c0" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;📅 Choose your week's start day&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now you can customize how calendars appear throughout Plane by setting your preferred first day of the week. Whether you follow a Sunday-start calendar, Monday-start workweek, or any other preference, Plane will display all date views according to your selection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This personalization option is available in &lt;strong&gt;Account Settings&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Preferences&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/185080fe-816c-4167-bbe2-efe3d7f14a43" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;⚡ Enhancements&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Optimized Workspace and Timeline layout queries for significantly improved performance.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New workspaces now include a demo project to help you get started immediately.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Members and admins can now create API tokens for automation and integrations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added comprehensive filter and grouping options for sub-work items&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added support for x-zip-compressed file attachments&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Project exports now include additional fields for more comprehensive data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Automatic redirection to newly created project view after creation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added select all/deselect all functionality in work item selection modals&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cycles now end at exactly 11:59 PM UTC on the end date&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Start and End dates now display as merged date ranges when both are updated&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added validation to prevent editing of archived work items&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;🔧 Bug fixes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed page table of contents overlapping with page content&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Resolved HTML character handling problems&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed alignment of project states in collapsed Kanban view&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Corrected AI environment variable configuration in God-mode&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added permission checks when duplicating project pages&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Resolved email notification template comments overflow&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;🔒 Security updates&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added restrictions for SVG file selection to prevent potential vulnerabilities&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Upgraded Django to version 4.2.22&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Updated Next.js to version 14.2.30&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Updated TypeScript to version 5.8.3&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Upgraded various security-related packages including tar-fs, brace-expansion, and TurboRepo&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/makeplane/plane/releases/tag/v0.27.0" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/makeplane/plane/releases/tag/v0.27.1</id>
    <title>New release for Plane: v0.27.1</title>
    <updated>2025-07-04T04:08:26-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>makeplane/plane</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h3&gt;Bug fixes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Resolved URL path generation issue causing double slashes in settings page links.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed UI misalignment in the top navigation bar of Work Item layouts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed minor translation issues in Workspace Analytics.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed bug preventing event trigger for Work Item comments submitted via external APIs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/makeplane/plane/releases/tag/v0.27.1" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
