<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://selfh.st/apps</id>
  <title>Plane Releases</title>
  <updated>2025-03-02T22:32:32.286409-05:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>selfh.st</name>
    <email>contact@selfh.st</email>
  </author>
  <link href="https://selfh.st/apps" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>Self-hosted software releases generated by selfh.st</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/makeplane/plane/releases/tag/v0.23.0</id>
    <title>New release for Plane: v0.23.0</title>
    <updated>2024-10-07T09:30:50-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>makeplane/plane</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;Here's everything that's new and better on Community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;❗❗ IMPORTANT: When upgrading to v0.23, make sure you are using the latest version of Docker Compose. If you are on a custom Docker setup, you'll need to install RabbitMQ and provide the necessary env variables in app-env.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;✨ New Features&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Lossless edits and version history in Pages&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Collaborate on Pages with your team without losing edits. Track changes in Pages with a version history going back 20 edits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Favorites&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Easily organize and access your favorite pages, projects, views, cycles, and modules under &lt;code&gt;Your Favourites&lt;/code&gt; on the sidebar on the left.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;👀 Improvements&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Guests can no longer create issues in projects or edit them. They can continue to create issues in Intake and see them through until they are closed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Viewers are now gone. Invite folks in as a Guest and toggle ↓ on to let them view all issues.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Three new external API endpoints are added. You can now add members to your workspace and projects, and attach files to issues with external IDs and sources.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Inbox&lt;/code&gt; is now &lt;code&gt;Intake&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;Notifications&lt;/code&gt; is now &lt;code&gt;Inbox&lt;/code&gt;. Simpler, we think.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pressing &lt;code&gt;/&lt;/code&gt; now brings the focus to a page.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The placeholder &lt;code&gt;Press / for commands&lt;/code&gt; in issue comments is now &lt;code&gt;Add comments&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Updated empty state image for project views.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Load more&lt;/code&gt; in layouts is now blue for better visibility.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Private pages can now be made public even when locked. The reverse is also true.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;My Work&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;My Projects&lt;/code&gt; are now &lt;code&gt;Your Work&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;Your Projects&lt;/code&gt;. It's all yours, after all.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Only admins and creators of issues, cycles, modules, views, and pages can delete them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The look and feel of your Profile is now better.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The drag experience in the page editor is now smoother.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clicking cycle stats now takes you to the cycle details page with relevant filters applied.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved UI for the empty state of workspace notifications.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Images can now be viewed in an expanded view by clicking on the expand icon on the image.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Removed &lt;code&gt;Workspace setting&lt;/code&gt;  form the sidebar now you can access it from the workspace dropdown.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;🐛 Bug fixes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Empty state for Views now has a button to add issues.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Archived sub-issues will now show under Archives by default.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Long project names are now truncated in the project dropdown in Analytics.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Left navbar auto-collapses on small screens.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tooltips no longer overlap in the icon select dropdown in Pages.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed text overflow in the project select dropdown in &lt;code&gt;Export Issue&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Leaving a project now redirects you to the home screen without refreshing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CMD + Z now works fine in issue descriptions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A warning now appears if you forget to add a title to an issue.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Switching projects resets filters applied on intake issues.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Restoring or deleting issues updates the issue count in the archived issues header.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Headings 4, 5, and 6 in markdown now work as they should.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed color inconsistencies in table headers for bold text.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Issue widgets for archived issues are no longer editable.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changes to issue details now instantly reflect on the issue cards in the calendar layout.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clicking &lt;code&gt;Mark as read&lt;/code&gt; now updates the inbox count properly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mentioning a user no longer causes the focus to disappear.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Removing an issue from a cycle now removes it from the board immediately.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Long display names (over 20 characters) now trigger an error message.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pressing Shift + Return in to-do lists correctly adds a new checkbox.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The image resizer outline now aligns correctly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All details are now visible at the bottom of &lt;code&gt;My work&lt;/code&gt; page.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changing layouts or adding display options no longer hides the &lt;code&gt;Update View&lt;/code&gt; button.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The progress bar now shows all state groups with their respective colors and state names on hover.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Workspace admins can now change the roles of other admins.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Exported issue file status updates automatically when processing is complete.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Toggling full-width mode in Pages is now faster in Safari.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Adding duplicate labels now shows a toast notification.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Adding an image to the &lt;code&gt;Create Issue&lt;/code&gt; modal no longer pulls images from a page.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cycle dates can no longer be changed for completed cycles.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Page links now work just fine.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Switching cycles or modules works even when one sidebar is already open.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Adding a parent to an issue from the peek-over view no longer reloads the screen.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Removed users’ avatars no longer appear on project cards.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Casing is now consistent throughout the platform.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Snoozed issues with past due dates no longer show the incorrect time remaining.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deleting a cycle, module, view, or page no longer shows a false "failed to delete" toast notification.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;code&gt;Help&lt;/code&gt; icon in the left navbar is better aligned.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Unauthorized users trying to delete issues now see the correct toast alert.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Password field no longer comes pre-filled during login.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Project members can no longer delete inbox issues.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Text overflow on hover is fixed for empty state comic buttons.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An error message now appears when you don't have permission to view a page.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed double placeholders for list items.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;After onboarding, users are now correctly redirected to the workspace.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Padding around the login screen is now consistent across all screen sizes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Module progress charts now switch between points and issues for archived modules.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;🏗️ Infra&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fixed &lt;a href="http://setup.sh"&gt;setup.sh&lt;/a&gt; for macOS support&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;setup.sh&lt;/code&gt; now runs smoothly on macOS, so you can install and set up Plane on your Mac without the previous issues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Self-hosted custom build&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can now create custom containerized versions of your self-hosted instance to suit your specific self-hosting setup.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/makeplane/plane/releases/tag/v0.23.0" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/makeplane/plane/releases/tag/v0.23.1</id>
    <title>New release for Plane: v0.23.1</title>
    <updated>2024-10-10T11:26:22-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>makeplane/plane</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h3&gt;⚙️ Improvements&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can now copy issue IDs by simply clicking on it once.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can now add more complex URLs to issue details.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;🪲 Bugs squashed&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Project admins can now change the project settings.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The drag handle in Pages scrolls smoothly now.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Guests can see images in full width across all editors.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No more flicker when making dropdown changes in the Table layout.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed aspect ratio issue with resizing images in editor&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;🔒 Security Patch&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Updated Django from 4.2.15 to 4.2.16&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/makeplane/plane/releases/tag/v0.23.1" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/makeplane/plane/releases/tag/v0.24.0</id>
    <title>New release for Plane: v0.24.0</title>
    <updated>2024-11-29T09:23:42-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>makeplane/plane</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;More performance, more security, and more beautiful. Read on to learn what's new and what has improved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;✨ New Features&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;⚡️ More perf. with Hyper Mode&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Switch layouts, apply filters, and open issues without loading screens (except Gantt view). While initial load may take a moment, subsequent actions are instantaneous thanks to our new no-load implementation. &lt;em&gt;Note: SSL configuration required for optimal security.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="CleanShot 2024-11-29 at 17 13 38" src="https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/0e93bd72-dad5-4e6f-91bd-14f16dec06f5" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;🔩 Introducing Workspace management from&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;code&gt;/god-mode&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You asked for it, and we've delivered. Instance administrators can now manage all workspaces directly from &lt;code&gt;/god-mode&lt;/code&gt;. View the total number of workspaces, track member activity, and access other essential metrics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="CleanShot 2024-11-29 at 17 40 42@2x" src="https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/d3f6bfb3-defe-4d11-8cf9-efdd4455e51a" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;✨ Callouts and text-alignment on Pages&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add callouts to your pages with a simple &lt;code&gt;/callout&lt;/code&gt; command. Create notes, warnings, tips, and more to highlight important information in your documentation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="CleanShot 2024-11-29 at 17 18 16@2x" src="https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/d76616f3-918b-4634-8025-def0fcdafacb" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All editors now support left, center, and right alignment for more professional-looking content.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="CleanShot 2024-11-29 at 17 21 10@2x" src="https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/2331fb7f-f348-44fc-bfe4-f8bbcf8d63c2" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;🔒 Enhanced data security for assets&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All assets on Plane—including attachments, cover images, profile pictures, logos, avatars, and images in issues and page descriptions—will now be stored in a private bucket. This upgrade means enhanced data security, so images uploaded to Plane will only be accessible within the platform. Read more &lt;a href="https://developers.plane.so/self-hosting/govern/private-bucket"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;🗞️ Workspace Drafts&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You will now find a new &lt;code&gt;Drafts&lt;/code&gt; section in the left navbar where all your drafts across all projects will show up. All under a single tab.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="CleanShot 2024-11-29 at 17 24 14@2x" src="https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/be19533a-1f37-46d0-8949-09f9e2116e0c" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;🛠️ Improvements&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Upload progress bars for Issue attachments: Track your file uploads in real-time so you know exactly when they're ready.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Better downtime communication: Clear maintenance page now shows when system updates are happening instead of blank screens.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Faster project navigation: Jump directly to favourite projects with one click - no more unnecessary sidebar scrolling.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Smarter issue linking: Redesigned interface makes it easier to connect and relate issues together.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Project consistency fix: Sub-issues now stay in their parent's project to maintain clear work hierarchies.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You'll now see a new &lt;code&gt;Language&lt;/code&gt; &lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1ALVs7CmunLtRpS3958rLvpyH4E6_FYlw/view?usp=drive_link"&gt;tab&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;code&gt;Profile Settings&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you have no items in favourites, workspace drafts, or active cycles, those sections will remain hidden for a cleaner interface.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The parent issue ID is now displayed at the top of the issue title in the peek-over view.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Layouts got &lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/16DRLn_Xup3M9qSNvaYxohK5kHVOo9per/view?usp=drive_link"&gt;new names&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;code&gt;Kanban&lt;/code&gt; is now called &lt;code&gt;Board&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;Gantt&lt;/code&gt; is now &lt;code&gt;Timeline&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code&gt;Spreadsheet&lt;/code&gt; is now &lt;code&gt;Table&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can now &lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1UxBUHkOl32UeAy1BayooFlNXSnd25A8K/view?usp=drive_link"&gt;export&lt;/a&gt; pages as PDF and markdown files.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;code&gt;Mark all as read&lt;/code&gt; option is now placed at the &lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1bpYmZu3ldECO6ORThXyb6OzFjNlbzERA/view?usp=drive_link"&gt;top&lt;/a&gt; of your Inbox for easy accessibility.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Editors now support text &lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1x6mONXw76mnXV6NcIwpWUHEoA_ZnXGX0/view?usp=drive_link"&gt;coloring&lt;/a&gt; and highlighting—no more plain black and white.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can now copy issue IDs by clicking on them once in peek-over view.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can now add more complex URLs to issue details links.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;🪲 Bugs crushed&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed notifications for removed users and project joins: Addressed an issue where notifications (inbox and emails) are incorrectly triggered or displayed when a user was removed from a project.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Resolved issues with relation issue IDs not visible in activity logs: Fixed a bug that prevented relation issue IDs from being displayed in the issue activity log, ensuring complete and transparent tracking of related issues.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Activity feed now instantly shows new attachments as they're uploaded.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed private project access: Members can no longer join via direct URL.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Project notifications stop when members are removed, even for subscribed issues.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Admins can now edit &lt;code&gt;Inbox&lt;/code&gt; issues directly from notification previews.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Calendar view: Clearer highlighting of current date for better navigation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Long project names now truncate nicely in analytics dropdown.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"Add Issue" button is now fully clickable (no more trying to hit that sweet spot!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Editor updates: Improved margins and fonts for better readability.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed parent issue pill styling in create issue modal.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Project members can't change other members' roles anymore,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Guests can now properly edit pages as intended.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reduced unnecessary API calls for snappier performance.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;🔒 Security Patch&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nivo Chart Package vulnerability is resolved.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/makeplane/plane/releases/tag/v0.24.0" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/makeplane/plane/releases/tag/v0.24.1</id>
    <title>New release for Plane: v0.24.1</title>
    <updated>2024-12-10T11:22:15-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>makeplane/plane</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;✨ New Features&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Real-Time Sync Enhancements on Pages&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When a member locks, unlocks, archives, or restores a page, it immediately happens for all users with access to that page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;⚙️ Improvements&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved UX by replacing User Notification Settings checkboxes with toggles&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pages access revamped for better security and flexibility, Guests can no longer create or edit pages.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Loader code refactor to improve page load performance.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reduced unused components to optimise application performance.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added sort order for issue activity.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Simplified navigation by removing Project Header Breadcrumb navigation from &lt;code&gt;project&lt;/code&gt; breadcrumb.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Preserved custom theme colors while checking todo list items in pages.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enhanced URL clarity for published Projects, Views, and Pages with meta data.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Optimized image aspect rations in pages across different screen resolutions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enhanced Hyper Mode performance with minor changes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added functionality to redirect users to the homepage when clicking the Plane logo on the invitations page.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;🐞 Bug Fixes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed an issue with estimates when enabled and not associated with any issue in the project is deleting the project&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Addressed an issue where removed cycles continued to appear in the issue detail page. The cycles list now dynamically updates to reflect changes accurately.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed a visibility issue with dropdown filters on Safari browsers to ensure consistent user experience across platforms.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed markdown rendering for images in pages.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Removed unused components to optimise application performance.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;UI fix for the shape of priority icons for improved visual clarity.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;Resolved intake issue permissions where users with member-level permissions couldn't edit their own issue immediately after creation without refreshing the page.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;🔑 Security&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Resolved Nivo Charts vulnerabilities.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Django and Express version upgraded for improved compatibility and security.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Updated UI package module resolution for better dependency management.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/makeplane/plane/releases/tag/v0.24.1" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/makeplane/plane/releases/tag/v0.25.0</id>
    <title>New release for Plane: v0.25.0</title>
    <updated>2025-02-24T10:20:56-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>makeplane/plane</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;The wait will be worth it. Bringing you the &lt;code&gt;v0.25.0&lt;/code&gt;. More features, more stability, more performance, and more secure. The notes might be brief, but this release is packed with over 400+ commits. Hit the &lt;a href="https://developers.plane.so/self-hosting/manage/upgrade-plane#community-edition"&gt;upgrade&lt;/a&gt; button as soon as you can!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;✨ New Features&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Introducing a brand new Home&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Home, now revamped from tons of your feedback, is now deliberately beautiful, extremely useful, and refactored for flexibility, whether you want to turn off everything or keep it all on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="60a5abd59d7d44068027ebea7fe90984-image" src="https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/95efe494-990e-4877-b5d5-78065d8694b4" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Widget controls&lt;/strong&gt; let you customize what you see and act on when you get Home.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Quicklinks&lt;/strong&gt; lets you paste links from anywhere should you want them handy as you go about your day.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Smart Recents&lt;/strong&gt; shows you a mixed bag of Plane entities so you can pick up from where you left.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can't wait to see how you use the new Home and what, if anything, doesn't work at all.&lt;a href="https://discord.com/invite/A92xrEGCge"&gt;Let us know&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;📘 Read more on &lt;a href="https://docs.plane.so/core-concepts/account/overview"&gt;Docs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;✍️ Issues are now Work Items&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the longest time, our top users and adopters were developers. &lt;code&gt;Issues&lt;/code&gt; made sense to them, and while they had a slightly negative meaning, other teams made do. Our audience split started changing after we launched Pro last year, though, and by the end of the year, we had overwhelming feedback, even from developers, to trade &lt;code&gt;Issues&lt;/code&gt; in for a more neutral term so more teams could get on Plane.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="ed0872a544ef481fa6bd97f8a11520dc-image" src="https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/7b6d14b9-04de-4f34-b7e0-f27d4ede44cc" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Introducing &lt;code&gt;Work Items&lt;/code&gt; as a worthy successor and a term that's wide in accommodating all teams anywhere&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Related changes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sub-issues&lt;/strong&gt; are now &lt;strong&gt;Sub-work items&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Issue Types&lt;/strong&gt; are now &lt;strong&gt;Work Item Types&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Work Items&lt;/strong&gt; goes beyond traditional issue tracking to more project management use cases in more teams than ever before.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It folds any term you like into a type, unlocked with &lt;strong&gt;Work Item Types&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It is the first of several planned steps to make Plane more collaborative, unifying, and flexible.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Customizable&lt;/strong&gt; left-nav pane&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Customize your left-nav pane with things you want at your fingertips and hide all else away for when you need them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="0308e9a579434aa9b9f75dcf5c6a862d-03" src="https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/4e219f31-8380-4e2d-94b0-cacb451dc630" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Short URLs for work items with Browse&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Who says you need to see sixteen-thousand characters in your work items’ URL when just eleven will do? Introducing &lt;code&gt;/browse/&lt;/code&gt; as the gateway to all your work items. Just add your work items’ ID to &lt;code&gt;instance-url/browse/**&lt;/code&gt; and voila!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Workspace invite links&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Invite someone to your workspace OR send them a link to join. Easy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="b14297dfe46d44ffacddf112e7e44a09-changelo-feb24-2" src="https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/8f75e867-495e-4fd4-a975-a080abdad422" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;🌍 Plane goes global with Language Support in beta&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use Plane in a language of your choice, starting with French, Spanish, and Japanese and several tens more planned in 2025. Available across all plans, making project collaboration truly global.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="43ef78debf434bf79af361af98796519-image" src="https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/1cdf0205-93aa-43e4-a2d7-fdd9ec7bd152" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We welcome contributions to language translations. Read the guidelines &lt;a href="https://github.com/makeplane/plane/blob/preview/CONTRIBUTING.md#contributing-to-language-support"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;🚀 Improvements&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;UI/UX Enhancements&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enhanced workspace experience with redesigned switcher and improved invitation system&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added floating toolbar functionality for pages&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enhanced date picker functionalities with improved user controls&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Updated empty states across the application for better user feedback&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved project navigation with enhanced breadcrumb redirection&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Project &amp;amp; Work item Management&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added functionality to add labels directly from dropdown&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enhanced project dropdown component with multiple selection capability&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added attachment support in intake work items&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added work item attachment external API endpoint&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enhanced member management with improved drop-downs and project member lists&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Performance&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Optimized project APIs for better performance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enhanced component modularity across the application: &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Command palette&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rich text editor with member mentions support&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Title/description loader&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Workspace invitation system&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Refactored pages' components for improved scalability&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Updated Home Quick links CRUD operations with validation and custom methods&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enhanced project cover image update functionality&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Resolved Cmd+k work items actions on work item detail pages.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Handled shift tab tab-index focus properly on work item create modal.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;🐛 Bug Fixes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Work item Management&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed mutation problem with work item properties while accepting intake work items&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Retained work item description when creating work item copies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added work item serializer to remove deleted labels and assignees&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed sub-work item collapsible visibility&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Restricted guest users from assignees and mentions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved handling of equal start and end dates in cycle creation and updates&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Disabled comment submit during image upload&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;UI/UX Fixes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enhanced image handling: &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved zooming for fullscreen images with proper magnification&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added trackpad pinch zoom support&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Implemented smooth movement of zoomed images&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved editor experience: &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Implemented smooth scrolling while dragging and dropping nodes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Removed drag handles from table cell content&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enhanced scroll thresholds and drag handling speed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed workspace-level toggle position, paddings, and tab navigation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Performance&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Avoided unnecessary API calls while creating work item drafts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Removed readonly collaborative document editor&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;🛠️ Deployments&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Docker Swarm support. Read more &lt;a href="https://github.com/makeplane/plane/pull/6406"&gt;[here](https://github.com/makeplane/plane/pull/6406)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;⬆️ System &amp;amp; Security&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Upgraded Django, Crypto and ESbuild versions to address vulnerability&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tiptap editor package version upgraded for better compatibility.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/makeplane/plane/releases/tag/v0.25.0" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
