<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://selfh.st/apps</id>
  <title>Pleroma Releases</title>
  <updated>2025-02-23T10:32:21.435476-05:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>selfh.st</name>
    <email>contact@selfh.st</email>
  </author>
  <link href="https://selfh.st/apps" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>Self-hosted software releases generated by selfh.st</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://git.pleroma.social/pleroma/pleroma/-/releases/v2.6.2</id>
    <title>New release for Pleroma: Pleroma Security Release 2.6.2</title>
    <updated>2024-02-20T08:45:08+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>pleroma/pleroma</name>
    </author>
    <content/>
    <link href="https://git.pleroma.social/pleroma/pleroma/-/releases/v2.6.2" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://git.pleroma.social/pleroma/pleroma/-/releases/v2.6.3</id>
    <title>New release for Pleroma: Security release 2.6.3</title>
    <updated>2024-05-22T15:19:04+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>pleroma/pleroma</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;Fixes an issue with webfinger impersonation&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://git.pleroma.social/pleroma/pleroma/-/releases/v2.6.3" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://git.pleroma.social/pleroma/pleroma/-/releases/v2.7.0</id>
    <title>New release for Pleroma: Pleroma 2.7.0</title>
    <updated>2024-08-01T13:18:11+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>pleroma/pleroma</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;Backend changes
Security&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;HTTP Security: By default, don’t allow unsafe-eval. The setting needs to be changed to allow Flash emulation.
Fix webfinger spoofing.
Use proper workers for fetching pins instead of an ad-hoc task, fixing a potential fetch loop
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Changed&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Update to Phoenix 1.7
Elixir Logger configuration is now longer permitted through AdminFE and ConfigDB
Refactor the user backups code and improve test coverage
Invalid activities delivered to the inbox will be rejected with a 400 Bad Request
Support Bandit as an alternative to Cowboy for the HTTP server.
Update Bandit to 1.5.2
Replace eblurhash with rinpatch_blurhash. This also removes a dependency on ImageMagick.
Elixir 1.13 is the minimum required version.
Document maximum supported version of Erlang &amp;amp; Elixir
Update and extend NetBSD installation docs
Make /api/v1/pleroma/federation_status publicly available
Increase outgoing federation parallelism
Change Hackney connection pool timeouts to align with the values Gun uses
Transmogrifier: handle non-validate errors on incoming Delete activities
Remote object fetch failures will prevent the object fetch job from retrying if the object request returns 401, 403, 404, 410, or exceeds the maximum thread depth.
- Change AccountView last_status_at from a datetime to a date (as done in Mastodon 3.1.0)
Improve error logging when LDAP authentication fails.
Publisher jobs will not retry if the error received is a 400
PollWorker jobs will not retry if the activity no longer exists.
Improved detecting unrecoverable errors for incoming federation jobs
Changed some jobs to return :cancel on unrecoverable errors that should not be retried
Discard Remote Fetcher jobs which errored due to an MRF rejection.
Oban queues have refactored to simplify the queue design
Ensure all Oban jobs have timeouts defined
Optimistic Inbox reduces the processing overhead of incoming activities without instantly verifiable signatures.
HTTP connection pool adjustments
Disable jit by default for PostgreSQL
Update the documentation for configuring Prometheus metrics.
Change the prometheus library to PromEx.
Publisher jobs now store the the activity id instead of inserting duplicate JSON data in the Oban queue for each delivery.
Activity publishing failures will prevent the job from retrying if the publishing request returns a 403 or 410
Publisher errors will now emit logs indicating the inbox that was not available for delivery.
Reduce the reachability timestamp update to a single upsert query
A 422 error is returned when attempting to reply to a deleted status
Rich Media backfilling is now an Oban job
Refactored Rich Media to cache the content in the database. Fetching operations that could block status rendering have been eliminated.
Set default values on validators for transient objects (attachment, poll options)
User profile refreshes are now asynchronous
Change mediaproxy previews to use vips to generate thumbnails instead of ImageMagick
Render nice web push notifications for polls
Refactor the Mastodon /api/v1/streaming websocket handler to use Phoenix.Socket.Transport
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Added&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Uploader: Add support for uploading attachments using IPFS
Add NSFW-detecting MRF
Add DNSRBL MRF
Add options to the mix prune_objects task
Add Anti-mention Spam MRF backported from Rebased
HTTPSignaturePlug: Add :authorizedfetchmode_exceptions configuration
Support /authorize-interaction route used by Mastodon
Add an option to reject certain domains when authorized fetch is enabled.
Include following/followers in backups
Allow to group bookmarks in folders
Include image description in status media cards
Implement /api/v1/accounts/familiar_followers
Add support for configuring favicon, embed favicon and PWA manifest in server-generated meta
Implement FEP-2c59, add “webfinger” to user actor
Framegrabs with ffmpeg will execute with a 5 second timeout and cache the URLs of failures with a TTL of 15 minutes to prevent excessive retries.
Added a Mix task “pleroma.config fixmrfpolicies” which will remove erroneous MRF policies from ConfigDB.
Add ForceMention MRF
[docs] add frontends management documentation
Implement group actors
Add contact account to InstanceView
Add instance rules
Implement /api/v2/instance route
Verify profile link ownership with rel="me”
Logger metadata is now attached to some logs to help with troubleshooting and analysis
Add new parameters to /api/v2/instance: configuration[accounts][maxpinnedstatuses] and configuration[statuses][charactersreservedper_url]
Add meilisearch, make search engines pluggable
Add missing indexes on foreign key relationships
Startup detection for configured MRF modules that are missing or incorrectly defined
Permit passing –chunk and –step values to the Pleroma.Search.Indexer Mix task
Deleting, Unfavoriting, Unrepeating, or Unreacting will cancel undelivered publishing jobs for the original activity.
Oban jobs can now be viewed in the Live Dashboard
Add media proxy to opengraph rich media cards
Support for Erlang OTP 26
Prioritize mentioned recipients (i.e., those that are not just followers) when federating.
PromEx documentation
Expose nonAnonymous field from Smithereen polls
Add Qdrant/OpenAI embedding search
Adds the capability to add a URL to a scrobble (optional field)
scrubbers/default: Add more formatting elements from HTML4 / GoToSocial (acronym, bdo, big, cite, dfn, ins, kbd, q, samp, s, tt, var, wbr)
Monitoring of search backend health to control the processing of jobs in the search indexing Oban queue
Display reposted replies with exclude_replies: true
Add “status” notification type
Support honk-style attachment summaries as alt-text.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fixed&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Fix Emoji object IDs not always being valid
Remove checking ImageMagick’s commands for Pleroma.Upload.Filter.AnalyzeMetadata
Ensure that StripLocation actually removes everything resembling GPS data from PNGs
Fix authentication check on account rendering when bio is defined
ap userview: add outbox field.
Fix #stripreportstatus_data
Fix federation with Convergence AP Bridge
ChatMessage: Tolerate attachment field set to an empty array
Config: Check the permissions of the linked file instead of the symlink
MediaProxy was setting the content-length header which is not permitted by RFC9112§6.2 when we are chunking the reply as it conflicts with the existence of the transfer-encoding header.
Restore Cowboy’s ability to stream MediaProxy responses without Chunked encoding.
Fix the processing of email digest jobs.
Client application data was always missing from the status
Elixir 1.15 compatibility
When downloading remote emojis packs, account for pagination
Make remote emoji packs API use specifically the V1 URL. Akkoma does not understand it without V1, and it works either way with normal pleroma, so no reason to not do this
Following HTTP Redirects when the HTTP Adapter is Finch
Video framegrabs were not working correctly after the change to use Exile to execute ffmpeg
Deactivated groups would still try to repeat a post.
Fix logic error in Gun connection pooling which prevented retries even when the worker was launched with retry = true
Connection pool errors when publishing an activity is a soft-error that will be retried shortly.
Gun Connection Pool was not retrying to acquire a connection if the pool was full and stale connections were reclaimed
TwitterAPI: Return proper error when healthcheck is disabled
Handle cases when users.inbox is nil.
Fix LDAP support
Use correct domain for fqn and InstanceView
The query for marking notifications as read has been simplified
Mastodon API /api/v1/directory: Fix listing directory contents when not authenticated
Ensure MediaProxy HTTP requests obey all the defined connection settings
Fix a memory leak caused by Websocket connections that would not enter a state where a full garbage collection run could be triggered.
Fix OpenGraph and Twitter metadata providers when parsing objects with no content or summary fields.
MRF: Log sensible error for subdomains_regex
MRF.StealEmojiPolicy: Properly add fallback extension to filenames missing one
Federated timeline removal of hashtags via MRF HashtagPolicy
Support objects with a null contentMap (firefish)
Fix notifications query which was not using the index properly
Notifications: improve performance by filtering on users table instead of activities table
Prevent Rich Media backfill jobs from retrying in cases where it is likely they will fail again.
Oban Jobs for refreshing users were not respecting the uniqueness setting
Fix Optimistic Inbox for failed signatures
MediaProxy Preview failures prevented when encountering certain video files
pleroma_ctl: Use realpath(1) instead of readlink(1)
ReceiverWorker: Make sure non-{:ok, _} is returned as {:error, …}
Harden Rich Media parsing against very slow or malicious URLs
Rich Media Preview cache eviction when the activity is updated.
Parsing of RichMedia TTLs for Amazon URLs when query parameters are nil
End of poll notifications were not streamed over websockets or web push
Fix eblurhash and elixir-captcha not using system cflags
Video thumbnails were not being generated due to a negative cache lookup logic error
Fix web push notifications not successfully delivering
Web Push notifications are no longer generated for muted/blocked threads and users.
Fix validate_webfinger when running a different domain for Webfinger
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Removed&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Mastodon API: Remove deprecated GET /api/v1/statuses/:id/card endpoint https://github.com/mastodon/mastodon/pull/11213
Removed support for multiple federator modules as we only support ActivityPub
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Frontend Changes
Known issues&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We got some reports related to emoji picker performance, this hopefully will be fixed in 2.7.1.
Notes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This release overhauls how themes work, themes now need to be “compiled”, which can cause some delay when loading for the first time and temporarily look “wrong” in some places (popups, menus, dialogs). Please do report any issues, especially if your theme looks wrong or breaks interface when loading. Also report issues if you’re experiencing constant performance issues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To admins: remember that you can update PleromaFE to recent master or develop in admin dashboard in “Front-ends” tab, scroll down to find PleromaFE box and click “Reinstall master” or dropdown and then “Reinstall develop”. Currently there is no mechanism to check if there is an update or not.
Changed&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Overhauled the way themes work, migrating to new Pleroma Interface Style Sheets system aka “Themes 3”.
Notifications are no longer sorted by “seen” status since interacting with them can change their read status and makes UI jumpy. Old behavior can be restored in settings.
Notifications are now shown through a ServiceWorker (since mobile chrome does not allow them otherwise), it’s always enabled, even if previously we only enabled it for WebPush notifications only. If you don’t like websites “running” while closed, check how to disable them in your browser. Old way to show notifications will be used as a fallback but might not have all the new features.
Reorganized Settings modal to move out visual stuff into Appearance tab
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Added&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Emoji pack management to the admin panel
Support status notification type (subscriptions/bell, fixes PleromaFE on newer PleromaBE versions)
Poll end notifications.
Added option to not mark all notifications when closing notifications drawer on mobile, this creates a new button to mark all as seen.
Option to always “show” notifications when using web push for better compatibility with some browsers (chrome, edge, safari)
Option to toggle what notification types appear in native notifications, by default less important ones (likes, repeats, etc) will no longer show up in native notifications.
Option to treat non-interactive notifications (likes, repeats et all) as seen for visual purposes (no read mark, ignored in counters, still can show in native notifications)
Ability to resize UI (and certain components) scale independent of browser/text scale
Ability to override certain aspects of UI style independent of theme used (UI roundness, fonts, underlay)
Theme selector with visual previews of the theme
Display loading and error indicator for conversation page
Option to only show scrobbles that are recent enough
Interacting (opening reply box etc) or simply clicking on non-interactive notifications now marks them as read. Clicking on native notifications for non-interactive ones also marks them as seen.
Support group actors
Focusing into a tab clears all current desktop notifications
Ability to change size of emoji
Ability to view APNG (Animated PNG) attachments.
Support showing extra notifications in the notifications column
Create a link to the URL of the scrobble when it’s present
Allow hiding custom emojis in picker.
Ability to mute sensitive posts (ported from eintei).
Native notifications now also have “badge” property that matches instance’s favicon (visible in Android Chromium at least)
Display public favorites on user profiles
Display quotes count on posts and add quotes list page
Show a dedicated registration notice page when further action is required after registering
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fixed&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Synchronized requested notification types with backend, hopefully should fix missing notifications for polls and follow requests
Error that appeared on mobile Chromium (and derivatives) when native notifications are allowed
Being unable to set notification visibility for reports and follow requests
Native notifications appearing as many times as there are open tabs. Clicking on notification will focus last focused tab.
The expiry date indication won’t be shown if the poll never expires
Profile mentions causing a 422 error on newer PleromaBE versions.
Color inputs are less ugly now
Unread notifications should now properly catch up between sessions (eventually) in polling mode
Video posters on Safari
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://git.pleroma.social/pleroma/pleroma/-/releases/v2.7.0" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://git.pleroma.social/pleroma/pleroma/-/releases/v2.7.1</id>
    <title>New release for Pleroma: Pleroma 2.7.1</title>
    <updated>2024-11-26T13:40:12+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>pleroma/pleroma</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h3&gt;Changed&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Accept &lt;code&gt;application/activity+json&lt;/code&gt; for requests to &lt;code&gt;/.well-known/nodeinfo&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Fixed&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Truncate remote user fields, avoids them getting rejected&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improve the &lt;code&gt;FollowValidator&lt;/code&gt; to successfully incoming activities with an errant &lt;code&gt;cc&lt;/code&gt; field.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Resolved edge case where the API can report you are following a user but the relationship is not fully established.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Swoosh email adapter for Mailgun was missing a new dependency on &lt;code&gt;:multipart&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix Mastodon WebSocket authentication&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://git.pleroma.social/pleroma/pleroma/-/releases/v2.7.1" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://git.pleroma.social/pleroma/pleroma/-/releases/v2.8.0</id>
    <title>New release for Pleroma: Pleroma 2.8.0</title>
    <updated>2024-12-19T10:18:30+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>pleroma/pleroma</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h3&gt;Changed&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Metadata: Do not include .atom feed links for remote accounts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bumped &lt;code&gt;fast_html&lt;/code&gt; to v2.3.0, which notably allows to use system-installed lexbor with passing &lt;code&gt;WITH_SYSTEM_LEXBOR=1&lt;/code&gt; environment variable at build-time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dedupe upload filter now uses a three-level sharding directory structure&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deprecate &lt;code&gt;/api/v1/pleroma/accounts/:id/subscribe&lt;/code&gt;/&lt;code&gt;unsubscribe&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Restrict incoming activities from unknown actors to a subset that does not imply a previous relationship and early rejection of unrecognized activity types.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Elixir 1.14 and Erlang/OTP 23 is now the minimum supported release&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Support &lt;code&gt;id&lt;/code&gt; param in &lt;code&gt;GET /api/v1/statuses&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;LDAP authentication has been refactored to operate as a GenServer process which will maintain an active connection to the LDAP server.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix 'Setting a marker should mark notifications as read'&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Adjust more Oban workers to enforce unique job constraints.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Oban updated to 2.18.3&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Publisher behavior improvement when snoozing Oban jobs due to Gun connection pool contention.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Poll results refreshing is handled asynchronously and will not attempt to keep fetching updates to a closed poll.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tuning for release builds to lower CPU usage.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rich Media preview fetching will skip making an HTTP HEAD request to check a URL for allowed content type and length if the Tesla adapter is Gun or Finch&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix nonexisting user will not generate metadata for search engine opt-out&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Update Oban to 2.18&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Worker configuration is no longer available. This only affects custom max_retries values for a couple Oban queues.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Added&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add metadata provider for ActivityPub alternate links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added support for argon2 passwords and their conversion for migration from Akkoma fork to upstream.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Respect :restrict_unauthenticated for hashtag rss/atom feeds&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;LDAP configuration now permits overriding the CA root certificate file for TLS validation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;LDAP now supports users changing their passwords&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Include list id in StatusView&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added MRF.FODirectReply which changes replies to followers-only posts to be direct.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add &lt;code&gt;id_filter&lt;/code&gt; to MRF to filter URLs and their domain prior to fetching&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added MRF.QuietReply which prevents replies to public posts from being published to the timelines&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add &lt;code&gt;group_key&lt;/code&gt; to notifications&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Allow providing avatar/header descriptions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added RemoteReportPolicy from Rebased for handling bogus federated reports&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;scrubbers/default: Allow "mention hashtag" classes used by Mastodon&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added dependencies for Swoosh's Mua mail adapter&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Include session scopes in TokenView&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Fixed&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Verify a local Update sent through AP C2S so users can only update their own objects&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed malformed follow requests that cause them to appear stuck pending due to the recipient being unable to process them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix incoming Block activities being rejected&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;STARTTLS certificate and hostname verification for LDAP authentication&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;LDAPS connections (implicit TLS) are now supported.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix /api/v2/media returning the wrong status code (202) for media processed synchronously&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Miscellaneous fixes for Meilisearch support&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix pleroma_ctl mix task calls sometimes not being found&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add a rate limiter to the OAuth App creation endpoint and ensure registered apps are assigned to users.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ReceiverWorker will cancel processing jobs instead of retrying if the user cannot be fetched due to 403, 404, or 410 errors or if the account is disabled locally.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Address case where instance reachability status couldn't be updated&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Remote Fetcher Worker recognizes more permanent failure errors&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;StreamerView: Do not leak follows count if hidden&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Imports of blocks, mutes, and follows would retry repeatedly due to incorrect error handling and all work executed in a single job&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make vapid_config return empty array, fixing preloading for instances without push notifications configured&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Removed&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Remove stub for /api/v1/accounts/:id/identity_proofs (deprecated by Mastodon 3.5.0)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://git.pleroma.social/pleroma/pleroma/-/releases/v2.8.0" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
