<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://selfh.st/apps</id>
  <title>Portainer Releases</title>
  <updated>2024-10-02T13:31:06.062040-04:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>selfh.st</name>
    <email>contact@selfh.st</email>
  </author>
  <link href="https://selfh.st/apps" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>Self-hosted software releases generated by selfh.st</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/portainer/portainer/releases/tag/2.20.1</id>
    <title>New release for Portainer: Release 2.20.1</title>
    <updated>2024-04-04T19:16:36-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>portainer/portainer</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h1&gt;2.20.1&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See &lt;a href="https://docs.portainer.io/start/upgrade"&gt;Upgrading Portainer instructions&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Overview of changes&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Introducing the new Portainer CE 2.20.1 release. This is an STS (Short-Term Support) release.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you gear up for the transition to Portainer CE 2.20.1, our latest STS (Short-Term Support) installment, ensuring a smooth upgrade is key. We urge you to back up your configurations via the Portainer UI beforehand. This backup acts as your safety net, ensuring you can gracefully revert to the prior version or state if the new frontier proves too wild. Additionally, pore over the release notes for catching any compatibility issues, understanding deprecated functionalities, and identifying essential tweaks to your current setup. Your diligence will pave the way for a seamless update.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A Short-Term Support release can be considered as "bleeding-edge" as it will contain the latest features and functionality we've developed. The STS releases (including this one) will go through a significant amount of pre-release testing, but there may be changes that could cause regressions and features that might see further iterations. As such, if stability is a crucial concern for your setup we wouldn't recommend deploying STS releases on production environments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read more in our "Portainer 2.20 STS" &lt;a href="https://www.portainer.io/blog/2024-release-principle"&gt;blog&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Important Note Regarding Docker 26 Support&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please be aware that support for Docker 26 is provided on an "as-is" basis and is primarily driven by best-effort principles. Minimal regression testing has been conducted to ensure basic functionality. Users should proceed with caution and report any issues they encounter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Docker&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Resolved an issue where Docker 25/26 API changes affected container-related pages and image size display &lt;a href="https://github.com/portainer/portainer/issues/11504"&gt;portainer/portainer#11504&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Kubernetes&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Resolved an issue where deploying GitOps edge stacks on a Kubernetes edge device resulted in error &lt;a href="https://github.com/portainer/portainer/issues/11503"&gt;portainer/portainer#11503&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Resolved an issue where the secret owner migration process could lead to a deadlock, preventing the HTTP(S) server from starting. &lt;a href="https://github.com/portainer/portainer/issues/11501"&gt;portainer/portainer#11501&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Portainer&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed an issue where local stacks were being overwritten by orphaned stacks with the same name in the regular stack listing page &lt;a href="https://github.com/portainer/portainer/issues/11502"&gt;portainer/portainer#11502&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/portainer/portainer/releases/tag/2.20.1" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/portainer/portainer/releases/tag/2.19.5</id>
    <title>New release for Portainer: Release 2.19.5</title>
    <updated>2024-04-21T17:10:31-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>portainer/portainer</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h1&gt;2.19.5&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See &lt;a href="https://docs.portainer.io/start/upgrade"&gt;Upgrading Portainer instructions&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Overview of changes&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;New Portainer CE  2.19.5 release&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Portainer&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Resolved CVE-2024-29296 by creating uniform response time for login attempts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/portainer/portainer/releases/tag/2.19.5" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/portainer/portainer/releases/tag/2.21.0</id>
    <title>New release for Portainer: Release 2.21.0</title>
    <updated>2024-08-26T14:31:53-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>portainer/portainer</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;This is our first Long-Term Support (LTS) release, which includes all the changes that have been added up to the 2.20.3 release, as well as various fixes aimed at enhancing the stability and scalability of Portainer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What’s Included:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Changes from 2.20.x&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This LTS release incorporates all the features, improvements, and bug fixes from the 2.20.x series of releases.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For detailed information about the changes included in the 2.20.x releases, please refer to the &lt;a href="https://docs.portainer.io/v/2.20/release-notes"&gt;[2.20.x release notes](https://docs.portainer.io/v/2.20/release-notes)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;New in this Release:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stability Improvements&lt;/strong&gt;: Various fixes have been applied to increase the overall stability of Portainer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scalability Enhancements&lt;/strong&gt;: Specific adjustments have been made to improve the usage of Portainer at scale, ensuring better performance and reliability in larger environments.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Security&lt;/strong&gt;: Critical and high security vulnerabilities (CVEs) associated with dependencies shipped within the Portainer images have been addressed. This includes updates to key components like the Docker client and kubectl to ensure a secure environment.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please review the sections below for more details on deprecated features included in this LTS release.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Deprecated Capabilities and Features:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We’re deprecating the platform and architecture-specific images named using the convention &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;platform&amp;gt;-&amp;lt;arch&amp;gt;-&amp;lt;version&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; in favor of the newer convention &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;version&amp;gt;-&amp;lt;platform&amp;gt;-&amp;lt;arch&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;. This change ensures standardization and consistency across our software distribution. In the future, we’ll only build and publish images using the new tag convention.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/portainer/portainer/releases/tag/2.21.0" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/portainer/portainer/releases/tag/2.21.1</id>
    <title>New release for Portainer: Release 2.21.1</title>
    <updated>2024-09-09T17:21:27-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>portainer/portainer</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h3&gt;What’s Included:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Changes from 2.21.0&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed an issue where Portainer would crash when cloning a large Git repository&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Introduced a JWT revocation mechanism to revoke JWTs after logout&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed an issue when re-creating a container on Docker 24&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/portainer/portainer/releases/tag/2.21.1" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/portainer/portainer/releases/tag/2.21.2</id>
    <title>New release for Portainer: Release 2.21.2</title>
    <updated>2024-09-23T17:02:57-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>portainer/portainer</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h3&gt;What’s Included:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Changes from 2.21.1&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Updated Linode branding to align with the new “Akamai Connected Cloud”.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed an issue with stack deployment on Docker when using a .env file from a Git Repository and referencing it in the Compose file.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/portainer/portainer/releases/tag/2.21.2" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
