<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://selfh.st/apps</id>
  <title>Portainer Releases</title>
  <updated>2024-10-09T21:31:03.274364-04:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>selfh.st</name>
    <email>contact@selfh.st</email>
  </author>
  <link href="https://selfh.st/apps" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>Self-hosted software releases generated by selfh.st</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/portainer/portainer/releases/tag/2.21.0</id>
    <title>New release for Portainer: Release 2.21.0</title>
    <updated>2024-08-26T14:31:53-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>portainer/portainer</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;This is our first Long-Term Support (LTS) release, which includes all the changes that have been added up to the 2.20.3 release, as well as various fixes aimed at enhancing the stability and scalability of Portainer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What’s Included:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Changes from 2.20.x&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This LTS release incorporates all the features, improvements, and bug fixes from the 2.20.x series of releases.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For detailed information about the changes included in the 2.20.x releases, please refer to the &lt;a href="https://docs.portainer.io/v/2.20/release-notes"&gt;[2.20.x release notes](https://docs.portainer.io/v/2.20/release-notes)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;New in this Release:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stability Improvements&lt;/strong&gt;: Various fixes have been applied to increase the overall stability of Portainer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scalability Enhancements&lt;/strong&gt;: Specific adjustments have been made to improve the usage of Portainer at scale, ensuring better performance and reliability in larger environments.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Security&lt;/strong&gt;: Critical and high security vulnerabilities (CVEs) associated with dependencies shipped within the Portainer images have been addressed. This includes updates to key components like the Docker client and kubectl to ensure a secure environment.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please review the sections below for more details on deprecated features included in this LTS release.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Deprecated Capabilities and Features:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We’re deprecating the platform and architecture-specific images named using the convention &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;platform&amp;gt;-&amp;lt;arch&amp;gt;-&amp;lt;version&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; in favor of the newer convention &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;version&amp;gt;-&amp;lt;platform&amp;gt;-&amp;lt;arch&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;. This change ensures standardization and consistency across our software distribution. In the future, we’ll only build and publish images using the new tag convention.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/portainer/portainer/releases/tag/2.21.0" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/portainer/portainer/releases/tag/2.21.1</id>
    <title>New release for Portainer: Release 2.21.1</title>
    <updated>2024-09-09T17:21:27-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>portainer/portainer</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h3&gt;What’s Included:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Changes from 2.21.0&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed an issue where Portainer would crash when cloning a large Git repository&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Introduced a JWT revocation mechanism to revoke JWTs after logout&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed an issue when re-creating a container on Docker 24&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/portainer/portainer/releases/tag/2.21.1" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/portainer/portainer/releases/tag/2.21.2</id>
    <title>New release for Portainer: Release 2.21.2</title>
    <updated>2024-09-23T17:02:57-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>portainer/portainer</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h3&gt;What’s Included:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Changes from 2.21.1&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Updated Linode branding to align with the new “Akamai Connected Cloud”.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed an issue with stack deployment on Docker when using a .env file from a Git Repository and referencing it in the Compose file.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/portainer/portainer/releases/tag/2.21.2" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/portainer/portainer/releases/tag/2.22.0</id>
    <title>New release for Portainer: Release 2.22.0</title>
    <updated>2024-10-02T17:33:07-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>portainer/portainer</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h2&gt;CE Release Notes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a STS (&lt;strong&gt;S&lt;/strong&gt;hort &lt;strong&gt;T&lt;/strong&gt;erm &lt;strong&gt;S&lt;/strong&gt;upport) release that includes all the changes added up to and including the 2.21.2 release, as well as various fixes aimed at enhancing the stability and scalability of Portainer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What’s Included:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Changes from 2.21.x&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This STS release incorporates all the features, improvements, and bug fixes from the 2.21.x series.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For more details, refer to the &lt;a href="https://docs.portainer.io/v/2.21/release-notes"&gt;2.21.x release notes&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;New in this Release:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Podman Support&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Portainer now supports Podman. It can be installed on Podman and manage Podman environments. Initial support includes Podman 5.x running on CentOS environments.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Better Kubernetes Management Experience&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Kubernetes management experience has been overhauled by relocating most of the logic from the client to the server, improving client speed and responsiveness. This update also introduces the ability to manage all Kubernetes resources via a simplified, abstracted API.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Edge Capabilities Improvements&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enhancements to the Edge features have resulted in a more stable, performant, and reliable experience when using Edge capabilities.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stability Improvements&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Various fixes have been applied to increase the overall stability of Portainer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scalability Enhancements&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Adjustments have been made to improve Portainer's performance and reliability at scale, especially in larger environments.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Security&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Critical and high-security vulnerabilities (CVEs) in dependencies shipped within the Portainer images have been addressed. Key components, such as the Docker client and kubectl, have been updated to ensure a secure environment.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Deprecated and Removed Features:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Deprecated features&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We are deprecating image tags named for various architectures using the convention &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;platform&amp;gt;-&amp;lt;arch&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;. This change ensures further standardization and consistency across our software distribution.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Removed features&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Platform and Architecture-Specific Images&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We are removing images named using the convention &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;platform&amp;gt;-&amp;lt;arch&amp;gt;-&amp;lt;version&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;. These images were deprecated in a previous release in favor of the newer convention &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;version&amp;gt;-&amp;lt;platform&amp;gt;-&amp;lt;arch&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;. This change ensures standardization and consistency across our software distribution.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kompose Logic&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All logic related to &lt;strong&gt;Kompose&lt;/strong&gt; has been removed, following its deprecation in a previous version.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nomad Support&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All logic related to &lt;strong&gt;Nomad&lt;/strong&gt; support has been removed after it was deprecated and subsequently removed from the client in version 2.20.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Breaking changes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As part of the changes in the Kubernetes experiences, some API operations for Kubernetes management may have changed slightly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Known issues&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Known issues with Podman support:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Podman environments aren't supported by auto-onboarding script&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It's not possible to add Podman environments via socket when running a Portainer server on Docker (and vice versa)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Support for only CentOS 9, Podman 5 rootful&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Unable to create an image from a container&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In-app CE to BE upgrade link doesn't appear on Podman&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Known issues with Kubernetes management:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Applications deployed via helm chart are no longer grouped on the App list screen&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Service accounts, Cluster Roles/Bindings, Roles/Role Bindings) show system resources when the toggle is off&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Standard users can't get cluster scoped ingress controllers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Unused label incorrectly showing on used volumes, and Used by column is blank&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;NaN value on Memory &amp;amp; CPU used bars on Node Details screen&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CPU/Memory Limit/Reservation values on &lt;strong&gt;Applications running on this node&lt;/strong&gt; table rounding down&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Volumes created within Portainer are incorrectly labelled as External&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Standard users on CE can no longer select and remove volumes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/portainer/portainer/releases/tag/2.22.0" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/portainer/portainer/releases/tag/2.21.3</id>
    <title>New release for Portainer: Release 2.21.3</title>
    <updated>2024-10-07T16:27:44-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>portainer/portainer</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h3&gt;What’s Included:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Changes from 2.21.2&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved home page search performance, addressing slow response times in certain environments.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed an issue where the CRL (Certificate Revocation List) request timeout may be too short, causing potential connection issues.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/portainer/portainer/releases/tag/2.21.3" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
