<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://selfh.st/apps</id>
  <title>ProjectSend Releases</title>
  <updated>2025-03-09T10:31:08.347926-04:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>selfh.st</name>
    <email>contact@selfh.st</email>
  </author>
  <link href="https://selfh.st/apps" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>Self-hosted software releases generated by selfh.st</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/projectsend/projectsend/releases/tag/r1415</id>
    <title>New release for ProjectSend: r1415</title>
    <updated>2022-05-26T11:15:46-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>projectsend/projectsend</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;New feature: throttle and ban failed log in attempts to prevent brute force attacks.
New in security Settings: whitelist or blacklist IPs from the log in ban feature.
New in Tools: unblock a banned IP address
New feature: cron jobs. Set up a task that can send pending email notifications in batches, deletes expired files and orphan files.
New Cron settings page: Enable/disable cron, change cron security key, select which tasks to run, enable or disable running via url, save log to database, send results via email.
New in Tools: Cron log viewer
Orphan files can now be filtered by allowed/not allowed.
If Recaptcha is enabled, use it on login, password reset request and register forms
New setting: disable sending email notifications of new files after adding/editing assignations. Enable this and combine it with a cron task to prevent long loading times after saving a file and overloading your mail server.
Updates are now separated into different files, with the latest database update number being independent from the software version. Cleans up the process and makes adding new updates easier.
Fixed installer issues (redirect loops and old sessions)
Fix: Category edit: verify parent id is not equal to same category id (by luca-rigutti)
While installing, get default timezone from system
Added max-width to the logo image on the gallery template.
Enable or disable debug from the custom config file, instead of using a core file
Fixed translations not loading and warnings on php 8+
Enable csv uploading by default
Use curl -if available- to get new versions and news data, enables timeout to prevent long loading times
Fixed: dashboard counters labels where not translatable
When editing a user, if role is not client, some fields should be always null (phone, contact, address)
Fixed XSS vulnerability on search forms
Fixed .htaccess (by RoboDoc)
Batch actions are sent as post instead of get to prevent malicious users from sending an action url to an admin user
Updated dependencies
Prevent registering via POST if self registration is disabled
Fixed Title TAG instead of file name (by deklica)
Spellchecking + Changed all instances of "his" to "their" when referencing an unknown individual (by ehawman-rosenberg)
Fixed JSON responses on widgets (by RiversideRocks)&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/projectsend/projectsend/releases/tag/r1415" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/projectsend/projectsend/releases/tag/r1420</id>
    <title>New release for ProjectSend: r1420</title>
    <updated>2022-05-28T10:16:50-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>projectsend/projectsend</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed deleting files as admin&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed deleting files from the database when they don't exist on the disk&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added filtering files by assigned/not assigned&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/projectsend/projectsend/releases/tag/r1420" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/projectsend/projectsend/releases/tag/r1584</id>
    <title>New release for ProjectSend: r1584</title>
    <updated>2022-10-14T14:46:41-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>projectsend/projectsend</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;Features&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Users with "uploader" role can now be limited to certain clients only
Added 2FA via email with a one time password
Added Custom assets manager (HTML, CSS, JS), to insert custom code into available locations (public pages, admin, templates, all)
New setting: set default expiration options (file expires or not, day before expiring)
New privacy settings: record user's IP for downloads of all users, anonymous only or never
File editor: added buttons to copy expiration, public and hidden settings to other files
Templates can be extended to the public files list and download file page
Added preview for public files in listing and download page&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UI&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Updated to Bootstrap 5
General update of colors, sizes and placing of elements.
Completely revamped the public files list page using the default template style.
Standardization of filters, search boxes and bulk actions.
Added a button to create new items in pages where they belong (ie: clients list -&amp;gt; Create client, manage files -&amp;gt; Upload file, etc)
Applied filters and search bar to public files list
Added a simple side modal class to show static content, or load it via ajax
Email template tags can now be clicked to insert them into the content area
Unsed email template tags are highlighted when editing a template
Removed grayed out effect from date selector on file editor, made the field look disabled
Copy file selection/settings (expiration, public, categories, clients, groups) grouped together for a cleaner experience.
File editor: added expand/collapse of each file
Updated the click to copy UI and functions, added Toastr for messages
Added copy to clipboard buttons to cron commands and social login callbacks
Public files list page group filter: show file count in each group
Download information UI fixes
Fixed a bug where installer errors were not showing&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;General Fixes and improvements&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Added language selector to all non-logged in pages. On language change, return to previous page instead of index
Fixed user password being changed during editing
Fixed social login with Linkedin, Twitter, WindowsLive and Yahoo
Fixed a bug that prevented removing all categories from a file
Import orphan: by default, show allowed files.
Improved loading time of Orphan files pages when traversing several thousand files
Orphan files can now be deleted. Updated UI to import via actions selector
Fixed memberships requests failing when requested_by had to be null
Fixed loading plupload language
General code cleanup
JS and SCSS files completely reorganized
Removed Open Sans font since it was loading externally just for the headings
Fixed button that loads default emails content
Fix for installer not creating the user
Separated installer instances into different files
Replaced chosen-js with select2
Public file: don't show title if it is equal to filename
Public download: file title used as page title
Replaced psendmodal with SweetAlert2
Highlight current submenu also on options and email templates
Upgraded to Gulp4 (by redondi88)
Cron fixes for FreeBSD (By xzenor)
Leave only html5 runtime on plupload
Updated dependencies&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/projectsend/projectsend/releases/tag/r1584" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/projectsend/projectsend/releases/tag/r1605</id>
    <title>New release for ProjectSend: ProjectSend r1605</title>
    <updated>2022-10-26T20:44:04-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>projectsend/projectsend</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added file version to CSS and JavaScript assets to prevent cache issues&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added an option to show a link to the public files repository under the log in form&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Show image file dimensions (manage files, public page, download page, templates)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Updated Gallery theme to flexbox&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added link to download translations to the languages dropdown (system users only)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix upload button on default template (by SnappyBird)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enlarged PDF preview (by ch1138 and serg499)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed side menu visibility on dashboard (by ch1138)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed public page not loading when no public groups were available&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Disabled autocomplete on 2FA verification form (by SnappyBird)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed PDO warning&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don’t add &lt;p&gt; tag to file description in email notifications if markup has HTML already&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use full path for sort links (by Koenari)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/projectsend/projectsend/releases/tag/r1605" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/projectsend/projectsend/releases/tag/r1720</id>
    <title>New release for ProjectSend: r1720</title>
    <updated>2024-08-03T00:07:20-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>projectsend/projectsend</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;Folders! Finally, the most requested feature is available. At the moment folders and subfolders can be created, rearranged by drag&amp;amp;drop and will be presented in all templates together with a breadcrumbs trail for easy navigation. There's much to do yet (select multiple, make an entire folder public, etc) but this basic implementation should give a great starting point.
Show image file dimensions (manage files, public page, download page, all templates)
Added Option to show public files on clients files lists
Added link to download translations to the languages dropdown
Fixed php &amp;gt;8 warnings
Allow underscores on usernames
Fixed 2FA token not validating due to php and mysql time differences.
Allow svg files as branding image
Manage files: show file assigned categories
Added option "Do not log downloads by the file's uploader"
Added an option to organize file uploads in year/month folders
Add support for Env vars for SMTP Configuration (by redondi88, &lt;a href="https://github.com/projectsend/projectsend/commit/26fc23e31d96efa684369ca7b31fc2bbea29479a"&gt;see variables here&lt;/a&gt;)
add aliases or virtual links for uploaded files (by mhpcc)
Fixed preview of video files (by Nimon77)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sanitize svg files uploaded in settings pages
Include local version of jQuery on templates&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Admin pages improvement: check user session before starting to process data
Do not load google's recaptcha js asset if recaptcha is disabled
Fix double "x" in close modal button (by rob4226)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fix: Extended remote_ip field on downloads table for long ipv6 addresses
FIxed showing validation errors when creating a client/user fails
Fix error 500 when self registering
Fixed XSS when changing template
fix upgrade failure when table prefix isn't tbl_ (by mhpcc)
Fixed getting links of previews by users with no access to the file (found by hassan al-khafaji and kiyell)
Fixed insecure strings being generated by a simple random string function (found by hassan al-khafaji)
Updated dependencies with known security issues (ie CKEditor5)&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/projectsend/projectsend/releases/tag/r1720" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
