<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://selfh.st/apps</id>
  <title>Recommendarr Releases</title>
  <updated>2025-04-12T14:35:41.405068-04:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>selfh.st</name>
    <email>contact@selfh.st</email>
  </author>
  <link href="https://selfh.st/apps" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>Self-hosted software releases generated by selfh.st</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/fingerthief/recommendarr/releases/tag/1.2.90</id>
    <title>New release for Recommendarr: Release 1.2.90 - Recommendations Improvements &amp; Bugfixes</title>
    <updated>2025-03-16T19:06:15-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>fingerthief/recommendarr</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h2&gt;Major Features&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Select a Plex User&lt;/strong&gt; 🆕&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Users can now choose what user to pull Plex history for.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;User selection is persisted for all watch history services now (Plex, Jellyfin, Tautulli)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sonarr/Radarr Tagging&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tags are now pulled back from Sonarr/Radarr&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can create new tags to use. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Recommendations Logic&lt;/strong&gt; 🎬&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Updated the LLM prompt to a new style to provide more personlized recommendations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Updated LLM prompt to return a JSON structure by default for improved parsing of recommendations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved LLM prompt for additional recommendations to prevent loops of suggesting already owned content.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed an issue filtering recommendations results. The results shown should no longer have instances where users see multiple items already in their library.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Further improved filtering of recommendations results to account for slight title differences in title names.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reduced LLM token usage with improved prompt strategy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What's Changed&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Full Changelog&lt;/strong&gt;: https://github.com/fingerthief/recommendarr/compare/1.2.80...1.2.90&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/fingerthief/recommendarr/releases/tag/1.2.90" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/fingerthief/recommendarr/releases/tag/1.3.0</id>
    <title>New release for Recommendarr: Release 1.3.0 - Enhancements and Bug Fixes</title>
    <updated>2025-03-20T13:25:38-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>fingerthief/recommendarr</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Key Highlights:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Improved Recommendation Handling:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Recommendations are now sorted by Recommendarr rating by default, surfacing the best suggestions first.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Recommendation cards have been redesigned for better readability and visual appeal.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved auto-compact mode for recommendation cards, optimizing display on various screen sizes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved responsive design to better utilize wider screens when displaying recommendation results.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added the ability to hide items from your history.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added 4 new recommendation prompt styles to choose from.&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Analytical&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Vibe&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Technical&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Creative &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Enhanced Media Information:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A new "Videos" section has been added to the TMDB dialog, allowing you to play trailers directly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;UI Refinements:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The application version number is now conveniently displayed in the navigation bar.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Several light theme UI elements have been adjusted for improved visual consistency.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Unnecessary controls have been removed from the "Manage Service" dialog, streamlining the interface.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bug Fixes:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Trakt Watch History Limit:&lt;/strong&gt; Resolved a critical issue where the Trakt watch history limit was not consistently respected, sometimes defaulting to 50 items.  The limit you set will now be correctly applied.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Plex Watch History Filtering:&lt;/strong&gt; Fixed a bug where Plex watch history was not filtering correctly when a date range (e.g., "last 30 days") was specified.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Full Changelog&lt;/strong&gt;: https://github.com/fingerthief/recommendarr/compare/1.2.90...1.3.0&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/fingerthief/recommendarr/releases/tag/1.3.0" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/fingerthief/recommendarr/releases/tag/1.4.0</id>
    <title>New release for Recommendarr: Release 1.4.0 - The Great Refactor &amp; Multi User Support</title>
    <updated>2025-04-11T22:44:40-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>fingerthief/recommendarr</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h2&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This release represents a comprehensive refactoring of the application's backend architecture to establish a solid foundation for future enhancements. What began as a personal Vue learning project has evolved into a widely-used application, necessitating significant architectural improvements to support growing user needs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The development journey progressed from a browser-based storage model to encrypted JSON files, resulting in inconsistent data management patterns. This release completes the major initital transition to a proper database system as the single source of truth for all application data, eliminating legacy localStorage and JSON file dependencies. While thoroughly tested, I would greatly appreciate your patience as I address any remaining issues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Key Enhancements&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Multi-User Support&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Admin users can now manage additional users through the "User Management" tab in Settings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;User permission model:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Admin users&lt;/strong&gt;: Full access to all application features, including service connections (Plex, Jellyfin, Tautulli) and library synchronization&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Standard users&lt;/strong&gt;: Limited to password management and personal Trakt connections, with the ability to select their user profile from watch history services&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Authentication Improvements&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;OAuth support added, including compatibility with custom OAuth providers (e.g., Authentik)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved session management for better security and reliability&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;See README for detailed OAuth configuration instructions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Performance Optimizations&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Watch History Caching&lt;/strong&gt;: History is now cached with a 24-hour refresh interval, significantly reducing API calls&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Radarr/Sonarr Synchronization&lt;/strong&gt;: New dedicated buttons for library synchronization, minimizing unnecessary API requests&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Enhanced Media Ratings&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Expanded rating information on recommendation cards for connected services:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sonarr&lt;/strong&gt;: IMDB ratings alongside Recommendarr ratings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Radarr&lt;/strong&gt;: IMDB, Rotten Tomatoes, Metacritic, and TMDB ratings in addition to Recommendarr ratings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Additional Improvements&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Watch history limits fixed and increased to 10,000 items (though I recommend a more selective approach using the Sampled Library toggle or recent watch history only for better personalization)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Updated Jellyfin setup to allow entering your Jellyfin Username for a more simplified connection experience instead of the more confusing User ID (Which was a string of characters in the profile URL)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Custom prompt only mode: Only base recommendations off of the "Additional Keywords/Themes" text field, ignoring your library etc..for recommendations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Trakt connections now processes the users ratings of shows and will automatically add anything rated 5 or below to the users "dislike" list.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Numerous minor bug fixes and stability improvements&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Important Notice&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Due to the extensive architectural changes in this release, &lt;strong&gt;you will need to reconfigure your service connections&lt;/strong&gt; (AI Settings, Sonarr, Radarr, etc.). I apologize for this inconvenience, but this one-time setup will provide a more stable and feature-rich experience going forward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Changelog&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Full Changelog&lt;/strong&gt;: https://github.com/fingerthief/recommendarr/compare/1.3.0...1.4.0&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/fingerthief/recommendarr/releases/tag/1.4.0" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/fingerthief/recommendarr/releases/tag/1.4.1</id>
    <title>New release for Recommendarr: Release 1.4.1 - Bugfixes</title>
    <updated>2025-04-12T01:29:22-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>fingerthief/recommendarr</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed issue causing users not to be able to connect to Trakt after the 1.4.0 update&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed issue causing the Jellyfin watch history section to not show on app load even if configured.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/fingerthief/recommendarr/releases/tag/1.4.1" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/fingerthief/recommendarr/releases/tag/1.4.2</id>
    <title>New release for Recommendarr: Release 1.4.2- Trakt Bugfix &amp; Wiki Creation</title>
    <updated>2025-04-12T11:59:27-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>fingerthief/recommendarr</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h3&gt;Changes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed an issue causing Trakt recent limit value not being properly displayed in the UI&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Created a new set of wiki pages for the application.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Updated README to be more concise and clean and link to the new wiki when needed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/fingerthief/recommendarr/releases/tag/1.4.2" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
