<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://selfh.st/apps</id>
  <title>Requestly Releases</title>
  <updated>2025-02-02T16:32:47.691618-05:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>selfh.st</name>
    <email>contact@selfh.st</email>
  </author>
  <link href="https://selfh.st/apps" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>Self-hosted software releases generated by selfh.st</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/requestly/requestly/releases/tag/v23.3.3</id>
    <title>New release for Requestly: Extension release v23.3.3</title>
    <updated>2023-03-03T06:05:51-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>requestly/requestly</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Show modifications on top URL in extension popup and browser console.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No need to refresh website after modifying or toggling Modify Request/Response rules.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added support for capturing cross-origin iframes in Session Recording.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bug fix: Clicking on View Recording showed &lt;code&gt;Something went wrong&lt;/code&gt; error.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bug fix: Early console logs were not captured in Session Recording.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bug fix: Rules with bad regex conditions impacted execution of other rules.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/requestly/requestly/releases/tag/v23.3.3" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/requestly/requestly/releases/tag/changelog-2025.01.21</id>
    <title>New release for Requestly: January 21, 2025</title>
    <updated>2025-01-21T04:29:42-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>requestly/requestly</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h2&gt;What's Changed&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;✨ New&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Resource Override Chrome Extension Importer&lt;/strong&gt;
    Introduced the ability to import configurations directly from Resource Override Chrome Extension, making it easier to transition. Refer &lt;a href="https://docs.requestly.com/general/imports/resource-override"&gt;Docs&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Markdown Support in Collections Overview&lt;/strong&gt;
    Added Markdown support for the Collection Overview tab, enabling users to format descriptions, notes, and documentation within collections.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Variables Autocompletion in API Client Requests&lt;/strong&gt;
    Implemented autocompletion for variables, improving speed and accuracy when working with dynamic data in requests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;💎 Improvements&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tabs and cursor positions are now preserved when switching between API Client tabs, whereas previously, switching back to a tab would default to the query parameters view.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Collections are now sorted alphabetically, improving readability and ensuring easy accessibility.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The API Client history screen now clearly informs users that history data is stored in local storage, with a message displayed at the top.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Collections are now collapsed by default upon import, improving readability and reducing visual clutter compared to the previous behavior where all collections were expanded.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;🐞 Fixes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Resolved an issue where unsaved changes to environment variables were lost when opening the importer modal.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed a bug in Codemirror where the cursor jumped to the beginning of the editor when typing rapidly, improving text editing functionality.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Request and Response bodies in the API Client now load prettified by default, enhancing readability.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Secret values are no longer visible in the autocomplete dropdown of the API Client.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Resolved an issue where tabs would display data from a different request when switching.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed an issue where unsaved changes to a request were lost upon duplicating it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed an issue where query parameters were lost when a request was loaded from history.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Addressed an issue where current values of API Client variables were cleared upon switching workspaces.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/requestly/requestly/releases/tag/changelog-2025.01.21" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/requestly/requestly/releases/tag/changelog-2025.01.27</id>
    <title>New release for Requestly: January 27, 2025</title>
    <updated>2025-01-27T10:43:52-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>requestly/requestly</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h2&gt;What's Changed&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="changelog-27-january-2025" src="https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/9fd4e966-7815-484e-936e-f542ddc31bfd" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;💎 Improvements&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;New Look for Desktop App on Mac&lt;/strong&gt; • &lt;a href="https://github.com/requestly/requestly-desktop-app/releases/tag/v1.8.0"&gt;v1.8.0&lt;/a&gt;
    The macOS desktop app now opens in a frameless window, providing a cleaner and more modern interface. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Improved Scripts in API Client&lt;/strong&gt;
    Refactored scripts feature in the API Client to optimize performance and reduce bugs. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;🐞 Fixes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Resolved an issue where the undo operation (Cmd+Z) was not functioning correctly in the API Client.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed incorrect data clearance warnings that appeared when changing resource or response types in rule editors, even when inputs were empty. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/requestly/requestly/releases/tag/changelog-2025.01.27" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
