<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://selfh.st/apps</id>
  <title>Review Board Releases</title>
  <updated>2025-08-08T05:38:29.381268-04:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>selfh.st</name>
    <email>contact@selfh.st</email>
  </author>
  <link href="https://selfh.st/apps" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>Self-hosted software releases generated by selfh.st</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/reviewboard/reviewboard/releases/tag/release-5.0.5</id>
    <title>New release for Review Board: Review Board 5.0.5: Improved SSO, New Installation Options</title>
    <updated>2023-06-20T18:29:02-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>reviewboard/reviewboard</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;Review Board 5.0.5 offers improvements and fixes to Single Sign-On, web-based login for the upcoming RBTools 5, improved support for installing with Python Virtual Environments (required in this year's Linux distributions), and more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let's dig in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Improved Single Sign-On&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We've fixed a handful of bugs in the Review Board 5's new Single Sign-On support, improving compatibility with most services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, if a page requires you to log in first, you'll be taken back to that page once successfully logged in. Thanks to everyone who let us know this wasn't working right.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Web-Based Login for RBTools 5&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;RBTools 5 is in development, and includes the ability to log in using the Review Board website. This means you can finally use your standard Single Sign-On authentication for RBTools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We're hard at work on RBTools 5, and will be shipping it later this year. If you'd like to beta test this, please &lt;a href="https://www.reviewboard.org/support/"&gt;reach out to support&lt;/a&gt; for pre-release builds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Python Virtual Environments&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Python Virtual Environments provide a way to isolate Python applications and services from the system or other Python applications. They help you avoid various forms of installation problems, and they're required in Ubuntu 23.04, Debian Bookworm, and Fedora 39 (with other Linux distros soon to follow).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Starting in 5.0.5, Review Board can now help you install into a Virtual Environment and will automatically make use of it no matter what web server you're using.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We've updated our &lt;a href="https://www.reviewboard.org/docs/manual/5.0/admin/installation/linux/"&gt;installation documentation&lt;/a&gt; to help you install and use Review Board in either Virtual Environments or in traditional setups.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please note: If you're not using a Virtual Environment today, you don't need to switch to one unless you're planning to upgrade to this year's Linux distributions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Plus...&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It's now easier to manage review groups and repositories when configuring an integration, such as Slack or Jenkins.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New &lt;code&gt;python&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;pip&lt;/code&gt; site management commands for running the correct versions for your environment.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Compatibility fixes for modern Python packaging support.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All the details can be found in the &lt;a href="https://www.reviewboard.org/docs/releasenotes/reviewboard/5.0.5/"&gt;release notes&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To learn more about upgrading your server, see our &lt;a href="https://www.reviewboard.org/docs/manual/5.0/admin/upgrading/upgrading-reviewboard/"&gt;upgrade instructions&lt;/a&gt;. You can also use our &lt;a href="https://hub.docker.com/r/beanbag/reviewboard"&gt;official Docker images&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you need assistance with your server, we can help under a &lt;a href="https://www.reviewboard.org/support/"&gt;support contract&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/reviewboard/reviewboard/releases/tag/release-5.0.5" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/reviewboard/reviewboard/releases/tag/release-6.0</id>
    <title>New release for Review Board: Announcing Review Board 6</title>
    <updated>2023-10-17T05:25:33-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>reviewboard/reviewboard</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;Review Board 6 is all about focusing on your code review experience in a pleasant environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The UI is bright, soft, and colorful. The diffs are easier on the eyes, and easier to navigate. The review process is streamlined, a new review banner guiding you through creating, managing, and publishing your review request, reviews, and replies. Rich commenting is effortless, with Markdown formatting aided by a helpful new toolbar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that's just the beginning. Let us introduce you to Review Board 6.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;A bright start&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ve been improving the look and feel of Review Board, softening and brightening the visuals, giving content some breathing room, and sanding down rough edges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/images.reviewboard.org/uploaded/images/2023/08/29/6.0-new-diff-visuals2x.png" width="1149" alt="An example of the new visuals seen in the diff viewer, with softer colors and better interaction controls"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The color palette and font size used in diffs have been refined to make it easier to read long blocks of code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Much of our UI has been made more accessible and mobile-friendly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the first step toward a larger UI refresh planned for Review Board 7.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking for something less bright? Say, a dark mode? That's in the works, but for now, we find &lt;a href="https://darkreader.org/"&gt;Dark Reader&lt;/a&gt; to be pretty useful ourselves!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;An improved review experience&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In past versions of Review Board, your draft review requests, reviews, and replies were all managed separately, each with its own green draft banner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Review Board 6 now includes a new &lt;a href="https://www.reviewboard.org/docs/manual/6.x/users/reviews/banner/#review-banner"&gt;Unified Review Banner&lt;/a&gt;, which summarizes every draft that still needs to be published on a review request.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/images.reviewboard.org/uploaded/images/2023/04/04/review-banner-grouped2x.png" width="735" alt="New review draft banner, with draft selection, Publish and Discard buttons, &amp;quot;Describe your changes&amp;quot; field, and Review menu"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This banner allows you to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;See all your drafts in one place&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Publish all your drafts together with fewer e-mails, or publish them independently as before&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create new reviews on a review request&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This banner is always visible on the screen, and will help guide you through the review process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The old &lt;strong&gt;Review&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Add Comment&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;Ship It!&lt;/strong&gt; buttons on the review request’s action bar have been moved to a new &lt;strong&gt;Review&lt;/strong&gt; menu on the banner, helping you create, manage, and publish your reviews from anywhere on a review request.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/images.reviewboard.org/uploaded/images/2023/04/04/review-menu2x.png" width="566" alt="New Review menu, with &amp;quot;Create a new review,&amp;quot; &amp;quot;Add a general comment,&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;Ship it!&amp;quot; items."&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To help get going, we’ve added new tips and tricks to the Review Dialog, shown when clicking &lt;strong&gt;Review -&amp;gt; Create a New Review&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/images.reviewboard.org/uploaded/images/2023/08/29/6.0-review-tips2x.png" width="595" alt="A sample tip in the Review Dialog, stating: &amp;quot;To add a comment to a code change or text file attachment, click on a line number or click and drag over multiple line numbers in the diff viewer. You'll be able to see and edit the comment from both the diff viewer and here in the review dialog.&amp;quot;"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And finally, you can review your own diffs and files before they’re published, helping make comments that guide reviewers through your change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Craft Markdown comments with a click&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s easier than ever to compose Markdown text for your reviews, comments, and review requests through the new Markdown formatting toolbar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/images.reviewboard.org/uploaded/images/2023/08/29/6.0-formatting-toolbar2x.png" width="662" alt="The new Markdown formatting toolbar at the bottom of a text field with buttons for Bold, Italic, Strike-through, Code Literal, Insert Link, Insert Image, Insert Bullet List, Insert Numeric List"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Toggle between &lt;strong&gt;bold&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;italic&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;del&gt;strike-through&lt;/del&gt;, and &lt;code&gt;code literals&lt;/code&gt;. Create lists, link to URLs, and then go beyond text by uploading and embedding images.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Better file attachment management&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;File attachments are an important part of many people's workflows. Review Board 6 now makes it easier to track which files are published, which you're introducing in a draft, and which are pending deletion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/images.reviewboard.org/uploaded/images/2023/10/16/file-attachments-undo-delete2x.png" width="404" alt="A file attachment titled Important Presentation with a label in the top right corner of its thumbnail stating that it is pending deletion. There is a menu of buttons beside the thumbnail, with options for reviewing, downloading, and undoing the delete."&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When adding, updating, or deleting file attachments, a label is now placed on the thumbnail showing its status:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;New:&lt;/strong&gt; The file attachment was newly-added in this draft.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;New Revision:&lt;/strong&gt; A new, updated revision of a file attachment was added in this draft.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pending Deletion:&lt;/strong&gt; The file attachment will be deleted when the draft is published.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Draft:&lt;/strong&gt; The file attachment’s caption has been updated in the draft.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If a file attachment is pending deletion, you can now restore it by clicking &lt;strong&gt;Undo Delete&lt;/strong&gt; in the &lt;a href="https://www.reviewboard.org/docs/manual/6.x/users/review-requests/uploading-files/#deleting-file-attachments"&gt;file attachment’s actions menu&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Take action with extensions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Review Board’s extension abilities have grown once again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new Actions system makes it easier to add, hide, and reorder actions on the review request’s action bar, on the page header, and the navigation bar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Client-side extensions can now be written using &lt;a href="https://www.typescriptlang.org/"&gt;TypeScript&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://github.com/beanbaginc/spina"&gt;Spina&lt;/a&gt;, and bound together using ES Modules.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Server-side extensions can benefit from enhanced &lt;a href="https://docs.python.org/3/library/typing.html"&gt;Python type hints&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://pytest.org"&gt;pytest&lt;/a&gt;-based unit tests. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Important compatibility updates&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ve dropped support for Python 3.7 and added 3.12. Please note that not all third-party repository support is compatible yet with 3.12.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ve also dropped Subvertpy support. To use Subversion with Review Board, make sure to &lt;a href="httpw://www.reviewboard.org/docs/manual/6.x/admin/installation/linux/#installing-svn"&gt;install PySVN&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Plus…&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Faster automated code review results&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A better default view for dashboards, showing all your incoming and outgoing review requests&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A service health check URL (&lt;code&gt;/health/&lt;/code&gt;) for monitoring, scaling, and fault tolerance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New Single Sign-On options, for wider Identity Provider compatibility&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enhanced API error reporting, with string-based error types&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Performance and usability improvements all throughout Review Board&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;And more!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.reviewboard.org/docs/releasenotes/reviewboard/6.0/"&gt;Review Board 6 release notes&lt;/a&gt; cover all the changes in this release in detail.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Ready to upgrade?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For most users of Review Board 5, Review Board 6 will be a drop-in replacement with minimal downtime.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still, make sure you have a backup of your database and site directory, and please perform a test upgrade on a test server. Then follow the &lt;a href="https://www.reviewboard.org/docs/manual/6.x/admin/upgrading/upgrading-reviewboard/"&gt;upgrade instructions&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re using Docker, follow our &lt;a href="https://www.reviewboard.org/docs/manual/6.x/admin/installation/docker/"&gt;Docker instructions&lt;/a&gt; to deploy new containers. Review Board 6’s official Docker images are based on Ubuntu 22.04 LTS and Python 3.11.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you need assistance, we can help &lt;a href="https://www.reviewboard.org/support/"&gt;support your Review Board server&lt;/a&gt; with a plan that meets your needs.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/reviewboard/reviewboard/releases/tag/release-6.0" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/reviewboard/reviewboard/releases/tag/release-6.0.1</id>
    <title>New release for Review Board: Review Board 6.0.1: Fixes for Publishing</title>
    <updated>2023-11-08T15:03:29-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>reviewboard/reviewboard</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;Review Board 6.0.1 fixes a handful of bugs found in the recent &lt;a href="https://www.reviewboard.org/news/2023/10/17/announcing-review-board-6/"&gt;6.0 release&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reviews and replies should now successfully publish in all cases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Administrators can once again see and edit another user's draft review requests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Compatibility issues with subdirectory installs or Local Site partitioning have been resolved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Plus other bug fixes throughout the product.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All the details can be found in the &lt;a href="https://www.reviewboard.org/docs/releasenotes/reviewboard/6.0.1/"&gt;release notes&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Asana and Trello integrations updates&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We've also released &lt;a href="https://pypi.org/project/rbintegrations/"&gt;Review Board Integrations 3.1.1&lt;/a&gt;, which fixes compatibility with Trello and Asana. This must be upgraded manually for now:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;console
$ pip3 install rbintegrations==3.1.1&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is compatible with both Review Board 5 and 6.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Let's get started!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To learn more about upgrading your server, see our &lt;a href="https://www.reviewboard.org/docs/manual/6.x/admin/upgrading/upgrading-reviewboard/"&gt;upgrade instructions&lt;/a&gt;. You can also use our &lt;a href="https://hub.docker.com/r/beanbag/reviewboard"&gt;official Docker images&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you need assistance with your server, we can help under a &lt;a href="https://www.reviewboard.org/support/"&gt;support contract&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/reviewboard/reviewboard/releases/tag/release-6.0.1" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/reviewboard/reviewboard/releases/tag/release-7.0</id>
    <title>New release for Review Board: Review Board 7: It's a bright day for code review!</title>
    <updated>2024-06-07T14:55:05-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>reviewboard/reviewboard</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;They say it’s darkest just before the dawn. And whether that’s when you’re most productive, or in the middle of a warm, sunny day, Review Board 7 will help you see the code, documents, images, and reviews in an all-new light.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Review Board 7 introduces Dark Mode, all-new support for reviewing images directly in the Diff Viewer, Microsoft Teams integration, mobile-friendly diff review, and lots more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And we’re not just releasing Review Board 7 today. We’re also releasing RBTools 5 and Review Bot 4, which help unleash the full power of Review Board 7’s new features.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Dark Mode&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There's nothing worse than staying up late to review code and feeling blinded by your screen. With Dark Mode in Review Board 7, you can reduce eye strain and work comfortably no matter the time of day. This sleek new look not only helps in low-light environments but also adds a modern, stylish touch to your code reviews.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="A sample review request shown in Dark Mode, with a cool-grey color scheme." src="https://static.reviewboard.org/uploaded/images/2024/06/06/7.0-dark-mode-review-request2x.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can activate Dark Mode in &lt;strong&gt;My Account -&amp;gt; Appearance&lt;/strong&gt;. You can also have Review Board automatically match your system theme, keeping it in sync with all your other applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dark Mode is currently in beta as we continue to fine-tune its look and expand its availability throughout the product. It's not available yet in the Administration UI, Reports, or Document Review, but those updates are coming soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Image Review in the Diff Viewer&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Projects aren’t made entirely of code and text files. Images can be a crucial part of your commits, too, often containing essential design updates, new artwork, or visual elements that define your feature. While this used to require uploading these images separately as file attachments, now they can be seen directly in the Diff Viewer with the rest of your change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="An image of a diff of two colorations for a ghostly blob character with a wooden belt, built for a game" src="https://static.reviewboard.org/uploaded/images/2024/06/06/7.0-image-diff-review.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To upload images as part of your change, you’ll need to use the new RBTools 5 release and a Git, Mercurial, Perforce, or Subversion repository. This will ensure new images and changes to existing images are included with your code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once uploaded, images can be viewed and diffed using several modes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Two-Up&lt;/strong&gt;: Shows the old and the new images side-by-side.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Color Difference:&lt;/strong&gt; Changes in colors are shown like an X-Ray, helping you spot even the smallest changes to an image.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Split Mode:&lt;/strong&gt; Overlays both images, using a slider to show or hide parts of each image.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Onion Skin:&lt;/strong&gt; Like Split Mode, but adjusting the transparency of the new image on top of the old.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Microsoft Teams Integration&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Staying on top of code reviews is now easier with our new &lt;a href="https://www.reviewboard.org/integrations/microsoft-teams/"&gt;Microsoft Teams integration&lt;/a&gt;. Slack and Discord users have enjoyed live notifications of review request activity for years, and now, Teams users can too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="A review request posted to a Microsoft Teams channel." src="https://static.reviewboard.org/uploaded/images/2024/06/06/7.0-msteams.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;New and updated review requests, as well as any reviews or replies, are sent directly to your Teams channels. This keeps your team informed and responsive, no matter where they are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An unlimited number of rules can be configured, helping you keep individual channels informed based on repositories, branches, or any other criteria. You can even keep sensitive review requests out of public channels automatically.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Mobile Diff Review&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reviewing code on the go is now easier with our improved Mobile Diff Review. On small screens, the diff viewer automatically switches to a single column, presenting changes in a mobile-friendly way without the need for side-by-side comparisons. This ensures a smooth and efficient review process, even when you're away from your desk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="The diff viewer in mobile mode, showing a single column with deleted and inserted code, moved lines, and comments." src="https://static.reviewboard.org/uploaded/images/2024/06/06/7.0-mobile-diff-viewer.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Plus…&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A more polished and accessible UI throughout the product.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved Jenkins CI compatibility.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Configurable timeouts for CI builds.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Updated default settings for the Dashboards for new users.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Better Markdown review compatibility.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Backed by Django 4.2 LTS for long-term security and support for your server.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Increased stability, faster performance, and many, many bug fixes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that’s just Review Board! We have improvements in RBTools 5 and Review Bot 4 that we haven’t even talked about yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To learn more, see the release notes for:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.reviewboard.org/docs/releasenotes/reviewboard/7.0/"&gt;Review Board 7&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.reviewboard.org/docs/releasenotes/rbtools/5.0/"&gt;RBTools 5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.reviewboard.org/docs/releasenotes/reviewbot/4.0/"&gt;Review Bot 4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Ready to upgrade?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For most users of Review Board 5 or 6, Review Board 7 will be a drop-in replacement with minimal downtime.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still, make sure you have a backup of your database and site directory, and please perform a test upgrade on a test server. Then follow the &lt;a href="https://www.reviewboard.org/docs/manual/7.x/admin/upgrading/upgrading-reviewboard/"&gt;upgrade instructions&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re using Docker, follow our &lt;a href="https://www.reviewboard.org/docs/manual/7.x/admin/installation/docker/"&gt;Docker instructions&lt;/a&gt; to deploy new containers. Review Board 7’s official Docker images are based on Ubuntu 22.04 LTS and Python 3.11.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Talk to us about &lt;a href="https://www.reviewboard.org/support/"&gt;Review Board Support&lt;/a&gt; to keep your server running smoothly and your developers happy.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/reviewboard/reviewboard/releases/tag/release-7.0" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/reviewboard/reviewboard/releases/tag/release-7.0.4</id>
    <title>New release for Review Board: Review Board 7.0.4: New SAML Options, Custom Tab Stop Widths</title>
    <updated>2025-08-06T00:18:35-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>reviewboard/reviewboard</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;Review Board 7.0.4 adds an assortment of new SSO SAML features to help meet the needs of IT departments everywhere, and long-awaited customization of tab stop widths in diffs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;All-New SAML Settings&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;IT departments now have greater control of user provisioning, access, and configuration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Automatic user provisioning can now be turned off in &lt;strong&gt;SAML Settings&lt;/strong&gt;, letting administrators better control who has access to the server.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Users can be explicitly disabled from logging into Review Board via SAML, even if the Identity Provider otherwise grants access. To do this, edit a user in the Administration UI and turn off their Active flag.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more specialized SAML configurations, you can now set &lt;code&gt;SAML_CONFIG_ADVANCED&lt;/code&gt; in your &lt;code&gt;$sitedir/conf/settings_local.py&lt;/code&gt; file to tweak any &lt;a href="https://github.com/SAML-Toolkits/python3-saml?tab=readme-ov-file#settings"&gt;python3-saml settings&lt;/a&gt; needed. For example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;python
SAML_CONFIG_ADVANCED = {
    'security': {
        'requestAuthnContext': False,
    },
}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking to provision a user for SAML SSO or automation purposes via the API? You can now create a user without specifying a password using the &lt;a href="https://www.reviewboard.org/docs/manual/7.x/webapi/2.0/resources/user/"&gt;User API&lt;/a&gt;. The user account will only be accessible using SSO or an API Token.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Customizable Tab Stop Widths&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using tabs instead of spaces? You can finally customize the width of tab characters in your diffs. You can set this system-wide in &lt;strong&gt;Diff Settings&lt;/strong&gt;. It defaults to 8.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Plus...&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved styling in Dark Mode&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Upgrade fixes when moving from very old versions of Review Board&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed preserving commit range selections when paginating diffs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed an issue on Postgres where downloaded diffs could sometimes reorder files&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All the details can be found in the &lt;a href="https://www.reviewboard.org/docs/releasenotes/reviewboard/7.0.4/"&gt;release notes&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Coming Up&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We've been working hard on a new major Review Board 7.1 and Power Pack 6 release, which offers Office document review and diffing, user roles and rules, new extension capabilities, a more seamless approach to managing licenses and getting support.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You'll hear more soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Let's get started!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To learn more about upgrading your server, see our &lt;a href="https://www.reviewboard.org/docs/manual/7.x/admin/upgrading/upgrading-reviewboard/"&gt;upgrade instructions&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can also use our &lt;a href="https://hub.docker.com/r/beanbag/reviewboard"&gt;official Docker images&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Review Board development is funded by Support and Power Pack&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you're using Review Board today, we'd like to see how we can work together. We offer:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Full-service &lt;a href="https://www.reviewboard.org/support/"&gt;support contracts&lt;/a&gt; to help your IT department keep things running smoothly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.reviewboard.org/powerpack/"&gt;Power Pack&lt;/a&gt; Document Review, Reports, new integrations, and more, with a &lt;a href="https://www.reviewboard.org/powerpack/trial/"&gt;free 30 day trial&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your support and licenses help us fund and grow Review Board and keeps food on our tables. Reach out to us and we'll work with you on a plan that fits your needs.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/reviewboard/reviewboard/releases/tag/release-7.0.4" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
