<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://selfh.st/apps</id>
  <title>SafeLine Releases</title>
  <updated>2025-06-03T05:34:48.976138-04:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>selfh.st</name>
    <email>contact@selfh.st</email>
  </author>
  <link href="https://selfh.st/apps" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>Self-hosted software releases generated by selfh.st</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/chaitin/SafeLine/releases/tag/v8.4.0</id>
    <title>New release for SafeLine: SafeLine-CE 8.4.0</title>
    <updated>2025-04-07T22:28:43-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>chaitin/SafeLine</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h3&gt;Fix&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed an issue where the sl-session in the response header contained an extra space.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Minor UI styling improvements.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/chaitin/SafeLine/releases/tag/v8.4.0" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/chaitin/SafeLine/releases/tag/v8.5.0</id>
    <title>New release for SafeLine: SafeLine-CE 8.5.0</title>
    <updated>2025-04-10T08:15:39-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>chaitin/SafeLine</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h3&gt;What's new&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Auth supports SSO, requiring only one authentication to access all applications that have joined SSO. &lt;a href="/reference/articles/Auth-SSO"&gt;SSO Guide&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Support editing application title and icon in application details. This content is only for display in SafeLine console and SSO center, and does not affect the original application configuration&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Modularization of Applications Functionality, with original global application configuration migrated to the Applications - Advancedpage&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Modularization of Attacks Functionality, with original custom rules and detection modules migrated to Attacks - Settingspage. The original detection Modulehas been renamed to Semantic Analysis Module&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Modularization of Settings Functionality, with original ssl cert, general configuration, and system settings migrated to the Settings page. The settings function list is as follows:&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Protections: IP Groups, SSL Cert, Blocking Pages, Performance, Clean Data, Config Auto Sync, Attack Alert, Syslog, Information Sharing Program&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Management: Manager User, API Token, SSL Cert (SafeLine Web Console), System Message&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Fix&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Applications list supports searching by application name&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed an issue where the exclusion of resources in Routings collection was not correctly implemented&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/chaitin/SafeLine/releases/tag/v8.5.0" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/chaitin/SafeLine/releases/tag/v8.6.0</id>
    <title>New release for SafeLine: SafeLine-CE 8.6.0</title>
    <updated>2025-04-24T08:16:53-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>chaitin/SafeLine</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h3&gt;What's new&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Auth supports OIDC integration, enabling unified user management and access control. Click to view feature introduction&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pro version enables [Group Management] feature in "Applications - Advanced"&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Supports application grouping and drag-and-drop sorting&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Allows specifying groups when adding applications&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pro version increases Auth seats to 100&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Applications optimized with card-style interface&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Original application "Edit" button now displays basic info edit instead of application edit; application edit can be accessed from details page&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Supports NTLM authorization authentication&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Fix&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed issue where scanners were not properly disabled in audited mode&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed issue where specific paths would not correctly return "website does not exist" response&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed issue where Anti-Bot incorrectly displayed IP filtering conditions when switching verification methods&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Optimized UA display in data statistics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/chaitin/SafeLine/releases/tag/v8.6.0" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/chaitin/SafeLine/releases/tag/v8.7.0</id>
    <title>New release for SafeLine: SafeLine-CE 8.7.0</title>
    <updated>2025-05-09T03:38:58-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>chaitin/SafeLine</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h3&gt;What's new&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pro Edition Auth now supports LDAP authentication, enabling unified user management and access control. Click to view &lt;a href="/reference/articles/Auth-LDAP"&gt;feature introduction&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Auth supports passing authentication information to application servers. Click to view &lt;a href="/tutorials/advanced/Auth"&gt;feature introduction&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Auth supports direct application access after authentication, without requiring approval.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Support for configuring general proxy settings, applicable to various system functions requiring proxy support. Currently, third-party login for Auth supports proxy configuration.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Personal/Lite Edition Auth users increased to 20, Pro Edition seats increased to 200.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Master-slave configuration synchronization logic optimized, resolving issues with delayed data synchronization in certain situations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Fix&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed the issue where plugins like APISIX couldn't correctly obtain the source IP when integrated.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed the issue where the auth page would remain in a continuous loading state under specific circumstances.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed the issue where Rate Limiting error rules for rate limiting were not taking effect.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/chaitin/SafeLine/releases/tag/v8.7.0" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/chaitin/SafeLine/releases/tag/v8.8.1</id>
    <title>New release for SafeLine: SafeLine-CE 8.8.1</title>
    <updated>2025-05-23T00:02:28-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>chaitin/SafeLine</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h3&gt;What's new&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IPv6 address location identification&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pro adds application-level data statistics, which needs to be manually enabled in application details. May increase system load, recommended to enable as needed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Original [Attack Alert] upgraded to [Notifications]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Supports proxy access configuration&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Event types expanded to include Anti-Bot, Auth, Waiting Room, and System notifications&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Attack detection, rate limiting, and Anti-Bot types support configurable notification frequency (options: 10 minutes, 1 hour, 2 hours)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Supports selection of application range, allowing notifications for selected applications only&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Attack detection type supports sending unblocked log notifications&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rate limiting type supports sending Error Limiting events&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;AUTH supports configuring mandatory 2FA (TOTP) when users access applications&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved display of blacklist and whitelist names when exporting attack logs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/chaitin/SafeLine/releases/tag/v8.8.1" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
