<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://selfh.st/apps</id>
  <title>SafeLine Releases</title>
  <updated>2025-03-23T00:34:10.103806-04:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>selfh.st</name>
    <email>contact@selfh.st</email>
  </author>
  <link href="https://selfh.st/apps" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>Self-hosted software releases generated by selfh.st</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/chaitin/SafeLine/releases/tag/v7.3.0</id>
    <title>New release for SafeLine: SafeLine-CE 7.3.0</title>
    <updated>2024-12-06T00:23:19-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>chaitin/SafeLine</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h4&gt;Improvements&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Anti-Bot Challenge adds a fault-tolerant mechanism which supports automatic switching to local verification when there is a cloud failure.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improve Custom Block Pages&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Allow custom page color schemes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Custom HTML supports online editing, online preview, and allow reset to the default page.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Web Services / SECURITY add Get Attack IP From&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pro version supports Data Dashboard&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improve Custom Rules&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;URL, URL path add Does Not Equal, Does Not Contain&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;BODY add Contain, Does Not Contain&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Fix&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clean Data supports more options.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Optimize SQL injection detection logic to allow non-injection attacks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make returning a built-in certificate when the site does not exist optional, to be compatible with IP certificate anomalies.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix CAPTCHA occasionally fails to close properly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix modifying the SSL protocol under specific conditions does not take effect.
*Fix the frontend styles are incorrect when selecting multiple websites for custom rules.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/chaitin/SafeLine/releases/tag/v7.3.0" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/chaitin/SafeLine/releases/tag/v7.5.0</id>
    <title>New release for SafeLine: SafeLine-CE 7.5.0</title>
    <updated>2025-01-02T05:14:18-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>chaitin/SafeLine</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h3&gt;Feature&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added &lt;code&gt;GitHub&lt;/code&gt; authentication in Auth&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Auth supports multiple types of IdP&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GitHub authentication supports granular user audit management&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added the feature of obtaining real IP through &lt;code&gt;PROXY Protocol&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added &lt;code&gt;Opt in to User Experience Program&lt;/code&gt; in &lt;code&gt;System&lt;/code&gt;. Users can opt out to stop us from getting your usage habits.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Fixed&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Custom interception pages no longer affect error codes returned by upstream&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Refactored FVM memory management, significantly reducing memory usage of FVM containers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed an issue where the default administrator account password would occasionally reset during upgrades&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed an issue where rate limiting would count approved attack requests in high-frequency attack calculations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Optimized master-slave configuration synchronization by adding error retry mechanism and improving sync performance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed inconsistency between browser favicon and title display in Pro versions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/chaitin/SafeLine/releases/tag/v7.5.0" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/chaitin/SafeLine/releases/tag/v7.6.2</id>
    <title>New release for SafeLine: SafeLine-CE 7.6.2</title>
    <updated>2025-02-14T01:58:32-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>chaitin/SafeLine</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h3&gt;Feature&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Free now supports viewing up to 20 latest Auth Logs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Free enables access to application logs including access log and error log&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pro increased maximum concurrent users allowed in waiting room to 5,000&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Fixed&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enhanced query performance for statistics dashboard&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved detection engine stability with optimized memory allocation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/chaitin/SafeLine/releases/tag/v7.6.2" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/chaitin/SafeLine/releases/tag/v8.0.0</id>
    <title>New release for SafeLine: SafeLine-CE 8.0.0</title>
    <updated>2025-02-27T06:10:32-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>chaitin/SafeLine</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h3&gt;Improvements&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SafeLine Community Edition has been renamed to Personal Edition  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New Lite Edition launched with premium features for personal use  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New IP Intelligence feature: Direct access to SafePoint IP Intelligence for comprehensive attack behavior analysis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SSE streaming enabled for applications &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Fix&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed delayed data updates in statistics module  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed high memory usage when Anti-Bot Challenge is enabled in certain scenarios  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed application routings limit not taking effect  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed database index length overflow issues&lt;br /&gt;
*Fixed QPS not displaying in SDK bypass mode&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/chaitin/SafeLine/releases/tag/v8.0.0" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/chaitin/SafeLine/releases/tag/v8.1.0</id>
    <title>New release for SafeLine: SafeLine-CE 8.1.0</title>
    <updated>2025-03-14T04:49:09-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>chaitin/SafeLine</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h3&gt;Improvements&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This version involves automatic migration of AUTH-related data. Relevant users are advised to review the data migration rules and upgrade at their discretion.&lt;/strong&gt;
* Modularization of AUTH Functionality
    * Supports application-level configuration to "Enable authentication for specific conditions" and custom whitelist conditions for AUTH
    * Supports selection of different login methods, currently supporting Account/password and GitHub
    * Supports global user management with new user authorization approval
    * Enhanced AUTH logs
    * No longer supports multi-factor authentication scenarios
    * Data Migration Rules
        * Original Custom AUTH Rules
            * Rules configured with "Application" parameter will be migrated to specified applications and automatically enable AUTH for those applications
            * Rules without "Application" parameter will be migrated to apply to all applications and automatically enable AUTH for all applications
            * No rule migration will occur for applications with AUTH already enabled
        * Original Identity Sources
            * Only active identity sources will be migrated; for GitHub, only valid users will be migrated
            * After migration, users will automatically be configured with application authorization based on original associations
* Modularization of HTTP Flood Functionality
    * Changed the entry point for global Rate Limiting configuration
    * Added parameter descriptions for Rate Limiting to provide intuitive understanding of current configurations&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Fix&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Optimized rule compilation module to accelerate rule compilation speed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enhanced detection engine health check mechanism&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved breadcrumb structure&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed issue with abnormal AUTH source IP acquisition under Proxy Protocol configuration&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed problem with site logs closing unexpectedly under certain conditions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed various translation errors&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/chaitin/SafeLine/releases/tag/v8.1.0" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
