<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://selfh.st/apps</id>
  <title>SFTPGo Releases</title>
  <updated>2024-12-02T05:31:25.205869-05:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>selfh.st</name>
    <email>contact@selfh.st</email>
  </author>
  <link href="https://selfh.st/apps" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>Self-hosted software releases generated by selfh.st</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/drakkan/sftpgo/releases/tag/v2.6.0</id>
    <title>New release for SFTPGo: v2.6.0</title>
    <updated>2024-05-15T12:48:03-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>drakkan/sftpgo</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h2&gt;New features&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rewritten WebClient and WebAdmin UIs: we hope you find these new user interfaces more modern and easier to use. They also include a dark mode. Thank you to &lt;a href="https://keenthemes.com/"&gt;KeenThemes&lt;/a&gt; for granting us a custom license to use their amazing &lt;a href="https://keenthemes.com/products/templates-mega-bundle"&gt;Mega Bundle&lt;/a&gt; for the new SFTPGo UIs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Documentation moved to &lt;a href="https://sftpgo.github.io/"&gt;sftpgo.github.io&lt;/a&gt;. The documentation source has been moved to this &lt;a href="https://github.com/sftpgo/docs"&gt;repository&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Notifier plugin: add login succeeded events.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add time-based access restrictions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;EventManager: allow to disable or delete inactive users.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;WebAdmin: allow to require password change and two-factor authentication also for admins.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;WebUIs: add experimental support for internazionalization.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;HTTP, WebDAV: allow to enable HTTP/2.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Several bug fixes, minor features and performance improvements.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Features added to golang/x/crypto/ssh&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This version benefits from some features I added to golang/x/crypto/ssh.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Expose negotiated algorithms so that they can be logged.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add server side multi-step authentication. We were using an out of tree patch in previous versions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add server side support for Diffie Hellman Group Exchange KEX. We were using an out of tree patch in previous versions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Allow to restrict allowed algorithms for public key authentication.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My work on golang/x/crypto/ssh is funded by @FiloSottile's clients. Thank you!!! &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;File transfer errors&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some errors for failed file transfers may reveal more information than necessary such as the actual filesystem path.
These errors are now filtered and the filesystem path is replaced with the virtual path.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to @nezzzumi for reporting this issue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Backward incompatible changes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The configuration file changed in a backward incompatible way. If you are modifying the configuration file instead of setting your customization via environment variables, make sure to adapt it to the new version.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Removed support for the metadata plugin because it is very slow and memory intensive with folders containing millions of files. We will look to add metadata support again in the future, in a smarter way, if companies using SFTPGo are interested enough to fund this work.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Data retention: removed &lt;code&gt;ignore_user_permissions&lt;/code&gt;. This is the default now.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RSA certificates/keys less than 2048 bits are no longer accepted.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SSH: removed moduli files. Diffie Hellman Group Exchange KEX is now built-in. No external moduli files are required.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Environment variables passed to plugins must respect a name convention: if the plugin name is named, for example, &lt;code&gt;sftpgo-plugin-eventsearch&lt;/code&gt; only environment variables starting with &lt;code&gt;SFTPGO_PLUGIN_EVENTSEARCH_&lt;/code&gt; will be made available to the plugin.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Removed support for &lt;code&gt;diffie-hellman-group18-sha512&lt;/code&gt; KEX because our previous implementation was too slow to be useful.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Virtual folders returned along with users by external authentication hooks/plugins must exist.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;EventManager: in previous releases we tried to automatically detect whether &lt;code&gt;{{ObjectData}}&lt;/code&gt; should be a JSON object or a JSON escaped string. This proved problematic and error prone, you now need to explicitly use &lt;code&gt;{{ObjectDataString}}&lt;/code&gt; if you need a JSON escaped string.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Web UIs branding: logo is now also used on the login page as the image is much smaller than in v2.5.x. A separate login image is no longer supported.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Contributions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We now require to agree to our &lt;a href="https://sftpgo.com/cla.html"&gt;Contributor License Agreement&lt;/a&gt; to accept contributions.
The CLA is based on a standard &lt;a href="https://www.apache.org/licenses/icla.pdf"&gt;Apache ICLA&lt;/a&gt;.
Agreeing to the CLA explicitly states that you are entitled to provide a contribution and that you cannot withdraw permission to use your contribution at a later date. This removes any ambiguities or uncertainties.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some past contributors did not respond to our request to sign the CLA or were unable to sign it, so we have rewritten or removed their contributions. The following (minor) features have been removed: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;redirecting output from external programs in SFTPGo logs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;robots.txt endpoint.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;reading data provider username and password from file. This feature was never included in a stable release.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;support for having a different folder prefix for SFTP and FTP. The same can be achieved using a pre-login hook.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[!NOTE] &lt;br /&gt;
Clarified &lt;a href="https://sftpgo.com/compliance.html"&gt;licensing and compliance&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/drakkan/sftpgo/releases/tag/v2.6.0" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/drakkan/sftpgo/releases/tag/v2.6.1</id>
    <title>New release for SFTPGo: v2.6.1</title>
    <updated>2024-06-19T03:45:10-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>drakkan/sftpgo</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h2&gt;New features&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Defender: allow to impose a delay between login attempts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SSH: allow to configure minimum key size for DHGEX.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Transfer logs: add error field.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Logs: redact plugin arguments, they may contain sensitive data.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Web UIs: added &lt;code&gt;robots&lt;/code&gt; meta tag to prevent pages from appearing in search results.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Bug fixes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Web UIs reset password: add proper access control. Fixes CVE-2024-37897.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Web UIs: fixed several minor CSS and rendering issues.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;EventManager: fix &lt;code&gt;ObjectDataString&lt;/code&gt; placeholder for provider events.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Windows installer: set the minimum version to Windows 10 or Windows Server 2016. See Go &lt;a href="https://go.dev/wiki/MinimumRequirements"&gt;minimum requirements&lt;/a&gt;. SFTPGo 2.6.x is compiled using Go 1.22.x.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/drakkan/sftpgo/releases/tag/v2.6.1" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/drakkan/sftpgo/releases/tag/v2.6.2</id>
    <title>New release for SFTPGo: v2.6.2</title>
    <updated>2024-06-21T13:44:24-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>drakkan/sftpgo</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h2&gt;Bug Fixes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Update chi router to v5.0.14 to fix a bug with the compressor handler. It may affect our WebDAV implementation. More &lt;a href="https://github.com/go-chi/chi/issues/923"&gt;details&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/drakkan/sftpgo/releases/tag/v2.6.2" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/drakkan/sftpgo/releases/tag/v2.6.3</id>
    <title>New release for SFTPGo: v2.6.3</title>
    <updated>2024-11-15T12:17:26-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>drakkan/sftpgo</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h2&gt;New features&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;EventManager: system commands are disabled by default and an allow list has been added to explicitly define which ones are allowed. &lt;a href="https://github.com/drakkan/sftpgo/security/advisories/GHSA-49cc-xrjf-9qf7"&gt;CVE-2024-52309&lt;/a&gt;. Thanks to @hyperreality for reporting.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;EventManager: add &lt;code&gt;{{EscapedVirtualPath}}&lt;/code&gt; placeholder.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;EventManager: add &lt;code&gt;{{DateTime}}&lt;/code&gt; placeholder.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Bug Fixes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;WebAdmin: check CSRF header when deleting blocked hosts in the same way we already do for all other state-changing endpoints.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;WebAdmin: correctly display multiple active connections for the same session.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;WebClient: improve readability of upload progress.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Plugins: fix passing additional environment variables.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Backward incompatible changes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you rely on EventManager to execute system commands, you should add the commands to the allowed list like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;SFTPGO_COMMON__EVENT_MANAGER__ENABLED_COMMANDS="/bin/command1,/usr/bin/command2"&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following admin permissions have been removed: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;manage_admins &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;manage_apikeys &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;manage_system &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;retention_checks &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;manage_event_rules&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;manage_roles&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;manage_ip_lists&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now you need to add the &lt;code&gt;*&lt;/code&gt; permission to replace the removed granular permissions because the removed permissions allow actions that should only be allowed to super administrators.
For example, you can define an administrator with the &lt;code&gt;manage_system&lt;/code&gt; permission and not with the &lt;code&gt;manage_admins&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;manage_user&lt;/code&gt; permission, but the &lt;code&gt;manage_system&lt;/code&gt; permission allows you to restore a backup and then create users and administrators.
There is no point in having separate, overlapping permissions.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/drakkan/sftpgo/releases/tag/v2.6.3" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/drakkan/sftpgo/releases/tag/v2.6.4</id>
    <title>New release for SFTPGo: v2.6.4</title>
    <updated>2024-11-28T01:29:43-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>drakkan/sftpgo</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h2&gt;Bug Fixes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;OIDC session cookie: use a cryptographically secure opaque random string, as we already do in all other security-sensitive code in SFTPGo. &lt;a href="https://github.com/drakkan/sftpgo/security/advisories/GHSA-6943-qr24-82vx"&gt;CVE-2024-52801&lt;/a&gt;. Thanks to @denisvr72 for reporting.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;EventManager: fix connection leak when performing file operations on a third-party SFTP server, for example, to copy a file to another SFTP server after an upload.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;CI&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Switch to Azure Trusted Signing to sign &lt;a href="https://github.com/drakkan/sftpgo/issues/1778"&gt;Windows binaries&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/drakkan/sftpgo/releases/tag/v2.6.4" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
