<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://selfh.st/apps</id>
  <title>Sharkey Releases</title>
  <updated>2025-07-22T21:34:35.223918-04:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>selfh.st</name>
    <email>contact@selfh.st</email>
  </author>
  <link href="https://selfh.st/apps" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>Self-hosted software releases generated by selfh.st</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://activitypub.software/TransFem-org/Sharkey/-/releases/2024.11.2</id>
    <title>New release for Sharkey: 2024.11.2</title>
    <updated>2025-01-01T17:29:49+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>TransFem-org/Sharkey</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed scheduled replies attaching a random note as a quote&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://activitypub.software/TransFem-org/Sharkey/-/releases/2024.11.2" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://activitypub.software/TransFem-org/Sharkey/-/releases/2025.2.2</id>
    <title>New release for Sharkey: 2025.2.2</title>
    <updated>2025-03-02T20:48:44+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>TransFem-org/Sharkey</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A fix for an annoying &lt;code&gt;corepack&lt;/code&gt;/&lt;code&gt;pnpm&lt;/code&gt; error.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Optimizations to SQL-based note search.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Support for &lt;code&gt;tsvector&lt;/code&gt; full-text search.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Support for filtering by Module and Flash file types.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixes for quote preview.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixes for hashtags and tag search.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Allow user-initiated object lookups to redirect. (makes the lookup function 100x more likely to actually work instead of throwing a vague error).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add missing translations in various places.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bulk fixes and refactoring of Mastodon API. (it may work better with some clients, and several known bugs are fixed.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Option to regenerate vapid keys without a CLI command.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Revision 2 of the new rate limit system- improved performance, simpler API, and the "role template" rate limit factor now applies to unauthenticated / logged-out requests.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixes for docker build &amp;amp; deployment.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixes for BSD build &amp;amp; deployment.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add a "follow back" button to "user followed you" notifications.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Buttons to accept/reject follow requests directly from a user's profile.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Various rate limit fixes and adjustments.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved support for MFM and HTML ruby.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved browser language detection, especially in cases where we don't have an exact-match language file.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Robots.txt can be configured through admin settings, instead of using the reverse-proxy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Federation fixes and improvements, particularly for software which produces null for Person.discoverable.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Build and development tooling improvements.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixes for import limits and config settings.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixes for reactions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixes for note visibility in streaming API&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Shift-click to automatically boost w/ visibility&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixes to emoji sorting, search, and categorization.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Emoji import now honours the &lt;code&gt;import.downloadTimeout&lt;/code&gt; setting&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Laxer validation for admin-controlled HTML.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add some missing MFM to the cheat sheet.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Record the person who created an invite code.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Classic and narrow UI layout fixes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixes for RSS widgets&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Remove unused "email notification type" settings to avoid user confusion.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Remove duplicate role badges&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add file extension to locally-stored media (allows the reverse-proxy to directly serve media)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The IP address that the server listens on is now configurable&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Users can set a default CW&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Moderators can force a CW for a user&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Moderators can remove the "quote" feature for specific users (local or remote) and remote instances&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Optional separate Redis connection for rate-limiting purposes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ability to log all AP objects- note that this respects deletes, and is optional, as a debugging aid.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Better support for PeerTube thumbnails&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Better interoperability with SocialHome&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Upstream changes:
- A new experimental custom emoji manager using a spreadsheet UI
- Support for PGroonga full-text search, which gives accuracy closer to Meilisearch with dramatically less system load and deployment headache.
- We can log full SQL queries for development
- A bunch of bug fixes for login, note hiding, MFM, and others.
- Remove unused "view source" button.
- Fixes to data saver mode.
- Fixes to Deck UI.
- Add missing translations in various places.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://activitypub.software/TransFem-org/Sharkey/-/releases/2025.2.2" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://activitypub.software/TransFem-org/Sharkey/-/releases/2025.2.3</id>
    <title>New release for Sharkey: 2025.2.3</title>
    <updated>2025-04-27T21:07:06+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>TransFem-org/Sharkey</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;This release fixes several serious security vulnerabilities as part of a coordinated release with Iceshrimp and Misskey. Disclosures for the relevant vulnerabilities will be made available once instances have been patched.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://activitypub.software/TransFem-org/Sharkey/-/releases/2025.2.3" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://activitypub.software/TransFem-org/Sharkey/-/releases/2025.4.2</id>
    <title>New release for Sharkey: 2025.4.2</title>
    <updated>2025-05-29T00:32:17+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>TransFem-org/Sharkey</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mfm now handles some punctuation inside bold/italic blocks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Users mentioned in DMs they can't see are no longer sent notifications.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Optional WebSocket compression.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hopefully a fix for the bug of your own reactions not being marked on posts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Blocks and mutes should now be more effective.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When a note is muted, the reason is shown.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed editing of scheduled posts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Additional moderation logs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Numerous fixes to the Mastodon API.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Users can now delete their own avatars.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Users are now warned when editing a poll, as it can lose all votes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Libretranslate is now supported in addition to DeepL.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Showing linked notes as quotes is no longer automatic (you have to click a button), and it works in more cases.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Admins can change the level of "authorized fetch" via the frontend ("never", "always", and the new "essential" that serves a reduced amount of data to non-signed requests), and users can override this for their own data.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The notification dot on the favicon should work in more cases, and be more visible.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The "replies" collection is now exposed on all notes (we still don't &lt;em&gt;fetch&lt;/em&gt; remote replies, but we enable other software to do so).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved compatibility with Lemmy and other ActivityPub implementations that &lt;code&gt;Announce&lt;/code&gt; activities other than &lt;code&gt;Note&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Numerous translation improvements (Daniel Ares for German, Ahri for Thai and Vietnamese).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Support for BunnyCDN in addition to S3-like object stores.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sensitive/content-warned content is not served to the Discordbot (Discord uses the mastodon api to fetch notes for their previews, and they've decided to ignore CWs in favour of their own &lt;code&gt;||spoiler||&lt;/code&gt; markers-- we don't agree with that decision).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Admins can now inject custom HTML in every page's &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;head&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; (e.g. custom CSS).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Admin set MOTDs can now use HTML.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Links in profile fields are now verified for remote users.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed signature verification for paginated AP requests.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Admins can now remove a role's color.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Admins can disable the use of the "proxy account" (although this &lt;em&gt;will&lt;/em&gt; break some lists!).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Disabling the local timeline also disables the "featured" timeline on the logged-out front page.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Drive cleaner now shows all files, even those inside folders.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Delivery of activities has been re-ordered a bit, this should mitigate the infamous "Yaseen bug".&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;URL previews once again follow redirects.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Config file(s) can now be placed in any directory.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can now configure the directory for drive files (when not using S3 or similar).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improvements to the admin UI.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved "delete account" process with better reliability.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New role setting "can trend".&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;new role conditions "is from bubble instance", "is from instance X", "has more/fewer than X local/remote followers", "follows more/fewer than X local/remote accounts".&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The config option &lt;code&gt;allowPrivateNetworks&lt;/code&gt; can now specify ports for each network.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New "pattern checker" tool to test your word mutes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The web frontend passes the user's authorization token in a header instead of the request body-- this should prevent accidentally leaking the token via logs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved interoperability with Akkoma and Wafrn "invisible mentions"&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;From Upstream&lt;/strong&gt;:
* Brand-new job queue dashboard
* All-new settings/preferences system that enables searching of settings!
* Admins can now limit the max file size for users, via roles-- if this is applied to remote users, it applies to caching.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Potential Gotchas&lt;/strong&gt;:
* If your browser is logged into more than one account, you may need to log in again, due to an upstream change.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://activitypub.software/TransFem-org/Sharkey/-/releases/2025.4.2" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://activitypub.software/TransFem-org/Sharkey/-/releases/2025.4.3</id>
    <title>New release for Sharkey: 2025.4.3</title>
    <updated>2025-06-19T22:20:26+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>TransFem-org/Sharkey</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Migrating frontend preferences from pre-2025.4.2 should be more reliable now.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Parsing of incoming activities should be faster and use less memory.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Many database queries are now faster.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Blocking / silencing many instances will no longer slow down yours.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Caches should be more correct.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The "slow query" warning in the server logs can now be configured.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;S3 errors during media uploads are now correctly reported to the frontend.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;More consistent handling of note visibility and silenced instances / users.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The MFM parser now accepts markdown image links like &lt;code&gt;![text](url)&lt;/code&gt;, and those images are fetched like attachments (they're not yet rendered inline, though).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Many privacy / security fixes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved notification grouping.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Suspending a user no longer severs their follows, so they'll be restored when the user is un-suspended.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;On a note's detailed view, the "reactions" tab shows all the details of the first reaction group by default.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;API endpoints emit a &lt;code&gt;X-Robots-Tag: noindex&lt;/code&gt; header to deter indexing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Videos will be optimized for streaming (not re-encoded, the metadata will just be modified slightly).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The admin view of a user's profile now shows their sign-up reason.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A few admin and moderation pages have been redesigned and should be more usable, especially on mobile.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Server logging has been improved, it should now provide more details with less noise.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved interoperability of quotes with Mastodon and other software that implements fep-e232 and/or fep-044f.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Show attributions (&lt;code&gt;fediverse:creator&lt;/code&gt;) in link previews, and allow users to set their "attribution domains".&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If enabled in the default policy, non-logged-in users can use translation features.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some frontend pages now retry API calls when they hit a rate limit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;DeepLX works again.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed receiving poll votes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Users can again set their custom search engine for MFM's &lt;code&gt;[search]&lt;/code&gt; feature.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"Show muted words" works the right way around.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reworked the "trending polls" page.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Recommendations to admins&lt;/strong&gt;:
- If your users had a broken migration, they can try re-importing via &lt;code&gt;Settings → other → 🗘 Migrate old client settings&lt;/code&gt;, but we suggest backing up their current preferences first.
- The default policy now disables translation, you may want to create a conditional role matching all local users to re-enable it for them.
- We've added many new indexes to the database, we recommend running a vacuum (analyse, verbose) after the migrations have completed.
- If you do not use Docker, to avoid potential crashes when rendering some SVG images, you should make sure that your system has &lt;code&gt;librsvg&lt;/code&gt; and some fonts (on Debian-style systems, that's &lt;code&gt;librsvg2-2&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;fonts-noto&lt;/code&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://activitypub.software/TransFem-org/Sharkey/-/releases/2025.4.3" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
