<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://selfh.st/apps</id>
  <title>Sharkey Releases</title>
  <updated>2024-10-29T19:33:44.080811-04:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>selfh.st</name>
    <email>contact@selfh.st</email>
  </author>
  <link href="https://selfh.st/apps" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>Self-hosted software releases generated by selfh.st</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://activitypub.software/TransFem-org/Sharkey/-/releases/2024.3.2</id>
    <title>New release for Sharkey: 2024.3.2 Security Release</title>
    <updated>2024-03-30T11:28:05+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>TransFem-org/Sharkey</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h2&gt;This is a minor release with important security fixes please update immediately&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Changes in this Release:
- prohibited words are now correctly checked when creating notes
- notes with CW are no longer shown on the welcome page for non-logged-in users
- database migrations should no longer timeout
- docker image improvements
- important security fixes &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Important Note for Users that do NOT use S3 and that USE Docker&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There have been some improvements made to the Docker images that should fix some issues with that the container now runs as a seperate Sharkey user with id 991:991 so its required to change ownership of the files directory to do that run the following in the directory where your docker-compose.yml file is
```bash&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;replace web with what ever you named the sharkey service if you changed the default docker compose file&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;docker compose exec --user=root web chown -R sharkey:sharkey /sharkey/files
```&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://activitypub.software/TransFem-org/Sharkey/-/releases/2024.3.2" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://activitypub.software/TransFem-org/Sharkey/-/releases/2024.3.3</id>
    <title>New release for Sharkey: 2024.3.3</title>
    <updated>2024-05-09T20:32:38+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>TransFem-org/Sharkey</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a security fix for a defect in the validation of JSON-LD signatures that could lead to account takeover&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;non-ascii characters are now allowed in custom emoji names (please don't go too wild, other instances may not recognise the names)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;UI language is now saved and restored in "preferences backup"&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;embedding a CW-ed note on other sites now only shows the CW, not the whole note&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;various imports, and the generation of movie thumbnails, are once again working&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ranged requests to proxied files are now correctly handled (should improve video playback on iOS)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the modtracker player is now loaded on-demand, so the frontend loads faster&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;floating UI windows now render custom emojis in the titlebar&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the "word mute" feature now includes poll choices and image alt-texts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;custom emoji should look better in admin panel&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;un-pinning emojis from the selector pop-up works better&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;editing a note to add/remove an attachment, or the edit alt-text, works properly now&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;instance description and server rules can now contain more HTML (images, centered text, details/summary, styled links)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;clearing cached files from drive should be more reliable&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;all paginated views (e.g. timelines, various admin pages) should be more stable and not randomly drop items&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://activitypub.software/TransFem-org/Sharkey/-/releases/2024.3.3" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://activitypub.software/TransFem-org/Sharkey/-/releases/2024.5.1</id>
    <title>New release for Sharkey: 2024.5.1</title>
    <updated>2024-06-26T20:16:59+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>TransFem-org/Sharkey</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;antennas can now include all users from an instance (e.g. &lt;code&gt;*@example.com&lt;/code&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;optional notification dot on browser icon (there are CORS restrictions, check &lt;a href="https://docs.joinsharkey.org/docs/install/faqs/"&gt;our FAQ&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;any configuration value can be overridden via environment variables (see &lt;a href="https://docs.joinsharkey.org/docs/install/fresh/"&gt;our installation guide&lt;/a&gt; for details)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;more timelines have the "show boosts" and "only notes with files" filters&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the "oneko" animation frames can be changed via &lt;a href="https://docs.joinsharkey.org/docs/customisation/themes/"&gt;theming&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;better rendering of notes with bidirectional and right-to-left text&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;parent notes can be collapsed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;search results in "manage custom emoji" should now show all matching emoji&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;more MFM effects: &lt;code&gt;$[followmouse]&lt;/code&gt; from Cutiekey, &lt;code&gt;$[crop]&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;$[fade]&lt;/code&gt; from Firefish&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;users can select their preferred search engine for MFM's &lt;code&gt;[search]&lt;/code&gt; feature&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;when editing a note, the update is now also sent to people who reacted or boosted the original note, even if they are not following the author&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;admins can delete all files of a user with a single button click&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;probably lighter load in some clustering setups&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;admins can set separate download timeout / max size for imports (e.g. note imports)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;some security fixes related to malicious notes and UI interactions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://activitypub.software/TransFem-org/Sharkey/-/releases/2024.5.1" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://activitypub.software/TransFem-org/Sharkey/-/releases/2024.8.1</id>
    <title>New release for Sharkey: 2024.8.1</title>
    <updated>2024-09-13T19:00:50+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>TransFem-org/Sharkey</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;User visible changes:
* You can now search your drive files by name or description.
* You can now disable the "edited" notifications.
* When you block a user, they're now also muted, so you won't see their notes even if they get boosted into your timeline (you can un-mute them if you want).
* "My Plays" page now shows the visibility of plays without clicking into each individual play.
* Users can now report pages, galleries, and plays.
* Follow requests from suspended accounts are no longer shown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of interest to admins:
* Password checks and websocket connections are rate limited now; this improves security and resistance to denial-of-service attacks.
* When an admin deletes all files of another user, those deletions are logged in the moderation log.
* All memory caches are now limited, Sharkey should use less RAM overall.
* new setting &lt;code&gt;attachLdSignatureForRelays&lt;/code&gt; to disable sending LD-Signatures to relays.
* More checks at startup: db reachability, config file presence.
* URL previews are cached on the server, this should reduce the load on websites that get linked in popular notes.
* Remote documents that return &lt;code&gt;text/html&lt;/code&gt; but specify &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;link rel="alternate" type="application/activity+json" href="..."/&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; tags are now supported.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Upgrade notes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some column sizes have changed; upstream recommendeds to run:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;sql
DROP INDEX "public"."IDX_e5848eac4940934e23dbc17581";
CREATE INDEX CONCURRENTLY "IDX_e5848eac4940934e23dbc17581" ON "drive_file" ("uri");&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;manually on your database&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://activitypub.software/TransFem-org/Sharkey/-/releases/2024.8.1" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://activitypub.software/TransFem-org/Sharkey/-/releases/2024.8.2</id>
    <title>New release for Sharkey: 2024.8.2</title>
    <updated>2024-09-23T19:37:44+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>TransFem-org/Sharkey</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;Of interest to admins:
- A pretty bad memory leak has been fixed. It was caused due to a leak that can sometimes occur in &lt;code&gt;happy-dom&lt;/code&gt; if you don't explicitly call &lt;code&gt;DetachedWindowAPI.close&lt;/code&gt; after you are done using a &lt;code&gt;Window&lt;/code&gt;.
- Sponsor information is now powered by OpenCollective.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://activitypub.software/TransFem-org/Sharkey/-/releases/2024.8.2" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
