<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://selfh.st/apps</id>
  <title>Sharkey Releases</title>
  <updated>2025-02-15T01:34:39.179554-05:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>selfh.st</name>
    <email>contact@selfh.st</email>
  </author>
  <link href="https://selfh.st/apps" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>Self-hosted software releases generated by selfh.st</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://activitypub.software/TransFem-org/Sharkey/-/releases/2024.9.2</id>
    <title>New release for Sharkey: 2024.9.2</title>
    <updated>2024-11-20T05:47:17+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>TransFem-org/Sharkey</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;This release fixes a 0day DoS exploit in active use against Sharkey instances.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Keep in mind that this is &lt;em&gt;different&lt;/em&gt; from the coordinated security release that will occur tomorrow.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://activitypub.software/TransFem-org/Sharkey/-/releases/2024.9.2" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://activitypub.software/TransFem-org/Sharkey/-/releases/2024.9.3</id>
    <title>New release for Sharkey: 2024.9.3</title>
    <updated>2024-11-21T03:03:14+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>TransFem-org/Sharkey</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;This release fixes several critical security vulnerabilities, as part of a coordinated disclosure with upstream, IceShrimp.js, and Firefish.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://activitypub.software/TransFem-org/Sharkey/-/releases/2024.9.3" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://activitypub.software/TransFem-org/Sharkey/-/releases/2024.9.4</id>
    <title>New release for Sharkey: 2024.9.4</title>
    <updated>2024-11-28T05:56:15+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>TransFem-org/Sharkey</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;This release provides the following fixes:
- Most endpoints now have an explicit rate limit set on them, and the ones that don't use a global default. If any of these limits end up being too strict for practical use, please let the team know.
- Media proxy rate limits are now more relaxed.
- When note API responses are redacted due to being blocked by the user that posted them, the means by which the notes reactions are redacted is now slightly different.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://activitypub.software/TransFem-org/Sharkey/-/releases/2024.9.4" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://activitypub.software/TransFem-org/Sharkey/-/releases/2024.11.1</id>
    <title>New release for Sharkey: 2024.11.1</title>
    <updated>2024-12-31T03:04:19+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>TransFem-org/Sharkey</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Flash player! You can now attach &lt;code&gt;.swf&lt;/code&gt; files to notes and play them back in the browser, using &lt;a href="https://ruffle.rs"&gt;Ruffle&lt;/a&gt;, an Adobe Flash emulator.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Scheduled notes, both through the web UI and through apps using the Mastodon API.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hostname contstraints for actors and activities are now slightly relaxed, restoring compatibility with Bridgy, an ActivityPub &amp;lt;-&amp;gt; AtProto bridge.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved interoperability with other Fediverse software (&lt;code&gt;Dislike&lt;/code&gt; activities are now handled, more types of "featured"/pinned activities are now allowed, activities interacting with other activities not known by the instance are no longer ignored).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;FriendlyCaptcha is now supported as a Captcha provider.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can now disable the RSS feed for your account.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can now disable the online status of your profile all together, rather than just making it always offline.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Notes containing links to other notes (IE how Mastodon users might imitate quotes) are now rendered similarly to quotes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;User profiles now show pinned notes by default when checking a profile, using the pinned notes tab.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can now configure the file permission bits used by locally-stored drive files via &lt;code&gt;filePermissionBits&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Poll edits are handled better.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Profile edits are now only federated if the ActivityPub representation of their profile changes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Several improvements to error messages in logs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enhanced ratelimiting logic.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Highlights of changes from Misskey:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Users are now notified when their account is logged into from another device&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Users can now hide all their notes from logged-out users.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Users can make past notes only visible to followers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If no administrators/moderators have logged in for a week, the instance will automatically switch to invite only.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"Resolve report" and "forward report" are now separate actions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Animated MFM is now disabled if the browser is set to "reduced motion" mode&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Possible surprises:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If your timeline is jumping around a bit while scrolling, try going to "settings -&amp;gt; other -&amp;gt; experimental features -&amp;gt; enable render note skipping" and turn it off.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;During the 2024.9 release series, setting up allow-list federation may in fact have added those instances to the &lt;em&gt;block list&lt;/em&gt;. Please double-check your allow-lists and block-lists.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The sign-in flow for the web UI has changed (username and password are now input separately), which may break some bots or clients.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The way themes are applied is slightly different now- previously, a theme setting &lt;code&gt;accent&lt;/code&gt; became the CSS variable &lt;code&gt;--accent&lt;/code&gt;, whereas now it becomes &lt;code&gt;--MI_THEME-accent&lt;/code&gt;. Most users won't be affected by this, except those using custom CSS.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Special upgrade notes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Instances setting CSPs via HTTP headers should add &lt;code&gt;raw.esm.sh&lt;/code&gt; (for Flash playback) and &lt;code&gt;cdn.jsdelivr.net&lt;/code&gt; (for FriendlyCaptcha) to their CSPs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A newer Node.js version is required- 22.11.0&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you're not using Docker, you'll have to &lt;code&gt;pnpm clean-all&lt;/code&gt; before &lt;code&gt;pnpm install --frozen-lockfile&lt;/code&gt;, otherwise some modules will break.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://activitypub.software/TransFem-org/Sharkey/-/releases/2024.11.1" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://activitypub.software/TransFem-org/Sharkey/-/releases/2024.11.2</id>
    <title>New release for Sharkey: 2024.11.2</title>
    <updated>2025-01-01T17:29:49+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>TransFem-org/Sharkey</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed scheduled replies attaching a random note as a quote&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://activitypub.software/TransFem-org/Sharkey/-/releases/2024.11.2" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
