<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://selfh.st/apps</id>
  <title>Sharkey Releases</title>
  <updated>2024-12-31T20:33:55.307558-05:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>selfh.st</name>
    <email>contact@selfh.st</email>
  </author>
  <link href="https://selfh.st/apps" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>Self-hosted software releases generated by selfh.st</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://activitypub.software/TransFem-org/Sharkey/-/releases/2024.9.1</id>
    <title>New release for Sharkey: 2024.9.1</title>
    <updated>2024-11-05T04:16:48+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>TransFem-org/Sharkey</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;new "following" view, inspired by Cohost's "following feed"&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;when following links to external sites, users are asked for confirmation (users and admins can set lists of destination domains that won't trigger the confirmation dialog, or disable it completely)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;users can turn off cat-speak for all notes they see&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;avatar decorations can be placed behind the avatar picture (so it can have a tail)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;users can now make in-app notifications clickable in settings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;capitalized emoji aliases are now properly found in the emoji picker&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;remote polls' vote counts can be manually refreshed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;on the user profile page, we show if they're blocked, muted, followed, &amp;amp;c&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;user profiles show their latest notes by default, not their pinned notes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;users can see their pending outgoing follow requests&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;note attachments are navigable via keyboard&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;users have a "default files as NSFW" setting, separate from "always mark files as NSFW" (the new one is fully under user control, the other one can be forced by admins)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;rejecting a new user's sign-up application frees that username for future users&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;admin have more control over the maximum text size for notes: they can limit main text, cw, and alt text, separately for local and remote notes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;moderators can delete all files from a remote instance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;local "system accounts" are protected from accidental deletion&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;information about remote instances includes following/followers
  relations, and actions that break federation will show how many
  relations will be severed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;when an instance is blocked or silenced because it's on a sub-domain
  of a blocked / silenced domain, admins get a clear message about it,
  and the buttons to un-block / un-silence are disabled instead of
  just useless&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;reports from an instance can be automatically rejected&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;abuse reports are rendered better in small viewports like phones&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;abuse reports federate correctly with Akkoma &amp;amp; Pleroma&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;welcome page and sidebar can have their own image, instead of
  sharing the instance icon, so an instance can have a big fancy logo
  without having to fork Sharkey&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;if the instance's donation link goes to Open Collective, supporters will
  be shown in the "about" page&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Highlights of changes from Misskey:
* dedicated view for notes and timelines to embed on websites
* allow-list federation
* users can set a message to be sent when accepting a follow request
* the list of blocked and silenced instances is now inside the "moderation" section of the admin  control panel&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Possible surprises:
* the client setting "other → experimental features → enable condensed line for acct" finally has an effect: it compresses usernames horizontally instead of truncating them; that setting has been there for several releases, but had next to no effect, so some users may have enabled it and forgot about it&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Special upgrade notes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When upgrading an existing instance to version 2024.9.1, the Following Feed will initially be empty.
The feed will gradually fill as new posts federate, but it may be desirable to back-fill the feed with existing data.
This database script will populate the feed with the latest post of each type for all users, ensuring that data is fully populated after the update.
Run this after migrations but before starting the instance.
Warning: the script may take a long time to execute!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;sql
INSERT INTO latest_note (user_id, note_id, is_public, is_reply, is_quote)
SELECT
    "userId" as user_id,
    id as note_id,
    visibility = 'public' AS is_public,
    "replyId" IS NOT NULL AS is_reply,
    (
        "renoteId" IS NOT NULL
            AND (
            text IS NOT NULL
                OR cw IS NOT NULL
                OR "replyId" IS NOT NULL
                OR "hasPoll"
                OR "fileIds" != '{}'
            )
        ) AS is_quote
FROM note
WHERE ( -- Exclude pure renotes (boosts)
                "renoteId" IS NULL
                    OR text IS NOT NULL
                    OR cw IS NOT NULL
                    OR "replyId" IS NOT NULL
                    OR "hasPoll"
                    OR "fileIds" != '{}'
                )
ORDER BY id DESC -- This part is very important: it ensures that we only load the *latest* notes of each type. Do not remove it!
ON CONFLICT DO NOTHING; -- Any conflicts are guaranteed to be older notes that we can ignore.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://activitypub.software/TransFem-org/Sharkey/-/releases/2024.9.1" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://activitypub.software/TransFem-org/Sharkey/-/releases/2024.9.2</id>
    <title>New release for Sharkey: 2024.9.2</title>
    <updated>2024-11-20T05:47:17+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>TransFem-org/Sharkey</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;This release fixes a 0day DoS exploit in active use against Sharkey instances.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Keep in mind that this is &lt;em&gt;different&lt;/em&gt; from the coordinated security release that will occur tomorrow.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://activitypub.software/TransFem-org/Sharkey/-/releases/2024.9.2" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://activitypub.software/TransFem-org/Sharkey/-/releases/2024.9.3</id>
    <title>New release for Sharkey: 2024.9.3</title>
    <updated>2024-11-21T03:03:14+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>TransFem-org/Sharkey</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;This release fixes several critical security vulnerabilities, as part of a coordinated disclosure with upstream, IceShrimp.js, and Firefish.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://activitypub.software/TransFem-org/Sharkey/-/releases/2024.9.3" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://activitypub.software/TransFem-org/Sharkey/-/releases/2024.9.4</id>
    <title>New release for Sharkey: 2024.9.4</title>
    <updated>2024-11-28T05:56:15+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>TransFem-org/Sharkey</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;This release provides the following fixes:
- Most endpoints now have an explicit rate limit set on them, and the ones that don't use a global default. If any of these limits end up being too strict for practical use, please let the team know.
- Media proxy rate limits are now more relaxed.
- When note API responses are redacted due to being blocked by the user that posted them, the means by which the notes reactions are redacted is now slightly different.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://activitypub.software/TransFem-org/Sharkey/-/releases/2024.9.4" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://activitypub.software/TransFem-org/Sharkey/-/releases/2024.11.1</id>
    <title>New release for Sharkey: 2024.11.1</title>
    <updated>2024-12-31T03:04:19+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>TransFem-org/Sharkey</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Flash player! You can now attach &lt;code&gt;.swf&lt;/code&gt; files to notes and play them back in the browser, using &lt;a href="https://ruffle.rs"&gt;Ruffle&lt;/a&gt;, an Adobe Flash emulator.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Scheduled notes, both through the web UI and through apps using the Mastodon API.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hostname contstraints for actors and activities are now slightly relaxed, restoring compatibility with Bridgy, an ActivityPub &amp;lt;-&amp;gt; AtProto bridge.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved interoperability with other Fediverse software (&lt;code&gt;Dislike&lt;/code&gt; activities are now handled, more types of "featured"/pinned activities are now allowed, activities interacting with other activities not known by the instance are no longer ignored).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;FriendlyCaptcha is now supported as a Captcha provider.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can now disable the RSS feed for your account.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can now disable the online status of your profile all together, rather than just making it always offline.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Notes containing links to other notes (IE how Mastodon users might imitate quotes) are now rendered similarly to quotes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;User profiles now show pinned notes by default when checking a profile, using the pinned notes tab.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can now configure the file permission bits used by locally-stored drive files via &lt;code&gt;filePermissionBits&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Poll edits are handled better.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Profile edits are now only federated if the ActivityPub representation of their profile changes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Several improvements to error messages in logs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enhanced ratelimiting logic.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Highlights of changes from Misskey:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Users are now notified when their account is logged into from another device&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Users can now hide all their notes from logged-out users.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Users can make past notes only visible to followers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If no administrators/moderators have logged in for a week, the instance will automatically switch to invite only.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"Resolve report" and "forward report" are now separate actions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Animated MFM is now disabled if the browser is set to "reduced motion" mode&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Possible surprises:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If your timeline is jumping around a bit while scrolling, try going to "settings -&amp;gt; other -&amp;gt; experimental features -&amp;gt; enable render note skipping" and turn it off.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;During the 2024.9 release series, setting up allow-list federation may in fact have added those instances to the &lt;em&gt;block list&lt;/em&gt;. Please double-check your allow-lists and block-lists.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The sign-in flow for the web UI has changed (username and password are now input separately), which may break some bots or clients.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The way themes are applied is slightly different now- previously, a theme setting &lt;code&gt;accent&lt;/code&gt; became the CSS variable &lt;code&gt;--accent&lt;/code&gt;, whereas now it becomes &lt;code&gt;--MI_THEME-accent&lt;/code&gt;. Most users won't be affected by this, except those using custom CSS.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Special upgrade notes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Instances setting CSPs via HTTP headers should add &lt;code&gt;raw.esm.sh&lt;/code&gt; (for Flash playback) and &lt;code&gt;cdn.jsdelivr.net&lt;/code&gt; (for FriendlyCaptcha) to their CSPs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A newer Node.js version is required- 22.11.0&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you're not using Docker, you'll have to &lt;code&gt;pnpm clean-all&lt;/code&gt; before &lt;code&gt;pnpm install --frozen-lockfile&lt;/code&gt;, otherwise some modules will break.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://activitypub.software/TransFem-org/Sharkey/-/releases/2024.11.1" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
