<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://selfh.st/apps</id>
  <title>Tailscale Releases</title>
  <updated>2024-07-04T21:31:32.100914-04:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>selfh.st</name>
    <email>contact@selfh.st</email>
  </author>
  <link href="https://selfh.st/apps" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>Self-hosted software releases generated by selfh.st</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/tailscale/tailscale/releases/tag/v1.66.3</id>
    <title>New release for Tailscale: v1.66.3</title>
    <updated>2024-05-14T17:23:01-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>tailscale/tailscale</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h3&gt;All platforms&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Login URLs did not always appear in the console when running &lt;a href="https://tailscale.com/kb/1080/cli#up"&gt;&lt;code&gt;tailscale up&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Android&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Reintroduced the Quick Settings title that v1.66.0 temporarily removed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Improved the VPN service connection logic, especially when rebooting the device with Always-On VPN enabled.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: The persistent VPN status notification now informs the user with a muted icon when the VPN is disconnected. VPN status notifications can be disabled in the system notification settings.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: The "Enable" button in the exit node selector banner now renders with the correct background color.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Kubernetes operator&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Breaking change: Starting with v1.66, the Kubernetes operator must always run the same or later version as the proxies it manages.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New: &lt;a href="https://tailscale.com/kb/1236/kubernetes-operator#expose-a-cloud-service-to-your-tailnet"&gt;Expose cloud services&lt;/a&gt; on cluster network to the tailnet, using Kubernetes &lt;code&gt;ExternalName&lt;/code&gt; Services. This allows exposing cloud services, such as RDS instances, to tailnet by their DNS names.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New: Expose tailnet services that use &lt;a href="https://tailscale.com/kb/1153/enabling-https"&gt;Tailscale HTTPS&lt;/a&gt; to cluster workloads. Refer to &lt;a href="https://github.com/tailscale/tailscale/pull/11019"&gt;#11019&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New: Cluster workloads can now refer to Tailscale Ingress resources by their MagicDNS names. Refer to &lt;a href="https://github.com/tailscale/tailscale/pull/11019"&gt;#11019&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New: Configure environment variables for Tailscale Kubernetes operator proxies using &lt;code&gt;ProxyClass&lt;/code&gt; CRD.
Refer to &lt;a href="https://github.com/tailscale/tailscale/blob/main/k8s-operator/api.md#proxyclass"&gt;&lt;code&gt;ProxyClass&lt;/code&gt; API&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New: Expose &lt;code&gt;tailscaled&lt;/code&gt; metrics endpoint for Tailscale Kubernetes operator proxies through &lt;code&gt;ProxyClass&lt;/code&gt; CRD. Note that the &lt;code&gt;tailscaled&lt;/code&gt; metrics are unstable and will likely change in the future. Refer to &lt;a href="https://github.com/tailscale/tailscale/blob/main/k8s-operator/api.md#proxyclass"&gt;&lt;code&gt;ProxyClass&lt;/code&gt; API&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New: Configure labels for the Kubernetes operator Pods with Helm chart values. Refer to &lt;a href="https://github.com/tailscale/tailscale/blob/main/cmd/k8s-operator/deploy/chart/values.yaml"&gt;Helm chart values&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New: Configure affinity rules for Kubernetes operator proxy Pods with &lt;code&gt;ProxyClass&lt;/code&gt;. Refer to &lt;a href="https://github.com/tailscale/tailscale/blob/main/k8s-operator/api.md#proxyclass"&gt;&lt;code&gt;ProxyClass&lt;/code&gt; API&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Kubernetes operator proxy &lt;code&gt;init&lt;/code&gt; container no longer attempts to enable IPv6 forwarding on systems that don't have IPv6 module loaded. Refer to &lt;a href="https://github.com/tailscale/tailscale/pull/11867"&gt;#11867&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Containers&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Tailscale containers running on Kubernetes no longer error if an empty Kubernetes &lt;code&gt;Secret&lt;/code&gt; is pre-created for the &lt;code&gt;tailscaled&lt;/code&gt; state. Refer to &lt;a href="https://github.com/tailscale/tailscale/pull/11326"&gt;#11326&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Improved the ambiguous error messages when Tailscale running on Kubernetes does not have the right permissions to perform actions against the &lt;code&gt;tailscaled&lt;/code&gt; state &lt;code&gt;Secret&lt;/code&gt;. Refer to &lt;a href="https://github.com/tailscale/tailscale/pull/11326"&gt;#11326&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/tailscale/tailscale/releases/tag/v1.66.3" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/tailscale/tailscale/releases/tag/v1.66.4</id>
    <title>New release for Tailscale: v1.66.4</title>
    <updated>2024-05-20T21:05:50-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>tailscale/tailscale</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h3&gt;All platforms&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Restored UDP connectivity through &lt;a href="/kb/1258/mullvad-exit-nodes"&gt;Mullvad exit nodes&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Linux&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Stateful filtering is now off by default. Stateful filtering was introduced in 1.66.0 as a mitigation for a vulnerability described in &lt;a href="/security-bulletins#ts-2024-005"&gt;TS-2024-005&lt;/a&gt;, and inadvertently broke DNS resolution from containers running on the host. Most vulnerable setups are protected by other mitigations already, except when &lt;code&gt;autogroup:danger-all&lt;/code&gt; is used in &lt;a href="/kb/1018/acls"&gt;ACLs&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/tailscale/tailscale/releases/tag/v1.66.4" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/tailscale/tailscale/releases/tag/v1.68.0</id>
    <title>New release for Tailscale: v1.68.0</title>
    <updated>2024-06-12T14:08:44-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>tailscale/tailscale</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h2&gt;All Platforms&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Build Tailscale with Go 1.22.4&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New: Auto-updates are allowed in containers, but ignore the tailnet-wide default&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New: Apply auto-updates even if the node is down or disconnected from the coordination server.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New: &lt;code&gt;tailscale lock status&lt;/code&gt; now prints the node's signature.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Windows&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: The exe installer no longer has the ability to automatically download MSI packages for Windows 7 and Windows 8. See the &lt;a href="https://tailscale.com/changelog#2023-05-24"&gt;v1.42.0 changelog&lt;/a&gt; for our initial end of life annoucement.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;macOS&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New: The Standalone variant of Tailscale can now install the Tailscale CLI in &lt;code&gt;/usr/local/bin&lt;/code&gt; for quicker and easier access.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New: Tailscale now detects any attempt to use DHCP Option 121 to misroute traffic meant for the VPN (TunnelVision attack), and presents a warning to the user. System administrators can disable this warning with a system policy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New: The Standalone variant of the client now supports notifications when a file is received using Taildrop.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Tailscale now starts more reliably if another VPN app was running when Tailscale was enabled.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: The .pkg installer now terminates Tailscale and the VPN extension before proceeding with the installation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Tailscale now properly detects any copy of TunnelBear installed on the Mac, and warns the user about incompatibility.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Resolved an issue that could have caused “Using Exit Node” to incorrectly appear in the app menu before completing onboarding, upon first app launch.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;iOS&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Battery life is optimized by offloading DNS resolution to iOS in more cases.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Tailscale now starts more reliably if another VPN app was running when Tailscale was enabled.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Opening the bug report view no longer copies the bug report ID to the Clipboard automatically.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: The Reauthenticate button within in-app key expiry notifications now works properly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Minor tweaks to UI colors when dark mode is enabled.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;tvOS&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Tailscale now starts more reliably if another VPN app was running when Tailscale was enabled.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: The Reauthenticate button within in-app key expiry notifications now works properly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Android&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed:  Exit node selection.  If the exit node location is available, we’ll now show the Country and City instead of the raw node name on the home screen&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: The on-off switch state better matches the VPN state&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Running as an exit node and using an exit node are now mutually exclusive&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Disconnect notifications are now background notifications and navigation from notifications is improved&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: Crash when running multiple VPN applications&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: MDM support for forced exit nodes and rendering of the organization name&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Tailscale will now start automatically after the first login&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/tailscale/tailscale/releases/tag/v1.68.0" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/tailscale/tailscale/releases/tag/v1.68.1</id>
    <title>New release for Tailscale: v1.68.1</title>
    <updated>2024-06-14T16:04:57-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>tailscale/tailscale</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h2&gt;All Platforms&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: &lt;a href="https://tailscale.com/kb/1201/4via6-subnets"&gt;4via6 subnet router&lt;/a&gt; advertisement works as expected.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Linux&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: &lt;a href="https://tailscale.com/kb/1193/tailscale-ssh"&gt;Tailscale SSH&lt;/a&gt; access to Security-Enhanced Linux (SELinux) machines works as expected.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/tailscale/tailscale/releases/tag/v1.68.1" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/tailscale/tailscale/releases/tag/v1.68.2</id>
    <title>New release for Tailscale: v1.68.2</title>
    <updated>2024-07-03T07:18:34-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>tailscale/tailscale</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h2&gt;All Platforms&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed: &lt;a href="https://tailscale.com/kb/1226/tailnet-lock"&gt;Tailnet lock&lt;/a&gt; validation of rotation signatures now permits multiple nodes signed by the same pre-signed reusable auth key.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;macOS, iOS&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed: Wake from sleep reliability is improved for re-connections and transitions between networks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/tailscale/tailscale/releases/tag/v1.68.2" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
