<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://selfh.st/apps</id>
  <title>Tamari Releases</title>
  <updated>2025-07-30T09:32:00.904830-04:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>selfh.st</name>
    <email>contact@selfh.st</email>
  </author>
  <link href="https://selfh.st/apps" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>Self-hosted software releases generated by selfh.st</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/alexbates/Tamari/releases/tag/v0.9</id>
    <title>New release for Tamari: Version 0.9</title>
    <updated>2024-09-22T14:30:11-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>alexbates/Tamari</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;Split Account page into two pages, Account Preferences and Account History. Account History displays a timeline of account events including account creation, email change, password change, recipe creation, and recipe edits. Added initial support for internationalization and localization. The first two supported languages are Spanish and German.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/alexbates/Tamari/releases/tag/v0.9" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/alexbates/Tamari/releases/tag/v1.0</id>
    <title>New release for Tamari: Version 1.0</title>
    <updated>2024-12-02T18:09:59-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>alexbates/Tamari</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;Addded new language support: Simplified Chinese, French, and Russian. Implemented pagination on Meal Planner Completed page. Developed a comprehensive REST API which can be used to interact with recipes, shopping lists, and meal plans. The API is disabled by default. Designed an API documentation page that correctly reflects app configuration.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/alexbates/Tamari/releases/tag/v1.0" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/alexbates/Tamari/releases/tag/v1.1</id>
    <title>New release for Tamari: Version 1.1</title>
    <updated>2025-02-26T20:44:20-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>alexbates/Tamari</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;Added accent color hover animations for recipes in My Recipes and Explore. Implemented a barcode scanning feature to quickly add items to Shopping Lists. Added the ability to print recipes and download as PDF. Updated translation files for all supported languages. Improved text contrast with light theme in My Recipes. Removed 2,000 recipes from Explore, reducing the number of recipes that fail to parse.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/alexbates/Tamari/releases/tag/v1.1" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/alexbates/Tamari/releases/tag/v1.2</id>
    <title>New release for Tamari: Version 1.2</title>
    <updated>2025-04-25T21:47:41-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>alexbates/Tamari</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;Redesigned the Meal Planner; a new Calendar page displays all meals planned for the current month. Days on the calendar can be clicked to view recipes planned for that day, and recipes can be scheduled with one click. Added a Recents page to My Recipes that displays the most recently viewed recipes. Redesigned page navigation buttons in My Recipes, Meal Planner, and Account. Added an Advanced Search page that allows searching recipes by Title, Category, Ingredients, and Instructions. It is accessible by clicking the search button in My Recipes and search-as-you-type functionality is retained.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/alexbates/Tamari/releases/tag/v1.2" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/alexbates/Tamari/releases/tag/v1.3</id>
    <title>New release for Tamari: Version 1.3</title>
    <updated>2025-07-13T19:56:18-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>alexbates/Tamari</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;Redesigned Login/Register pages with moving star effect and larger scaling. Implemented option to sort by Last Prepared in My Recipes. Added title attributes to many buttons to provide hover labels. Adjusted animations for popup modals. Bug fixes and other display improvements.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/alexbates/Tamari/releases/tag/v1.3" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
