<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://selfh.st/apps</id>
  <title>Tamari Releases</title>
  <updated>2025-03-06T08:31:53.752596-05:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>selfh.st</name>
    <email>contact@selfh.st</email>
  </author>
  <link href="https://selfh.st/apps" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>Self-hosted software releases generated by selfh.st</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/alexbates/Tamari/releases/tag/v0.7</id>
    <title>New release for Tamari: Version 0.7</title>
    <updated>2024-06-24T14:04:56-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>alexbates/Tamari</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;In My Recipes, added a third display option called 'Details' and added three new 'Sort By' options. Created an Autofill from URL feature on Add Recipe page. Developed client side recipe export (.ZIP download) and import (restore from backup) to give users better control of account data. Increased font size of Recipe Detail page when viewing on smartphone.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/alexbates/Tamari/releases/tag/v0.7" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/alexbates/Tamari/releases/tag/v0.8</id>
    <title>New release for Tamari: Version 0.8</title>
    <updated>2024-08-07T11:21:39-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>alexbates/Tamari</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;Developed UI scaling, users can select a preference on Account page that applies app wide. Implemented keyboard shortcuts that can be used to quickly highlight search boxes or navigate between pages. Improved app accessibility to allow navigating with TAB key. Added automated data rebuilding for "demo@tamariapp.com" demo account every 30 minutes. Redesigned Meal Planner with a "Completed" page that displays past meals and meal statistics.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/alexbates/Tamari/releases/tag/v0.8" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/alexbates/Tamari/releases/tag/v0.9</id>
    <title>New release for Tamari: Version 0.9</title>
    <updated>2024-09-22T14:30:11-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>alexbates/Tamari</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;Split Account page into two pages, Account Preferences and Account History. Account History displays a timeline of account events including account creation, email change, password change, recipe creation, and recipe edits. Added initial support for internationalization and localization. The first two supported languages are Spanish and German.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/alexbates/Tamari/releases/tag/v0.9" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/alexbates/Tamari/releases/tag/v1.0</id>
    <title>New release for Tamari: Version 1.0</title>
    <updated>2024-12-02T18:09:59-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>alexbates/Tamari</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;Addded new language support: Simplified Chinese, French, and Russian. Implemented pagination on Meal Planner Completed page. Developed a comprehensive REST API which can be used to interact with recipes, shopping lists, and meal plans. The API is disabled by default. Designed an API documentation page that correctly reflects app configuration.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/alexbates/Tamari/releases/tag/v1.0" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/alexbates/Tamari/releases/tag/v1.1</id>
    <title>New release for Tamari: Version 1.1</title>
    <updated>2025-02-26T20:44:20-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>alexbates/Tamari</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;Added accent color hover animations for recipes in My Recipes and Explore. Implemented a barcode scanning feature to quickly add items to Shopping Lists. Added the ability to print recipes and download as PDF. Updated translation files for all supported languages. Improved text contrast with light theme in My Recipes. Removed 2,000 recipes from Explore, reducing the number of recipes that fail to parse.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/alexbates/Tamari/releases/tag/v1.1" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
