<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://selfh.st/apps</id>
  <title>Tinyauth Releases</title>
  <updated>2025-04-18T08:34:54.125439-04:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>selfh.st</name>
    <email>contact@selfh.st</email>
  </author>
  <link href="https://selfh.st/apps" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>Self-hosted software releases generated by selfh.st</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/steveiliop56/tinyauth/releases/tag/v3.0.0</id>
    <title>New release for Tinyauth: v3.0.0</title>
    <updated>2025-02-16T15:58:01-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>steveiliop56/tinyauth</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h1&gt;Tinyauth v3.0.0&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[!WARNING]
This is a breaking update, please follow the migration instructions below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hello everyone! This is tinyauth &lt;code&gt;v3.0.0&lt;/code&gt; bringing support for both Nginx and Nginx Proxy Manager! You can now use tinyauth to protect all of your services running in it with just a few clicks! There is also a new feature allowing you to login to all tinyauth protected apps using HTTP basic auth so you can avoid cookies and login screens and immediately access your apps/APIs with code or command line. Lastly there are a lot of improvements in the codebase making it more readable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apart from the release, I would also like to invite everyone to tinyauth's discord server, a place where we can discuss about the project and self-hosting in general. If you are interested the link is available &lt;a href="https://discord.gg/eHzVaCzRRd"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Migration guide&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To migrate to &lt;code&gt;v3.0.0&lt;/code&gt; you need to change your authentication paths.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are using traefik for your reverse proxy, change your forward auth URL to &lt;code&gt;http://tinyauth:3000/api/auth/traefik&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are using caddy for your reverse proxy, change your auth URL to &lt;code&gt;http://tinyauth:3000/api/auth/caddy&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;COOKIE_EXPIRY&lt;/code&gt; environment variable has been also renamed to &lt;code&gt;SESSION_EXPIRY&lt;/code&gt; (&lt;code&gt;--session-expiry&lt;/code&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;New features&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Support for Nginx/Nginx Proxy Manager (https://tinyauth.doesmycode.work/docs/guides/nginx-proxy-manager)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Authentication to apps using HTTP basic auth (https://tinyauth.doesmycode.work/docs/reference/api)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Improvements&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Handle &lt;code&gt;null&lt;/code&gt; values from query parameters better in the frontend.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The cookie contents also expire based on the &lt;code&gt;SESSION_EXPIRY&lt;/code&gt; environment variable increasing security.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Fixes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix the &lt;code&gt;OAUTH_WHITELIST&lt;/code&gt; not allowing any users by default.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Parse the redirect URI correctly to support older browsers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Technical&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add multiple comments throughout the codebase to make it more understandable.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add tests for the API and utils.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you encounter any issues please let me know so I can fix them as soon as possible.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/steveiliop56/tinyauth/releases/tag/v3.0.0" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/steveiliop56/tinyauth/releases/tag/v3.0.1</id>
    <title>New release for Tinyauth: v3.0.1</title>
    <updated>2025-02-19T11:01:40-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>steveiliop56/tinyauth</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h1&gt;Tinyauth v3.0.1&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just a small patch fix that fixes #38 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Fixes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix the redirect URI not getting passed correctly to the continue screen&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you encounter any issues please let me know so I can fix them as soon as possible.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/steveiliop56/tinyauth/releases/tag/v3.0.1" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/steveiliop56/tinyauth/releases/tag/v3.1.0</id>
    <title>New release for Tinyauth: </title>
    <updated>2025-03-10T16:12:17-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>steveiliop56/tinyauth</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h1&gt;Tinyauth v3.1.0&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hello everyone! It's been quite a long time since the last cool release of tinyauth, so today I am changing that! With tinyauth v3.1.0 you can add 2 factor authentication to your user account with a single command! Additionally, I have added a much requested feature, the ability to change the login screen title and the name of the generic OAuth provider, all these can be now configured with environment variables (of course). Lastly tinyauth can now selectively ignore app paths using regex so you can avoid having to authenticate to trivial paths that do need authentication (like APIs).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apart from the new features I would like to announce the new domain of the project, &lt;a href="https://tinyauth.app"&gt;https://tinyauth.app&lt;/a&gt;, this was made possible by my awesome sponsors &lt;a href="https://github.com/erwinkramer"&gt;Erwin&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://github.com/nicotsx"&gt;Nicolas&lt;/a&gt;. If you find this project interesting and you would like to donate, I recently set up &lt;a href="https://github.com/sponsors/steveiliop56"&gt;Github Sponsors&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://buymeacoffee.com/steveiliop56"&gt;Buy me a coffee&lt;/a&gt;. Thank you for the support!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Side note:&lt;/em&gt; You can now use the &lt;code&gt;v3&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;v3.1&lt;/code&gt; tags so as you don't have to worry about breaking updates and still get new features and fixes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;New features&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;TOTP support&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ability to disable authentication on specific app paths using regex&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ability to change the login screen name&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ability to change the generic OAuth provider button name&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tinyauth now sets the &lt;code&gt;Remote-User&lt;/code&gt; header so you can use it to sign in to other apps&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Improvements&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved docker handler for checking labels&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved release workflows for faster build times&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rewritten login page for more modularity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Provide JSON responses if they client does not accept HTML&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Fixes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix the oauth whitelist not allowing any users in apps when &lt;code&gt;null&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you encounter any issues please let me know so I can fix them as soon as possible.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/steveiliop56/tinyauth/releases/tag/v3.1.0" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/steveiliop56/tinyauth/releases/tag/v3.2.0</id>
    <title>New release for Tinyauth: v3.2.0</title>
    <updated>2025-04-09T11:29:38-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>steveiliop56/tinyauth</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h1&gt;Tinyauth v3.2.0&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hello everyone!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before talking about the new release I would like to thank everyone for the 1k stars! It is an amazing achievement I never thought I would reach with any of my projects but with your support we managed to hit that milestone and I am grateful for that!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway back to the release stuff. It's been quite a long since the last release but since this one includes internalization I had to wait a bit for the app to get translated with some languages before releasing. Most of the languages are not translated yet but you can help translate tinyauth through &lt;a href="https://crowdin.com/project/tinyauth"&gt;Crowdin&lt;/a&gt;. Additionally basic brute force protection and rate limiting was added to the app and also the ability to tell tinyauth to add custom headers to your app. Lastly a ton of refactors took place ensuring the code is easily extendable and maintainable. As always, below is the full list of changes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;New features&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Internalization through &lt;a href="https://crowdin.com/project/tinyauth"&gt;Crowdin&lt;/a&gt; and the tinyauth CDN&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Healthcheck in Dockerfile to ensure the app runs smoothly&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ability to tell tinyauth to add additional headers to the authentication response (needed for future OIDC provider support)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Brute force protection/Rate limiting by @DragonStuff&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Light mode&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Amd64 and arm64 binaries are now available for download if you prefer bare metal over docker&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Improvements&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Split API to server and handles for better code readability&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Refactor error handling to not initialize new variables for every error&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All services now use a single config struct for all of the configuration options for better code readability and extensibility&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Removed dependency on GIN sessions as the app now uses gorilla sessions directly&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The redirect URI is now stored inside the &lt;code&gt;tinyauth&lt;/code&gt; session cookie&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you encounter any issues please let me know so I can fix them as soon as possible.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/steveiliop56/tinyauth/releases/tag/v3.2.0" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/steveiliop56/tinyauth/releases/tag/v3.2.1</id>
    <title>New release for Tinyauth: v3.2.1</title>
    <updated>2025-04-10T09:04:58-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>steveiliop56/tinyauth</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h1&gt;Tinyauth v3.2.1&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hello everyone, just a small patch fix release that parses the secret files correctly (removing new lines and whitespaces). Additionally I had to remove the Tailsale OAuth provider (for now) due to their OAuth API not working as intended and basically allowing everyone to click the Tailscale button to login without being logged in to any Tailscale account. As always, below is the list of all the changes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Fixes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ignore whitespaces and new lines in the secret files&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Remove Tailscale OAuth provider for security reasons&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you encounter any issues please let me know so I can fix them as soon as possible.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/steveiliop56/tinyauth/releases/tag/v3.2.1" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
