<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://selfh.st/apps</id>
  <title>Tinyauth Releases</title>
  <updated>2025-07-02T04:35:42.606106-04:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>selfh.st</name>
    <email>contact@selfh.st</email>
  </author>
  <link href="https://selfh.st/apps" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>Self-hosted software releases generated by selfh.st</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/steveiliop56/tinyauth/releases/tag/v3.2.1</id>
    <title>New release for Tinyauth: v3.2.1</title>
    <updated>2025-04-10T09:04:58-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>steveiliop56/tinyauth</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h1&gt;Tinyauth v3.2.1&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hello everyone, just a small patch fix release that parses the secret files correctly (removing new lines and whitespaces). Additionally I had to remove the Tailsale OAuth provider (for now) due to their OAuth API not working as intended and basically allowing everyone to click the Tailscale button to login without being logged in to any Tailscale account. As always, below is the list of all the changes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Fixes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ignore whitespaces and new lines in the secret files&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Remove Tailscale OAuth provider for security reasons&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you encounter any issues please let me know so I can fix them as soon as possible.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/steveiliop56/tinyauth/releases/tag/v3.2.1" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/steveiliop56/tinyauth/releases/tag/v3.3.0</id>
    <title>New release for Tinyauth: v3.3.0</title>
    <updated>2025-05-01T15:29:08-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>steveiliop56/tinyauth</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h1&gt;Tinyauth v3.3.0&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hello everyone! The release &lt;em&gt;almost&lt;/em&gt; everybody has been waiting for just dropped.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tinyauth can now act as a simple middleware between your OIDC server and your apps. It automatically maps OIDC claims like &lt;code&gt;prefered_username&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;name&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;groups&lt;/code&gt; into &lt;code&gt;Remote-User&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;Remote-Email&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;Remote-Name&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;Remote-Groups&lt;/code&gt; so as you can easily authenticate to your favorite apps using your existing OIDC server. Additionally you can easily manage access controls with your existing user groups and filter which group can access which app by using the &lt;code&gt;tinyauth.oauth.groups&lt;/code&gt; header.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, both the OAuth whitelist and the user whitelist support regex (regex cannot be used simultaneously with the comma list) for easier user matching. Last but not least a lot of security improvements and refactors have took place. Documentation for all of the changes and new features will come in the following days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A big thank you to our new sponsors @jmadden91 and @tribor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;New features&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added warning login screen when the redirect URI does not match the configured domain&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Regex support for both OAuth and user whitelist&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New forgot password screen with the ability to change the text using markdown&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Map information from OIDC claims to headers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Support for auto redirecting to your favorite OAuth provider&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Improvements&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add dependabot for dependency updates @gurukulkarni&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add CSRF cookie for protection against cross-site request forgery&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Log actual errors alongside the information message&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Fixes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Disable basic authentication for TOTP users&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Move the redirect URI back to a separate cookie&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Technical&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ensure the dist directory exists during development&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bump dependencies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you encounter any issues please let me know so I can fix them as soon as possible.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/steveiliop56/tinyauth/releases/tag/v3.3.0" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/steveiliop56/tinyauth/releases/tag/v3.3.1</id>
    <title>New release for Tinyauth: v3.3.1</title>
    <updated>2025-05-02T08:25:33-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>steveiliop56/tinyauth</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h1&gt;Tinyauth v3.3.1&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hello everyone, this just a small patch release to fix an OAuth whitelist issue described in #132.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Improvements&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Log when using Github primary email or the first available one&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Fixes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use the email instead of the username in the OAuth whitelist&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/steveiliop56/tinyauth/releases/tag/v3.3.1" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/steveiliop56/tinyauth/releases/tag/v3.4.0</id>
    <title>New release for Tinyauth: v3.4.0</title>
    <updated>2025-06-01T10:46:04-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>steveiliop56/tinyauth</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h1&gt;Tinyauth v3.4.0&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hello everyone! This is a very exciting release as tinyauth now has a new UI based on Shadcn! I believe it gives the UI a fresh new look and at the same time allows for much more extensibility since we are now not tied to mantine components. Additionally this release includes some quality of life updates like the ability to negotiate the docker API version (instead of just failing to start up), using unique cookie names so you can have multiple instances of tinyauth under the same domain and lastly the option to ignore self-signed certificates in the generic OAuth provider. Oh and have some eye candy:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="tinyauth" src="https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/e40a8d06-7938-4b60-ad84-97225b308102" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;New features&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Show the commit hash and build date alongside the version in the version command&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Option to disable SSL certificate check in generic provider&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Improvements&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rebuilt UI from the ground up using Shadcn, Tailwind, React Query and React Hook Form&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Negotiate the API version with the docker host instead of failing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Remove the &lt;code&gt;WWW-Authenticate&lt;/code&gt; header to prevent basic auth browser pop-ups&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Store version, build date and commit hash in constants instead of files&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Generate unique cookie names based on the app URL to avoid conflicts with other instances&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Only use 302 redirects to avoid browser caching&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Technical&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Update dependencies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deprecate translations CDN&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Update translations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create nightly release workflow&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Remove healthcheck from dockerfile as it was causing errors with a custom port&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you encounter any issues please let me know so I can fix them as soon as possible.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/steveiliop56/tinyauth/releases/tag/v3.4.0" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/steveiliop56/tinyauth/releases/tag/v3.4.1</id>
    <title>New release for Tinyauth: v3.4.1</title>
    <updated>2025-06-11T03:53:44-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>steveiliop56/tinyauth</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h1&gt;Tinyauth v3.4.1&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hey everyone! This release includes a simple patch fix for &lt;a href="https://github.com/community-scripts/ProxmoxVE/issues/5096"&gt;proxmox helper scripts&lt;/a&gt; which ensures CGO is not being used when building and thus allows tinyauth to run on musl based systems like alpine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Technical&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ensure CGO is disabled when building tinyauth binaries&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bump dependencies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Update translations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you encounter any issues please let me know so I can fix them as soon as possible.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/steveiliop56/tinyauth/releases/tag/v3.4.1" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
