<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://selfh.st/apps</id>
  <title>Tube Archivist Releases</title>
  <updated>2024-11-18T13:31:23.983378-05:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>selfh.st</name>
    <email>contact@selfh.st</email>
  </author>
  <link href="https://selfh.st/apps" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>Self-hosted software releases generated by selfh.st</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/tubearchivist/tubearchivist/releases/tag/v0.4.7</id>
    <title>New release for Tube Archivist: v0.4.7</title>
    <updated>2024-04-10T14:48:56-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>tubearchivist/tubearchivist</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h2&gt;Project Updates&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This will trigger a playlist migration in ElasticSearch, adding a &lt;code&gt;playlist_type&lt;/code&gt; field. As always that happens at first start and should be automatic.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This updates yt-dlp to the &lt;a href="https://github.com/yt-dlp/yt-dlp/releases/tag/2024.04.09"&gt;latest release&lt;/a&gt;. After a change on YT, comment extraction needs to be modified, that is tracked &lt;a href="https://github.com/yt-dlp/yt-dlp/issues/9358"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. Please be patient.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Added&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added user created custom playlists, by @greg321321, &lt;a href="https://docs.tubearchivist.com/playlists/#playlist-overview"&gt;docs&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://docs.tubearchivist.com/video/#video-page"&gt;docs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added better error message for cookie errors, by @Gentoli&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Changed&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed disable video autoplay on the video detail page to avoid too many &lt;em&gt;continue watching&lt;/em&gt; items.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed first watch progress is now only sent after 10 seconds to avoid too many &lt;em&gt;continue watching&lt;/em&gt; items.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Fixed&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed failed empty subtitle return from YT, #663&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed empty comment author return for some old comments, by @dot-mike&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed edge cases for failed channel title building&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed download progress bar for very small videos, by guarantee sending 100% progress&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed download progress messages getting called multiple times in DOM&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed failed legacy channel migration trigger by removing &lt;code&gt;ta_migpath&lt;/code&gt; from startup, #687&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/tubearchivist/tubearchivist/releases/tag/v0.4.7" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/tubearchivist/tubearchivist/releases/tag/v0.4.8</id>
    <title>New release for Tube Archivist: v0.4.8</title>
    <updated>2024-05-22T12:55:04-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>tubearchivist/tubearchivist</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h2&gt;Hotfix published&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a hotfix published for ARM64 builds where the ffmpeg binaries weren't downloaded correctly into the container. If you are affected, pull again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Project updates&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This ships various fixes for playlist refresh limitations. Also see the docs &lt;a href="https://docs.tubearchivist.com/playlists/#playlist-overview"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; clarifying that functionality.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This fixes a comment extraction problem due to a change on YT&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;See below for a manual fix for your comments&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This also partially fixes failed channel extraction, we are waiting for upstream fix, that’s tracked &lt;a href="https://github.com/yt-dlp/yt-dlp/issues/9893"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;See below to manually trigger a refresh of your failed channels&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This ships a new schedule management system, fixing various previous limitations. Your existing schedules and notification URLs should migrate automatically at first start, monitor your startup logs and validate on your schedule settings page that everything transferred correctly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Added&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added delete and ignore for videos, &lt;a href="https://docs.tubearchivist.com/video/#video-page"&gt;docs&lt;/a&gt; #286&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added new notification hook for add to queue task, #714&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added thumbs clean up in Thumbnail Check task&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added 404 handler for detail views&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added better error handling for invalid urls&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added a few unit tests&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Changed&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed build to use python script to download best ffmpeg build&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed schedule store to use beats model, no longer requiring restart to apply schedule, &lt;a href="https://docs.tubearchivist.com/settings/scheduling/"&gt;docs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed task notification management, &lt;a href="https://docs.tubearchivist.com/settings/scheduling/#notifications"&gt;docs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed playlist matching logic in download post processing, &lt;a href="https://docs.tubearchivist.com/playlists/#playlist-overview"&gt;docs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed queue handling to use Redis as temporary store, #500&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed queue handling progress and position tracking to use score in ordered set&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed to cleaner and more concise seconds to date parser&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Fixed&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed comment extraction&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed playlist subscription bool logic in template, #684&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed playlist rescanning logic, ensuring refresh, #686&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Partial fix channel subs extraction with workaround, #701, &lt;a href="https://github.com/yt-dlp/yt-dlp/issues/9893"&gt;upstream link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed adding existing playlist to queue again, #634&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed playlist matching not removing deleted videos&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed rescan negative total notification&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed schedule cron parser, you are no longer able to enter an invalid schedule&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed logout&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed application startup dependency making tests unrunnable, #564&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Manual updates&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You don’t &lt;em&gt;need&lt;/em&gt; to run these commands, the regular metadata refresh should fix these problems, at least for active videos. That’s just if you want to fix it &lt;em&gt;now&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First command will “relink” comments with your video. Due to a failed comment extraction, that link got lost, but all your comments are still here. Run &lt;code&gt;python manage.py ta_fix_comment_link&lt;/code&gt; in your Tube Archivist container, e.g.:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;bash
docker exec -it tubearchivist python manage.py ta_fix_comment_link&lt;/code&gt;
Depending on your index size and system performance, expect this to take around 15 seconds for 10k videos. You will see &lt;code&gt;✓ task completed&lt;/code&gt; once that’s done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Second command will trigger a reindex for channels that have failed to extract before, run &lt;code&gt;python manage.py ta_fix_channels&lt;/code&gt; in your Tube Archivist container, e.g.:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;bash
docker exec -it tubearchivist python manage.py ta_fix_channels&lt;/code&gt;
This will scan your channels and add faulty channels to the regular reindex queue. That should return in a few seconds, you will see &lt;code&gt;✓ task queued&lt;/code&gt;. Then you can monitor the reindex progress on your settings page and in your docker logs.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/tubearchivist/tubearchivist/releases/tag/v0.4.8" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/tubearchivist/tubearchivist/releases/tag/v0.4.9</id>
    <title>New release for Tube Archivist: v0.4.9</title>
    <updated>2024-07-15T14:43:10-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>tubearchivist/tubearchivist</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h2&gt;Project updates&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This ships the latest fixes for channel extractions by the amazing yt-dlp team.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;See below to manually trigger a refresh of your failed channels.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some users have reported problems for index mapping updates, particularly on bigger archives. To counteract issues like that, increase the memory limit defined in &lt;code&gt;ES_JAVA_OPTS&lt;/code&gt; for ES so there is enough space to sync the index in bulk.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;That is also represented in the official &lt;a href="https://github.com/tubearchivist/tubearchivist/blob/master/docker-compose.yml#L48"&gt;docker-compose.yml file&lt;/a&gt;, make the same changes as &lt;a href="https://github.com/tubearchivist/tubearchivist/commit/b0b72a6e6eb190e767345a6d30968ecb65a1f951"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you maintain any installation help, guides, templates or similar, please update it there too.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ideally make the change &lt;em&gt;first&lt;/em&gt; before applying the update.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This will trigger a rebuild for the &lt;code&gt;video&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;channel&lt;/code&gt; indexes at first start, as always this should be mostly automatic.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you encounter any problems, see &lt;a href="https://docs.tubearchivist.com/advanced/#es-mapping-migrations-troubleshooting"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This will probably be the last release for some time. We’ll make a cut here to start refactoring things in the backend, and rewrite the frontend in a modern JS framework. Check the open issues and reach out if you want to help with that process&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Added&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added per channel page size, aka deactivating shorts or streams per channel, &lt;a href="https://docs.tubearchivist.com/channels/#about"&gt;docs&lt;/a&gt;, by @Boo1098&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added retry logic for failed download tasks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Changed&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed behavior when changing the TZ (Time Zone) environment variable. Existing schedules will now get changed to use the new TZ value. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Fixed&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed error when adding video not part of a channel, #741&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed error when a previously failed download would raise an incorrect &lt;code&gt;FileNotFoundError&lt;/code&gt;, #752&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed issue allowing retrying from cache on previously failed download.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed issue where version check task would never trigger depending on your TZ value and uptime. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Manual updates&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As yt-dlp fixed all issues with channel extraction, you can run trigger a reindex for channels that have failed to index properly before, run &lt;code&gt;python manage.py ta_fix_channels&lt;/code&gt; in your Tube Archivist container, e.g.:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;bash
docker exec -it tubearchivist python manage.py ta_fix_channels&lt;/code&gt;
This will scan your channels and add faulty channels to the regular reindex queue. That should return in a few seconds, you will see &lt;code&gt;✓ task queued&lt;/code&gt;. Then you can monitor the reindex progress on your settings page and in your docker logs.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/tubearchivist/tubearchivist/releases/tag/v0.4.9" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/tubearchivist/tubearchivist/releases/tag/v0.4.10</id>
    <title>New release for Tube Archivist: v0.4.10</title>
    <updated>2024-08-03T16:03:59-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>tubearchivist/tubearchivist</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h2&gt;Project Updates&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This is a minor release to ship the latest fixes from the amazing yt-dlp team.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/tubearchivist/tubearchivist/releases/tag/v0.4.10" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/tubearchivist/tubearchivist/releases/tag/v0.4.11</id>
    <title>New release for Tube Archivist: v0.4.11</title>
    <updated>2024-11-08T22:36:38-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>tubearchivist/tubearchivist</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h2&gt;Project Update&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Another minor release shipping latest dependencies while we continue the progress on our new frontend.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you for your patience. &lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/tubearchivist/tubearchivist/releases/tag/v0.4.11" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
