<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://selfh.st/apps</id>
  <title>Typemill Releases</title>
  <updated>2024-10-09T19:33:46.169548-04:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>selfh.st</name>
    <email>contact@selfh.st</email>
  </author>
  <link href="https://selfh.st/apps" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>Self-hosted software releases generated by selfh.st</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/typemill/typemill/releases/tag/1.1.3</id>
    <title>New release for Typemill: Introduce Admin Dashboard</title>
    <updated>2018-04-20T16:41:08-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>typemill/typemill</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;Please follow the instructions for major updates in the &lt;a href="http://typemill.net/getting-started/update"&gt;documentation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Version 1.1.3 introduces an author panel. Now you can authenticate, configure the system, themes and plugins and manage users. This is the first step towards a full authoring panel that helps you to manage, create and edit everything online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Author panel.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Authentication.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Configuration of the system, the theme and the plugins.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;User management (create update and deleted).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bugfix: Footnotes in Markdown didn't work due to parsedown library. Fixed in the new library version.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/typemill/typemill/releases/tag/1.1.3" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/typemill/typemill/releases/tag/1.1.4</id>
    <title>New release for Typemill: Refactor Author Panel</title>
    <updated>2018-04-30T10:08:05-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>typemill/typemill</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;Version 1.1.4 is mainly an optimization and refactoring of the author panel released in version 1.1.3. Some details of the changes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Length of description is optimized for SEO now.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can display a last modified date on each page now (update the TYPEMILL theme for that).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Optimized mobile version of the author-panel navigation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Form rendering is now done in a seperate form template.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SettingsController is deeply refactored and some bugs are fixed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;FormModel partly fixed and refactored.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ValidationModel fixed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Update notifications for system, themes and plugins are completely refactored and unified.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Welcome page is fixed, so that the linked themes- and plugin settings show the initial values now.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Settings functions for plugins and themes are cleaned up and unified.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Design is partly fixed and unified (open-close icons and more).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;User documentation has been enhanced and corrected.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/typemill/typemill/releases/tag/1.1.4" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/typemill/typemill/releases/tag/1.1.5</id>
    <title>New release for Typemill: Typemill Learns Math</title>
    <updated>2018-05-10T00:11:16-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>typemill/typemill</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;Please follow the instructions for &lt;a href="http://typemill.net/getting-started/update"&gt;simple updates&lt;/a&gt; in the documentation. Please also update the Typemill theme and the plugins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With version 1.1.5 Typemill learns math. There is a plugin called "math" that you can activate in the author panel. you can choose between MathJax and KaTeX. For the syntax to write math in markdown, please check the &lt;a href="http://typemill.net/info/markdown-test"&gt;markdown reference page&lt;/a&gt;. Here are the details of this version:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Extend markdown to support latex syntax.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New plugin to activate MathJax or KaTeX.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Highlight for code blocks is now a plugin.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Share buttons for twitter, facebook and xing can be added to the TYPEMILL theme.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Optimized mobile startpage.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Table of content has now permanent ids and anchors (headline) instead of dynamic numbers. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/typemill/typemill/releases/tag/1.1.5" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/typemill/typemill/releases/tag/1.1.6</id>
    <title>New release for Typemill: Refactoring</title>
    <updated>2018-05-23T12:11:31-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>typemill/typemill</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;Please follow the instructions for minor updates in the &lt;a href="https://typemill.net/getting-started/update"&gt;documentation&lt;/a&gt;. Please also update the Typemill theme and the plugins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added security headers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added a temporary ip-blocker if login fails 3 times.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added fieldsets for configuration fields of themes and plugins.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added logic for user roles.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed url-structure from tm-author to tm.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Activated twig cache.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Started to refactored css for author panel.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/typemill/typemill/releases/tag/1.1.6" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/typemill/typemill/releases/tag/2.6.0</id>
    <title>New release for Typemill: Version 2.6.0</title>
    <updated>2024-06-18T08:34:30-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>typemill/typemill</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;Please note that releases DOES NOT CONTAIN the VENDOR folder. After downloading the release please make a composer update to pull in the vendor with the libraries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This release contains version 2.6.0. check the changelog at https://typemill.net/info/changelog&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/typemill/typemill/releases/tag/2.6.0" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
