<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://selfh.st/apps</id>
  <title>Uncloud Releases</title>
  <updated>2025-07-06T18:35:53.937580-04:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>selfh.st</name>
    <email>contact@selfh.st</email>
  </author>
  <link href="https://selfh.st/apps" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>Self-hosted software releases generated by selfh.st</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/psviderski/uncloud/releases/tag/v0.6.0</id>
    <title>New release for Uncloud: v0.6.0</title>
    <updated>2025-04-25T04:12:46-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>psviderski/uncloud</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h2&gt;Highlights&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Extended Docker Compose support:&lt;/strong&gt; 🎉 Added support for deploying services from Docker Compose files with volumes, environment variables, resource limits, and more.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;New volume management:&lt;/strong&gt; Create, list, inspect, and remove volumes across your cluster with the new &lt;code&gt;volume&lt;/code&gt; command.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Context management:&lt;/strong&gt; Switch between different cluster contexts using the new &lt;code&gt;ctx&lt;/code&gt; command.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Improved resource control:&lt;/strong&gt; Specify CPU, memory, and environment variables for containers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Breaking changes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Configuration format changed from TOML to YAML&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;--cluster&lt;/code&gt; flag renamed to &lt;code&gt;--context&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Revised machine placement system using &lt;code&gt;--machine&lt;/code&gt; flag instead of machine filters&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Features and improvements&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Volume management:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Full volume lifecycle management with &lt;code&gt;uc volume create/ls/inspect/rm&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Support for volume scheduling across machines based on service constraints&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Automatic volume creation for services that need them&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Compose support:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deploy services from Docker Compose files with &lt;code&gt;uc deploy&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Support for volume, bind, and tmpfs mounts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Environment variables and resource constraints&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Context management:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Switch between multiple cluster contexts with &lt;code&gt;uc ctx&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Manage multiple clusters with &lt;code&gt;uc ctx ls&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;uc ctx use&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Container improvements:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CPU and memory limits with &lt;code&gt;--cpu&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;--memory&lt;/code&gt; flags&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Environment variables via &lt;code&gt;-e&lt;/code&gt; flag&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Container user via &lt;code&gt;-u&lt;/code&gt; flag&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Log driver configuration&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Machine management:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Support for selecting specific uncloud version during initialising (&lt;code&gt;machine init&lt;/code&gt;) or adding (&lt;code&gt;machine add&lt;/code&gt;) a new machine to the cluster&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Changelog&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;948201cb6fe419e3ee3d67a58f66d2e3e7aef184 add VolumeScheduler with one flaky test&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;df4ab40e12249a8cbcbb95d3fec41af32e6a763e chore(volumes): add client methods for volume management, e2e test&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;590a1b231f80d0d8bc7e13f26fa9ce2c52fc3b0f chore(volumes): e2e test when volume doesn't exist&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;13dea92311f0e102deb456353bf1bfd6c5b24890 chore(volumes): gRPC methods for managing Docker volumes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;c6205d4f5779261a3b73c2595b88a44b84bdfe7e chore(volumes): map volume specs to container config, diff specs with volumes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;b3885b08889da47e450e18fee3feb67bd8b7b5bb chore: activate the context of a newly initialised cluster&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;02a418aafbdaf02adb17146b82686e9567c6bf7d chore: add --version flag for 'machine init|add' to specify uncloud daemon version&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;b605a64fbe02d338bdd1b28d91d230e56fd444e1 chore: add e2e compose test with volumes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;87331a926563150d027499bba40e90d4a8952bb9 chore: add filter to ListMachines&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;5fce84d33c3f6505fc4e2d97acad54bc0d4301b9 chore: cleanup compose-basic test&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;03c2681792cfb285828b607e275931135d38b730 chore: cleanup unused machine filter struct&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;835c310987abfe170c84fea3830e1020d6fedb1d chore: delete old basic-compose.yaml fixture&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;143e68cc9563fcebae15de3a84bf0c67f5cc7c76 chore: do not set default volume driver to local, distinguish behaviour when it's set or not&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;f71fc57f34facd2be6f9128b6d6287fc4d6b9d8e chore: e2e tests for replicated and global deployments with volumes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;8709ac0ed5ac8f5053872b922825fd6d06cca567 chore: fix Errorf arguments&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;c9452f1509ae47868828e8fc957c675cf036992a chore: ignore uc binary in the repo root&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;badb8ecd3cbd62381ed9ecee53b675ed4833ffe7 chore: implement EvalContainerSpecChange for new container properties&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;565a8d8366475b435faec05ddca269855ee3b21d chore: implement VolumeScheduler to determine what missing volumes should be created and where&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1acb0ff1101c6924346f92b6d087c87169fa7f70 chore: implement VolumesConstraint to only schedule on machines with required volumes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;000a8a1d3e74bb985e2774e0ce9fc51937b66205 chore: init scheduler entities&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;6125553a97f17d0e19d236cb102a0a34ace1e324 chore: introduce VolumeSpec supporting different volume types (bind, volume, tmpfs)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;e5957d9d6b0eac4cb8cdd3264ef7a0e9c8ee66b2 chore: map compose volumes to server spec, initial volume scheduling&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;72bf34632fc44b4d0a8a606bea0a89f3b1702845 chore: map new container properties to Docker container configs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;9100c22e7faf43deca3393f1aded4abaa6466b97 chore: new specs for defining service volumes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;4532b985d47847ae46d644d05115e56882429df6 chore: populate ucind cluster machines with IDs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;cacfca7a88c23ad9b5a1c5ae2a053b9feaa8bb35 chore: print message about changed context for 'ctx use' command&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fcf164dda1b003a2993506b1a704f8ad04b9e399 chore: refactor schedulers to work with cluster state snapshot, VolumeScheduler updates state with scheduled volumes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;4e40a939916d4bef1385f413aecac56d6cd3260b chore: remove anonymous volumes for ucind containers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;d8818ba77015b72bec2a92a1fefce22fc227e6b1 chore: remove unnecessary fields from containers table in machine.db&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;f467fad84c25040831d4ff698f05f52f22a05c9b chore: rename cluster term to context in CLI and config, convert config toml -&amp;gt; yaml&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;f3cb6657aec8a4cfe48effc6a36cf68e2d4d7306 chore: replace machine filter with placement constraint in service spec&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;97e032cb7bbdcc9b218c58cc769ebe5a615b8bb2 chore: update ListVolumes to accept a filter&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;45497fd20cf791a0c5f8d35061a68cabad6616f3 chore: update api.ServiceClient interface to include service creation and removal&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;edad2429c50f1e5c1cfd370f2f3e3d997f587ea2 chore: verify idempotency for compose deploy with volumes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;410a95ec88a55d2a32cd5136b6fc89df4b838d9a chroe: add TODO to fix empty context in output message when adding machines&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;8ee551ca8fef6bf56aa66f15370d3c4c1810c784 cleanup&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;20b2ca2ea536ec5814c746d34c398ec3f6912d3c feat(ctx): interactive ctx command to switch between cluster contexts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;25b173128ac9944d51b01f87d15a65ddc9e4e662 feat(env): support env vars for services (both run command and compose)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;f8ebd94a796c47b2b5b85b1f445027836c7f36ab feat(volumes): create and mount data volumes when running service with 'uc run' command&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2f5a2c63443d7a09987b45388cab8a32b79776e4 feat(volumes): new 'volume create|inspect|ls|rm' CLI commands to manage volumes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1bbefdd0d2481d8715f4515a2304a2cccf3bd905 feat: add 'ctx ls' command to list available cluster contexts in config&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;6c2759f3151449f1821e55358c5d9fb183e0658b feat: add --cpu, --memory, --privileged, --user options for 'service run'&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;938e7d05c009e9f38750843dd907acb43b67f298 feat: add support for entrypoint, cpus, mem_limit, mem_reservation, priviliged, user to Compose deployment&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;9413f1c0b1dda7099f92100f47e5b79663774e44 feat: define essential container spec parameters&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;343357adf9fa5661d4dcf063a5b79f0f5e7f839c find optimal solution in VolumeScheduler&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;440215b811e7888fbd6a4f13ac2aed4378a77fb8 fix: TestInstallCmd test&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3ada89c4f81ecf0a1c35d3ed452dff1636a2bce3 fix: adding ucind cluster with tcp connections to config&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;16c876d83fca6de7c24802a449170bd3c59ceb1b fix: compare container specs with equate empty option (nil map == {} map)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;33550be65e22534ad8831871a1fef768c58313c0 fix: compose deployment plan preview&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;d6ff62159d419d0a440ba0c089370734ac80d6d1 fix: compose deployment: use mutex to correctly collect service specs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;9fc54c9d64360ad0cb92d3d7a65ab2467a64d32d fix: format config.Path method&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;f08d9fe405d28d5ee5fbc144a6fd58618d8795dc refactor: 'service run' create missing volumes satisfying all placement constraints&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;7db8bba6ea2c69100f73bfd1cf9b640b8ed20d5d refactor: cpu and memory under Resources struct&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;7705db2c4f9dc620ce67c4700b07c56e5a4f7a62 refactor: machine listing for replicated plan&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/psviderski/uncloud/releases/tag/v0.6.0" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/psviderski/uncloud/releases/tag/v0.7.0</id>
    <title>New release for Uncloud: v0.7.0</title>
    <updated>2025-05-01T00:31:39-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>psviderski/uncloud</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;This release introduces embedded DNS service for internal service discovery, Compose profiles support, and several improvements for CLI and machine daemon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;New Features&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Embedded DNS service&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Runs on each machine's IP (10.210.X.1) and handles &lt;code&gt;.internal&lt;/code&gt; domain.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Automatically configured for all service containers and used for service discovery (resolves &lt;code&gt;service-name&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;service-name.internal&lt;/code&gt; to IP addresses of the &lt;code&gt;service-name&lt;/code&gt; service containers).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Transparently forwards non-&lt;code&gt;.internal&lt;/code&gt; queries to upstream DNS servers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Can be used as the main nameserver on the machine to simplify service troubleshooting from the host shell. K8s, don't be jealous!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fast failure during &lt;code&gt;machine init/add&lt;/code&gt; if DNS port is already in use.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Compose profiles&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Support for Compose profiles via &lt;code&gt;-p/--profile&lt;/code&gt; flag.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;CLI enhancements&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Display version information for &lt;code&gt;uc&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;uncloudd&lt;/code&gt; binaries with &lt;code&gt;--version&lt;/code&gt; flag.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Made all confirmation forms accessible.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Bug fixes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed Caddy proxy to only route to healthy containers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed panic in &lt;code&gt;ctx&lt;/code&gt; command when Uncloud config contains only one context. Thanks to @tonyo for reporting.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed loss of message from child loggers (created with &lt;code&gt;slog.With&lt;/code&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Contributors&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to @cedws for contributing the Compose profiles and CLI &lt;code&gt;--version&lt;/code&gt; features!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Changelog&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ef57b62625dae11631d62b6c1ee53b85124682de Merge pull request #50 from cedws/version&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;7861d56dffe524980400702a7fb982e59a960750 Merge pull request #54 from cedws/profiles&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;c56385602e93b2866aaee456405ff3ef4b14e6eb chore(dns-server): authoritative responses for internal DNS queries and forwarding to ustream servers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;70e9385032185e91c596d3211af895007f3dfc9a chore(dns-server): implement resolver for service records that watches container changes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;6e1165ec57625c71e2895e30632a1f0f334967ec chore(dns-server): make TCP server non-critical; do not exit if it fails to start&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fbbf839258cc42eec789c705a37720aac26496c0 chore: init embedded DNS server&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;769f5e47c326498f6a351e5f2bc7544fae7619c0 feat(dns-server): check system prerequisites when init/add machine: DNS port is not in use by another DNS server&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;8d16da596c6d09b0e6a664c9960870e69a50f83f feat(dns-server): run embedded internal DNS server on machine IP in uncloudd daemon process&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;cf7e333579561316a8f41cca9d378c1e33e5c2aa feat(dns-server): use embedded DNS server for all service containers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;7bc69b9a9e1ccbc973ae5f91a940fc79a3b53466 feat: add support for Compose profiles&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;e854bbb3e179ac37ed140366a417e9f01a0422b7 feat: add version flag to main cmd&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;eee28e2eada83c7c01840322fa3e1d8e7fa8d8a8 feat: add version flag to uncloudd binary&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;0b8495e96421bea3e0533677333045786be49c24 feat: make all confirmation forms accessible&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;38800924edf19f20142d9d958ca23686832ea20b fix(caddy): proxy to only healthy containers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;6068e24f4f67fea46d1f0d5fe13f7039f505031b fix(ctx): panic: index out of range when only one context in uncloud config (closes #52)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;d6c06828b311828c3c343be462ea2590060aec6e fix(dns-server): fix constructor and log messages&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;db3016fe898f3630660622ce462f2c3c215e5fbd fix: --file flag description for uc deploy cmd&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fe93d91894a049960bb4f981d92e958dc70a5013 fix: attributes handling in SlogTextHandler for child loggers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3f70018e7c4e07beb9bbb88c7652d01e9fd9b3ff fix: import cycle in pkg/api&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/psviderski/uncloud/releases/tag/v0.7.0" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/psviderski/uncloud/releases/tag/v0.7.1</id>
    <title>New release for Uncloud: v0.7.1</title>
    <updated>2025-05-05T06:06:21-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>psviderski/uncloud</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;This minor release improves iptables firewall management:
* Introduce a new &lt;code&gt;UNCLOUD-INPUT&lt;/code&gt; iptables chain that manages rules for the Uncloud needs.
* Allow DNS queries from Uncloud containers to access the embedded DNS server in case the host has restrictive &lt;code&gt;INPUT&lt;/code&gt; rules.
* Allow WireGuard traffic to the machine on &lt;code&gt;51820/udp&lt;/code&gt; port.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Changelog&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3648187219fd9ba3a382a06c914c9d2d164704a6 chore: allow DNS queries from Uncloud containers to the embedded DNS server&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;93346301fbb4713eac97b8862facbf230913d9cd chore: clarify zero-downtime deployments feature&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;cc86c8660c941024f8d051c14e47665a44291048 chore: rearrange features in README&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;6e326277bbc3cb4d267e11619693c70d1480ca16 chore: set up UNCLOUD-INPUT iptables chain and allow WireGuard traffic to the machine&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;29634365386e163acb90fac5b4da7570e5c70d85 chore: update available features in README&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/psviderski/uncloud/releases/tag/v0.7.1" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/psviderski/uncloud/releases/tag/v0.7.2</id>
    <title>New release for Uncloud: v0.7.2</title>
    <updated>2025-05-07T02:07:55-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>psviderski/uncloud</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h2&gt;Bug fixes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed &lt;code&gt;uc caddy deploy&lt;/code&gt; to check latest Caddy image only when not explicitly specified&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed service name validation to properly enforce RFC 1123 label format (1-63 characters, lowercase letters, numbers, and dashes only; must start and end with a letter or number)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Changelog&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;469d6fadcddb58fcff9289ffc73148293245b919 Fix: restrict validation to RFC1123 label name&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;11c2e641f1764d7278e70a33663d079715f26160 Merge pull request #58 from Tova-Rozovsky/valid_DNS&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;5f214247ca7322568c430a7b3dfd0e881fa98adc added validition for service name&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;f7b079c4f28e51df704b05b70e0531b6dcffec8c chore: collapse how it works section in readme&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;e35e69b4be5d9e8a78adea8e577a3d0037a6f793 fix: check latest Caddy image only if not specified for 'uc caddy deploy'&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;bb97537df7b62269dce4591664a2d96498f5000d fix: format error message&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;9f4b8179b52460de3edf6bee99cf5bc92e1f8421 valid service name&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/psviderski/uncloud/releases/tag/v0.7.2" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/psviderski/uncloud/releases/tag/v0.8.0</id>
    <title>New release for Uncloud: v0.8.0</title>
    <updated>2025-06-12T04:52:04-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>psviderski/uncloud</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;This release introduces build &amp;amp; push capabilities for Compose deployments, enables &lt;a href="https://caddyserver.com/docs/caddyfile/directives/reverse_proxy#passive-health-checks"&gt;passive health checks&lt;/a&gt; for upstreams in Caddy reverse proxy, minor bug fixes and improvements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also launched:
* &lt;a href="https://docs.uncloud.run/"&gt;Uncloud Documentation&lt;/a&gt;
* &lt;a href="https://discord.gg/eR35KQJhPu"&gt;Discord server&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;New features&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Initial build &amp;amp; push support (still experimenting) ✨&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New &lt;code&gt;uc build&lt;/code&gt; command to build service images from &lt;code&gt;Dockerfile&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;build:&lt;/code&gt; configuration in Compose files&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Integrated build step in &lt;code&gt;uc deploy&lt;/code&gt; automatically builds and pushes an image to the registry specified in &lt;code&gt;image:&lt;/code&gt; before deployment&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use &lt;code&gt;--no-build&lt;/code&gt; flag to skip building when deploying&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Caddy reverse proxy improvements&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enabled &lt;a href="https://caddyserver.com/docs/caddyfile/directives/reverse_proxy#passive-health-checks"&gt;passive health checks&lt;/a&gt; to automatically detect unhealthy upstreams&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added automatic retry logic (3 retries) for failed requests to gracefully handle temporary unavailable upstreams&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Logging enabled by default for better observability&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Documentation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Launched a new documentation website at &lt;a href="https://docs.uncloud.run/"&gt;docs.uncloud.run&lt;/a&gt; with a &lt;a href="https://docs.uncloud.run/category/getting-started"&gt;Getting started&lt;/a&gt; guide.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Documentation itself is deployed using Uncloud across multiple machines (dogfooding FTW!) See the &lt;a href="https://github.com/psviderski/uncloud/blob/main/docs/compose.yaml"&gt;&lt;code&gt;compose.yaml&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; file if curious.
&lt;img alt="" src="https://github.com/psviderski/uncloud/blob/main/.github/images/compose-deploy.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;User experience&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Default SSH key path is now set to &lt;code&gt;~/.ssh/id_ed25519&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added &lt;code&gt;m&lt;/code&gt; alias for the &lt;code&gt;machine&lt;/code&gt; command&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Bug Fixes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed Caddy deployment after adding new machine by using cluster client instead of machine client (#65)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Testing &amp;amp; CI&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added GitHub Actions workflow for automated Go tests&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enhanced e2e tests with build &amp;amp; push verification&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Contributors&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to @tonyo for the build &amp;amp; push RFC and implementation, test improvements, and the make &lt;code&gt;install-dev&lt;/code&gt; helper!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Changelog&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;624caf037ba24fbdc22108c2a599a959d51f3e01 chore(docs): init overview page&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2a0d31cec0a1470b0effa07965cdc5f54270b367 chore: Helper make target to install protobuf/grpc plugins&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;6a4e63dbd4cb431a41280e7304c108ddcfdeb204 chore: add Discord to landing, remove crossed out Kubernetes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;6f9ac1fcc71ed362bbb1f5038d03be1490430044 chore: add Docker image for docs and Uncloud Compose deployment (dogfooding!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ae04dea808165cd175a72aeedcd01c3e9d559994 chore: add Docs to website navbar and footer, add other resources to footer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;f1abbbea6da743cdf03cd38562d0fc1bed163c95 chore: add discord and X badges to README&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;23dfe45b2feb0e56190919ecc4f9032dd2303331 chore: add docs badge to github README&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;d2dd5e3c891557f418dce1a961810ebc043fab6c chore: add inspiration &amp;amp; acknowledgements section to README&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;7edd8f2976af6ddec202bbe02a2a7028ee061a80 chore: add m alias for machine command&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;8f00e0082e525c528488a57e9e3a3c93d1aff4d3 chore: add social links in the footer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2bfcce7803091ea0fb3e4621d3bb3786e1e0c6e5 chore: add uncloud-docs deploy from compose to demo section in README&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;f49ec465d07e8e21c8e5d7943620873566eeaf83 chore: bring terminal on landing back, update hero, move demo to bottom&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;365a5fc0b54e6553d8ab2c941342067c099d6686 chore: build multiarch images for corrosion and ucind to support e2e tests on amd64&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3aa8fead76638fea2edbff6f01e83adc776f7b09 chore: configure docs custom styles, init intro page&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;dfa6e001c50f1b446731e7a6b5eeefe428892e74 chore: cross over kubernetes on landing hero&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;735e36012a2490d2b69f06132d0c2dd7372ef3af chore: delete unused ucind-image-push target in Makefile&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ff1a8fbcf9857e94ae0d1e73349e1341bdab4d4e chore: fix comment&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;59f6fa75ca234218d631f30650ccc19cfb9a5d10 chore: init docusaurus docs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fd3facb6b03a044d35c7c7c8a28f42f672184bac chore: minor README change&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;eec728620b9c67a2cb7b5a50660c505d132aecc9 chore: minor README change&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;bd03bb9bfa1ff422393cc0218b19ad269b112fd0 chore: minor README change&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1ffe9acdd7781fac4d4fcbb391e0fdaf9b270854 chore: minor README rearrangement&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;4075f85b72a95afae45b92c16f187dd046a739a4 chore: minor website update&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fa3d992dbc81c27880c26a9f6d651b16ba0352f4 chore: period&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;7699b530c2b1adf0237dd4dbc5813195751cb735 chore: refine links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;683ad2235849b75340a19b491f68ea00f89ec9d2 chore: remove extra [FLAGS] from volume commands help, add SERVICE for inspect&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;0d820bc75a29c1be812b878a82f0cacd49dd8f90 chore: replace github discussions with discord in subscribe section&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;009c0e1b4c2d5e25629a7484748099780548bcf7 chore: scale docs service to 2 replicas in different regions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1ec5184f21644a161fcbb0bf7344a6341113735f chore: self-hosting focused front page (first screen)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;4590a516ad8eb05ffcd29d328596adf78ea0e462 chore: set default ssh key path to ~/.ssh/id_ed25519 and handle home expansion&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a5fe9fbfb21952b123564738ee0d3fd35910d2bc chore: update -p flag help for run command&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;8b66a11394c8aa0db44f1a29e6e487345add3baa chore: update hero&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a7d8afb052e1e08f9aab209e74aa569a47f95e8c chore: update value section wording&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;c34542a9d89b63ac3421a44c2b3ef545bb91a4c6 chore: update website title&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;971b21d6c13168c401ff692d2260847bd5762c72 feat: Implement basic build &amp;amp; push capabilities for services (#68)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fc61e2fc07fd8ee8cf22f58f43350d567677c813 feat: enable passive health checks and upstream retries in Caddy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;4df1820f96ab605556746377915832e2d988fae1 fix(doc): Tiny fixes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;88db1cb6a9b099ceada0f9b09ddf92149ad6bc44 fix: hero svg on safari&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;12c86f1dd407741f905f4aebcdc0a41976c266bc fix: use existing cluster client when deploying caddy after adding new machine #65&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/psviderski/uncloud/releases/tag/v0.8.0" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
