<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://selfh.st/apps</id>
  <title>Viseron Releases</title>
  <updated>2025-04-19T00:32:18.232147-04:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>selfh.st</name>
    <email>contact@selfh.st</email>
  </author>
  <link href="https://selfh.st/apps" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>Self-hosted software releases generated by selfh.st</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/roflcoopter/viseron/releases/tag/v2.3.0</id>
    <title>New release for Viseron: v2.3.0 - CodeProject AI and License Plate Recognition</title>
    <updated>2023-09-14T09:53:01-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>roflcoopter/viseron</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;This is a smaller release with a few new features and fixes.
I am working hard on 24/7 recordings that I hade planned to release together with these changes, but its taking a bit longer than i had anticipated.
If you are interested in that, sit tight for the next release! You can follow my progress here: #619 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;CodeProject AI component&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A new component which leverages CodeProject AI's computer vision capabilities is included in this release.
As of now it supports object detection, face recognition as well as a new post processor, Automatic License Plate Recognition!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Automatic License Plate Recognition (ALPR)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A new post processor is now available for ALPR.
Currently only CodeProject AI supports it, but in the future more variants may be supported.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Developer Experience&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have started to work on a better Developer Experience together with some proper Developer documentation.
It is still in early stages and the inner workings of Viseron are not explained yet, but it will improve over time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The biggest addition to the Developer Experience this release is the support for VSCode Devcontainers.
This makes it significantly easier to get going with development, as all you have to do is spin up the container!
I have been using this myself for some time now and it has accelerated my work significantly&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new Developer docs can be found here : https://viseron.netlify.app/docs/developers&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Changes and fixes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are also a small number of changes and improvements.
- New config option for the camera domain, &lt;code&gt;still_image&lt;/code&gt;
It allows you to configure a URL to fetch the snapshots that are displayed in the UI from.
Useful if you woudl lke to get full resolution still images in the UI while still using the substream for detection
Under &lt;code&gt;still_image&lt;/code&gt; you can specify &lt;code&gt;refresh_interval&lt;/code&gt; which makes the UI refresh more often. Default is 10 seconds.
- A &lt;code&gt;mask&lt;/code&gt; helper has been added to the docs: https://viseron.netlify.app/components-explorer/components/mog2#mask
This makes it a bit clearer how to configure them until its possible to do it from the frontend directly.
- &lt;code&gt;ffmpeg&lt;/code&gt; has a new config option &lt;code&gt;raw_command&lt;/code&gt; that makes it possible to specify an FFmpeg command that will be used directly.
Great if you want to test out some specific command that is hard to accomplish using the other available options.
There are a number of things to keep in mind tho, so if you are going to use it, make sure to read the docs thoroughly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What's Changed&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Developer Experience by @roflcoopter in https://github.com/roflcoopter/viseron/pull/545&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;add initial developer documentation by @roflcoopter in https://github.com/roflcoopter/viseron/pull/565&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;add frontend proxy docs by @roflcoopter in https://github.com/roflcoopter/viseron/pull/572&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;add CodeProject.AI component and ALPR by @roflcoopter in https://github.com/roflcoopter/viseron/pull/577&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;add a simple mask helper to the docs by @roflcoopter in https://github.com/roflcoopter/viseron/pull/578&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;show min/max list length in config docs page by @roflcoopter in https://github.com/roflcoopter/viseron/pull/579&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix ffmpeg crash when running without substream by @roflcoopter in https://github.com/roflcoopter/viseron/pull/580&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;add recommended vscode extensions by @roflcoopter in https://github.com/roflcoopter/viseron/pull/581&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;resize using INTER_AREA instead of INTER_CUBIC by @roflcoopter in https://github.com/roflcoopter/viseron/pull/582&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;small updates to the docs by @roflcoopter in https://github.com/roflcoopter/viseron/pull/593&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;include yolov7 model in rpi3/armv7 image by @roflcoopter in https://github.com/roflcoopter/viseron/pull/594&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;update intel drivers and opencl by @roflcoopter in https://github.com/roflcoopter/viseron/pull/596&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;run gstreamer using python-gst by @roflcoopter in https://github.com/roflcoopter/viseron/pull/608&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;improve logging for pcie startup scripts by @roflcoopter in https://github.com/roflcoopter/viseron/pull/633&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;allow audio codec to be null by @roflcoopter in https://github.com/roflcoopter/viseron/pull/634&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;extract only the necessarry information from ffprobe by @roflcoopter in https://github.com/roflcoopter/viseron/pull/635&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;install gst/gi in ci by @roflcoopter in https://github.com/roflcoopter/viseron/pull/637&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;switch back to @jy95/material-ui-image by @roflcoopter in https://github.com/roflcoopter/viseron/pull/638&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix recorder audio codec not being set by @roflcoopter in https://github.com/roflcoopter/viseron/pull/639&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;add ffmpeg raw_command option by @roflcoopter in https://github.com/roflcoopter/viseron/pull/641&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;set max number of threads in data_stream by @roflcoopter in https://github.com/roflcoopter/viseron/pull/642&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;add new config option for still image by @roflcoopter in https://github.com/roflcoopter/viseron/pull/643&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Feature/devcontainer improvements by @roflcoopter in https://github.com/roflcoopter/viseron/pull/644&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Full Changelog&lt;/strong&gt;: https://github.com/roflcoopter/viseron/compare/v2.2.0...v2.3.0&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/roflcoopter/viseron/releases/tag/v2.3.0" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/roflcoopter/viseron/releases/tag/v2.3.1</id>
    <title>New release for Viseron: v2.3.1 - Jetson Nano GStreamer fix</title>
    <updated>2023-09-18T07:20:59-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>roflcoopter/viseron</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;Fix &lt;code&gt;Failed to load component gstreamer: No module named 'gi'&lt;/code&gt; for the &lt;code&gt;jetson-nano&lt;/code&gt; container.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Closes #672 &lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/roflcoopter/viseron/releases/tag/v2.3.1" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/roflcoopter/viseron/releases/tag/v3.0.0</id>
    <title>New release for Viseron: 3.0.0 - Continuous Recordings</title>
    <updated>2025-03-15T04:04:29-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>roflcoopter/viseron</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;This release is a big one. It mainly focuses on continuous recordings, but also includes a lot of other features and fixes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have been working on this release for a long time and I am very happy with the result. I hope you will enjoy it as much as I do.
The release cadence has been very slow lately and for that I am sorry. I will try to make smaller releases more often in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Breaking changes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New docker volumes are required. Please see the updated &lt;a href="https://viseron.netlify.app/docs/documentation/installation#running-viseron"&gt;docker documentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Old recordings will not be compatible with the new version and wont be viewable in the UI&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Files will no longer be stored in the &lt;code&gt;/recordings&lt;/code&gt; folder, and should be removed from your docker volumes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Recordings are now in HLS format. If you need to have the recordings saved as full MP4 files you can use the new config option &lt;code&gt;create_event_clip&lt;/code&gt;, or use the new &lt;code&gt;Export&lt;/code&gt; feature in the UI.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;mp4&lt;/code&gt; file extension is now forced and &lt;code&gt;extension&lt;/code&gt; is removed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;segments_folder&lt;/code&gt; is removed in favor of tier paths from the new &lt;a href="https://viseron.netlify.app/components-explorer/components/storage"&gt;&lt;code&gt;storage&lt;/code&gt; component&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Thumbnails are now stored in &lt;code&gt;/thumbnails&lt;/code&gt; folder (depending on the tier config)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;filename_pattern&lt;/code&gt; in &lt;code&gt;thumbnail&lt;/code&gt; is removed, stored as ID of the recording&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;audio_codec&lt;/code&gt; behavior changed. It is now only used as stream information. To transcode Audio, set &lt;code&gt;audio_codec&lt;/code&gt; under &lt;code&gt;recorder&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;trigger_recorder&lt;/code&gt; is removed in favor of &lt;code&gt;trigger_event_recording&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The FFmpeg command has been changed, so if you use &lt;code&gt;raw_command&lt;/code&gt; you need to update it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;New features&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;24/7 recordings&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main feature included in this release is the option of having 24/7 recordings.
With this comes a new component, &lt;code&gt;storage&lt;/code&gt; which will allow you to retain data based on time (like it is today) and based one consumed space.
This allows you to use your storage to its maximum.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Documentation for how the recordings work can be found &lt;a href="https://viseron.netlify.app/docs/documentation/configuration/recordings"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Updated screenshots for the frontend can be found &lt;a href="https://viseron.netlify.app/docs/documentation#screenshots"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Storage Tiers&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another feature of the &lt;code&gt;storage&lt;/code&gt; component are &lt;code&gt;tiers&lt;/code&gt;.
They allow you to store recordings on multiple media.
Say you have one 256GB SSD and a 1TB HDD, you can keep the most recent recordings on the SSD for fast access while offloading the older recordings to the HDD for archiving.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Timeline&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To easily view 24/7 recordings, a new Timeline view is available.
It currently shows continuous recordings and different events such as motion, detected objects, face recognition etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Timelineview" src="https://viseron.netlify.app/img/screenshots/Viseron-screenshot-events-timeline.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Events&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Events view is a more concise view than the Timeline.
Here you can scroll through and view all the Events.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Events view" src="https://viseron.netlify.app/img/screenshots/Viseron-screenshot-events-events.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Other new features&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A new safe mode has been added. If Viseron cant startup due to config errors, it will restore the last known good config and start up with a minimum amount of components. This will allow you to fix the config in the UI and restart Viseron without having to manually restore the config.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Allow empty password for cameras&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A logfile is now created in the &lt;code&gt;/config&lt;/code&gt; folder. This will allow you to see the logs without having to enter the container.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New telegram component provided by @smelis, which allows sending of clips and thumbnails using Telegram.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New ptz component provided by @smelis, which can be used by the Telegram component to control a camera.
  The PTZ functionality will be ported to the web UI as well at some point.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;max_recording_time&lt;/code&gt; has been added to the &lt;code&gt;recorder&lt;/code&gt; component. This will allow you to set a maximum recording time for each recording. This is useful if you have a lot of motion events and want to keep the recordings short.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;record_only&lt;/code&gt; has been added to the &lt;code&gt;recorder&lt;/code&gt; component. This will allow you to record without running any detectors.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;still_image_width&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;still_image_height&lt;/code&gt; has been added to the &lt;code&gt;camera&lt;/code&gt; component. This will allow you to set the resolution of the still images.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Changes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A PostgreSQL database is now running inside the container. It is not possible to use an external database at the moment.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Upgraded to Ubuntu 22.04 which gives updated drivers to support newer hardware&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Updated to React 18&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Updated to Python 3.10&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Updated to OpenCV 4.10.0&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Updated to FFmpeg 5.1.2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Updated CUDA&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Updated DLIB&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Updated OpenCL&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Updated VA-API&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Updated all Python dependencies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The documentation has been updated with a lot of new chapters&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Fixes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Camera passwords are now escaped, meaning that passwords with special characters are now supported.
  This has been a long standing issue which caused FFProbe to fail when trying to connect to the camera.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Properly redact sensitive information in logs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reduce the occurence of &lt;code&gt;KeyError: UUID&lt;/code&gt; in the logs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix a long standing bug where frames with drawn items (like bounding boxes, masks etc) would bleed through to other frames.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Docker images will be on Docker Hub shortly&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/roflcoopter/viseron/releases/tag/v3.0.0" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/roflcoopter/viseron/releases/tag/v3.1.0</id>
    <title>New release for Viseron: 3.1.0 - User and Role Management</title>
    <updated>2025-04-16T06:01:51-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>roflcoopter/viseron</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;Multiple users, finally! Viseron has had authentication for quite some time, but you could only create one initial admin user during the onboarding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This release brings a new &lt;code&gt;User mangement&lt;/code&gt; page to the frontend, and with it a new &lt;code&gt;Settings&lt;/code&gt; page.
&lt;img alt="settings-page" src="https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/9e9652a8-e8fd-4ba9-b281-3254a76d05bf" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Roles&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Users can be assigned different roles: admin, write or read.
See the updated documentation: https://viseron.netlify.app/docs/documentation/configuration/authentication#roles&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Assign cameras&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to restrict what cameras each user can see, you can do so by assigning specific ones to each user.
See the updated documentation: https://viseron.netlify.app/docs/documentation/configuration/authentication#assigning-cameras
&lt;img alt="image" src="https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/4694cacd-c08e-4b9d-9989-f0511b1e43a0" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;New features&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Masks can now be configured for &lt;code&gt;Post processor&lt;/code&gt;. They are configured the same way as masks for object/motion detection. A new config option &lt;code&gt;draw_post_processor_mask&lt;/code&gt; is also available for the MJPEG streams in order to debug the masks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Discord notifications component, provided by @InterN0te &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gotify notifications component, provided by @InterN0te &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New config option &lt;code&gt;use_last_snapshot_on_error&lt;/code&gt; for FFmpeg/GStreamer. It allows for returning the previously retrieved snapshot for a camera incase of a flaky connection&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New filter option on Events page to group cameras. 
&lt;img alt="image" src="https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/9dd853dc-3665-43d9-93c8-7652c00f5877" /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New filter option on Events page to adjust the requested timestamp with the configured lookback.
&lt;img alt="image" src="https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/419a4cef-c847-4b3b-904a-3b9859b2becb" /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Fixes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wait for file updates when shutting down and using &lt;code&gt;move_on_shutdown: true&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix Docker compose documentation examples&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix Codeproject AI Face recognition training. Previously faces were never recognized when training&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix Compreface failing to start when &lt;code&gt;use_subjects&lt;/code&gt; was set to &lt;code&gt;false&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Avoid reloading page when submitting login form. This caused some issues where you sometimes had to login twice&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Events are now properly sorted by timestamp in the details popup on the Events page&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When clicking on an event in the Events page, a snapshots is shown instead of video if its not available.
  This calculation is now more forgiving and now has a 10 seconds grace period&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Docker images will be on Docker Hub shortly&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;All Changes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix typos in docker compose examples by @roflcoopter in https://github.com/roflcoopter/viseron/pull/930&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;catch OSError when closing ffmpeg pipe by @roflcoopter in https://github.com/roflcoopter/viseron/pull/935&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;make sure we wait for file size update timers on shutdown by @roflcoopter in https://github.com/roflcoopter/viseron/pull/934&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix cpai face recognition training by @roflcoopter in https://github.com/roflcoopter/viseron/pull/939&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;new config option use_last_snapshot_on_error for still_image by @roflcoopter in https://github.com/roflcoopter/viseron/pull/940&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix mask image coordinates being reversed by @roflcoopter in https://github.com/roflcoopter/viseron/pull/943&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add Notification Category to Components Explorer by @InterN0te in https://github.com/roflcoopter/viseron/pull/947&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Discord component for notifications by @InterN0te in https://github.com/roflcoopter/viseron/pull/944&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add Gotify notification component by @InterN0te in https://github.com/roflcoopter/viseron/pull/941&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Post processor masks by @roflcoopter in https://github.com/roflcoopter/viseron/pull/953&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;update docs on how to add timestamp to recorded video by @roflcoopter in https://github.com/roflcoopter/viseron/pull/954&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;allow for grouping events for different cameras by @roflcoopter in https://github.com/roflcoopter/viseron/pull/955&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;better handling of compreface initialization by @roflcoopter in https://github.com/roflcoopter/viseron/pull/962&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;User management by @roflcoopter in https://github.com/roflcoopter/viseron/pull/965&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Feature/auth improvements by @roflcoopter in https://github.com/roflcoopter/viseron/pull/968&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;assign cameras to users by @roflcoopter in https://github.com/roflcoopter/viseron/pull/969&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;properly cleanup axios interceptor and add tests for AuthContext by @roflcoopter in https://github.com/roflcoopter/viseron/pull/970&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;updated required roles for some endpoints by @roflcoopter in https://github.com/roflcoopter/viseron/pull/972&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;docs: clarification on events and timeline by @roflcoopter in https://github.com/roflcoopter/viseron/pull/973&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;add lookback adjustment when clicking on an event by @roflcoopter in https://github.com/roflcoopter/viseron/pull/974&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix event sorting on the Events page by @roflcoopter in https://github.com/roflcoopter/viseron/pull/975&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;New Contributors&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;@InterN0te made their first contribution in https://github.com/roflcoopter/viseron/pull/947&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Full Changelog&lt;/strong&gt;: https://github.com/roflcoopter/viseron/compare/v3.0.0...v3.1.0&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/roflcoopter/viseron/releases/tag/v3.1.0" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/roflcoopter/viseron/releases/tag/v3.1.1</id>
    <title>New release for Viseron: 3.1.1 - Camera storage config fix</title>
    <updated>2025-04-17T16:49:01-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>roflcoopter/viseron</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;Hotfix release to resolve an issue where you couldnt specify &lt;code&gt;recorder&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;snapshots&lt;/code&gt; without also specifying the other under a cameras &lt;code&gt;storage&lt;/code&gt; config&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What's Changed&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix undefined check for recorder and snapshot tiers by @roflcoopter in https://github.com/roflcoopter/viseron/pull/981&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3.1.1 by @roflcoopter in https://github.com/roflcoopter/viseron/pull/982&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Full Changelog&lt;/strong&gt;: https://github.com/roflcoopter/viseron/compare/v3.1.0...v3.1.1&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/roflcoopter/viseron/releases/tag/v3.1.1" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
