<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://selfh.st/apps</id>
  <title>WatchState Releases</title>
  <updated>2025-06-04T13:35:04.694730-04:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>selfh.st</name>
    <email>contact@selfh.st</email>
  </author>
  <link href="https://selfh.st/apps" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>Self-hosted software releases generated by selfh.st</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/arabcoders/watchstate/releases/tag/master-20250522-6d494bc0</id>
    <title>New release for WatchState: master-20250522-6d494bc0</title>
    <updated>2025-05-22T19:07:56-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>arabcoders/watchstate</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;9856ca78 Added URL Checker into tools menu. by arabcoders&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fa4eda07 Filter every line output in the basic report to strip known sensitive information like accesstokens or apikeys. by arabcoders&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;0102f56a Hide sub-users page when logged in as non-main user. by arabcoders&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;689f6884 Add more php ini configuration options to make frankenphp behave like standard php-fpm by arabcoders&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Full Changelog&lt;/strong&gt;: https://github.com/arabcoders/watchstate/compare/master-20250513-57580fbc...master-20250522-6d494bc0&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/arabcoders/watchstate/releases/tag/master-20250522-6d494bc0" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/arabcoders/watchstate/releases/tag/master-20250523-42281eba</id>
    <title>New release for WatchState: master-20250523-42281eba</title>
    <updated>2025-05-23T16:53:54-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>arabcoders/watchstate</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;b5386111 Add new generic webhook endpoint. by arabcoders&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;82c1a8ef Update the guides pages. by arabcoders&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;428e3eda Make it possible to cache metadata request cross users. by arabcoders&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;c053fe84 Make it possible to mark specific webhook events as generic that would trigger for all users who has the same backend setup. by arabcoders&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;d45eacdf Disable automatic release note generation and update package dependencies by arabcoders&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/arabcoders/watchstate/releases/tag/master-20250523-42281eba" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/arabcoders/watchstate/releases/tag/master-20250525-c934375c</id>
    <title>New release for WatchState: master-20250525-c934375c</title>
    <updated>2025-05-25T12:37:52-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>arabcoders/watchstate</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;5d3d5644 When processing generic event, re-validate the metadata to prevent items which user doesn't have access to make it into his db. by arabcoders&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;23e19f62 Support generic events more widely for plex client. by arabcoders&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3aef2ce9 Support generic events more widely for jellyfin&amp;amp;emby clients. by arabcoders&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3c7d1e6e Add Logger proxy class. by arabcoders&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;af688358 Document downsides of the new generic webhook system and caching behavior. by arabcoders&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;666c6de4 Fix logged exception when a generic event trigger metadata httpException 404 by arabcoders&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;dd3833a7 When parsing webhook and requesting metadata from backend, before throwing error, check for IS_GENERIC and prevent expected error for generic events. by arabcoders&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/arabcoders/watchstate/releases/tag/master-20250525-c934375c" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/arabcoders/watchstate/releases/tag/master-20250527-5df09c15</id>
    <title>New release for WatchState: master-20250527-5df09c15</title>
    <updated>2025-05-27T12:57:27-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>arabcoders/watchstate</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;14204a51 Ignore task scheduler http log messages. by arabcoders&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3274b36f Update TaskScheduler status to initialize true by arabcoders&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;c854949e Refactor task runner to scheduler and update related components by arabcoders&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;5c2203d0 Add back the pid file for runner. by arabcoders&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;689591ba Change output verbosity to debug level in RunnerCommand by arabcoders&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;d1a607ca switch to internal job runner. by arabcoders&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;b991479e Add cache purging functionality and update UI components by arabcoders&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/arabcoders/watchstate/releases/tag/master-20250527-5df09c15" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/arabcoders/watchstate/releases/tag/master-20250530-6224b76c</id>
    <title>New release for WatchState: master-20250530-6224b76c</title>
    <updated>2025-05-30T11:05:43-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>arabcoders/watchstate</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;d98abf22 forgot to remove beta tag from guide. by arabcoders&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;0dcdcc4c Added caching to webui backgrounds. by arabcoders&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;54136826 Add help links to the default view and improve FAQ customization instructions by arabcoders&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;b0ba2e18 Deprecate old webhook endpoint in favor of the generic endpoint. by arabcoders&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;0c3eea52 switch db to WAL mode, it's little slower, but more durable by arabcoders&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;83e1af43 add the ability to kill process via processes page. by arabcoders&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3f1c8eac Fixed unformatted point in setting up Tautulli webhook by arabcoders&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/arabcoders/watchstate/releases/tag/master-20250530-6224b76c" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
