<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://selfh.st/apps</id>
  <title>YoutubeDL-Material Releases</title>
  <updated>2024-12-07T17:31:32.047938-05:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>selfh.st</name>
    <email>contact@selfh.st</email>
  </author>
  <link href="https://selfh.st/apps" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>Self-hosted software releases generated by selfh.st</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/Tzahi12345/YoutubeDL-Material/releases/tag/v4.1</id>
    <title>New release for YoutubeDL-Material: YoutubeDL-Material v4.1</title>
    <updated>2020-07-04T12:23:57-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tzahi12345/YoutubeDL-Material</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;New update inbound! This one is focused on bug fixes and accessibility improvements. Subscriptions got its third iterative update as well, so we hope you enjoy those features as well. Since the last update, our Docker pulls have grown almost 600%, we're almost at &lt;strong&gt;1 million&lt;/strong&gt; now! Thank you everyone for your support, suggestions, bug fixes, and PR's. It's been amazing!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;New features&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Subscriptions v3!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can now use custom args and file outputs for subscriptions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added ability to make subscription audio-only - thanks @Code-Slave for this suggestion!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Subscription videos are now stored in the DB, meaning the list of videos should load quicker and additional features like subscription video sharing can be added in the future&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can now input and use your YouTube cookies in YoutubeDL-Material using the new cookies uploader in the settings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This allows you to download private videos and playlists&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It may prevent 429 errors from occuring for some users&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New playlist modification dialog&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Change the playlist name, the videos in the playlist, and their order. Thanks @bodzio4749 for inspiring this!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Docker build now runs as non-root by default, adding an extra layer of security&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Grateful to @SuperSandro2000 and @Wonderfall for getting this implemented, thank you both!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Support for the German language&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can now select Deutsch in addition to English and Spanish in the language select in the settings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Thanks to @UnlimitedCookies, @SuperSandro2000, and @GlassedSilver for their organized efforts!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Minor additions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added &lt;code&gt;Safe download override&lt;/code&gt; checkbox in the settings which will force the backend to use the safer downloading option&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you enable this override, you will lose the ability to see download progress&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added ability to clear all downloads from a session in the downloads manager&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The ID for videos in the file manager will now by default use the youtube ID, rather than the file name - thanks @CountParadox for suggesting this!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pressing enter in the URL input will now trigger a download&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you delete a video that was downloaded with a thumbnail, the thumbnail will autodelete as well - Thanks @GlassedSilver for recommending this!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Bug fixes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed bug that prevented sharing videos with non-users if multi-user mode was enabled&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed bug that caused the server to crash when attempting to update youtube-dl&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed bug where updating a user's password would update the admin's password instead - thanks @UnlimitedCookies for finding this one!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;@web-connect fixed a typo in the logger section of the settings, thank you!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed several bugs preventing non-YT videos from download - thanks @CountParadox for submitting bug reports on this front!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's all for this update (hope I didn't miss anything). In the next update, we'll hopefully see a redesign of the home screen with a unified view of subscription and non-subscription downloads, focusing on providing a much stronger user experience. If you'd like to read more or provide input, you can see the &lt;a href="https://github.com/Tzahi12345/YoutubeDL-Material/issues/106"&gt;issue here&lt;/a&gt;. Cheers!&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/Tzahi12345/YoutubeDL-Material/releases/tag/v4.1" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/Tzahi12345/YoutubeDL-Material/releases/tag/v4.2</id>
    <title>New release for YoutubeDL-Material: v4.2</title>
    <updated>2020-12-24T03:35:01-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tzahi12345/YoutubeDL-Material</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;Merry Christmas! We got a &lt;em&gt;huge&lt;/em&gt; update incoming, with major feature additions, optimizations, and a ton of bug fixes. The community has been integral in helping track these down, so if I forgot to give a shoutout, this is my way of thanking you all. Between the PRs, the suggestions, and the bug fixes, the support from you guys has been incredible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NOTE: This update has breaking changes so if you'd like to revert, you can rename the backed up database files in the &lt;code&gt;appdata&lt;/code&gt; folder to their original name and get back to the old setup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Features&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Homepage redesign&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The home page has been redesigned with new file "cards", you can customize their size in the "about" dialog&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"My videos" shows both subscription and regular downloads in one (paged) list, which can now be filtered and ordered to your choosing&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Paging the files means much better performance for users with a high number of videos&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Video duration and download date is shown&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"Custom playlists" replaces the old playlist section&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Subscriptions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added ability to edit subscriptions&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added ability to "pause" a subscription, set a maximum quality, and custom file output&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added ability to redownload "fresh" downloads (thanks @GlassedSilver for suggesting this!)&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;TL;DR is that newly uploaded videos will get redownloaded on the next day to avoid the issue where a video is downloaded before a higher quality version is processed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can now add subscriptions with the same URL (caveat: the name has to be different)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can directly access subscriptions from the hamburger menu&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added a loading bar to the subscription view when a subscription is checking/downloading videos&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Video player improvements&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Video description is now included if available&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Updated save and share icons styling and location so that it doesn't hide important content anymore&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Categories (thanks @GlassedSilver for this feature request!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can now create rule-based "categories" in the settings menu where videos can be organized and searched based on the given category&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Automatic (uneditable) playlists are created from categories&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Twitch chat support (thanks @GlassedSilver for this great suggestion!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can now download and view Twitch chats in the video player. You can add a Twitch API key in the settings menu and on Twitch VODs a "chat" icon will pop up in the player&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;These can be automatically downloaded as well&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Minor improvements&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Downloading&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Max quality will always download the max quality (instead of the best mp4)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Progress bar is now visible for all videos&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Downloading in general is a lot more stable, and you can now choose to download with either youtube-dl or youtube-dlc&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Thumbnails are now downloaded automatically&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can opt not to download the JSON metadata as well, though it's recommended you keep it as in future updates we may draw more information from it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added a "Kill all downloads" button in the settings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Backend&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Simplified database structure to allow for less code reuse (this is a breaking change)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Files that have been downloaded but not registered in the database will now be automatically added on startup&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bcrypt.js is now used to avoid security vulnerabilities with bcrypt&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved performance by using async functions in key areas (thanks @NotWoods for doing this!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Docker&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ARM builds now use the normal Docker tags and autobuild without issue (it is now done through GitHub rather than Dockerhub, thanks @diveflo for implementing this!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Misc&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added ability to login using LDAP&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added French, Chinese, and Norweigan support&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use encryption option is now deprecated, if you would like to use encryption please use a reverse-proxy (instructions here)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tab title in browser now matches the top title set in the settings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ctrl-clicking files opens them in a new tab, right clicking files lets you simply open it or open it in a new tab&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Side nav (hamburger menu) can now default to "open"&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Updated Chrome and Firefox plugin to v0.4 which supports non-YT links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Frontend binaries are removed from the repo, on Docker they are now built alongside the backend (thanks @SuperSandro2000 for implementing this!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When a login token expires, users are now redirected to the login page (thanks @UnlimitedCookies for the suggestion!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Bug fixes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed bug where a non-user could edit the settings when not logged in&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed bug where audio files were incorrectly downloaded as webm (thanks @ItsGonzoHD for pointing this out!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed bug where deleting an audio file would result in an error&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed bug where videos were not downloaded at the max quality (mentioned above)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed bug that prevented subscription videos from being downloaded and non-users from viewing shared videos&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed bug where non-shared videos could be viewed by non-users&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed bug that prevented playlists from being downloaded as a zip&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixes bug where an error would occur on startup if a user's file folder was missing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm definitely missing some other features and bug fixes since it's been nearly 6 months from the last update. But I hope this Christmas update will help your download experience. That's all for now, thanks again for all the support. Happy downloading!&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/Tzahi12345/YoutubeDL-Material/releases/tag/v4.2" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/Tzahi12345/YoutubeDL-Material/releases/tag/v4.3</id>
    <title>New release for YoutubeDL-Material: v4.3</title>
    <updated>2022-06-27T00:51:20-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tzahi12345/YoutubeDL-Material</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;Hi everyone! It's been about a year and a half since the last update, so we've been due for one to say the least. If you're on the &lt;code&gt;nightly&lt;/code&gt; tag, most of these you'll have already seen. If not, then you're in for a lot of improvements!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Features&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MongoDB support!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MongoDB is now preferred over the default, local DB. It's much quicker and at scales, leads to a much smoother experience&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can transfer your local DB to MongoDB using the &lt;code&gt;Database&lt;/code&gt; tab in the settings menu&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No more corrupt DBs! Regardless, please back up your DB regularly&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New download manager&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Downloads can now be tracked and managed through a new interface. Downloads can be paused, restarted, and errors can be viewed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Subscriptions now use the new download manager, preventing subs from getting locked up checking for new downloads and streamlining the download process&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New tasks &amp;amp; maintenance page&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added ability to run or schedule specific tasks&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Backup/Restore DB&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MongoDB backups can be done through MongoDB, we simply store it into a JSON file locally&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Check for DB records with missing files&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Import missing DB records&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix duplicate files in DB&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Update youtube-dl (or whatever repo you use)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Concurrent streams&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can now watch your videos simultaneously with friends! &lt;a href="https://github.com/Tzahi12345/YoutubeDL-Material/pull/378#issue-892631464"&gt;Click here&lt;/a&gt; for a demo.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;File metadata can now be modified from the UI&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Just click the info button on files and you'll see a new edit button on the top right of the dialog!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Much faster downloads with yt-dlp as the new default downloader!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Minor improvements&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;UI&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dedicated settings page&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Settings dialog has been converted into a page for ease-of-use&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added option to rate-limit downloads&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added pagination to files on the home screen&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Home screen files can now be filtered by type (audio or video)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Version and commit info can now be viewed from the &lt;code&gt;About&lt;/code&gt; dialog&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Updated subscription pages to use the new file cards (icons) from the home page&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hovering over a file card will now show a preview of that video&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fonts and bootstrap are now hosted locally (Thanks @firstdorsal for the PR!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added ability to crop files prior to downloading&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New translations. We now support:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;English&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spanish&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chinese&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dutch&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;French&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;German&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Italian&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Czech&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Norwegian&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finnish&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Korean&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Macedonian&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Portuguese&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Russian&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Telugu&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Indonesian&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some of these are only partial translations. If you'd like to help out &lt;a href="https://hosted.weblate.org/projects/youtubedl-material/ytdl-material/"&gt;click here!&lt;/a&gt;. Special thanks to everyone who's helped out so far!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Backend&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added args overriding support&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;E.g. global custom args will override default args, per-subscription args will override all other args&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;File sharing should work a lot more reliably&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved arg simulation (it now occurs on the backend)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Dependencies/Integrations&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added Kodi .nfo file generation support&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Helm chart added (Thanks @benashby for the PR!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Heroku deployments now use Docker&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Angular updated to v13&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PM2 is now used instead of nodemon to enable server restarts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Updated Twitch VOD chat downloading to use new Twitch API&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/PetterKraabol/Twitch-Chat-Downloader"&gt;Twitch-Chat-Downloader&lt;/a&gt; is now required, and a client secret must be set along with a client ID&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Benefit is chat downloads are much faster!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://sponsor.ajay.app/"&gt;SponsorBlock&lt;/a&gt; integration! Enable it in the settings and all supported videos will show a "skip ad" button where appropriate&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Behind-the-scenes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;API docs now automated&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Much improved wiki (Thanks to @GlassedSilver for the support!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tons of new automation using GitHub Actions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added unit tests (coverage will be a long-term WIP)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Bug fixes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Way too many to name! Sorry if this section excites you, but we've worked hard to minimize bugs and make this an extra-stable release.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you to everyone who has contributed since the last update. There are literally dozens of you but I can't express my appreciation enough. Even when I was too busy to work on the project, it brought me joy to see notifications of PRs going up and new translations submitted. A special thanks to @GlassedSilver for his work on community management, reviewing PRs, code improvements, and suggestions (as always).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We're now at 20 million Docker pulls which is an insane number. The Firefox browser extension alone has ~350 active concurrent users. There's still loads of improvements to come, but the last 5+ years has been incredibly fun. Happy downloading!&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/Tzahi12345/YoutubeDL-Material/releases/tag/v4.3" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/Tzahi12345/YoutubeDL-Material/releases/tag/v4.3.1</id>
    <title>New release for YoutubeDL-Material: v4.3.1</title>
    <updated>2023-05-06T23:40:36-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tzahi12345/YoutubeDL-Material</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;Hi all! Got a bigger update than I originally intended, but I doubt anyone will complain :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before I get to what's new, one thing I want to mention is Node.js v16 is now required for those not using Docker. So many people helped make this update possible, between translations, pull requests, feature suggestions, and bug reports. I really do appreciate the support.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Features&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/Tzahi12345/YoutubeDL-Material/wiki/Notifications"&gt;Notifications&lt;/a&gt; (#440)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Supports third party services&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Discord&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Telegram&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Slack&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ntfy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gotify&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can also use a generic webhook URL to connect with Zapier-like services&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Download archive now (mostly) handled in DB rather than text files (#809)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Should prevent file lock errors from occurring. New archive viewer is now available with ability to import/export archives&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Even with youtube-dl archive setting disabled, subscription videos can be permanently deleted&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;UI refresh&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added ability to favorite/unfavorite videos&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added RSS feed for downloads (#388)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added task to delete old files (#358)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Minor improvements&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Removed allow_autoplay setting and replaced it with force_autoplay (#695)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Updated to Angular 15&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Node.js v16 is now required&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Expected file size now visible from UI in the quality select menu (#838)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added settings for tasks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For non-YT videos, available resolutions will now be shown rather than presenting maximum desired values&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Bug fixes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed broken Twitch VOD chat downloads (#859)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed an issue where subscriptions would only show 10 downloads (#715)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed an issue where encrypted streams could not be decoded (#819)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed an issue where download progress was not displayed (#774)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed an issue related to duplicate subscription names (#801)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed an issue preventing custom args with values from being used (#745)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Switched default mongo version to v4 due to AVX incompatibility issues (#733)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed an issue where videos would still download for a subscription after unsubscribing (#689)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed an issue where task scheduling wasn't considering the container time-zone (#810)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed an issue where role/user permissions could not be changed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed an issue where the simulated output in Advanced download mode would only appear once changes were made to args&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing I've had in the works is trying to get an electron app (desktop version) functional. I'm ~95% of the way there, but the last bit will be tough. I'll keep everyone posted on that here: https://github.com/Tzahi12345/YoutubeDL-Material/discussions/409&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/Tzahi12345/YoutubeDL-Material/releases/tag/v4.3.1" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/Tzahi12345/YoutubeDL-Material/releases/tag/v4.3.2</id>
    <title>New release for YoutubeDL-Material: v4.3.2</title>
    <updated>2023-05-25T22:23:07-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tzahi12345/YoutubeDL-Material</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;Very small update :) Mainly to fix some permissions issues some users were seeing in Docker. Excited to introduce a new Task that will help rebuild your database if it ever breaks. Also for those using armv7, this update reintroduces it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;New features&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reintroduced armv7 support&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added task for rebuilding the database&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Minor additions&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved mobile UI for downloads (home screen &amp;amp; downloads manager)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Translations updates&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Bug fixes&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed issue related to docker UID/GID permissions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed issue where temp archives would get generated for subscriptions even if none were present&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Full Changelog&lt;/strong&gt;: https://github.com/Tzahi12345/YoutubeDL-Material/compare/v4.3.1...v4.3.2&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Special thanks to @martadinata666 for helping introduce some of these key fixes.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/Tzahi12345/YoutubeDL-Material/releases/tag/v4.3.2" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
