<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://selfh.st/apps</id>
  <title>Zoraxy Releases</title>
  <updated>2025-02-25T22:32:33.754142-05:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>selfh.st</name>
    <email>contact@selfh.st</email>
  </author>
  <link href="https://selfh.st/apps" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>Self-hosted software releases generated by selfh.st</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/tobychui/zoraxy/releases/tag/v3.1.4</id>
    <title>New release for Zoraxy: v3.1.4</title>
    <updated>2024-11-24T02:04:28-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>tobychui/zoraxy</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="圖片" src="https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/4979fa78-2235-4bed-9f35-7e3b0e2406e1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Updates v3.1.4&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This version mainly improve on user experience with the introduction of the new dark theme mode and more automatic sniffing logic. As seen there are a lot of users exposing their webmin interface to the internet, the &lt;code&gt;robots.txt&lt;/code&gt; file is introduce to prevent search engine bot from indexing the webmin panel. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Notes for Docker Users&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ZeroTier configuration data is no longer stored in &lt;code&gt;/var/lib/zerotier-one/&lt;/code&gt; and is now included in the Zoraxy configuration directory &lt;code&gt;/opt/zoraxy/config/zerotier/&lt;/code&gt;. If you still have a ZeroTier configuration mounted in the original location, you shouldn't experience breaking changes, however this is now an unsupported configuration and is recommended to move the configuration data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Notes for Dark Theme&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The dark theme feature is done using CSS override. If you encounter any wired issue in dark theme mode including "text is hard to see" or "color is too close between two sections", please consider reporting them as a UX bug. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Change Log&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Added Dark Theme Mode&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added an auto sniffer for self-signed certificates.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added robots.txt to the project.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Introduced an EU wrapper in the front-end for automatic registration of 26 countries.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Moved all hard-coded values to a dedicated def.go file.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed a panic issue occurring on unsupported platform exits.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Integrated fixes for SSH proxy and Docker snippet updates.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed the default listening port to 443 and enable TLS by default&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Optimized GeoIP database slow-search mode CPU usage&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/tobychui/zoraxy/releases/tag/v3.1.4" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/tobychui/zoraxy/releases/tag/v3.1.5</id>
    <title>New release for Zoraxy: v3.1.5</title>
    <updated>2024-12-27T20:23:54-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>tobychui/zoraxy</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="圖片" src="https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/fe54b307-06ce-4db4-b933-964dccba1035" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;v3.1.5&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This version introduce the new architecture for future SSO implementation, the authentication provider settings. With the first PR in place (authelia), you can now use Authelia to replace basic auth on your preferred proxy host names. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This release also include a new default site options to close the connection without responding (or just send empty response in TLS mode, as SNI header sniffer already processed the request and can't be closed directly). A slightly different alternative to nginx's 444 response. 
&lt;img alt="圖片" src="https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/ebed6d24-354e-43db-885b-0b8674f714e8" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another cool feature is that this version of Zoraxy introduced an external geoIP database mode where you can place the required csv file under &lt;code&gt;conf/geodb/geoipv4.csv&lt;/code&gt; (and &lt;code&gt;geoipv6.csv&lt;/code&gt;) to use your own table. You can also use the new flag &lt;code&gt;-update_geoip&lt;/code&gt; to start zoraxy in automatic geodb update mode, pull the two files from cdn and exit. Suitable for those who want to setup and forget their zoraxy instance to keep their access list up-to-date.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Notes: This version ship with an internal config updater where it will upgrade your config to the v3.1.5 format. Please remember to backup your config (from v3.1.4) before drop-in replacing the executable with v3.1.5.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Change Log&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed hostname case sensitive bug&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed ACME table too wide css bug&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed HSTS toggle button bug&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed slow GeoIP resolve mode concurrent r/w bug&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added close connection as default site option&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added experimental authelia support&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added custom header support to websocket&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added levelDB as database implementation (not currently used)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added external GeoIP db loading support&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Restructured a lot of modules&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/tobychui/zoraxy/releases/tag/v3.1.5" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/tobychui/zoraxy/releases/tag/v3.1.6</id>
    <title>New release for Zoraxy: v3.1.6</title>
    <updated>2024-12-31T09:04:17-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>tobychui/zoraxy</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h2&gt;v3.1.6&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a quick patch version of v3.1.5 for Proxmox websocket. This version also introduced the new toggle for uptime monitor per HTTP proxy rule, suitable for NAS and low power devices which will enter sleep mode when there are no incoming requests. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Change Log&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Exposed log file, sys.uuid and static web server path to start flag (customizable conf and sys.db path is still wip)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Optimized connection close implementation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added toggle for uptime monitor&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added optional copy HTTP custom headers to websocket connection&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/tobychui/zoraxy/releases/tag/v3.1.6" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/tobychui/zoraxy/releases/tag/v3.1.7</id>
    <title>New release for Zoraxy: v3.1.7</title>
    <updated>2025-02-08T05:53:16-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>tobychui/zoraxy</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="圖片" src="https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/ae5a0c53-1674-4adb-ad66-132f264c9fce" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;v3.1.7&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This release updated the dark theme color palettes to make it less dark. New updates include details viewing for uptime monitor and a few minor features. @adoolaard also introduced a new tag system for managing HTTP proxy rules in #509 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Change Log&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Merged and added new tagging system for HTTP Proxy rules&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added inline editing for redirection rules&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added uptime monitor status dot detail info (now clickable)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added close connection support to port 80 listener&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Optimized port collision check on startup&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Optimized dark theme color scheme (Free consultation by &lt;a href="https://www.3sdesign.io/"&gt;3S Design studio&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed capital letter rule unable to delete bug&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed docker statistic not save bug by @PassiveLemon &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/tobychui/zoraxy/releases/tag/v3.1.7" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/tobychui/zoraxy/releases/tag/v3.1.8</id>
    <title>New release for Zoraxy: v3.1.8</title>
    <updated>2025-02-16T04:25:23-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>tobychui/zoraxy</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="圖片" src="https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/70edcaea-fc9b-446e-ba40-09de88d78aeb" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;v3.1.8&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This releases fixes the docker ssh bug as well as a few minor improvements including exposing the dpcore timeout value to the UI. 
If you want to further increase the concurrent connection counts to your upstream server, you can also change such setting under HTTP Proxy Rule &amp;gt; Upstreams &amp;gt; Max Concurrent Connections. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note: The bandwidth between your gateway and upstream servers are fixed. More concurrent connection doesn't directly translate to faster proxy speed. As this setting is really use-case dependent, you can keep it as default if you do not what value to use.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Change Log&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Exposed timeout value from dpcore to UI&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added active load balancing (if uptime monitor is enabled on that rule)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Re-factorized io stats and remove dependencies over wmic (by @eyerrock )&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Removed SMTP input validation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed sticky session bug&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed passive load balancer bug&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed dockerfile bug (by @PassiveLemon )&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/tobychui/zoraxy/releases/tag/v3.1.8" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
