<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://selfh.st/apps</id>
  <title>Zoraxy Releases</title>
  <updated>2024-06-01T23:32:44.785305-04:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>selfh.st</name>
    <email>contact@selfh.st</email>
  </author>
  <link href="https://selfh.st/apps" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>Self-hosted software releases generated by selfh.st</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/tobychui/zoraxy/releases/tag/3.0.1</id>
    <title>New release for Zoraxy: Update v3.0.1</title>
    <updated>2024-04-04T03:09:42-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>tobychui/zoraxy</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h2&gt;Update v3.0.1&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This update fixed a few minor bugs from the v3 big updates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Change Log&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added regex support for redirect (slow, don't use it unless you really needs it) #42 &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added new dpcore implementations for faster proxy speed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added support for CF-Connecting-IP to X-Real-IP auto rewrite #114&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added enable / disable of HTTP proxy rules in runtime #108 &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added better 404 page&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added option to bypass websocket origin check #107 &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Updated project homepage design&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed recursive port detection logic&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed UserAgent in resp bug&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Updated minimum required Go version to v1.22 (Notes: Windows 7 support is dropped) #112&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/tobychui/zoraxy/releases/tag/3.0.1" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/tobychui/zoraxy/releases/tag/3.0.2</id>
    <title>New release for Zoraxy: Update v3.0.2</title>
    <updated>2024-04-24T04:28:21-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>tobychui/zoraxy</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h2&gt;Update v3.0.2&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This updates added the new alias hostname function as well as rewritten the access rule set to support per Proxy Hostname access filter architecture. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="圖片" src="https://github.com/tobychui/zoraxy/assets/24617523/9066765f-d41b-439a-884d-8aa8ce1fe166" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To use the alias hostname during creating a new Proxy Rule, use comma to separate the different hostname. Wildcards are also supported in the alias hostname. Here is an example.
&lt;code&gt;main.example.com,*.main.example.com,alias.example.com&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;img alt="圖片" src="https://github.com/tobychui/zoraxy/assets/24617523/eb4f4bd0-c76d-44bd-98d1-6034940cc840" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can also find the alias hostname editor in the HTTP Proxy list (Edit mode)
&lt;img alt="圖片" src="https://github.com/tobychui/zoraxy/assets/24617523/092c0551-d490-4c6a-99c3-dcff1e7e3a0f" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Windows 7 support was restored due to my test bench is still running Windows 7 and I am too busy to upgrade it. If you are still using a Windows 7 machine, you can use the &lt;code&gt;zoraxy_windows_amd64_NT6_1.exe&lt;/code&gt; executable. &lt;strong&gt;Note that Windows 7 support might be discontinued anytime and as it is build with older version of Go compiler, it might also come with some minor security issues.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Change Log&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added alias for HTTP proxy host names #76&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added separator support for create new proxy rules (use "," to add alias when creating new proxy rule)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added HTTP proxy host based access rules #69&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added EAD Configuration for ACME (by @yeungalan) #45 &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed bug for bypassGlobalTLS endpoint do not support basic-auth&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed panic due to empty &lt;code&gt;domain&lt;/code&gt; field in json config #120 &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Removed dependencies on management panel css for online font files&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/tobychui/zoraxy/releases/tag/3.0.2" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/tobychui/zoraxy/releases/tag/3.0.3</id>
    <title>New release for Zoraxy: Update v3.0.3</title>
    <updated>2024-04-30T02:46:30-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>tobychui/zoraxy</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h3&gt;Update v3.0.2&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This update primarily contains bug fixes for many of the issues introduced due to the new implementation of the access filter rule system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Breaking Change&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;For users using SMTP with older versions, you might need to update the settings by moving the domains (the part after @ in the username and domain setup field) into the username field.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Change Log&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Updated SMTP UI for non email login username&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed ACME cert store reload after cert request&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed default rule not applying to default site when default site is set to proxy target&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed blacklist-ip not working with CIDR bug&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed minor vdir bug in tailing slash detection and redirect logic&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added custom mdns name support (-mdnsname flag)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added LAN tag in statistic&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/tobychui/zoraxy/releases/tag/3.0.3" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/tobychui/zoraxy/releases/tag/3.0.4</id>
    <title>New release for Zoraxy: v3.0.4</title>
    <updated>2024-05-18T03:10:12-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>tobychui/zoraxy</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h2&gt;V3.0.4 Updates&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This release tidied up the contribution by @Teifun2 and added a new way to generate DNS challenge based certificate (e.g. wildcards) from Let's Encrypt without changing any environment variables. This also fixes a few previous ACME module EAB settings bug related to concurrent save.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can find the DNS challenge settings under TLS / SSL &amp;gt; ACME snippet &amp;gt; Generate New Certificate &amp;gt; (Check the "Use a DNS Challenge" checkbox)
&lt;img alt="圖片" src="https://github.com/tobychui/zoraxy/assets/24617523/b3fe10e2-93f2-4a68-a1b5-4f24c4a84c05" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Optimized DNS challenge implementation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Removed dependencies on environment variable write and keep all data contained&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed panic on loading certificate generated by Zoraxy v2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added automatic form generator for DNS challenge / providers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added CA name default value&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added code generator for acmedns module (storing the DNS challenge provider contents extracted from lego)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed ACME snippet "Obtain Certificate" concurrent issues in save EAB and DNS credentials&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Remarks: If you are using Windows 7, you can use the NT6-1 release. However, some DNS challenge provider like cpanel and mailinabox are missing from this build due to library &amp;amp; compiler limitations.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks for all the contributors and developers involved testing out the DNS challenge feature 🎉🎉🎉&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/tobychui/zoraxy/releases/tag/3.0.4" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://github.com/tobychui/zoraxy/releases/tag/3.0.5</id>
    <title>New release for Zoraxy: v3.0.5</title>
    <updated>2024-05-26T01:30:29-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>tobychui/zoraxy</name>
    </author>
    <content>&lt;h2&gt;v3.0.5 Updates&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This update mainly fixed the ovh DNS challenge field generator bug and header bug when using NextCloud in container. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a side notes, if you really want to use domain names as proxy target and you have a private DNS server, use &lt;code&gt;.local&lt;/code&gt; (mDNS style), &lt;code&gt;.internal&lt;/code&gt; (docker style) or &lt;code&gt;.home.arpa.&lt;/code&gt; (RFC 8375) as your domain name TLD for internal service. This can help Zoraxy to understand and automatically rewrite headers for internal networking instead of external one and prevent &lt;code&gt;HTTP_HOST&lt;/code&gt; rewrite errors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Remarks: If you are using Windows 7, you can use the NT6-1 release. However, some features are missing from this build due to library &amp;amp; compiler limitations. This version is purely here to support legacy device and might be dropped anytime soon. Please consider to upgrade your server to a new version of Windows.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Change Log&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Optimized uptime monitor error message #121 &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Optimized detection logic for internal proxy target and header rewrite condition for &lt;code&gt;HTTP_HOST&lt;/code&gt; #164 &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed ovh DNS challenge provider form generator bug #161 &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added permission policy module (not enabled)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added single-use cookiejar to uptime monitor request client to handle cookie issues on some poorly written back-end server #149 &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://github.com/tobychui/zoraxy/releases/tag/3.0.5" rel="alternate"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
